


<P ID="1">Despite news of mad cow disease, cattle still being sold in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/30/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Livestock Commission</ENAMEX> held its first sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, since the announcement that a case of mad cow disease had been detected in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. While <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s hastily organized sale can only be reported as fair, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> sales yard officials are feeling a bit more secure about the future of the beef market.
</P><P ID="5">   The livestock sales usually slow down during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> holidays, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s news caused local cattle growers to fear the bottom would fall out of the beef market.
</P><P ID="6">   With uncertainty about the immediate future of beef sales in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Livestock Commission</ENAMEX> officials decided it would close the popular sales yard until further notice.
</P><P ID="7">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>, commission staff members announced the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> sale and any future sales would be canceled until further notice, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Top</ENAMEX>, a commission spokesman.
</P><P ID="8">   Top said the commission was prepared to wait out the news that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>' first case of mad cow disease has been found just 20 miles east of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> on a Mabton dairy farm.
</P><P ID="9">   "We knew there would be a lot of uncertainty in the market following that news," Top said.
</P><P ID="10">   But, at the last minute, responding to a demand for cows, the sales yard owners decided to hold its regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> sale.
</P><P ID="11">   The numerous buyers calling with demands for beef convinced the commission to go ahead with its regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> sale. "We started getting calls from buyers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> needing beef," said Top.
</P><P ID="12">   "So we got on the phones and started calling our suppliers," he explained.
</P><P ID="13">   He said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s market prices were "fair" and just shy of 100 animals passed through the sales arena.
</P><P ID="14">   "We didn't know how many bids we'd get under the circumstances," he said, noting the buyer response was good enough to convince the commission to resume its regular sales schedule.
</P><P ID="15">   Top said the commission will hold its regularly scheduled sales beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   "We'll hold sales <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, like normal," he said.
</P><P ID="17">   "We're feeling better about the situation," he added.
</P><P ID="18">   "Beef is still moving off the grocery counter and processors need cows, so we're going to sell to them," he said.
</P><P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="20">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jsmart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




