
<P ID="1">County commissioner candidates participate in forum
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Councilman Chad Werkhoven served as moderator for a political forum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, which featured candidates running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County commissioner positions.   Three candidates featured at the forum, sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX>, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leita</ENAMEX>, Republican, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erv Wandler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Constitution Party of Yakima</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl S. Lee</ENAMEX>, Democrat. All three candidates are vying for the open position being left by current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County Commissioner Tim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> in district one.   The other candidates <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> were current district two <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay</ENAMEX>, Republican, and Independent candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Swanson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul George</ENAMEX>, Democrat, was unable to be in attendance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   Each of the candidates were given a couple of minutes to introduce themselves.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said he was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> with a business degree.   "I am fully committed to this process," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX>, referring to his commitment to becoming a county commissioner. "We do need new leadership."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> concentrated for a minute on the problems facing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>, especially from the fiscal end. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said to help with the fiscal issues he would promote a business attitude within the county.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandler</ENAMEX> was direct in his comments to the audience <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   "If you elect me, I will never let you down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandler</ENAMEX> smiled.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandler</ENAMEX> said the problem with county government is officials say they hear the problems of the people, but they never address the issues.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>, one of 13 children raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> by his parents, cited his extensive education background as one of the reasons why he should be elected to office.   "I have dealt with every issue," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> said he has dealt with issues from agriculture to education to business in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> for years. One of the areas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> would focus on if elected county commissioner would be to do more grant writing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> believes the county hasn't utilized grants enough.   "I know how to get you money," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> said he also wanted to stress the importance of the county working together with residents.   "The key to a community and success is we all work together," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> is a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>. She has a varied background, which includes working in the agriculture field and running a small business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> was at the forefront fighting several measures government officials in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> tried to implement, including a tax issue that would have cost residents millions of dollars and the formation of a port district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> spoke proudly of how she is not affiliated with any of the parties.   "That is what I bring to the table, an independent voice," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>, a Toppenish resident, spoke about his knowledge of issues facing people in the county, including matters facing farmers, citing his 34 years in the industry.   "I care about what happens to the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>. "I am committed to my job."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> cited the successes of the county commissioners in recent years, including their work in helping bringing in the Wal-Mart distribution center to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   The forum then switched to each of the candidates answering questions from the audience.   One of the first questions focused on the 3/10's of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> sales tax Yakima County Sheriff Ken Irwin is proposing to fund law and justice services and whether the candidates were in favor of the issue.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said commissioners decided to leave the issue of the sales tax to the people, who will vote on the matter in the upcoming election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said the sales tax idea is a viable solution to help with funding law and justice matters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said law and justice eats up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82 percent</NUMEX> of the county's yearly budget.   "This is something I could never vote for," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> said the sales tax issue will take millions of dollars out of the county's economy yearly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> suggested the county look at bombarding the state legislature to get back the 42¢ of every law and justice dollar spent that goes to the state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> said he is not in favor of the tax either. He felt a more productive way to save money would be to eliminate the overtime the county has a problem controlling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> said officers should be rewarded with comp time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> also felt privatization could be utilized with the sheriff's department to save taxpayers millions of dollars.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandler</ENAMEX> said addressing law enforcement would be a priority of his. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandler</ENAMEX> said where the county ran into problems with law and justice was it spent money it didn't have for various programs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said he would support whatever the people decided on the tax. But he wasn't necessarily in favor of the tax, feeling the county was looking at a short-term solution to addressing money problems.   Another question had to do with the county possibly shutting down the parks department.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> felt there is no reason the county should close the parks when it is such a small part of their budget. She felt that parks would be another ideal area for privatization services.   "I am convinced we can keep our parks open," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX>.   "There are many ways to keep the parks open," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> felt the county could work with different training agencies to utilize people to take care of the parks.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandler</ENAMEX> didn't offer much of a suggestion on how to keep the parks open.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> also suggested privatizing to keep the parks system going.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said he felt the commissioners should look else where to make budget cuts before cutting the parks department.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said the county is doing its best to keep the parks department open, but money is tight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said the county is looking at ways to make a profit from the parks.   "We are trying to do the best we can with what we have," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>.   One of the hot topics addressed had to do with the jail debacle the county is currently going through.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said if he was elected commissioner his first order of duty would be to finish construction on the 288-bed jail, the first phase of the project. He would then halt construction and form a committee to examine ways the county allegedly mishandled the jail construction project.   "It is a solution to a problem," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>. "We are going to run out of jail space in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 10 years</TIMEX> and that is a fact."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said the jail project has no fiscal impact on the county's general budget, as it is being paid for with bonds commissioners approved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said the jail project will help the county fiscally.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX> said she would also finish construction on the first phase of the jail project, but halt matters after that. She said the county is going to have financial problems paying for the jail because of the competition for jail space.   "We need to stop and take a whole new look at this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> cited the financial problems the county will have with the jail, which is expected to lose nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> in its first couple of years of operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> said both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tri-Cities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> are working on jail facilities that will cut into the county financially.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wandler</ENAMEX> said he was under the impression the current jail facility was more than adequate for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>. He said he felt the county bit off more than it could chew with the jail project.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

