
<P ID="1">Andean sound coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Alborada, a band with a decided Andean flavor, will be on the stage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium for a Latin music concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 14</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX>   Tickets are still available for the concert, which is the third in the 2003-04 series, hosted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Concert Association</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milo Batista</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lourdes</ENAMEX>, and children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jhoanna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX>, who make-up the group, are skilled in playing more than 30 different instruments from Central and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>.   In addition to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> concert, Alborada will present a outreach musical program to local high school and junior high music students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 15</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> outreach program is sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Education Association</ENAMEX>.   Individual tickets for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s concert will be on sale at the door at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. Series tickets will also be available at the door for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> for students. Series tickets will allow tickets holders to attend the final three season performances of Overholt and Velta on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Kirby</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

