
<P ID="1">Display of 4,000 flags a reminder of the abortions that occur every day
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 3</TIMEX>, after the first of what would ultimately be days of snowfall, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Director Shelley VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> and approximately 20 other volunteers, ranging from middle school students to other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX> staff members, spent the afternoon planting flags in the ground at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   The 4,000 pink and blue flags make up the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">National Sanctity</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Human Life Day</TIMEX> display. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> explained that President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> proclaimed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18, 2004</TIMEX> to be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">National Sanctity</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Human Life Day</TIMEX>, and that the small flags that make up the local display represent the average number of children aborted each day in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said this is the second year the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX> has participated in the national event, which started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> administration</ENAMEX>. She explained that the original idea behind the event was to give people a visual reminder of the value of human life.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said she feels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">National Sanctity</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Human Life Day</TIMEX> is an important event to take part in because it gives people a reason to think about the value of human life. She pointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United State</ENAMEX>'s constitution and noted that it provides for the protection of life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness.   She said there are many people out there who seem to challenge the idea that every life is precious. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said there are some people who think that the life of an unborn child or an elderly or infirmed person isn't as valuable as that of a productive person.   "All expressions of life are extremely valuable," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said.   And it's that idea that lays the foundation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">National Sanctity</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Human Life Day</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said the 4,000-flag display is a way to make people stop, think and examine their feelings on the sanctity of human life.   "That's the whole point of this <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanctity</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Life</ENAMEX> [event]," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said.   The flags will be on display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX> at the corner of Fifth Street and Velma Avenue in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 25</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> a new component has also been added to the display. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said those who are interested can sponsor a flag <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. The cost to sponsor a flag is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VanBuskirk</ENAMEX> said the money will go to support the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX>. For more information on flag sponsorship contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX> at 882-1899 or email the center at lvpc@bentonrea.com.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

