


<P ID="1">Voters urged to test new voting system
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Those voters who didn't get a chance to use <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>'s new eSlate voting system during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s primary election still have a chance to familiarize themselves with the machines before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Auditor's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> has placed two demonstration machines in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. The demonstration machines give voters a chance to walk up to the voting booth, and actually go through the action of casting a demonstration ballot.
</P><P ID="6">   "We felt if we had the machine here, people would feel comfortable coming in here and asking us questions," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Martinez</ENAMEX>, station manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Radio KDNA</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The radio station at 120 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Ave. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> is one of two locations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> where demonstration machines are set up for voters to get a closer look. A voting machine is also set up at Grand Cinemas, located off of Interstate 82 at exit 69 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The machines will be on display at these locations through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 25</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said staff members at the local radio station are bilingual, which is another reason he felt it was important to have a demonstration machine set up in the building.
</P><P ID="9">   The eSlate voting system replaces the county's old punch-card system of voting. The elimination of the punch card system was required through legislation passed by the federal government.
</P><P ID="10">   The eSlate machine is able to serve the general public, voters with disabilities and can provide people with a bilingual ballot.
</P>





 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




