


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> says no to consent agenda
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> cast the lone vote at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting against approval of the consent agenda.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> didn't clarify why he voted against the consent agenda, but his track record shows he does so when there are liquor license renewal requests on the agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> is an advocate for stricter city guidelines on the advertising of alcohol.
</P><P ID="5">   As part of the consent agenda, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approved the liquor license renewal requests for the following <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> establishments: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Edison Food & Deli</ENAMEX>, 1620 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Edison</ENAMEX>; TM Market, 417 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cemetery Road</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safari Restaurant</ENAMEX>, 616 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Edison</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Also on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s consent agenda was the approval of the meeting minutes from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</TIMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="7">Webmaster
</P><P ID="8">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




