
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berkompas</ENAMEX> recognized for theater lighting work
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/25/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SIOUX CENTER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">IOWA</ENAMEX> - A former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> student, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Berkompas</ENAMEX>, has been honored for her work in the theater while attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dordt College</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berkompas</ENAMEX> is one of four Dordt students who recently received notification she was given a commendation from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">National Selection Team</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennedy Center American College Theatre Festival</ENAMEX> for her work on the university's fall production of "All My Sons."   Nationwide, only 53 college productions received this recognition for special achievement in production for the 2001-02 academic year.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berkompas</ENAMEX> was cited for her work as lighting technician.   "All My Sons" was just the second show in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dordt College</ENAMEX>'s history to be invited to perform at the Region 5 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College Theatre Festival</ENAMEX>, which is made up of undergraduate and graduate theatre programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Dakota</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Dakota</ENAMEX>.   "I think that the commendation to all of us reflects the positive assessment of what we do as a department in a small college," said the director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dordt College</ENAMEX> play, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeri Schelhaas</ENAMEX>.   Also honored from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dordt College</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schelhaas</ENAMEX> for program development and production achievement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Olsen</ENAMEX> for his performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Deever</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Persenaire</ENAMEX> for her performance as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Deever</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

