


<P ID="1">Candidate for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>'s seat addresses <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> club
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">There are several issues that Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed Davis</ENAMEX>, a candidate running for the U.S. Senate seat currently filled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Patty Murray</ENAMEX>, feels very strongly about. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), during a quick stop over in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> was given a chance to talk about the different issues that make up his campaign.
</P><P ID="5">   The guest speaker at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said he feels spending is the key issue during this election season.
</P><P ID="6">   "This <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is the most expense <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> next to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LBJ</ENAMEX>'s," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said, noting that in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX> discretionary spending has increased 25 to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "I'm a deficit hawk," he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said he believes all of the spending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> is doing will ultimately mean passing a huge debt on to the nation's children and grandchildren.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said he also feels that the spending that has been going on is affecting the Social Security system.
</P><P ID="9">   "Social Security is going broke," he said. "We need to fix Social Security, but we can't until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> quits spending."
</P><P ID="10">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, one way to curb the spending he feels is happening is for voters to elect "...congressmen and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> who are committed to fiscal responsibility."
</P><P ID="11">   When it comes to Social Security reform, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said he supports a plan being proposed that would allow younger workers to put their Social Security taxes in a personal investment account.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said another important issue is the marriage amendment recently proposed by President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "I support the marriage amendment," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said. "I think most Americans believe a strong family is the foundation of everything in American society."
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> added that one of the problems with civil unions of any kind is that they tend to end in separation at two to three times the rate of marriages. He said these separations can have a devastating effect on children.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> is running against Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> for the Republican nomination to run for the U.S. Senate currently held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maple Valley</ENAMEX>, is an associate professor at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Pacific University</ENAMEX>, where he teaches classes on political science.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said he decided to run for the senate seat because he is alarmed by the spending that is going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. He said having taught classes on federal budgeting and publishing both a book and different articles on public policy, as well as having served as the chair of the King <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Republican Party</ENAMEX> for eight years, he feels he is ready to take on a race for the senate.
</P><P ID="18">   "I think Republicans will be grateful to have a choice in this primary," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said. "I think it's time to get someone in there with credibility when it comes to fiscal responsibility."
</P>





 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




