


<P ID="1">Open Mike
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">In case you didn't know, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was perhaps the most important election to take place in recent memory, at least since the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin D. Roosevelt</ENAMEX> days.
</P><P ID="5">   Like many, I woke up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> trying to figure out what went on.
</P><P ID="6">   I am trying to figure out if we should still have faith in Democracy. Do we really know what is best for us as a society or should we have all voted for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>. I spent the night asking myself how difficult is it to count a vote? It is not rocket science.
</P><P ID="7">   The biggest issue <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> is that there is still not officially a president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. I mean, President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> all but has the election in the bag, but the little state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX> is keeping us hanging. Votes are still being counted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX>, where over 200,000 jobs were lost during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s first term. It may be days before those votes are officially tabulated and a president is named, as both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> strive to get the necessary 270 electoral votes.
</P><P ID="8">   I don't understand American voters.
</P><P ID="9">   Why re-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>? The economy is in the toilet. We are at war in a foreign country that doesn't really want us there and our national debt is only getting larger as we speak. In another year, we could all be collecting welfare and hoping we can pay our light bill because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> just doesn't have a plan to get us back on track. To better illustrate what I am trying to say is that the light bulb is just not on for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and it is only going to get worse over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next four years</TIMEX>. Remember this, I told you so.
</P><P ID="10">   Let's look at some other election day issues.
</P><P ID="11">   One <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state issue that I found interesting was Initiative 884, which had to do with the creation of an education trust fund that would have pumped more money into education. I voted against this issue and I am glad the measure failed at the polls. The reason I am against this issue is that schools aren't putting out smarter kids. It doesn't matter how much money we throw at the schools, the job isn't getting done. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> districts complain there isn't enough money to better the education for our children. Teachers complain they aren't getting paid enough money, but yet these are people who have one of the most desirable work schedules you will find. Who wouldn't want to work a six-hour day, only work 180 days out of each year and get to work with children? As a parent, I am not getting the bang for my buck from the educational system and I won't support any more initiatives, taxes or anything else that allocates more money until school districts start performing.
</P><P ID="12">   I also voted against charter schools. Do we really need more oars in the water. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> districts have a hard enough time adequately teaching our children now. Why add more confusion to the process?
</P><P ID="13">   I didn't know anything about Initiative 297 heading to the polls, but who can really argue with a matter that allows for hazardous waste to be cleaned up.
</P><P ID="14">   I was disappointed to see the issue with slot machines fail. I wanted something to do with my spare change. There is something all these people who are against gambling haven't realized. People who want to gamble are going to gamble. Why not put it close to home, instead of making me travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pendleton</ENAMEX>. Wait, I guess I can go to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob and Sue Rice</ENAMEX>'s new establishment out by the golf course and support <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> with my money while having a fantastic steak dinner.
</P><P ID="15">   Well, people, we really screwed up this election. I can hardly wait until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> seats are up for grabs.
</P><P ID="16">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




