


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> inches closer to being named governor
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Exactly who will be leading the state in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is still up in the air, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Christine Gregoire</ENAMEX> has seen her lead increase since ballots were first counted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Tuesday</TIMEX>'s general election.
</P><P ID="5">   According to the latest ballot counts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> has taken nearly an 18,000 vote lead over her opponent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican Dino Rossi</ENAMEX>, who had 1,062,427 votes as of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="6">   When votes were first being tabulated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> was in the lead, but less than 1,000 votes separated the two candidates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> was listed as having <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48.96 percent</NUMEX> of the vote, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48.94 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> is in the lead with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49.35 percent</NUMEX> of the vote and 1,080,382 ballots marked in her favor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> is listed as having <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48.53 percent</NUMEX> of the vote.
</P><P ID="8">   Since initial counts were reported by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, little has changed in other races that affect residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Democrat Patty Murray has maintained her commanding lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican George R. Nethercutt</ENAMEX> in the U.S. Senate race. As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53.9 percent</NUMEX> of the vote, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   In the race for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Representative, although more votes have been counted, things remain very similar to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s initial results. Republican Doc Hastings is still in the lead with 120,444 votes, compared to 65,998 votes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Sandy Matheson</ENAMEX>. It was reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hastings</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.6 percent</NUMEX> of the vote, versus <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37.7 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX>. Those numbers have moved very little with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hastings</ENAMEX> maintaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.73 percent</NUMEX> of the vote and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX> having <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37.26 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   In the races for the 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Legislative District</ENAMEX> positions, Representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX>, who ran unopposed for the position one seat, received 12,369 votes. In the race between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Michael H. Kepcha</ENAMEX> for position two, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> has increased his lead since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>. As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> had 10,073 votes, which is up from the 8,866 votes that had been tallied in his favor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX>, as of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, had 4,426 votes, up a few votes since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s 4,023 vote tally.
</P><P ID="12">   When it comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican Mike Leita</ENAMEX> still has a commanding lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Earl S. Lee</ENAMEX> in the race for the district one seat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> has received 35,209 votes, compared to 14,852 votes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>. In the race for the district two seat, Republican and incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay</ENAMEX> has increased his initial lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Paul George</ENAMEX>. It was reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> held a more than 6,000 vote lead over the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> mayor. As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, his lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> was sitting at 7,907 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> now holds <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48.32 percent</NUMEX> of the vote, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33.48 percent</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   Maintaining their leads, which were announced following initial vote counts, are Lt. Governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Owen</ENAMEX>, Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Murphy</ENAMEX> for state treasurer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Sonntog</ENAMEX> for state auditor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob McKenna</ENAMEX> for state attorney general and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Bergeson</ENAMEX> for state superintendent of public instruction.
</P><P ID="14">   Results also remain the same <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Wednesday</TIMEX>'s initial report of the outcome of several initiatives and measures.
</P><P ID="15">   Election results won't be certified by county canvassing boards until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 17</TIMEX>, with the Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> certifying results sometime before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




