


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> proposes publicly condemning councilmen who owe back taxes, fees
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> presented at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting a proposed amendment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> rules of procedure. The amendment is not set to be discussed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> until the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> provided audience members with a brief explanation as to why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> adopts a set of rules to abide by. He said about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> adopted the rules of procedure. One of the problems the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was facing at the time was low attendance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said once the rules for attendance were adopted it made a big difference amongst the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "Since we have a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> coming in, I would like to set a high standard for ourselves," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s proposed amendment to the rules of procedure concerns councilmen and any public debt they might incur.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> presented his proposed amendment to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in a handout.
</P><P ID="9">   "One of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> member's primary responsibilities is the formation and approval of the city budget," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> wrote in his proposal. "This includes determining city spending and revenue. It is incumbent on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members to lead by example."
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members need to lead by example, especially when dealing with finances for residents.
</P><P ID="11">   "It is hypocritical for a (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>) member to vote on taxes and fees when they themselves are delinquent on those taxes and fees," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> further elaborated.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> outlined a set of steps to be taken if it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s attention that any member is more than 60 days delinquent on any <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city tax or fee or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> property tax bill. The steps include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s vote on a resolution of censure within two regular meetings of discovering the issue. The resolution of censure will also include all the information on the delinquent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member's bill. Once the resolution is passed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, which will only require a simple majority, the censure will become an agenda item on every <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting agenda until the delinquent bill is paid. If the delinquent bill is owed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the member's stipend will be withheld until the bill is brought current.
</P><P ID="13">   Council members receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> per every regular meeting held.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX> asked Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> if city residents will have an opportunity to discuss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s proposed amendment at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX> meeting. The mayor said he would provide the public with ample time for input.
</P><P ID="15">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




