
<P ID="1">Grizzlies maul the Wolves in Homecoming game
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A fumble prone second half was about the only drawback for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football team in this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s Homecoming game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>.   The two-headed monster of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX> did most of the damage for the Grizzlies, as they helped record a commanding 42-21 victory over the Wolfpack.   "I thought we played well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Mark Marro</ENAMEX>, "but we didn't hold onto the ball."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> got on the board early in the game when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> returned an interception 40 yards for a touchdown. The Grizzlies' other early score came in the first quarter when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> popped off a 20-yard touchdown run.   The fun for Grizzly fans didn't stop with the end of the first quarter, as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> scored twice in the second period. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> scored both second quarter touchdowns, one off a one-yard run and the other a 22-yard pass from quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cantu</ENAMEX>.   The Wolfpack was able to sustain a drive in the second quarter that led to a touchdown, when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Pitt</ENAMEX> found receiver <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark McDaniel</ENAMEX> on a five-yard pass.   The second half was sort of a different story for the Grizzlies, as they didn't look anything like they did in the opening two quarters.   The second half saw the Grizzlies fumble three times inside the Wolfpack's 20-yard line.   "We can't afford to cough up the ball," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> took advantage of the slippery hands of the Grizzlies in the second half.   The Wolfpack drove nearly the length of the field in the third quarter to see the drive end on a one-yard touchdown run from Art Weaver.   With the score 28-14, the Grizzlies got back to pounding the ball on the ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> scored on a four-yard touchdown run in the fourth quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammate Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX> added a 17-yard touchdown run to account for the final score.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Clements</ENAMEX> gave the Wolfpack its last score when he ran past the Grizzly defense on a 74-yard touchdown run.   The Grizzlies did a nice job of keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>'s defense guessing. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was able to mix in an effective passing game with a dominating run attack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> went 10-for-16 on the night through the air for 186 yards.   "We wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> to throw the ball," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "We are going to need him to throw the ball in the next couple of weeks."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said he was impressed with the way <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> played, as the Wolfpack was putting some hard hits on the Grizzlies.   "They have steadily gotten better," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> was also impressed with the play of his offensive line, which opened holes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> all night.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> ended up rushing for 158 yards on 24 carries while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> had 101 yards off 14 totes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> also had two receptions for 67 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> set a new school record for most points scored in a game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> scored 30 points on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, breaking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Coleman</ENAMEX>'s record set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> of 26 points against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley-Spokane</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> also tied the record with a host of other players for most rushing touchdowns in a game with three.   One <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> player who performed extremely well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe Zamarron</ENAMEX>, who was both a force on the offensive and defensive sides of the ball. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zamarron</ENAMEX> had three catches for 52 yards.   "He has great hands," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe</ENAMEX> is an exceptional athlete."   The only drawback in the game that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> saw was the fumbles by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the second half. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> also felt his defensive unit could have done a better job of tackling in the second half.   "We missed a lot of tackles," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   Besides the fumbles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> felt his team did an exceptional job of playing the game.   "We got pretty much what we expected from the players," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> (2-2, 4-3) will be without the services of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> for a crucial <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> match-up at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> was ejected late from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s game for an altercation with a Wapato player.   "It is always a tough place to play at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "I am excited about the game."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> is a must win if <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> wants to stay in playoff contention.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

