
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> approves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50.1 million</NUMEX> budget
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> unanimously approved a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50.1 million</NUMEX> budget for the 2004-05 school year. The newly approved budget is an increase over the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45.6 million</NUMEX> budget school board members approved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   Although budget expenditures are greater <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, so is the amount of revenue the district is expecting to bring in during the 2004-05 school year. According to the new budget the district is expecting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$51.9 million</NUMEX> in revenue for the year, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$47.9 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Plesha</ENAMEX>, executive director of business for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, explained that one of the reasons for that increase is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> grant for which the district applied. He noted that the grant would make the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Secondary Education of Migrant Youth (SEMY) location the keeper of the national database for migrant students. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> explained that even if the district ends up not receiving the grant it is something that had to budgeted for, just in case the district is selected.   Also increased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is the number of students expected to walk through the doors of the schools that make up the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s enrollment is expected to increase by approximately 48 students. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the district is expecting to have 5,442 students enrolled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools, which is up from the 5,394 that attended classes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> also pointed out there are 34 students expected to take advantage of the Running Start program, which allows students to attend classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> while still being a student at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   Often times when there is an increase in the number of students, there is also an increase in the number of teachers and other school staff members, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is no different. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> plans to employ 364 certified staff members and 230 classified staff members. This is an increase of seven certified staff members over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, and an increase of 10 classified staff members.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> noted that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s budget reflects only a few small raises for district staff members holding certain positions. He explained that the state allowed for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> pay rate increase for classified staff members. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> also pointed out that teachers will be receiving anywhere from no raise to a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> raise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> depending on how many years they have been teaching and whether or not they earned any college credits over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> noted that the state also granted no raise for administrators <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   When it comes to the capital projects fund, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> explained that the entire amount of the bond issue recently passed by voters is included in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.4 million</NUMEX> budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> money from the capital projects fund will help get the new middle school project started. The new school is expected to be constructed on land located along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said although the entire amount to the bond is in the budget, he is only expecting to spend about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   The transportation vehicle fund is also seeing an increase in funding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. According to the budget, the fund totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$784,600</NUMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$767,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the debt service fund shows a slight increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> total expenditures are budgeted at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 million</NUMEX> compared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.31 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   The dollar amounts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Student Body Fund</ENAMEX> only shifted by roughly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the budget is set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$517,801</NUMEX>, which is a little more than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$510,710</NUMEX> budgeted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

