
<P ID="1">Tragedy strikes
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A shooting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> has left an 11-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girl dead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood police</ENAMEX> officers responded to a shooting incident at 713 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Fourth Street</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Ortiz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX> said the initial call had officers responding to an attempted break-in at the residence.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX> confirmed the name of the victim at the scene <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nala Hernandez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX> said that officers arrived at the scene to find <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> with a gunshot wound to her forehead.   "It is tragic," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX>. "It was something that could have been prevented."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX> said the incident is even more tragic since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> had only turned 11 years old on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 22</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> was transported to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>. She was later taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harborview Medical Center</ENAMEX> in Seattle, where she died later in the evening.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> and her 16-year-old brother and 14-year-old cousin were not in school. The place where the incident occurred is the residence of the 14-year-old cousin, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX>.   It is believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> was shot in the forehead with a small caliber handgun by her cousin, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX> had limited information on the case <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> as it is being handled by the detective unit within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>.   The initial report given by the two boys is that someone was trying to break-in to the residence. That report was proven wrong upon further questioning, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX>'s cousin was taken into custody and is currently being held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Juvenile Detention Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX>'s 16-year-old brother is not in custody.   According to representatives of the juvenile division of the Yakima County Prosecutor's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX>'s cousin was to have had a preliminary hearing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 p.m.</TIMEX> The cousin has not officially been charged yet, according to officials at the prosecutor's office. Prosecutors did say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> has requested first degree manslaughter charges against the cousin.   In response to the incident, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> implemented its lockdown protocol. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hughes</ENAMEX>, director of safe and effective schools, said each building went into lockdown sometime between 1:30 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> Under the lockdown procedures, students were confined to the school buildings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> said the district has had such protocol in place for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>, as part of its crisis management plan.   "We just react to situations as we feel is necessary," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> said in such cases as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s shooting the district implemented the lockdown to ensure the safety of district students.   The school district is offering counseling services to students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> was a sixth grade student. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> has been a student in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> since she was in kindergarten and has a lot of friends who may need counseling.   .
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

