
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> ACT scores within national average
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Even though only 24 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> juniors and seniors took the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American College Test</ENAMEX> (ACT) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>, the students' combined average on the test fell within the national averages, according to local school officials.   "More of our students take the more recognized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SAT</TIMEX> test," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Kilian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> counselor. But of the 24 students who took the ACT <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>, the average score was 20.8 on the test, she said.   The national average is 20.9. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students' average was slightly below the state average of 22.5.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> was ranked among the top three states in the nation for outstanding performance on the ACT. Only <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vermont</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maine</ENAMEX> ranked higher than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Bergeson</ENAMEX>, the state superintendent of public instruction.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> said the state's results from the ACT is a strong indication that the work being done in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> schools is better preparing students for life after college.   "I'm particularly pleased to see that, as more of our diverse students participate in this test, our scores remain high. This is truly a success story we can be proud of in our state," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> said.   ACT is one of two widely recognized exams used to gauge readiness for college. While not a required state assessment tool, the ACT, like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SAT</TIMEX>, measures a student's readiness for college in English, reading, math and science. Scores are given on a scale of 1 to 36 with 36 being the best possible score.   "Our students earned scores from 13 to 29," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>.   Mirroring the national increase in participation, more <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> graduates are choosing to take the ACT.   "We are seeing more of our students taking the ACT," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said.   Nevertheless, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SAT</TIMEX> remains the most popular of the college readiness exams taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students, she added.   "It (the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">SAT</TIMEX>) is just the test most students are more familiar with as a pre-college exam requirement," she explained.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

