


<P ID="1">Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> company faces L&I fines
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PASCO</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Department of Labor & Industries</ENAMEX> issued citations <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasco's Paragon Construction Co.</ENAMEX> for six alleged work place safety violations at an underground utility installation project in the Tri-Cities. The citations carry a combined penalty of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$245,700</NUMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">Five "willful" violations and one "serious" violation were issued on charges of exposing workers to serious injury or death from cave-in hazards while working in trenches as deep as 30 feet in "type C" soil. L&I officials maintain the company repeatedly failed to use proper shoring, sloping or shielding protections during work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last October</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">"This is the most dangerous trench work I've ever seen," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reuel Paradis</ENAMEX>, L&I regional administrator for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>. "We're very fortunate nobody was killed or seriously injured."
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Paragon Construction Co.</ENAMEX> has 15 business days to appeal the citations.
</P>

 


<P ID="9">Enticing investors topic of workshop
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - Technology firms can learn how to present to investors at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Technology Center</ENAMEX>'s Tri-Cities Eye of the Investor Workshop.
</P>

<P ID="11">The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 9</TIMEX>, workshop will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest National Laboratory</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> Attendees will learn from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alliance of Angels</ENAMEX> professionals about how to present to investors, with two local case studies included.
</P>

<P ID="12">Those interested in attending the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> workshop, lunch included, should contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Small Business Development Center</ENAMEX> (509-735-6222).
</P>

 


<P ID="13">‘Friends of Scouting’ breakfast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob McKenna</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Metropolitan</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Council</ENAMEX> member, will be the guest speaker at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> "Friends of Scouting" breakfast to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday, May 13</TIMEX>. The 6:45 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> breakfast will be held at the newly constructed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15">The annual event is designed to heighten the awareness of Scouting within the community, and provide an opportunity for community members to contribute to the fund-raising campaign. Those community members interested in attending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s fund-raiser can reserve a seat by calling 839-8066.
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKenna</ENAMEX>, who has earned Eagle Scout status, has served on the King <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Council</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1996</TIMEX>. He is also a sitting member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Transportation Investment District Executive Board</ENAMEX>, and was the co-founder of the King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Transportation Coalition</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17">The special honoree at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> breakfast will be Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>, superintendent of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s public schools.
</P>

 


<P ID="18">Open government topic of meeting set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - If open government in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state is important to you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> is the place to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Wednesday</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="20">Government, media and legal experts will meet from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, May 12</TIMEX>, to discuss and clarify <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s open public meetings and open records laws. The meeting will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Technical Institute</ENAMEX> auditorium.
</P>

<P ID="21">"Through legislation like the Open Public Meetings Act and our public records laws, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> lawmakers have made it clear that the public's business needs to be conducted in an open manner," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Balmelli</ENAMEX>, news director for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KAPP-TV</ENAMEX>, one of the sponsors of the event.
</P>

<P ID="22">"Unfortunately, these laws have sometimes set up confrontations between agencies and the public they serve.
</P>

<P ID="23">"We hope this meeting will help all parties better understand their rights and responsibilities in this important arena," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balmelli</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

<P ID="24"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima Herald-Republic Publisher Michael Shepard</ENAMEX> said he hopes this meeting will help demystify the state's very good, but sometimes tricky access laws. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shepard</ENAMEX> said the public is not only invited, but is being encouraged to attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P>

<P ID="25">The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12</TIMEX> meeting is being co-sponsored by several <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> news media agencies, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




