
<P ID="1">Kindergarten parent orientation evenings set
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Realizing that the first day of school can be exciting and scary for the parents of kindergarten children, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parent Information Resource Center</ENAMEX> is hosting a series of parent orientation meetings beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 19</TIMEX>.   The meetings, to be held at each of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s elementary schools, will cover such topics as the importance of attendance and tardiness. Other topics will include how to prepare children for school and monitoring of their homework, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yesenia Rodriguez</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parent Resource Center</ENAMEX>.   She said issues, such as bus routes, student insurance and lunches, will also be covered.   The first orientation meeting will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 19</TIMEX>, for parents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> kindergartners at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Aug. 24</TIMEX>, the parent meeting will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX>, also at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> The parents of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> kindergarten students are invited to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 26</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>   The meetings are being provided jointly by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parent Information Resource Center</ENAMEX>.         
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

