


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Library</ENAMEX> says no to Initiative 864
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">In an effort to prevent further cuts in revenues, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> will host an informational meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>. The meeting, to be chaired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Weyhe</ENAMEX>, executive director of the regional library system, will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Masonic Hall.
</P><P ID="4">   "We are hoping to educate voters to the devastating impact further tax rollbacks will have on the state's library system," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Saunders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> public librarian.
</P><P ID="5">   She said people's Initiative 864, being proposed by tax activist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Eyman</ENAMEX>, is being distributed in an effort to collect enough signatures to be placed on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> ballot.
</P><P ID="6">   "We are asking people to forego signing the initiative petition, in order to keep it from being placed on the ballot," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="7">   She encourages the public to attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s informational meeting.
</P><P ID="8">   "If the measure gets on the ballot, we fear voters will see it as yet another tax saving measure. But the long term impact will be that poor counties, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, will be losing services.
</P><P ID="9">   "This is not a manner of being thrifty," she said. "It's a manner of closing libraries," she said.
</P>   






 










<P ID="10">Webmaster
</P><P ID="11">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




