


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX> gives city ambulance service preferential treatment
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/21/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> took a major step at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting to ensure that area residents will continue to have a quality ambulance service.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> approved an agreement with the hospital that gives the city the right of first refusal for responding to patient calls.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said the city and the hospital currently didn't have such an agreement in place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the benefit for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is that the city gets the first opportunity to service patients, resulting in extra revenue for coffers. The benefit for the hospital, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>, is that patients will benefit from the close proximity of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> ambulance service.
</P><P ID="7">   The term of the agreement is for 10 years. There are a couple of exemptions, noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>. First, patients do have the right to request another ambulance service. The other exemption is that patients can be transferred for immediate care if needed, even if they were transported to the hospital by another ambulance service.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> Chief Executive Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Smiley</ENAMEX> was on hand at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting. He had a written report available for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. In his report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> said the hospital has long been a supporter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> ambulance service. The hospital has made past contributions totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55,000</NUMEX> to the city to start the current ambulance service. The written report also stated the hospital board of trustees has a concern with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wanting to privatize the ambulance service.
</P><P ID="9">   "The board of trustees and members of the medical staff are concerned that should <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> decide to privatize the ambulance service, there will be a diminishment of quality and availability," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> wrote. "Both entities have a responsibility to serve those in need of medical care in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> goes on to highlight that the hospital staff is very pleased with the work done by the city's ambulance personnel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX>'s report also expressed concerns about the city losing ground with its fire protection rating, which means increased fire insurance premiums for businesses and citizens. The city currently has a level five fire protection rating. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX> wrote in his report if the city does privatize the ambulance service that rating would fall to a level six, resulting in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7-1/2 percent</NUMEX> increase in fire insurance premiums.
</P><P ID="11">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> said he was glad the city and the hospital could work together in such a manner.
</P><P ID="12">   "If we work together, we can benefit both the citizens and the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smiley</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




