18 10 10 24 14 32
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  The name of peace is sweet, and the thing itself is beneficial, but there is a great difference between peace and servitude. Peace is freedom in tranquillity, servitude is the worst of all evils, to be resisted not only by war, but even by death.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cicero</ENAMEX> (106 BC - 43 BC)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>