


<P ID="1">Commissioner needed
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Interested in helping shape the direction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s parks and recreation programs? Then you're needed as on the seven-member <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   "We currently have a vacancy on the commission, created when former Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andie Bieber</ENAMEX> located out of the area," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Stiles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> director.
</P><P ID="5">   For the past several months, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has been unable to hold a meeting due to a lack of a quorum, he said.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said while the search for a new commissioner has been underway for several months, only one application has been submitted.
</P><P ID="7">   "We'd like to see a few more potential candidates before a decision is made," he explained.
</P><P ID="8">   The commission members are appointed by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, he added.
</P><P ID="9">   Commissioners meet once a month to hear reports about parks and recreation department programs. "Commissioners offer recommendations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> concerning parks and recreation budgetary and program needs," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   "The time commitment for candidates is the once a month meeting held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX> on the third <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> of the month," he explained.
</P><P ID="11">   Persons interested in volunteering their time to oversee <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s diverse youth and adult recreation programs and park facilities may pick up an application at the city parks and recreation office, 818 E. Edison Ave.
</P>   






 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




