
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/26/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
‘How’s Bayou’in Yakima <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Billed as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>'s leader in Cajun music, "How's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bayou</ENAMEX>" will appear in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 2</TIMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Hall</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX>.
The performance is part of the Yakima Folklife Concert Series. Tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> for children, will be available at the door of the museum that evening. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX> concert will get underway at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
"How's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bayou</ENAMEX>" offers an evening of red hot Cajun music, coupled with the genre of Zydeco and Swamp Pop.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Basket show public reception <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 4</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - A public reception to help kick off the Invitational Contemporary Baskets Show will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland's Allied Arts Association Gallery</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 4</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX>
The gallery is located at the entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Howard Amon Park</ENAMEX>, 89 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Blvd.</ENAMEX>
The curator of the show is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Metcallf</ENAMEX>, a well known <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> artist, designer and craftsman. The exhibition will feature 18 regional and nationally known artists working in traditional basket techniques of twining, plating, coiling, lamination and stitching.
Some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> artists who will have their work featured in the show include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Nordfors Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Metcalf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">C.A. Michel</ENAMEX>. Also, nationally known artists such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Abrams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Filippelli</ENAMEX> and Helen Frost Way will present their new visions of old crafts.
Basket lovers from the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> will be able to enjoy the art works in their traditional container forms of baskets, along with more sculptural approaches.
</P> 
<P ID="5">NPR journalist coming to Yakima
YAKIMA - Nationally renowned broadcast journalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Stamberg</ENAMEX> will discuss the importance as such legendary artists as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Hemingway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elia Kazan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georgia O'Keefe</ENAMEX>, when she comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stamberg</ENAMEX>, a special correspondent for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Public Radio</ENAMEX>, will be the guest speaker in the Yakima Town Hall lecture series to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, April 14</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at the Capitol Theatre.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stamberg</ENAMEX>, who has been awarded every major honor in broadcasting, serves as the guest host of National Public Radio's Morning Edition, Weekend Edition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and the Weekly Edition, specializing in cultural issues.
To purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Town Hall</ENAMEX> tickets call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Linneweh</ENAMEX> at (509) 966-3006.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Woodinville wineries host tasting event
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodinville</ENAMEX> - The annual "Passport to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodinville</ENAMEX>" will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 3</TIMEX> and 4 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodinville Wine Country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Washington</ENAMEX>.
The weekend will include tours of the area's 14 wineries from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, of which many are not normally open to the public.
Passports to attend the event are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>, giving ticket holders entrance admission, a commemorative glass and a keepsake passport filled with wine labels.
To purchase passports call (425) 424-2902. For more information about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> wine tasting tours  visit woodinvillewinecountry.com.
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

