
<P ID="1">Grizzlies say goodbye to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> playoff picture
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football team had its postseason hopes dashed this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> with a 20-0 loss to the Bulldogs.   But despite postseason aspirations having to wait another season, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Mark Marro</ENAMEX> is hoping his team can muster up some pride as the Grizzlies will try to finish with a winning season.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> (2-3, 4-4) will finish <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>. The Grizzlies will then end the regular season at home the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following week</TIMEX> against the fifth seed out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX>.   The shutout loss to the Bulldogs has more of a story than the final score might indicate.   "We played with a lot of young guys," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>) got a gift."   Due to injuries and other reasons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> had to go into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> with several of his younger players, who aren't used to performing at this level.   "Overall, I thought we played phenomenal," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "We were thin, but we played hard."   Grizzly fans might be inspired by the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> led the game just 7-0 with about four minutes to go.   One performance that stood out for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was the play of B.J. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>, who played safety with a cast on his hand.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the Grizzly offense was able to put together several offensive threats throughout the game, driving down inside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s 20-yard line on a couple of occasions, but could never finish off a drive.   "We had our shots at it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   The offense was a bit troubled with the absence of one of its stars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> had to miss the game after an altercation during Homecoming with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>. The duties in the backfield were mainly left to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> ran the ball hard, but it is hard when you are by yourself," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said his defense did well on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. He said his defensive line was pounding <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   "The linebackers did a really good job," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> is looking forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX>'s game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> have a new addition to their coaching staff this season in former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyhound</ENAMEX> head coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Purdom</ENAMEX>, who is heading up the defense.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> is a lot like us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "They throw the ball minimally and they just run the ball at you."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the Grizzlies should be at full force <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> with everyone in the line-up.   "Now it is about pride," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   .
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

