


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton City Council</ENAMEX> considers fencing change
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton City Councilman Ernesto Armendariz</ENAMEX> has his way, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> residents will have the option of building six-foot tall fences in their front yards.
</P><P ID="5">   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> residents are restricted to installing four-foot fences in their front yards with options for taller fences in side and back yards.
</P><P ID="6">   Even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton City Council</ENAMEX>, meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, tabled the proposed fencing ordinance change, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armendariz</ENAMEX> thinks its time to change the height requirement.
</P><P ID="7">   "It's a matter of security," said the councilman, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> was forced to lower his own six-foot fence because of the town's ordinance.
</P><P ID="8">   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Reynolds</ENAMEX> feels lower fences in the front yard help police and other emergency workers in their jobs.
</P><P ID="9">   "Higher fences will slow them down in getting to the scenes of fires or other emergencies," he said.
</P><P ID="10">   "I don't think we should change the ordinance," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reynolds</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed to take home the ordinance to review. They will discuss it again at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX> meeting, said Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="13">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




