
<P ID="1">Police nab six teens at busted party
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/15/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Six teens were cited for minor in possession and/or consumption of alcohol <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early Sunday morning</TIMEX> when a large party was busted in the 100 block of NW Crescent Avenue.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> Capt. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Bank</ENAMEX>, officers were called to a loud teen party just after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 a.m. Sunday morning</TIMEX>.   "When officers arrived kids were running everywhere," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>.   Officers were able to catch six of the party-goers.   An 18-year-old was arrested and charged with minor in possession and/or consumption of alcohol. He was one of the youths police arrested just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> graduation. At the time, nine students, were apprehended by police on various charges, including trespassing on school property, possessing and consuming alcohol, and drug possession. The school district chose to allow the teens caught at that time to walk in graduation, pending good behavior the rest of the school year.   Also cited early this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> were five minors under the age of 18, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>. They will be facing charges of minor in possession and/or consumption in juvenile court.   Three of the young men cited are 17 years old. A 16-year-old male and female were also cited.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> said, at this time, it appears that none of the teens arrested and cited actually lived at the address. He said the department will be looking into who hosted the party.   "We've been aggressively targeting teen drinking parties. When we hear of them we do our best to arrest as many as possible," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> added.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

