


<P ID="1">Planning for new aquatic center continues
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The compiled results of the nearly 300 surveys concerning a new aquatic center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> proposal were reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   According to Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX>, some of the most important services members of the community desire are swim lessons, open swim, family swim and parent-taught classes. Also scoring high was picnicking. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said the zero-depth portion of the pool, which would be a pool experience much like going to the ocean, was also looked upon positively by those surveyed, as were water slides and a competition pool tank. Also important to potential users is a playground area.
</P><P ID="6">   The surveys were collected over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> to help the board focus on what the community would like to see in a new aquatic center. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said they received completed surveys from pool users, senior citizens, service club members and residents at-large.
</P><P ID="7">   According to the survey, of those surveyed at the swimming pool 122 people would vote in favor of a bond for a new pool. Four said they would not vote for an aquatic center and five were undecided, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>. Of the business persons who completed the survey, 15 said they would vote in favor of a bond to pay for the new aquatic center. One said they would not support the venture. Of the senior citizens who returned surveys, two said they would vote in favor of a new pool and two said they would vote against it. Ten of the surveys returned from service groups indicated they would vote in favor of the bond. Three service group members were undecided. Fifty-two members of the community at-large said they would support a bond for a new aquatic center and six said they would not vote in favor of the bond, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "That's huge," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview City Councilwoman Pam Horner</ENAMEX>, who sits on the board, speaking of the support that was indicated in the surveys.
</P><P ID="9">   Board chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Copeland</ENAMEX> said that a concern he has heard in recent days is where the playing fields will be located when the new aquatic center is built on what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Park</ENAMEX>, which is located on the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Road</ENAMEX> and W. Second Street.
</P><P ID="10">   "We need to be very sensitive to the things that are being displaced at that park," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   Currently there are two softball fields, tennis courts and soccer fields at the park, all of which are used on a regular basis.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> has developed two additional ball fields, which should meet the softball needs of the community. He added that there may be room at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Country Park</ENAMEX> and Fairgrounds for a soccer field.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said that working with the school district they may be able to find other fields that can be utilized for some of the sports programs.
</P><P ID="14">   Another concern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> has heard regards congestion in the area.
</P><P ID="15">   "I thought it was one of the better locations," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> added.
</P><P ID="16">   The board members agreed that with the traffic lights and widened streets the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Park</ENAMEX> area is the best place for the aquatic center. He added that the location is also the most visible since anyone going to a middle school or high school ballgame in town has to pass by the park.
</P><P ID="17">   The park and rec service area board spent the majority of the meeting in a teleconference with engineers with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE Architecture</ENAMEX>, Engineering and Planning discussing the direction of the pool campaign.
</P><P ID="18">   A date for the pool vote is still up in the air, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> hopes to nail down a time in a meeting with a campaign specialist <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. The group is looking at holding the election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September of 2005</TIMEX>. The board hopes to be on a ballot by itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> said that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> they were part of the general election. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX> of the votes, or 1,377, were in favor of the pool. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">51 percent</NUMEX>, or 1,421, voted against the aquatic center. 326 ballots were blank, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> believes is partly attributed to placement on the ballot.
</P><P ID="19">   The board shared a community update with the engineers explaining that since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, when the SPLASH committee first pushed for a swimming pool, there have been some major improvements to the community.
</P><P ID="20">   Besides the construction of new homes and two new schools, the community also has a large, new tax base in the Wal-Mart distribution center.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> said that the new distribution center has already reduced the school levy impact by about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 cents</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value.
</P><P ID="22">   "There's another opportunity to lessen that with additional hiring," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> added.
</P><P ID="23">   He said that where the aquatic center bond in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> was for about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.20</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value, he expects that the new bond will be for less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> shared with the engineers the survey findings and said that in the most recent survey an indoor facility isn't as high of priority with the group polled.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> is also concerned about an indoor component since they tend to lose money. He said that the indoor <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pullman</ENAMEX> facility costs about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> to operate each year and only generates about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> in revenue.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> indicated that the aquatic center will be scaled back from the original facility proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>. He said there is a possibility to phase in other components, such as an indoor pool or extra slides.
</P><P ID="27">   In preparation for the campaign, the board has visited other aquatic centers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="28">   Board members discussed the possibility of finding grant funds to help with the development of the pool.
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said the only grant he is aware of is with the Interagency for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outdoor Recreation</ENAMEX>, but one of the requirements is to have an updated parks and recreation comprehensive plan, which the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> does not have.
</P><P ID="30">   "We don't have any budget at this time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> of the parks and rec service area board.
</P><P ID="31">   The committee would also have to come up with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> match, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horner</ENAMEX> suggested could be the city's donation to the park. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX> representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Ruud</ENAMEX> said he will look into the possibility of finding the funds to develop a parks and rec plan for the city, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said isn't much different than past comprehensive plans they have had.
</P><P ID="32">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruud</ENAMEX> also suggest they look at economic development grant opportunities to help fund the pool. He said that it is important to look at how an aquatic center will impact a city and a region.
</P><P ID="33">   He explained that aquatic centers draw visitors. The center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pendleton</ENAMEX> draws rodeo attendees and those attending softball tournaments, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruud</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="34">   "It really is an enlivening of the city and economic development. It clearly is seen as an economic generator," he added.
</P><P ID="35">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruud</ENAMEX> added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Naches</ENAMEX> was able to receive grant funding because their old swimming pool was not heated, which is the same for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> pool.
</P><P ID="36">   Another possibility, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX>, is building a scaled back aquatic center and then having a catalogue with items members or businesses in the community can purchase for the center.
</P><P ID="37">   One woman in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX> signed a page of a catalogue purchasing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> slide for that community's aquatic center.
</P><P ID="38">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> could purchase one slide and make sure the infrastructure is ready in case someone wants to purchase the other one in the future.
</P><P ID="39">   "I think the people will buy something if they see value in it," said County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX>, who sits on the parks board. "They'll see value in it if it's not stripped down too much."
</P><P ID="40">   "We can't sell ourselves short, either," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> added. "We've got to build something that's going to make money."
</P>   
<P ID="41">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="42">Webmaster
</P><P ID="43">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




