
<P ID="1">Greyhound boys finish fourth in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> play
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/16/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> boys basketball team ended its regular season campaign with stops in two of the toughest places to play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, winning 52-42. But, the Greyhounds saw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>'s No. 2 seed slip out of their hands the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">following night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> pounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> in the second half on their way to a 48-34 victory.   The loss by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> coupled with a win by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> gave the Greyhounds the No. 4 seed. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> lost in overtime to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The Falcons and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> finished with identical 9-5 league records, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> won both the head-to-head match-ups during the regular season against the Greyhounds, grabbing the No. 3 seed. The Greyhounds ended the regular season 14-6 overall.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will now host <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, the league's No. 5 seed, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Wednesday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> in a first-round loser-out game.   "We played really well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Scott Parrish</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s win over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. "We did a nice job of shutting them down."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> couldn't keep up with the much quicker Greyhounds, which led to a lot of transition baskets.   The Greyhounds built a comfortable 26-19 lead at the half. The key for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> in the first half was it was 11-of-14 performance from the free throw line. For the game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> outscored <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> 22 to 9 at the free throw line.   Despite outscoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> 16-15 in the third quarter, the Bulldogs didn't shoot very well from the field for the game, going just 15-of-41. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> missed a lot of 3-point opportunities in the second half, going 1-of-8 from downtown.   The closest <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> got in the game was 43-41 in the third quarter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> went on an 11-7 run in the fourth to finish out the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said his team did a nice job of getting some easy buckets.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mejia</ENAMEX> had another nice outing for the Greyhounds with 15 points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Andrews</ENAMEX> had 13.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> on the glass with nine rebounds.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> didn't play badly, the Greyhounds were able to just beat the Bulldogs off the dribble.   "We also played pretty good defense," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> was a different story for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, which had just 11 second half points.   "We really struggled in the second half," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>. "We were real tentative."   The game started out promising for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, which went on a 5-0 run at the beginning.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis Pendleton</ENAMEX>, though, fired back for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>, scoring 11 of his 16 points in the first quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> outscored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> 18-10 in the opening period and 13-12 in the second quarter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>'s defense smothered his players in the second half. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> were all over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX>, who finished with 5 and 11 points, respectively.   "We didn't get the ball inside," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>. "And they (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>) rebounded well."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Bell</ENAMEX>'s 25 points didn't help the Greyhounds any either.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said he feels his team will rebound from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s loss. He expects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> to do well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   1 2 3 4 T   Grandview 12 14 15 11 52   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> 9 10 16 7 42   Scoring: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview-Chris Mejia</ENAMEX> 15, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Andrews</ENAMEX> 13, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake McFerran</ENAMEX> 9, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabe Reyes</ENAMEX> 8.   Ellensburg-Jason Brozovich 17.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebounds-James Vela</ENAMEX> 9.   Assists: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake McFerran</ENAMEX> 6.         1 2 3 4 T   Grandview 10 13 4 7 34   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> 18 13 6 11 48   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

