
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> volunteer struck, killed by motorist
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident and community volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Shifflett</ENAMEX>, 54, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> after he was struck by a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford Aerostar van</ENAMEX> in the 200 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX>, a volunteer crossing guard with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, was riding his bicycle when at about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:45 p.m.</TIMEX> he was struck by the vehicle. It was driven by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo R. Maciel</ENAMEX>, 43, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Patrol Trooper Todd Sharpe</ENAMEX>. When booked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maciel</ENAMEX> told jailers that he lives in Outlook.   According to a report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Patrol</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maciel</ENAMEX> was traveling eastbound in the westbound lane on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX> when he hit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX>, who was riding his bicycle westbound on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX>'s family was at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornerstone Assembly of God Church</ENAMEX> at the time of the crash.   His daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Shifflett</ENAMEX>, said that as she was leaving the church she saw a police car with a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van</ENAMEX> in front of it.   "I just thought they were getting pulled over," she said. "I prayed for the people in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">van</ENAMEX> and went on my way. I didn't think there was an accident at all."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX> and her mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Shifflett</ENAMEX>, left the church and went to a local retail business, where they were later notified of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Shifflett</ENAMEX>'s death.   When the family returned home the day after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX>'s death, they found that their house had been burglarized, too.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> called in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Patrol</ENAMEX> to investigate the crash because of its expertise, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Capt. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Bank</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX> was named the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District Volunteer</ENAMEX> of the Year for the 2003-04 school year and was presented a Golden Apple at a ceremony held this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past spring</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> gave him a bicycle to honor his achievement. He was a volunteer with the school district for 10 years, working at the high school, middle school and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX>.   During the school year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX> could be found wearing a bright orange safety vest carrying a crossing flag. He served as a crossing guard for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> students at the intersection of 16th Street and Harrison Avenue.   "He was a real asset to the school district," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>. "He cared a great deal for kids and for their safety."   He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX>'s death is a great loss to the school district.   "We're going to miss him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX>'s body was taken to the Yakima County Coronor's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> for an autopsy. According to the Yakima County Coronor's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX> died from instantaneous cardiac arrest due to blunt trauma.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maciel</ENAMEX>, who was uninjured in the crash, was arrested and taken to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail and initially charged with vehicular or negligent homicide. He was transferred to Yakima County Jail <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>), where he will be arraigned.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

