


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds remain undefeated as they head into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">EPHRATA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> continued their winning ways over the weekend, earning the number one seed at the State Championship tournament.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the Lady 'Hounds faced off against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ki-Be</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> tournament. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> defeated both teams in three, winning over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX> by scores of 25-18, 25-13, 25-15 and beating Ki-Be by scores of 28-26, 25-19, 25-18.
</P><P ID="6">   "They played well," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said of his team. "Everyone was pretty excited."
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> noted that the Lady 'Hounds put forth a good team effort <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "All of the players did all of their parts well," he said. "It was a good <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> championship."
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said going into the tournament he knew <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX> was going to be a tough team to beat, only because they were playing on their home court.
</P><P ID="10">   "That's a little bit of an advantage," he noted.
</P><P ID="11">   However, it was an advantage that ended up not working out for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> powering past them.
</P><P ID="12">   Helping the Lady 'Hounds win over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ki-Be</ENAMEX> were a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> players, including senior Danelle Cowan who finished the day with 36 kills, 34 digs, 9 blocks and 2 service aces. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Senior Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> finished with 18 kills, 9 blocks, 4 aces and 21 service points, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> had 4 kills and 6 blocks, Chante Bottineau had 3 kills, 57 assists and 18 digs, Kealey Johnston had 8 kills, 47 digs, 3 aces and 17 service points, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> had 2 kills, 37 digs and 3 aces, and Tonhya Wysong had 63 digs.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said he can't remember a time when the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team went this far into the postseason with no game losses. He noted that even in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, when his team placed second at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>, they lost their first game of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> tournament.
</P><P ID="14">   "So they're doing ok," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s team.
</P><P ID="15">   The Lady 'Hounds will take to the court for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, where they will face off against the team from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steilacoom</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament will be held at the Yakima SunDome.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




