
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Men's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slowpitch</ENAMEX> association meeting set
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Men's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slowpitch Association</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 4</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at Chompis' Sports Bar.
Team and players' fees will be collected during the meeting. Games for the season are scheduled to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>. For more information call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Sarmiento Sr.</ENAMEX> at 836-2236 or 830-5727.
</P> 
 
<P ID="4">Prosser Farmers Market opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX>
PROSSER - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">1, marks</NUMEX> the opening of the Prosser Farmers Market, which is located on Sommer Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, next to the city park and library.
The market, which is open from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, offers people a place to purchase different wares from the more than 10 vendors who are expected to fill the street. Items for sale include everything from nursery plants to garden crafts and furniture.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> will be offering breakfast at the market. The breakfast is a fund-raiser for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> organization.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

