


<P ID="1">School board advances plans to build new school
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The voters have given their approval, the land has been purchased and a plan has been formed for constructing a new middle school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north Alderwood</ENAMEX> to ease the growing public school population.
</P><P ID="5">   With that work completed, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to approve a resolution to seek new school construction project approval from the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction.
</P><P ID="6">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> also approved an application seeking low interest rates from the state, as the district moves forward with the sale of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> in bonds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "We are moving ahead as quickly as possible to ensure we can get the lowest interest rates possible for our bonds," explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Plesha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> executive director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">finance</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said the bond sale, which will be handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gores</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle-Northwest Securities Corp.</ENAMEX>, will move ahead once the state gives it approval for the project.
</P><P ID="9">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s special board meeting was the first step towards the completion of a new middle school on a portion of the 57 acres of district land located along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX>, just to the north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   With the state's approval of the construction project, as well as its assurance of low interest rates for the bonds, the district will be on the road to building the new school as early as mid-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   "Once the state is assured we have the money to begin construction, it will match our efforts, " he said.
</P><P ID="12">   The district hopes to transform the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> bond, passed by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.97 percent</NUMEX> approval rating, into <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> for new projects, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> administrators encouraged the board to approve the state applications as quickly as possible based on the current low interest rates.
</P><P ID="14">   "This is a presidential election year and while the interest rates are low now, that could change," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="15">   Moving quickly now through the preliminary processes may also ensure the district will be able to get low bids <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> when the construction is scheduled to begin.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said the district may be able to open bids on the district's new middle school by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2005</TIMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




