


<P ID="1">High occupancy rate a sign of improvement in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/17/2003</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="4">     Apartments in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, until recently suffering a severe economic downturn, has achieved near 100-percent occupancy at prevailing market rates -- a remarkable performance since the property was purchased by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX>. 
</P>
<P ID="5">     One development, the Parks, which has 364 units, was at 48-percent occupancy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2002</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> took ownership of the five complexes of apartments and townhouses and began the conversion process that became The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Villages</ENAMEX>. 
</P>
<P ID="6">     All new leases since then have been to residents renting prevailing market rates without any form of government assistance whatsoever. More than 180 new residents moved into The Parks during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past six months</TIMEX> at an incredible record-setting pace for the area. 
</P>
<P ID="7">     All new applicants are required to complete an extensive screening and criminal-background check process prior to move-in. 
</P>
<P ID="8">     "This enormously successful lease-up effort indicates a very strong demand that is present in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for safe, clean and affordable rental housing in a quality environment," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Norris</ENAMEX>, President and Chief Operating Officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rohtuh, Inc.</ENAMEX>, which is managing the redevelopment efforts at The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Villages</ENAMEX>. 
</P>
<P ID="9">     "We are truly moving toward a quality mixed-income community at The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Villages</ENAMEX> that will be a sustainable development to be enjoyed by the residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for years to come." 
</P>
