
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to meet twice per month
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">During the retreat at Whistlin Jack Lodge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> agreed to reduce the number of meetings it holds each month.   At the recommendation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed to hold its meetings twice per month now instead of four times each month.   The previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> policy had the governing body meeting at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> each of the first four Mondays of the month. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> offered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the option of meeting twice per month on either a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> or a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> to discuss business.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> suggested the change in meeting schedules to help streamline city government operations.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> expressed concern about reducing the number of meetings each month. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> was concerned that meetings only twice a month would extend the amount of time for each meeting into the late hours. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meetings shouldn't take any longer gathering just twice per month. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it is a matter of reorganizing the meetings to make more efficient use of the time.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said another reason for reducing the meeting to twice per month is that the city would save money in advertising costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said under the current schedule, the city is spending additional money every time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> cancels a meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said under the new schedule <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> could still hold an additional meeting each week, when needed. This would allow the city to incur only the additional costs of advertising when a special meeting was called.   Also having a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting every two weeks would allow city staff to compile more information to be used in a work session study atmosphere, he suggested.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also recommended that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> do away with one of the public comment periods. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> allows the public to provide input at the beginning and at the end of each <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> decide to either allow one comment period at the beginning or end of the meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> put a cap on the amount of time people can speak, limiting the entire comment period to 15 minutes. The reasoning behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>'s suggestion is to help speed up the meeting process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the city has a number of speakers from different organizations on hand at each meeting, many of whom are being paid for the time they are there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it is important the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> get to the people representing the different agencies as quick as possible.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> was concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>'s suggestion would limit the amount of public input. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it wouldn't, but his suggestion would force people to be more direct with their comments.   "Allowing people to comment is a healthy thing, but there has to be a limit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.   Citizens will still be able to comment on additional agenda items as each of them are brought before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. However, citizens will be limited to the amount of time they can speak.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said city staff will also improve the way it presents reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that will help improve that process.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will receive a full report on the changes at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX> meeting.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

