
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> church speaker believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books not appropriate reading for children at school or at home
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/25/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">As a student, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabitha Sanders</ENAMEX> was assigned to read one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books. She refused in protest.   Beforehand, she had read half of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> and the Goblet of Fire," but devout in her faith she refused to read any more of the books because of the deep rooted occult teachings she believes are evident throughout the series.   To <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this day</TIMEX> she has not finished any of the books, but rather has read excerpts from the series. She spoke about the books <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hilltop Church</ENAMEX> of God in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books fall into a specific genre of books known as fantasy.   "When you think about fantasy you think of things that cannot happen in the world around them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books are also known as "high fantasy" because they have an element of magic, but they take place in both the real and fantasy world.   "Fantasy books are important to the development of our children," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, adding that it helps develop the child's mind, imagination and ability to think outside of given parameters.   But with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> series, written in both the real and magical world, it takes the book from true fantasy, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   The books, which were written by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> author J.K. Rowling, took the writer from the British welfare system to the ranks of a top-selling multi-millionaire.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said the first three books released in the series made <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$480 million</NUMEX> and an estimated 116 million books are in print.   "It's estimated that half of all children in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> between ages 6 and 17 have read at least one of the books," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   Since the books have been released, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said they have been integrated into school curriculums. She said it is being used during read aloud times in classrooms and as texts in schools. She added that there are study books and classroom guides that have been made available for teachers.   She said the study guides take students into the common language of the occult, including Satanism and witchcraft. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said it is a child's guide to the history of witchcraft.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said that in interviews she read, Rowling admitted to studying witchcraft and mythology when writing her books. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> added that about 1/3 of the books are based on occultism.   The books tell the story of a young orphan boy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX>, who is a living in the non-magic world of "muggles," or non-magical humans. He learns of his magical heritage and chooses to attend the magical school "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogwarts School of Magic and Wizardry</ENAMEX>."   She said muggles are everyone who do not practice witchcraft.   "They're depicted as being mean, dumb, ugly and as living a life that isn't worth living," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   Voldemort is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s enemy and the wizard that killed his parents and continues to attempt to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said that in the books <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Potter</ENAMEX> lives his life between reality and the fantasy world. She said the name of Voldemort is made of three French words, that when translated means flight of a deadman.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said that there are satanic and occult references throughout the books.   One of the ways the occult is evident in the books, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, is through symbols. She said that symbols are images that have an inner meaning.   "You think you understand the meaning, but it's so much more," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   In writings by occultists, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> found descriptions of "brain wasting" or brainwashing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said there is heavy symbolism on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> book covers.   Three symbols <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> pointed out on the cover of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> and the Sorcerer's Stone," the first book in the series, are the unicorn, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s scar and the Sorcerer's stone.   The Sorcerer's stone, or Philosopher's stone, as it was released in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, is the fifth and final stage of the transmutation of the soul to reach or achieve eternal life, as believed by many occultists, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>. She said no one has reached the level of eternal life in occultism.   She said once the level is reached the occultists believe they can bring themselves back from the dead.   She explained there is a belief amongst occultists that in the fifth stage the person who reaches that level will be their messiah, or the anti-Christ.   The scar on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s forehead, which is a curse scar, is the result of a spell cast by Voldemort to kill <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>. The spell killed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>'s parents, but only scared <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>.   "There's a belief in witchcraft that if you cast a spell that is stronger than you, it will come back on you," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   She said it is believed the anti-Christ will require people to have the mark of the beast on their hand or forehead, adding that the mark is said to be a curse mark.   "So many of these kids look up to this character as their hero," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, who said kids lining up for the books show up with scars painted on their foreheads in order to mimic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX>. "Kids are slowly being conditioned to accept the curse mark. They think once they have that curse mark they can do the things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> does."   Unicorns are believed by Illuminists to be the symbol of their "christ," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   In the books unicorns are one of the most powerful ingredients in potions, and powerful wands which are owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and Voldemort, have unicorn hairs in them.   The cover of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> of Secrets" has pictures of serpents and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> grasping the tail feathers of a Phoenix.   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX>, Satan takes the form of a serpents body, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   The Phoenix is one of the oldest symbols of the occult and is in the Egyptian Satanic Mysteries, she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said that it is believed that there is only one Phoenix and it lived for 500 years. The bird burns up and then rises from the ashes. She said that in the five levels of the transmutations of the soul the Phoenix is the last level.   The Phoenix parallels the life of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jesus</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   The bird makes its nest primarily of frankincense and myrrh, which were both given to Christ at the time of his birth. Myrrh foretold of the coming death of Christ, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, who added that in stories the Phoenix dies and then rises from the ashes.   Sorcery is the attempt to manipulate animals, elements and other aspects of life by using rituals, ceremonies or objects, such as amulets, talismans and charms.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said in witchcraft there are believed to be two different kinds of witchcraft, good and bad.   White, green and blue witchcraft is said to be good magic, and red and black magic are bad. Both good and bad mix magical spells using herbs, which are grown in gardens.   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books the young witches and wizards are learning about different kinds of herbs used in their spells.   One of the plants used in both the books and in real life witchcraft is theyone, a dangerous and psychedelic drug that was outlawed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1915</TIMEX>.   Another herb used both in witchcraft and in the book is mandrake, which in the book is depicted as a screaming infant that is deadly if students at the school don't wear earmuffs while harvesting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said mandrake is a poison that was used in ancient times as a narcotic.   The root, herb and seed of monkshood is deadly poisonous, but is used in witchcraft in small doses. Combined with wormwood, it is used to create a drug that is known as "draught of the living dead," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>. The combination of herbs slows the heart rate so that a person can appear dead, but isn't.   The Exliar of Life is a potion that gives a person the power to life forever. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said it is part of the fifth stage of the transmutation of the soul.   She said in the book charms and casting spells are part of everyday life of students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hogwarts</ENAMEX>, and the names of the spells and words from them are real, researched by Rowling.   "To achieve these things (casting spells) they use a lot of drugs and herbs in dangerous doses," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>. "They are suffering the effects of the drugs, not actually doing what they think, like flying."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said in witchcraft there is a flight spell that uses pig fat and either rat or bat blood and herbs to make a paste. She said a witch will rub the black paste on their face, hands and broomstick and when the person moves it gives them the feeling that they are flying.   She added that in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX> a sorcerer is said to be of the devil.   Another aspect of witchcraft in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books is divination or fortune telling, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>. She said fortune telling mediums include tarot cards, tea leaves, astrology, Oujia boards, palmistry, crystal balls, mirrors and other types of crystals.   In the books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> is called a true seer with the gift of divination powers.   The books have reference to "remember balls," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, which she said are marble sized balls that remind the holder of something they have forgotten.   Also in the book is the parseltongue language, which is known to be the language of snakes, and a language <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> knows in the books.   "The occult believe they need to learn parseltongue to be able to speak directly to Satan," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   The books also have reference to the "Mirror of Erised," which is designed to show a person's heart desires, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   Also evident in the book, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, is the teaching of dualism, which says there is no such thing as absolute good or absolute evil.   "Occultists believe that there are two equal and opposite sides of the force and that there is good in evil and there is evil in good," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton LaVey</ENAMEX>, the writer of the Satanic bible, said that no creed must be accepted that there is an authority of a "divine" nature, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anton LaVey</ENAMEX> tells us there is nothing sacred about moral code," she added.   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and his enemy Voldemort aren't that far apart, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   Both have wands made of the same unicorn hair. Both have the gift of parseltongue and Voldemort gained full strength and, he believes, the power to defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> by drinking a vile of his blood.   In I <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> 1:5, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX> says there is no evil in good, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   "There is not both good and evil <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wizardry</ENAMEX> or witchcraft," she said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX> says all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">wizardry</ENAMEX> and witchcraft is evil."   Another teaching in the book, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, is that of spiritism or necromancy, which is the occult belief, held by witches, wiccans and other occult followers that they can contact the dead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said throughout the books, Rowling uses ghosts as characters that interact with students.   The belief of reincarnation is also taught in the books, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>. Although many religions believe in reincarnation, she said in the occult, it is believed to be a body living a soul-less existence.   She said in the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> and Prisoner of Azkaban," the book tells of people existing as empty shells, "...the body is still living but the soul is gone."   "The occultists believe your body can continue to live, but you won't know who you are," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   She said that the book has creatures known as dementors that can suck the soul out of a human.   "Witches do believe that there are creatures that can scare their soul out of them," she added.   "The standard witchcraft belief is that no one ever dies, they change to another dimension. In that dimension the living can contact the dead," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>.   In "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> and the Sorcerer's Stone," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> said there is a quote that reads, "After all to the well organized mind, death is just the next great adventure."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX> encourages parents to be wary of what their children read in school and at home.   "You can request for an alternative book or alternative assignment," she said. "There are lots of great books you can request rather than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX> books.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

