42 21 0 34 29 7
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  My whole career can be summed up with 'Ignorance is bliss.' When you do not know better, you do not really worry about failing.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Foxworthy</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>