


<P ID="1">Brieflys
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/28/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Silent auction
set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 22-23</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents are being urged to pick up a bargain at a silent auction to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 22-23</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">The auction will be held from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:30 p.m.</TIMEX> each of the two days, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Senior Center</ENAMEX> (401 W. 2nd St.). All proceeds raised from the auction will benefit the Grandview senior citizen programs.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esparza</ENAMEX> issued cease, desist order
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state health officials have issued a cease and desist order against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Esparza</ENAMEX>, who allegedly represented himself as a physician's assistant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> while performing physical examinations and signing examination reports.
</P>

<P ID="9">Officials for the state's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Unlicensed Practice Program</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esparza</ENAMEX> has been convicted of criminal impersonation.
</P>

<P ID="10">State officials also noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria L. Mendoza</ENAMEX>, an applicant to practice as a nursing assistant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, has been charged with unprofessional conduct on charges of possessing stolen property.
</P>

<P ID="11">In addition, the state's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nursing Commission</ENAMEX> has reinstated the license of registered nurse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy J. Trump</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> resident. Her license is subject to probation, and she must cooperate with a monitoring program. Charges against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trump</ENAMEX> include diverting controlled substances for her own non-therapeutic use and showing signs of impairment at work.
</P>

 


<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UW</ENAMEX> scientists want to build underground lab near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LEAVENWORTH</ENAMEX> - A preliminary plan for a national science and engineering laboratory deep underground in an area near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX> was unveiled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> as a starting point for a formal proposal.
</P>

<P ID="14">"This is a starting point for the people of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX> area to decide what they want the project to look like and define how it will fit into the community, if it is ultimately selected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX> and the venture goes forward," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wick Haxton</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> physics professor.
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haxton</ENAMEX> and another <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UW</ENAMEX> professor are the co-leaders of a collaboration proposing construction of a national science and engineering lab beneath <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cashmere Mountain</ENAMEX>, located eight miles west of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX>. In their plan, the lab would be carved deep in the 8,501-foot granite mountain, with access through two 3-mile long access tunnels.
</P>

<P ID="16">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX>, which is underwriting the project, is expected to accept formal proposals for financing feasibility studies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17">A pre-proposal document is available for viewing on-line at: int.phys.washington.edu/NUSEL/icicle.html.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="18">Webmaster
</P><P ID="19">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




