


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> rejects public hearing request
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> admitted at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting that an official public hearing on a proposed landscaping ordinance was not held as he said it would be. But that didn't stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> from passing the controversial ordinance, much to the dismay of one of its members, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> brought her concerns before the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> stated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that she had additional information on the landscaping ordinance she wanted to introduce before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> called for the vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   When a councilman calls for the vote it basically means all discussion on the matter is closed and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is being asked to take action on the matter before them.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> used <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s forum to add some of the additional comments she was looking to touch on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> asked that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> honor the requests of local businessmen to have a public hearing on the matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> read from minutes where <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> Chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Warren</ENAMEX> had said a public hearing would be held on the matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> also mentioned the acknowledgment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> meeting that a public hearing would be held.
</P><P ID="9">   "The request that was made was really important," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>. "I think it is very important we hear from the citizenship."
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> also read from a list of 14 businesses that long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> businessman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sartin</ENAMEX> presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> meeting, who were against the landscaping ordinance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> added that four more businesses are opposed to the landscaping ordinance.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, though, refused to acknowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s request to provide the public hearing and reconsider the landscaping ordinance.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> then took to the podium and expressed his disappointment with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> said that sometimes he admires the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members for the tough issues they address and then other times he sits there trying to figure out what is going on.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> once again reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that the landscaping ordinance will be expensive for local businessmen to implement.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> then turned his direction towards <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>, whom he accused of using his political power to put an end to the discussion that was taking place at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> meeting prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> adopting the landscaping ordinance.
</P><P ID="15">   "Shame on you," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX>. "Shame on all of you who voted for it."
</P><P ID="16">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




