


<P ID="1">Depopulation totals rise as more dairy cattle found
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/29/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The number of cattle euthanized goes up daily as additional cows are killed and tested for the brain wasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, or mad cow disease.
</P><P ID="4">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Tuesday</TIMEX> 15 "animals of interest" were euthanized and sampled from the Moxee facility where one cow, which had been imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> with the infected cow, was found.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United State Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> officials continue to track down the 80 animals that crossed the border with the infected animal.
</P><P ID="6">   The cow found with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> was being milked on a Mabton dairy until the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of December</TIMEX>, when it was sent to a slaughterhouse after sustaining injuries giving birth. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>, after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> testing had been completed, it was found that the animal had contracted mad cow disease. Another was found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Taking protective measures, the USDA started tracking all the animals that were imported from an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX> dairy with the infected cow.
</P><P ID="8">   Nine additional cows from the original 81-cow herd imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> were located on the Mabton dairy where the infected cow had been milked. So far, 131 cows from the Mabton dairy, 39 cows from a Mattawa dairy and 15 animals from a Connell dairy were killed and tested for the disease. All were found negative for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Officials are still awaiting tests from animals that were depopulated from facilities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quincy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moxee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boardman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="10">   In addition to the dairy cows that were believed to be imported with the infected cow, an additional 449 bull calves were euthanized. The calves were part of an operation that had purchased the infected cow's calf. Officials were unable to positively identify the calf, so all of the animals were euthanized.
</P>   
<P ID="11">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




