


<P ID="1">'Eat beef' rally, b-b-q planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/8/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - An "eat beef" rally aimed at counteracting consumers' fears of becoming infected with mad cow disease will be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 10</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   Sponsored by Clear Channel Radio of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and the Yakima and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton County</ENAMEX> cattlemen's groups, the event has been organized in light of the mad cow discovery in the last few weeks in the small farming community, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delynn Otis</ENAMEX>, a spokesperson for the radio station.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX> said the beef barbecue luncheon and rally will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Hoping to eliminate the current fears surrounding beef consumption, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX> said the rally will offer factual information about the safety of beef consumption. "With proper education these fears can be put to rest and the beef industry can continue to produce quality beef products as they have done for many years," she said.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX> said a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Health Department</ENAMEX> inspector and a communicable disease team member will also be on hand to provide information on mad cow disease.
</P><P ID="8">   Helping to organize the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> event are the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Cattleman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton County Cattleman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Livestock Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Health Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>, the Van de Graaf, Lommers and Kallenberger families, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ray</ENAMEX>'s Meats of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>'s Valley Meats of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca-Cola Company</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M&M Catering</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "There is no charge to attend the barbecue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otis</ENAMEX> said.
</P>   






 










<P ID="10">Webmaster
</P><P ID="11">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




