
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> to host <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> bash
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> Bash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>" will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hisey Park</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, April 10</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
Community residents are invited to participate in an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> egg hunt, with a grand prize offered to the youngster who finds the special egg. Also at the park that day, there will be food, music, prizes and entertainment.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> gets <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.44</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">millionfor Union Gap</ENAMEX> project added to transportation bill
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WASHINGTON D.C</ENAMEX>. - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fourth District</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> has worked to get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.44 million</NUMEX> added to a transportation bill that is moving through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. The money is earmarked to rework two congested I-82 interchanges near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>.
"Improving these interchanges is important both for traffic flow and for economic growth and development," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>. "These funds will help get this needed project underway. It will benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX> and the greater <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> area."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> secured <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX> project <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.44 million</NUMEX>, if left in the transportation bill, would complete the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.94 million</NUMEX> total needed to complete the design phase.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Mabton Community Days organizers seek vendors, marchers
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - The organizers of Mabton Community Days are seeking food vendors and individuals and groups interested in participating in the annual parade.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s community event is slated to be held the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12-13</TIMEX>.
A parade is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, with food and fun planned for the rest of the weekend at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton City Park</ENAMEX>.
Food vendor and parade applications are now available at Mabton City Hall, which is open from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> Mondays, Tuesdays and Fridays, and from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on Thursdays.
</P> 
<P ID="6">‘Come Meetthe Son’ sunrise service planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX>
All Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> residents are being invited to a "Come Meet the Son" sunrise service <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday, April 11</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football field.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> sunrise service, to offer services in both English and Spanish, will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX> A continental breakfast at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood's Christian Reformed Church</ENAMEX> will follow.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Port earns financial reporting awards
A certificate of achievement for excellence in financial reporting has been awarded to the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Government Finance</ENAMEX> Officers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
An award of financial reporting achievement was also awarded to the local port's finance officer/treasurer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M'Liss Bierlink</ENAMEX>.
The two awards are the highest form of recognition in the area of governmental accounting and financial reporting.
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

