
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">JOHN <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“JACK” MARSHALL FARMER
JOHN “JACK” MARSHALL FARMER
John “Jack” Marshall Farmer</ENAMEX>, 79, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX>, beloved husband, father, grandfather, and great-grandfather passed away from this life <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1, 2004</TIMEX>, at his home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, surrounded by loving family. He will be greatly missed by all who knew him for his wonderful sense of humor and his love of living.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30, 1925</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jess Crosby Farmer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ester Daphna Marshall Farmer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyo.</ENAMEX>
He married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Wold</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 27, 1946</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salt Lake Temple</ENAMEX> and they became the parents of seven children, who gave them 35 grandchildren and 16 great-grandchildren.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> was raised on a farm in the little town of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deaver</ENAMEX> located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northwestern Wyoming</ENAMEX> where he attended grade school and high school. He graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wyoming</ENAMEX> with a Bachelor of Science degree in agriculture. He was a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpha Zeta</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Agriculture Honorary Society</ENAMEX> and was also a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lambda Delta Sigma</ENAMEX> while attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wyoming</ENAMEX>.
He worked in the field of agriculture all his life and was transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Oil Company</ENAMEX>. He made <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX> his home for the remainder of his life. He taught vocational agriculture at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho State University</ENAMEX> for several years.
He enjoyed gardening and became a Master Gardener. He particularly enjoyed growing roses and entered them in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Idaho State Fair</ENAMEX>, taking ribbons on them.  He loved tinkering is his shop, where he built machinery and was always looking for new ways to do old things.
He was an active lifetime member of The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of Jesus Christ of Latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saints</ENAMEX>, where he held numerous positions.  He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> enjoyed serving two missions for the church, first in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Virginia</ENAMEX> and the second in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX>.
What he enjoyed most and took the greatest pride in was the wonderful family he was blessed with.  He loved each of them dearly and they loved him in return.  He has left them a great legacy of love.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>; four sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Centerville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hemet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolene</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>; three daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McFarland</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Crites</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janette</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mesa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ariz.</ENAMEX>; 33 grandchildren and 15 great-grandchildren; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quincy</ENAMEX>; and two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ilene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Whaley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Conrad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Krueger</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his parents; two grandchildren; and one stillborn great-grandchild.
Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 4, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX> 2nd <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ward LDS Chapel</ENAMEX>, 660 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Teton Drive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackfoot</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>.  The family will meet with friends and relatives from 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 3, 2004</TIMEX> at Hawker Funeral Home and again for one hour prior to services at the church.
Interment will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Riverside-Thomas Cemetery</ENAMEX>.
The family would like to thank the Aspen Home Health and Hospice and Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Liles</ENAMEX> for their loving care.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HERMINIA V. MENDOZA
Herminia V. Mendoza</ENAMEX>, 68, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Aug. 31, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Regional Hospital</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herminia</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 5, 1936</TIMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philippines</ENAMEX>, daughter of Catalina Santos and Patrocinio Villanueva. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herminia</ENAMEX> received her education in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philippines</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 1962</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo Mendoza</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philippines</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herminia</ENAMEX> worked in housekeeping at Hillcrest Manor.
She enjoyed traveling, shopping, cooking and watching Filipino movies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herminia</ENAMEX> is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo Mendoza</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florencio Mendoza</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jocelyn</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Lisa Mendoza</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilfredo</ENAMEX>, of The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philippines</ENAMEX>; her mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catalina Sutton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; three grandchildren; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlinda Soliman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Sutton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; and a niece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roma Joana Mendoza</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.
She was preceded in death by her father.
Memorial Mass will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 4, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.  
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

