


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/15/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naylor</ENAMEX> honored as youth of the month
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Naylor</ENAMEX> was honored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> as the Mayor's Youth of the Month.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naylor</ENAMEX> was present at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>'s city council meeting, where he received a certificate, city pin and a T-shirt.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves preliminary
sub-division
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> to approve the preliminary sub-division of Westridge Addition No. 5.
</P>

<P ID="9">The subdivision will include 20 single family lots on nearly 7.95 acres.
</P>

 


<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves annexation and rezone of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young</ENAMEX> property
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> voted to approve the petition for annexation and rezone of just over 18 acres of property located at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Stover Road</ENAMEX> and Lindsey Lane.
</P>

<P ID="12">The petition, submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert and Jacqueline Young</ENAMEX>, asked that the property be annexed with a multi-family residential zoning designation.
</P>

 


 






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




