


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> receives extra money for new playground
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation</ENAMEX> program recently received word that it was not only awarded the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> it requested from the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX>, it was given an extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   The funds will be used to install lighting and electrical upgrades at the new playground at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> which, along with private funds and donations, was used to complete the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX> playground.
</P><P ID="6">   Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX> said that the grant money allows the city to have some seed money to start on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Park</ENAMEX> playground program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   With the council's approval, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> signed a resolution amending the contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>, allowing for the additional funding.
</P>   
   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




