
<P ID="1">Future drivers urged to register to traffic safety class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 7</TIMEX> 
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> students wishing to take traffic safety education are urged to pre-register for the courses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept</TIMEX>, 7.   Fall term traffic safety classes will begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Sept. 13</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 p.m.</TIMEX> in the high school auditorium.   Registration for students, who are age 15 as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX>, will be held at the high school <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASB</ENAMEX> office from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX>   Cost for the course, which is limited to 100 students, is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$285</NUMEX>, payable in cash or by check.   If additional students are registered, priority will be given to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> students, by age.   Call the high school at 837-2601 for additional information.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

