


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area herd to be killed
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture Chief Veterinarian Ron DeHaven</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>) that a decision has been made to kill the 450 bull calves at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> bull calf operation that was quarantined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The bull calf operation has been under scrutiny since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> after it was found that one of the calves of the Holstein infected with bovine spongiform encephalopathy had been sent there.
</P><P ID="6">   The Holstein dairy cow, which was non-ambulatory at the time of slaughter, entered the beef market after sustaining injuries giving birth.
</P><P ID="7">   The infected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX> cow was tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> at a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> slaughter facility <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>. The test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, or mad cow disease, came back positive on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>. Immediately, the Mabton herd where the infected cow was from was quarantined.
</P><P ID="8">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> bull calf operation where the infected cow's calf was sent to shortly after birth was next quarantined.
</P><P ID="9">   The decision to depopulate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area herd stems from the USDA's inability to determine which calf was birthed by the Holstein diagnosed with mad cow disease. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said it is unlikely that the cow transmitted the disease to her calf, but the USDA made the decision out of precaution.
</P><P ID="10">   The calves will be transferred to a slaughter facility sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, depending on the weather. The undisclosed location is currently not being used, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>. The calves will be humanely euthanized and blood will be taken in case of needed DNA testing.
</P><P ID="11">   None of the calves will be tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said the calves will not test positive at this time, since the disease doesn't show up in animals until they are 30 months or older, he said.
</P><P ID="12">   He added that the calves will not enter the human food chain or be used in rendered products.
</P><P ID="13">   The calf carcasses will not be discarded in an alkaline digester or incineration process because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said there aren't any infectious materials due to the animal's ages. All of the calves are under a month old.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said the owner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area calf operation will be part of the indemnity program, which will pay the owner of the cows a price based on fair market value.
</P><P ID="15">   "Before the depopulation we will agree on the fair market value," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   As a part of the program the USDA actually purchases the calves.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> added that DNA test results by two private labs, one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> and one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, should be available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late this week</TIMEX> to learn for sure if the cow already found to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> is indeed from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   He added that the USDA is still seeking 70 of the cows believed to have entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> at the same time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow did.
</P><P ID="19">   Nine of the cows were found on the Mabton dairy where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow was at. One was found to be at a Mattawa dairy operation, which was quarantined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX>, and one is believed to still be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="20">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




