


<P ID="1">Council touches up graffiti ordinance
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/2/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">One still has to be 21 years of age to purchase any sort of graffiti-causing materials, but <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> did approve some changes in its newly adopted ordinance.
</P><P ID="5">   On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> adopted an ordinance banning the sale of graffiti-marking materials to people under 21 years of age. The ordinance was adopted as a way to help curb a significant increase in the amount of graffiti incidents being seen around <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The new ordinance also empowers the city to take graffiti offenders or their parents/guardians to civil court to recoup damages.
</P><P ID="6">   When the ordinance was adopted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> cast the lone vote against the measure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> expressed some concern with prohibiting young adults from purchasing such materials. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> also had doubts that businesses would be able to comply with certain parts of the ordinance with such short notice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she would have liked to have seen city staff receive input and work with local businesses before composing such an ordinance.
</P><P ID="7">   The amendments to the ordinance the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> adopted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> were minimal.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said he feels the graffiti ordinance gives the city an avenue to hold graffiti offenders accountable.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said he visited with several businesses about the ordinance following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="10">   "Every retailer I talked to is in support of the ordinance," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   One of the recommended amendments approved <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> came from Ace Hardware. The amendment states that every business owner who owns an establishment that sells graffiti-marking implements will post a sign at each cash register or where graffiti implements are displayed, stating that no such items will be sold to anyone under 21 years of age.
</P><P ID="12">   The other amendment defines the tip of a felt-tip marker. The amendment states any felt-tip marker with tip one-half inch or greater shall be required to be stored in the direct line of sight of a staff member.
</P><P ID="13">   Another amendment <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> defines graffiti-related items that can't be sold to those under 21 years of age. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said there was some cleaning up of the section dealing with which items fell under the requirement for having to be placed in a storage display. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the verbage was condensed and made more concise because the store managers pointed out that almost any item, such as a nail, could be used to cause graffiti. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the ordinance reads better now because it defines which items, such as aerosol paint containers, aerosol paint brushes and felt-tip markers, have to be either stored or be in direct line of sight of an employee.
</P><P ID="14">   Another section was removed from the ordinance which could conceivably allow parents, whose children have been found liable in a civil court for damages, to hold a store financially responsible. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said this section might be revisited later, but for now it was best left out.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the ordinance will now become effective five days from legal publication. The only exception is the portion regarding the displaying of such graffiti-causing items. Businesses will have until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX> to be in compliance with this part of the ordinance.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she was pleased staff went back and spoke with the different retailers in town.
</P><P ID="17">   "When we do that we really value our business community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> was also content with the ordinance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said the ordinance will hold parents responsible for what their children do.
</P><P ID="19">   Anyone found guilty of causing graffiti, which is defined as a misdemeanor, can be assessed up to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> fine.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> felt the ordinance very much empowers city officials, such as police officers, judges and prosecutors, to tackle head on the issue of graffiti.
</P><P ID="21">   "I am extremely happy with the process," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>, who initiated the ordinance. "The process was good. We got the job done."
</P>   






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




