
<P ID="1">No one grabs lead on downtown revitalization efforts
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> and the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> support the idea of revitalizing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s downtown corridor. However, exactly who will take the lead is something that has yet to be decided.   Downtown revitalization is something the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> has looked at during two of its recent meetings. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members asked representatives from the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> to join in the discussion.   "Downtown revitalization is a high priority in this community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX>. "But the chamber needs to take the lead."   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX> reported to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> is currently in a state of rebuilding both its membership and its involvement in the community.   "Our motto <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is 'More in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>,'" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said. "We're striving for the chamber <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of</ENAMEX> commerce to be self sufficient and a very professional organization in this community."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said the issue of downtown revitalization is one the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> board of directors discussed at its last meeting.   "Everyone on the chamber is for it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said. But, he added that since the chamber is in the process of rebuilding, it doesn't have a lot of resources, as far as taking the lead on a project the size of downtown revitalization.   Instead, he said he would like to see someone put in charge. A single person whose sole duty it would be to drive the downtown revitalization project.   "We would like to see someone put in that position that has that desire," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said. "[Someone] to fill in the gap when we're sitting in our offices running our businesses."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said another route the city and chamber can take when it comes to downtown revitalization is hiring a consulting firm to lay the groundwork.   "But it's going to cost," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said, noting that it might be possible to acquire grants to help cover the cost of the consultant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> then pointed to a packet of information presented by the city about past revitalization efforts. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, an economic development plan was created for the community, outlining objectives that included revitalizing downtown and increasing tourism. The plan, which was unveiled in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>, included improvements to the intersection at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX> streets, adding directional signage to Main Street, constructing a civic plaza and putting in trees.   "We've already done the consulting," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said. "We spent the money already to develop a plan."   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Robert Morales</ENAMEX> noted that the climate of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> has changed since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. He said before the plans from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">17 years ago</TIMEX> could be used, an assessment would have to be done to ensure that what would have worked nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two decades ago</TIMEX> would still work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> suggested hiring someone to put together some preliminary guidelines for a revitalization plan as a way to ensure that everyone involved is on the same page. He also noted that the community has an important resource in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>, suggesting that perhaps students from the school could help do some of the legwork for the project.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> said the important thing right now is determining whether or not downtown revitalization is something the businesses located in the downtown corridor would support.   "They should all be involved in what downtown should look like," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said.   He asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> if he thought the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> could work to contact local business owners and ask them to take a look at downtown and decide if revitalization is something they would support, and if so what they are looking for in a revitalization plan.   "We want to see the downtown revitalized," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said. "[But] we want to see the chamber revitalized too."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said the downtown revitalization project is something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> can't take on by itself.   "It's going to take everybody," he said. "I don't think it should just fall on one organization."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> that the project is something the city is not trying to "dump" on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>. Instead, he said the city simply wants to find out if it's something local businesses are interested in.   "I think there's a heck of an opportunity here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said. "I think the more we put into it at this juncture the better off we'll be in the future."   In the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> will work to gather as much information as possible from downtown business owners, and help to shape the plan for downtown revitalization.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

