12 22 31 12 15 3
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  You know what charm is: a way of getting the answer yes without having asked any clear question.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Camus</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>), La Chute (The Fall),1956
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>