


<P ID="1">New city pool idea resurfaces in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">GRANDVIEW - Plans to tour regional swim centers were approved during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> meeting held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Pools in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quincy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX> will be inspected by the seven-member board beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 14</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The board, which is in the final phases of putting together a swimming pool needs survey, also plans to examine the aquatic centers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> cities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Milton Freewater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermiston</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pendleton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-June</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The tours of the regional water recreation centers is part of an effort by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> parks board to learn more about the components which make the centers popular with the public, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX>, director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Recreation and Park Services</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> had sought to replace the 55-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> pool, but the public vote failed, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "We are now hoping to gather as much data as possible to inform the public of the need to replace the center and improve its services," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="10">   He said the board hopes to create a proposal which best reflects the community needs.
</P><P ID="11">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Four years ago</TIMEX>, the aquatic center project, projected to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.9 million</NUMEX>, called for a 25-meter competitive eight-lane area, a zero depth pool, play water features, indoor and outdoor spas, as well as two water slides. At that time, other amenities being considered included sand volleyball pits, re-covering of the city tennis courts, additional parking space and an indoor lap pool, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="12">   "We will be asking the citizens to prioritize what their wishes are for the new city pool proposal," he said.
</P><P ID="13">   The survey is expected to be distributed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   In the meantime, the service board members, led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> Chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Copeland</ENAMEX>, will be visiting with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> businesses and service clubs to explain the issues surrounding the need for a new city pool.
</P><P ID="15">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> pool was last renovated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   He said the pool currently serves an average of 500 swimmers per day during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> for swim lessons, swim team competitions and open and family swim times.
</P>   






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




