
<P ID="1">Credit retrieval program helps keep high school students on track for graduation
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Failing a class at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> used to mean having to attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> school and hoping that any of the courses failed would be offered at that time. However, in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> something has changed in the way the high school deals with credit retrieval.   Instead of being put on a waiting list for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> school courses, students are now given a chance to make up the missed credits during the regular school day or after school through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learning Center</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Principal Dennis Birr</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the school started operating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX>, a computer-based credit retrieval program. The program offers curriculum in the subjects of math, English, social studies, science and health. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said the school district looked long and hard before it was decided that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> would be used for credit retrieval, noting that teachers and other staff members were looking for a curriculum that closely matched the state's essential learning requirements, as well as the curriculum already being used at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> is a web-based program that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> accesses through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX>) 105, based out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> recently approved a service agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105 for the use of 50 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> ports. The cost of the agreement was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>.   Half of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> ports are set up in one of the high school's computer labs, a space that contains 25 computers. There are also nearly a dozen laptop computers that can access <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> that are used in other classrooms. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> will also be using nearly a dozen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> ports <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, offering the computer-based credit retrieval curriculum there, as well.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> was available to students in need of credit retrieval for a couple of periods during the school day, as well as after school through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learning Center</ENAMEX>. He noted that during that time there was a teacher who oversaw the computer lab and helped ensure students were progressing as needed.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said, even offering the credit retrieval program on a limited basis, more than 115 credits were retrieved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> through the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX>.   "We were just really pleased with it," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said.   The school was so pleased with the program that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> eight</TIMEX> periods of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> are being offered during the school day, and it is still being made available through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learning Center</ENAMEX> for those students who need the service but can't fit it into their regular schedules.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said one of the reasons the school is able to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> every period all day long, including several periods where two teachers are offering additional credit retrieval, is because of a switch in staffing. He said a teacher left the school from one area of teaching was moved into credit retrieval.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> explained that teachers who oversee students using the credit retrieval program help with pre-testing students to find out which portions of the curriculum they might need to repeat, or whether or not a student will have to repeat an entire class. He said the teachers are also responsible for going back to the teacher the student had for the original class they failed, to find out where the student struggled. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> noted that another responsibility of the overseeing teacher is to test students after they have completed the curriculum to ensure that they have an understanding of what the class was about and will be able to get the credits they need.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> was something the school chose to offer to mostly 11th and 12th grade students, those students who were closer to graduation. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said, the school is already offering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> to 10th, 11th and 12th graders and has plans to open it up to ninth grade students at the end of the semester.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said he feels that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> is something that will help the local graduation rate.   "It helps them stay on track," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX>, before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX>, students who were in need of credit retrieval would have to either attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> school or take classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> to get back on track for graduation.   "Some students were going [to school] full time here," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said. "And catching up on credits at PRIDE after school."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birr</ENAMEX> said at this point in the school year there are already 194 10th, 11th and 12th grade students using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NovaNET</ENAMEX> during the school day.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

