
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> allocates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> to four local groups
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">GRANDVIEW - Four <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> organizations are now <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> richer thanks to the efforts of the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>).   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board members voted to allocate their remaining <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX>, providing grants to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horizons</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Each of the four organizations submitted a request for funds after the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board was reminded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> required that enterprise communities have all of their remaining money obligated by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1</TIMEX>.   During the board's meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, members decided to only accept funding requests from the five organizations that had already been through the request for proposal (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX>) process. Each of the four groups that received money were a part of that process.   However, a fifth letter for funding was also received. The letter, from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX>, requested additional funds for the city's downtown neighborhood outreach program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board president <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Souders</ENAMEX> noted that the downtown neighborhood outreach program was something that had been funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>, but it was not a project that had gone through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> process. She noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> project that had been through the process dealt with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>'s grape and wine education center.   "We were pretty clear that we were going to fund the groups that had been through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> process," Souders said. "I don't feel this letter is in response to the request we put out. If we accept this letter then we have to open it up to every group we funded."   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board decided not to review the request from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> because it did not follow the guidelines set by the board.   Originally, it was thought that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board would have only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,000</NUMEX> left to allocate. So when the board sent letters out looking for requests for additional funding from the groups that had been through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX> process, it was specified that each group could receive anywhere from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX></NUMEX> for their projects. However, after the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> failed to utilize all of the funds that were set aside for its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Neighborhood Outreach project, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX> found itself with an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,500</NUMEX> to spend.   Although each of the funding requests ranged from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX></NUMEX>, the board decided to evenly distribute the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> among the four groups.   "If you look at these they are all very good proposals," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> program administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hill</ENAMEX>. "They're all going to use [the additional funds] for a good purpose."   According to the proposals, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> plans to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds to purchase anatomical teaching models, including hands-on models of the brain and heart, as well as a life-sized plastic skeleton.   The request from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> noted that the additional funds will be used to purchase catering supplies for use at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>. The letter, submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristina Klatovsky</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX>, states that the supplies will create another source of income for the center, noting that the center will be able to offer catering services to those who rent out the building.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> will use the additional funds received from the board to help cover the cost of installing lighting and bringing electricity out to the site of the new playground at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.   According to the request from Horizons, the funds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board will be used to help provide additional monies for Project UNITE. The program offers intermediate and advanced computer classes to students taking part in Project UNITE.   The funds allocated to each of the organizations will have to be spent by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31</TIMEX>.   Despite having allocated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> to the four groups, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> pointed out that it still leaves the board with nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> in its budget. He noted that the money has been earmarked to cover closing costs that will come at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX> when the board is disbanded, as well as the cost of storing 10 years of records that group has created. He added that the records will have to be kept for seven years.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

