
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">This is an open letter to all farmers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>:   If you do not want another tax shoved down your throat that is hard to swallow, I would urge everyone who can to attend the storm water runoff open house at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Convention Center</ENAMEX> (10 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Eighth Street</ENAMEX>) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 22</TIMEX>. The doors will open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> The question and answer session begins at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>   Most of the farmers do not have a storm water runoff problem. But we will be taxed anyway if we do not act now.   /s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark D. Clemmens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

