
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> school district enrollment grows in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/29/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">   Enrollment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> grew 22 students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from February to March</TIMEX>.   The latest enrollment figures were released during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>.   Enrollment for the month of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> totaled 5,288 full-time equivalent students. Enrollment at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of March</TIMEX> had the district housing 5,310 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> each absorbed a significant portion of the growth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of February</TIMEX> there were 818 students at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> school. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> figures had 828 students at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>. The biggest increases were at the first and fourth grades. The first grade saw enrollment increase by three students to 216. Fourth grade students increased from 144 in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to 149 in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. Pioneer rose from 740 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to 750 for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. Most of the increase in student enrollment was felt across the board at Pioneer. The second grade class at Pioneer saw the most increased enrollment, rising from 147 students to 151.   Enrollment at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> increased from 596 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to 602 for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. The biggest leap in student enrollment was at the third grade level, which went from 137 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to 141 for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> increased by five students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> to 918. All of the enrollment increase was at the fifth grade level, which went from 468 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to 473 for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.   Enrollment at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> was unchanged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, staying at 808 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> enrollment dropped three students from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to 149 for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. The ninth grade class at PRIDE lost three students from the previous month. PRIDE's freshman class now has 12 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> also lost six students from the previous month. Enrollment at the high school is now 1,253 students. The biggest loss in enrollment at the high school was in the 10th grade, which fell four students to 322. The 12th grade class also lost three students, leaving <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> enrollment at 277.   The largest grade of students in the school district is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s first grade class, which has 574 students. The smallest class besides kindergarten, which has 227 students, is the 11th grade, which has 329 students.   The school district is housing 220 more students than it was at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of March</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>.      
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

