
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wash. State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> teaching people how to drive
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Not far from where thousands of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> residents took their driving test years ago, a new generation of drivers is getting a chance to study up before heading over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Driver Licensing</ENAMEX> office in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to try for their driver's license.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> is offering drivers education classes at 105-D <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Sixth St.</ENAMEX>, on the east end of the old driver licensing department, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX>'s executive office.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristina Klatovsky</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Ortega</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>, the local non-profit organization was certified to teach drivers education classes at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of July</TIMEX> and by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the month</TIMEX> the first set of classes was off the ground.   The first question most people ask when they hear that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> has taken on the task of offering drivers' training - is how does that fit in with what the organization is doing? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> admitted that when you first look at it there doesn't seem to be a connection.   However, she explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> started thinking about offering classes after a successful car seat program. She said during the car seat clinic parents bring their vehicles in to ensure that they are properly using car seats for their children. What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> found out during the clinic is that although they were able to ensure that children were riding in cars safely, what they weren't able to do was ensure that the person driving the car had a driver's license or knew how to properly operate a vehicle.   "Talking to mom and dad we kept hearing, 'We don't have a license,'" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> said.   She added that driving without a license ends up not only being a safety issue for the person behind the wheel and their passengers, but also for everyone who uses the road.   "It seemed to be a problem of high priority," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortega</ENAMEX> noted that upon further inspection the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> discovered there was no place for bilingual or monolingual Spanish speakers to learn about drivers training. She added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> driving school is the first bilingual certified driving school in the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.   "There is a huge need out there," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortega</ENAMEX> said of bilingual drivers training.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> said when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> was first thinking about taking on a driving school, thoughts were of helping prepare adult drivers to pass the tests necessary to receive their license. However, when the school opened its doors staff members were surprised by the number of youths who were signing up for the class.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> was fortunate enough to put two of its staff members, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert Garza</ENAMEX> and Abdon Valdez, through training and both were certified to teach both adult and youth drivers education classes in English and Spanish.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> driving school has been getting quite a few <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> students in its class, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School</ENAMEX> is no longer offering drivers education. She added that because there were so many <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> students in the first class, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> actually had to run a van up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> every day to pick up the students and bring them to class.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> explained that even though there are quite a few youths taking advantage of the local driving school, there are also a number of adults who are turning out to gain a better understanding of the rules of the road.   There are class times set up, but the schedule is very flexible and allows for one-on-one instruction. Someone who can't make it in during the regular class time or who doesn't necessarily feel comfortable in a setting like that, can come in whenever their schedule allows and go through training.   Although the driving class is sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> said it is open to the entire community. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klatovsky</ENAMEX> added that it is a private pay program. The cost of the class is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85</NUMEX> for the classroom training and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225</NUMEX> for the behind-the-wheel training. She noted that the driving school currently has two state certified vehicles for use in the behind-the-wheel training.   For more information about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> driving school call 1-800-478-2219 or 837-2525.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

