
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> physician honored for dedication to elder care
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A decision to attend his 30th high school class reunion changed the course of Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Loffer</ENAMEX>'s medical career.   Originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, the tall, lanky man had been gone from the area since high school, spending several years in the military before heading to medical school and private practice.   On the occasion of his class reunion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> had a perfectly nice medical practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orlando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fla.</ENAMEX>, where he dealt with all types of patients, including a large number of elderly patients.   "I took a look around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> and found there might be a place for me here," he said.   That spot was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> offices of Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Clevenger</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> was about ready to retire. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> leaped at the opportunity to return to his home state.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> medical practice closely resembles his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> clientele. He is again serving a large population of elderly patients, who have a multiple of special medical needs.   His dedication to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s senior citizens recently earned him the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>'s Volunteer of the Year honors.   "He is willing to go way beyond his call of duty to do house calls for his elderly patients who cannot come into the office to be seen," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Gable</ENAMEX>, his loyal office nurse.   "He is very good with the elderly and will even see patients at the different nursing homes who are not even his patients," she explained.   Further testimony of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>'s dedication to the health of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>'s senior patients is his willingness to serve as the rehabilitation doctor for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hillcrest Manor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He regularly sees anywhere from 30 to 60 patients at Hillcrest Manor and at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Health Care Center</ENAMEX>.   "I believe we have a duty to provide quality end of life care to our elderly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> said.   His dedication to the end of life issues extends to those people who are suffering from life-threatening and terminal illnesses. For most of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 10 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> has also served as the medical director for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>'s dedication to the medical profession has led him into the realm of teaching young doctors some lessons in empathy for patients and their families. He currently serves as the medical director for a teaching program for third and fourth year medical students in cooperation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Health Sciences</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kansas City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX>   "We work with young medical students who are on core rotations in their studies," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> explained. He became involved in the teaching program several years ago when local physicians, led by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Butler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, took on the role of being a teaching hospital.   The program is dedicated to exposing third and fourth year students to rural medicine," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> said. "Our aim is to make rural medicine a consideration for the young physicians. We've had very good success with the students," he said.   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> is working with Doctors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Opalenik</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Dumbolton</ENAMEX>, who are doing their rotations in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dumbolton</ENAMEX>'s husband is expecting to take over Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>'s practice in the near future.   "So, it's a good bet, she, too, will be practicing here, eventually," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> said.   As for his own retirement plans, he admits they are a bit off in the future.   But in the meantime he and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maureen</ENAMEX>, spend a lot of quality time with their 11-year-old son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigel</ENAMEX>. The family is planning a well-deserved vacation to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. In the meantime, the Loffers enjoy season tickets at a number of regional theaters from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to Seattle. "When young doctors ask me what there is to do in this area, I always hold up my theater tickets. I also tell them about the many fine recreational opportunities which are within easy reach.   "This is a wonderful place to live," he said.   "I've never regretted moving back home," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

