


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/11/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> pulls item from agenda
</P>

<P ID="5">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> that city staff asked him to remove an item from the agenda.
</P>

<P ID="6">The item was an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Conference of Governments (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX>) to apply for a Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) for a city-wide housing rehabilitation project.
</P>

<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>, who is heavily involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing rehabilitation program, asked about the delay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> was concerned that any delays would stop <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX> and the city from being able to obtain CDBG funds.
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rockford</ENAMEX> said he asked the mayor to remove the item because he felt there were too many blanks in what was being presented. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he wanted to bring a complete document before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, instead of asking members to approve a document without knowing all the facts.
</P>

<P ID="9">"We do have time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the application for CDBG funds doesn't have to be submitted until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> he was scheduled to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX> representatives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>) to further discuss the issue.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman</ENAMEX> concerned about loud music and reports of racers
</P>

<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> expressed his concern at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting about problems with loud music and street racing over the weekend.
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he had received several comments from residents about the problems with loud music and street racing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he was even amazed to hear during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s power outage that people were still able to play loud music.
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX> responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>' concerns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said he didn't know if there was an increase in activity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>, but his officers did make a couple of street racing related arrests. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> also said the police department received 15 reports of loud music from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The police chief said a majority of the complaints were from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="16">911 board to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Wednesday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="17">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> there will be a special meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County 911 Board</ENAMEX> of Directors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Wednesday</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>, who sits on the board, said the lone discussion item will be the possibility of consolidating dispatching services in the county.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> committee
</P>

<P ID="20">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved a request from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to serve on a marketing committee overseen by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> representative to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> expressed a desire to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> marketing committee. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> gave his blessing to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s request.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to hold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX> meeting at community center
</P>

<P ID="23">At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved a motion to change the venue for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX> gathering.
</P>

<P ID="24"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX> instead of at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="25">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> explained the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had to formally approve the change of location for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s meeting to comply with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Municipal Code. The city's municipal code establishes the time and location of council meetings.
</P>

<P ID="26"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting will formally begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will be involved in a set of activities prior. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said unless there are any pressing issues he would like to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s meeting set aside for the dedication of the community center.
</P>

<P ID="27">"This is a fantastic facility," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


 


 


 


 


 


 


 


 


 


 






 










<P ID="28">Webmaster
</P><P ID="29">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




