
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox</ENAMEX> names honor roll students
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> officials have released the names of the students who earned honor roll status for the second quarter of the 2003-04 school year. To qualify, students had to earned all A's and B's.   Sixth graders named to the honor roll include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Barnett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Cardenas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashlee Cerrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene Espinoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alicia Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rigoberto Leon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janneth Orellana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Reyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayra Reyna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Sexton</ENAMEX>.   Fifth graders earning honor roll accolades include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esmeralda Alcada</ENAMEX>, Ereida Amezcua, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Aviles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Brambilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Carreon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josselyn Castro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cendejas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leticia Enriquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alma Leon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Magallon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roxanna Nunez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Peralez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecila Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmen Reyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crysta Reynolds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, Lourdes Serrano and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Valdez</ENAMEX>.   Fourth graders listed on the second quarter honor roll include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan Arellano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Aceves</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dominique Martinez</ENAMEX>.   Third graders achieving honor roll status include Itzel Barajas, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sierra Cerrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erika Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo Chavez</ENAMEX>, Tre De Zoete, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celia Diaz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Leon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Luis Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carina Magallon</ENAMEX>, Vicente Mireles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Montoya</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joana Nunez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Orellana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leopoldo Reyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Salgado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danysha Salinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Sexton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luz Vergara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Destiny Zavala</ENAMEX>.   Second graders who qualified for the honor roll include Rhapsodi Escobar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Carreon</ENAMEX>, Judit Herrera, Jahaira Jurado, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Martinez</ENAMEX>, Dorimar Mendoza, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Rios</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica Zavala</ENAMEX>.   First graders who excelled academically include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Alatorre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellyruby Castro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Izazaga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel Jimenez</ENAMEX>, Cassidy McCallum, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damaris Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Munguia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Nash</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda Penaloza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Ruiz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zachary Salinas</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

