
<P ID="1">Greyhounds leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> will be ending its two-year stint in the 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> at the end of this school year. The Greyhounds will drop down to the 2A ranks through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>.   This is a result of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Interscholastic Activities Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIAA</ENAMEX>) enrollment count that takes place during odd school years. The last enrollment count marks the first time that counts were taken for an eight-month period, in hopes of gaining a truer enrollment count.   The enrollment counts, which use student numbers in the top three grades, for the four classifications in the state are as follows. The 'B' schools consist of enrollments from zero to 150 students in the top three grades. The 1A schools have enrollments from 151 to 300 students while 2A schools are from 301 to 600. The 3A schools have a broad range to fall within, ranging from 601 to 1,200 students. The 4A schools are all schools with enrollment counts over 1,200.   While <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> will see the Greyhounds return to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX> (CWAC), other local schools such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> will stay the same.   However, while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> will be staying in the Greater Columbia 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two years</TIMEX>, don't look for it to stay that way too long. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School Athletic Director Denny Brown</ENAMEX> said there are large class sizes coming up through the high school that will push <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> into the 1A classification at the next enrollment count.   With the departure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> will drop to seven schools-Alderwood, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley-Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   But while the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> is losing a school, the schools in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WIAA</ENAMEX> district 8 will actually gain a school. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX>, which is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WIAA</ENAMEX> district 5, partners with district 8 in Regional berths. The two new 3A schools in district 8 are <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley-Spokane</ENAMEX>, which is the largest 3A school in the state with 1,184 students, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Central</ENAMEX>, which is the fifth largest 3A school with an enrollment of 1,154. Those two schools will join <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> (849 students), <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clarkston</ENAMEX> (755) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley-Spokane</ENAMEX> (682) to make-up district 8.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley-Yakima</ENAMEX> is the largest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> school with 1,115 students in its top three grades. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is the second biggest <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> school with 1,085 students, and the 16th largest in the state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Athletic Director Bill Daley</ENAMEX> said the departure of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> created some problems with scheduling.   "It creates a unique situation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>. "It is a challenge for everyone. It changed a lot of schedules."   One of the major changes for football fans will be the non-league games scheduled. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is going back to the CWAC South, which includes schools such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>, the total number of schools in that league will increase to seven. As a result, the schedules for certain events in both leagues had to be changed around to accommodate the switch. Grizzly football will not be playing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> any more as a result of the change. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> to find a non-league football game to fill the hole left in the schedule. The Greyhounds and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will play in the opening game of the season in a non-league contest. The other non-league football contests will be against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was also set to have a bye in football in its 10th week, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> managed to get a commitment from the CWAC's No. 5 seeded team to play the Grizzlies.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> is looking at still holding a tournament with six of the seven teams qualifying for the postseason. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> schools will be meeting with schools from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Spokane League</ENAMEX> to discuss the Regional postseason format.   "We have still yet to look at what we are going to do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> finished nine students under the enrollment count for the 3A classification, with 592 students. Despite being so close to the 3A enrollment figures, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School Athletic Director Zane Wells</ENAMEX> thought the move would be good for the students.   "I think that the move down gives all of our kids a better opportunity to be successful," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>. "I think it is a good move for our kids and for our community."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will be the second largest 2A school in district 5 behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX>, which has 593 students. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Baker</ENAMEX> is the largest 2A school in the state with 595 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said scheduling wasn't much of a problem for him because he had made other schools aware that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> might be dropping down in classification next school year.   "We knew that we were going to be close," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.   With the economic growth in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, which includes the new Wal-Mart distribution center, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> acknowledged there might be a chance that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s enrollment goes above 600 at the next enrollment count in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, but said the move he made now was what he felt was best for the students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will continue to schedule the non-league rivalry games that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> is used to seeing.   "We want to keep those rivalry games going," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> is the largest 'B' school in the state with 150.6 students. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said, though, when enrollment was tallied <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> had to include local students who were attending alternative schools in other communities.   Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> was right near the 1A enrollment count, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> opted to stay at the 'B' ranks, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> have had success. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> said a driving factor was that he didn't want to have the other schools have to change their schedules to accommodate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, wanting to maintain continuity.   "(We) would have destroyed all the work that went into those schedules," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>.   But don't look for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> to stay in the 'B' ranks too long as large classes coming through the ranks will boost <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>' enrollment counts to the 1A level at the next cycle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, though, said it is good for his athletes to stay at the 'B' ranks for now.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian has an enrollment count of 62 students and is the 72nd largest 'B' school in the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> has 22 students in its top three grades and is the 106th largest school.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   Greater Columbia 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> (based on student enrollment counts)   1. Mabton - 150   2. LaSalle - 117   3. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyle - 98</ENAMEX>   4. Riverside Christian - 86   5. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian - 62   6. Yakama Tribal - 60   7. Trout Lake - 46   8. Klickitat - 36   9. Glenwood - 24   10. Bickleton - 22      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX>      1. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello - 593</ENAMEX>   2. Grandview - 592   3. Toppenish - 574   4. Ephrata - 529   5. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley - 528</ENAMEX>   6. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quincy - 472</ENAMEX>   7. Connell - 413   8. Cascade - 393   9. Kiona-Benton - 392   10. Omak - 384   11. Naches - 371   12. Cashmere - 358   13. Chelan - 319         <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>      1. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley-Yakima - 1,115</ENAMEX>   2. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> - 1,085   3. Hanford - 1,002   4. Selah - 838   5. Ellensburg - 726   6. Prosser - 673   7. Wapato - 650   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

