


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> float headed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/28/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> community float, "A Midsummer Night's Dream" will be headed to the Moses Lakes community festival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 29</TIMEX>. The float will appear in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> torch light parade beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, according to a float spokesperson.
</P><P ID="4">   The float has already collected a number of trophies since its debut at the Granger Cherry Festival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>. Most recently the float collected first place honors at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX> Spokane Lilac Festival Lighted Parade and the Zillah's Mayor Award at the Zillah Community Days parade.
</P>   






 










<P ID="5">Webmaster
</P><P ID="6">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




