
<P ID="1">SCHS freshman student ambassador for European trip
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> student <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Van Oostrum</ENAMEX> will be making his first trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> as a People To People student ambassador.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX> will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from July 2 to July 26</TIMEX>. He will be on the European Heritage tour, which will allow him to visit places such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">London</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Normandy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bruges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rotterdam</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rhine Valley</ENAMEX>, The Black Forest and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zurich</ENAMEX>. His itinerary will be finalized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX> was nominated to be a member of the team, but he's still not sure who nominated him.   While on his tour he is expected to meet a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">British Parliament</ENAMEX> and visit some of the great historical sites.   "I hope to see the different cultures and how they live," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX>. He added that he hopes to see places such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Normandy Beach</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry and Marilyn Van Oostrum</ENAMEX>, is currently raising money for the trip, which will cost more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX>, which includes all of his costs while in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX> will be traveling with nine other students from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> and his team will meet up with 10 students from the Tri-Cities area. The 20 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> students will be joining 20 delegates from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX>.   His family is currently selling raffle tickets for a garden trellis made by the teen's father. Other gardened themed items will also be raffled off to help pay for the trip. He has already had cookie sales at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian basketball games and is working on other fund-raisers.   The raffle items will be displayed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banner Bank</ENAMEX> and other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> locations through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. Tickets are available at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banner Bank</ENAMEX> or from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX> family. There is also an account in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX>'s name where donations can be deposited.   As a student ambassador, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Oostrum</ENAMEX> will also be able to earn high school credits for his time in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.      
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

