


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Mayor pro-tem absent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> was absent from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had granted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> an excused absence at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 14</TIMEX>, meeting.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Next two Council</ENAMEX> meetings canceled
</P>

<P ID="8">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> voted to cancel the next two scheduled meetings because of a lack of agenda items.
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will not meet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 28</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 6</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was scheduled to meet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6</TIMEX> instead of its regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> meeting because of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> holiday.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> was the only member to vote against canceling both scheduled meetings.
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is scheduled to meet again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 12</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="12">Councilwoman apologizes for walking out
of meeting
</P>

<P ID="13">This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> extended an apology for walking out of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX> meeting.
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> inexplicably left <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting following a vote on a landscaping ordinance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she left the meeting because she was feeling ill.
</P>

<P ID="15">"I didn't mean to leave so abruptly," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman</ENAMEX> wants several issues brought up for discussion
</P>

<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> had a variety of issues this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that he wanted brought back before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at a future date.
</P>

<P ID="18">At the top of the list was a report on compliance with the mobile vending ordinance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said in his travels around town he has noticed that mobile vending businesses aren't complying with the ordinance the city passed.
</P>  


<P ID="19">"It is being abused like crazy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>. "We have some people who totally disregard it."
</P>

<P ID="20"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> also asked that the issue of the city leasing vehicles instead of purchasing new ones be brought up for discussion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> also wanted to talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> about implementing some sort of educational program within the planning department that will help residents with various building tasks.
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




