
<P ID="1">Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> ready to stand tall
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Working as one. Standing together through good times and bad and trusting in one another just a few of the reasons the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> girls basketball team is having one of its best seasons to date under first year head coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolfo Hinojosa</ENAMEX>. While the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls basketball program has had its problems over the last few years, there is no one who can deny that the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> are a team, united as one this season.   "I enjoy working with them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>. "They want the same kind of things I want."   One part of coaching the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> he enjoys is that the team is very competitive.   "They want to win," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>.   A part of the program that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> feels this team understands is that they are laying the foundation for the future of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls basketball program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the team is taking a firm stand in developing the future for Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhound</ENAMEX> basketball.   Regardless of where the season leads <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> is hoping his team takes with them new abilities they can utilize for life, such as class, character and the ability to realize they can obtain their goals.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, 17, has been playing on varsity for three years. She agrees the team's attitude is one of the reasons for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s surprising success <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   "We are positive," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>. "We have a good bond together."   Sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonhya Wysong</ENAMEX>, 15, has only been on varsity for two years, but said what makes the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> so successful is their ability to come together in the best and worst of times.   Coming into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> season both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wysong</ENAMEX> felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> was going to have a good year. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> won two of the three <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> tournaments they played in.   Both also attribute the turn-around in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls program, which only won four <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, compared with 10 this season, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>.   "He is full of energy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>. "He is more of a friend than a coach. When we play, though, he is intense."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wysong</ENAMEX> added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> never gives up on the team, even in bad times.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meghan Waddle</ENAMEX>, 17, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keitha Robertson</ENAMEX>, 18, are two of the senior captains on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s team that have been through the good and bad times with Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhound</ENAMEX> basketball. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> players have seen varsity time each of their four years.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> said the one part that makes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s team unique is its ability to stay in games, despite having no height. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> elaborated by saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is unique because of the intensity it shows during a contest.   "We are really in your face the whole game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> added that she feels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is a special team because the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> view themselves as one on the court. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> said there are several different players capable of carrying the team at any given time. She said no one ever gets upset with one another if somebody has a good night while someone else doesn't. But there is also a less serious side to the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> that gives the team that right balance, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX>.   "We have a lot of fun together," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX>. "Part of the fun is messing around with each other."   Much like her teammates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> attributes a majority of the change in the program to the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX>' new coach.   "We never had the right leader before," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> referring to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>. "He is just so cool."   "He understands us," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX>. "He turns it on when we need to have it turned on, but he doesn't try to push you when you can't be pushed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> said the game that really stands out in her mind for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is the first time the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> played <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> went into the game as underdogs, but very much rose to the occasion, winning by 21 points.   "We knew we needed to show people we could dominate them," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>.   While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> entered the season with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament aspirations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> was a bit more unsure about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s campaign.   "I really didn't know what our chances would be," admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>. "But I think we have really surprised a lot of teams."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX> added that the community has really taken to supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls program, which makes her take a lot of pride as a Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhound</ENAMEX>. Both she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> feel since the community is so active is supporting youth sports that is one of the reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> has a dominating overall athletic program.   "People recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robertson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Arteaga</ENAMEX>, 17, another of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX>' senior leaders, said the biggest difference this season is that it is fun to be part of the girls basketball program.   "I want to be here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX>. "We want to work hard because we enjoy it. We have a really good team with a lot of talent."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said the strength of the team is its individuals who make-up the whole.   "Every girl is strong in their own way," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX>. "We can handle things."   Like many of her teammates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> has one goal this season and that is a trip to the 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>.   "I want to end this season with a bang," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX>. "It would be nice to finish (my) high school (career) off like that."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> also takes a lot of pride in representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, as a Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhound</ENAMEX>.   "It just means being a part of something special," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX>. "I consider it a great privilege to be a part of these girls."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danelle Cowan</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">16, marks</NUMEX> her third year on the varsity. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhound</ENAMEX> junior would also like to make a trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament, following the steps of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> volleyball team, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX> excelled this past season.   "We did it in volleyball," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX>. "There is no reason we can't go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> here."   The chemistry is what makes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls team unique this season, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX>.   "I have been with a lot of these girls for three years," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX>. "I like how we have developed together."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX> also said what works for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is each player knows what to expect from the other.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX> said early in the season the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> had some problems because they weren't focused on the same goal. She said the team has really started to gel with one another as the season progressed.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX> feels, also want to do their best because they take pride in the community.   "I am proud to be a Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhound</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX>. "When I put on my jersey I feel like I am representing my school, my community and I am really proud of that."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said his first season at the helm of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhound</ENAMEX> program has been an enjoyable one.   "It has been a good first year," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>. " We are learning how to communicate with each other. We have learned how to trust each other. That is why we are playing at the level we are now."   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

