
<P ID="1">Check forgers sought by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood police</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/31/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> is looking into seven cases of fraud that occurred at local businesses this holiday season.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Resource</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Rivard</ENAMEX>, who is assisting the police department's detective division over the school holiday, all of the information in the case has finally been gathered and sifted through. He said the cases involve three people who were writing forged checks and cashing them.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivard</ENAMEX> said the department is in the process of getting arrest warrants for the suspects, who are believed to be associated with each other.   He estimates that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> in bad checks were written at local businesses, including Wal-Mart and Rite Aid.   The checks were cashed on private checking accounts, he said.   Other police jurisdictions are also hoping to clear up fraud cases with the arrest of the suspects. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rivard</ENAMEX> said bad checks have allegedly been written by the suspects from the Tri-Cities to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.         
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

