


<P ID="1">Plesha outlines bond/levy election at Rotary meeting
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/14/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> bond and levy election, set to face voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>, was the topic of conversation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> as Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Plesha</ENAMEX> talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX> about the coming election. The school district's chief finance officer outlined the costs of the bond and levy, as well as what the two ballot issues will mean for the district.
</P><P ID="5">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, or as early as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> when absentee ballots are sent out, residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> will be asked to approve both an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> bond and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> special levy.
</P><P ID="6">   "We have two issues that need a yes vote," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="7">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX>, residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> are currently paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.41</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value for the current bond and levy. The special levy being submitted for voter approval will go into effect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> and will replace the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,246,000</NUMEX> special levy that was approved by voters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   If both the bond and levy are approved by voters, school district residents will see a tax increase of 20¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value. This means the tax rate will go from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.41</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.61</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="9">   "For the little expense we really get a lot," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   He said the reason for the small increase is that although the school district will be asking for a new bond and a replacement levy, it will continue to only collect taxes on the levy while using excess general fund revenue to pay for the bond.
</P><P ID="11">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




