
<P ID="1">Twenty-six <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX> students pull all A's
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">A total of 26 students at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>, 24 of them girls, earned all A's for the second quarter of the 2003-04 school year.   Sixteen of the 26 students are seventh graders. They include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Alvarado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Bridger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvira Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Correa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maribel Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Gudino</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Autumn</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hathaway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kassandra Luther</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Palacios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Pearson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey Rollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Salmeron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsee Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Winters</ENAMEX>.   The 10 eighth graders to earn perfect marks include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Brandvold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashlie Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Herndon</ENAMEX>, Jordyne Jaquish, Kelsea Means, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Southern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Tellez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Wedam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joceline Wynn</ENAMEX>.   Numerous other students at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX> were named to the regular honor roll for maintaining at least 'B' grades.   Eighth graders earning regular honor roll status include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Abundiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Alanis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Alanis</ENAMEX>, Alondra Alarcon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Alejandre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Alvarado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Alvarez</ENAMEX>, Nereida Alvizo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittney Amaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Amaro</ENAMEX>, Sadelle Arevalo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe Avalos</ENAMEX>, Kody Bacon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Baldovinos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Ballesteros</ENAMEX>, Matthew Barr, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Barrios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Bautista</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Benitez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Benitez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Bobadilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norberto Bobadilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Boboth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Boogerd</ENAMEX>, Aristeo Borges, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibby Briones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Burgard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Camacho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Cambron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Candido</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deyma Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianeli Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatriz Carrillo</ENAMEX>, Araceli Castaneda, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Castellanos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriana Cisneros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Clements</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Cornelius</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Cornwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Corona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Corona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Dawson</ENAMEX>, Challea DeCann, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela DeLaBarrera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Delgado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuel Delgado</ENAMEX>, Derrick Denson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dacia Drollinger</ENAMEX>, Maegen Elizondo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Estrada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Estudillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Flodin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kassandra Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizbeth Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Martinez Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Garibaldo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Garza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanca Godinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Gonzales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocio Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isidro Granados</ENAMEX>, Kassaundra Guillen, Yesenia Gutierrez, Diedree Hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Haringa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Harvey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Henry</ENAMEX>, Jordan James, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaitlin Jeske</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Jongsma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel Juarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clara Justo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Kaiser</ENAMEX>, Araceli Lepez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Licona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Linde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Longoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Macias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Macias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelita Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zachary Mains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Marquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christella Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelica Mata</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paloma Mata</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah McNerney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Mendias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Messmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Montero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Monterrey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Olivarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Ortiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consuelo Pacheco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Palomarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Partida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Pearson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Perales</ENAMEX>, Araceli Peralta, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pina</ENAMEX>, Beverleigh Quenan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catalina Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvia Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Razey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brice Rinehold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Rios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayra Rios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Ritchey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianna Robert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahna Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kayla Rollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Romero</ENAMEX>, Erendira Rosas, Lucerito Salcedo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celeste Salinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Samaniego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Santoy</ENAMEX>, Mayra Serna, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leandro Solis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Stamschror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Stiteler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Talbert</ENAMEX>, Mayra Tapia, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Valencia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Van Corbach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jovan Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Velasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Velazquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Vidales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilberto Villalobos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Villanueva</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erick Vizguerra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyson Waddle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Watts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigel Weenink</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Wolfe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shana Zamarron</ENAMEX>, Anika Zamora and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Zijlstra</ENAMEX>.   Seventh graders achieving regular honor roll accolades for the second quarter of school include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Abbott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Almeida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catalina Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Amaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Barcenas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebeca Barrios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geneda Benitez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Bieber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Bonilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Bonny</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eduardo Brambila</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Bridges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susana Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubi Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Comstock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Correa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Crank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Cuevas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Del Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Dolan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashleigh Emery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Frausto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Guizar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levi Hagert</ENAMEX>, Dallas Hall, Antassia Hammond, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aarika Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Isquierdo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Jensen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayra Juarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kilian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Louie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Lundquist-Luther</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad Martinez</ENAMEX>, Kathia Medina, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regina Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Meza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio Mojica</ENAMEX>, Udi Nassar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Navarro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haydee Navarro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carina Ocampo</ENAMEX>, Nelida Ochoa, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Pacheco</ENAMEX>, Zchavonna Patina, Thailee Paxton, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Pena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Perales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Picazo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocio Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Reihs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Rivera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karina Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Rubalcava</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabrina Ruelas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Sambrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katya Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristal Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Serrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Slinker</ENAMEX>, Jerica Wells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Solano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Solis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Sosa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hali Soto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humberto Soto</ENAMEX>, Henedina Tavares, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Valencia</ENAMEX>, Teagan Van Gundy-Carlson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomy Velasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Verduzco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Seeger</ENAMEX>, Katelyn Wutzke and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Zamorano</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

