


<P ID="1">It's official!
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">After months and months of looking, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> finally found its man to take the reigns as new city manager.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members unanimously approved the contract of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rockford</ENAMEX> to serve as the new city manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, who currently lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Provo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX>, was hired from a pool of 17 applicants. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> replaces former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>, who now holds a similar position in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> has been serving as interim city manager since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>'s resignation in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> will officially begin his duties as city manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 3</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> announced its intentions to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> a contract for the position of city manager. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McClure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brush</ENAMEX>, Col. were the two finalists in the running for the city manager position. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> selected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> following a trip by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilmen Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Greenway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX> to conduct background research in the hometowns of both finalists.
</P><P ID="9">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all of last week</TIMEX> hashing out contract details. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting both sides had reached an agreement to formalize a contract <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> was officially hired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and will begin work as city manager on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> will be paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$87,500</NUMEX> annually for his job as city manager. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Per</ENAMEX> an agreement by both sides, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> will not receive regular step pay increases. Rather, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>, any increases or salary adjustments will be done during the city manager's annual review. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is the lone employee of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is not entitled to overtime pay, but rather will receive compensation for any hours worked in excess of 40 hours per week, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is terminated by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, he will receive a severance package, including six month's worth of pay. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also agreed to pay for vacation, holidays, health and life insurance and executive leave in the compensation package. However, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is terminated as the result of violating any laws, he will not be eligible for the severance package.
</P><P ID="13">   The city also agrees to pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the premium for health, vision, dental, short and long-term disability and life insurance coverage for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> will receive a monthly reimbursement of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> as a phone allowance for use of his private telephone.
</P><P ID="15">   The contract also calls for the allocation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> in moving from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The city will pay the moving expenses as long as they are billed to the city by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> will also receive a monthly car allowance in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$325</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> will receive 160 hours, or one month, of vacation annually beginning with the first year of his employment.
</P><P ID="17">   Following approval of the city manager contract, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he learned a lot about what kind of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the city has through the mayor's negotiations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he is excited about starting his new position as city manager.
</P><P ID="18">   Several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members voiced their pleasure in having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> aboard as the new city manager.
</P><P ID="19">   "I feel like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is going to be really well served by having Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem Greenway</ENAMEX> said he feels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> brings the city an opportunity to move forward into new areas to better the community.
</P><P ID="21">   "This employment agreement will treat Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>. "I also believe it will treat this city very well."
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> holds a Bachelor of Science degree in justice administration and a Master's in public administration, both of which he obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is the former city manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamogordo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, and the former city administrator for the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Provo</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue</ENAMEX>, have six children and 14 grandchildren.
</P>





 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




