


<P ID="1">Columbia River Steel celebrates grand opening in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Port District</ENAMEX> 
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - A construction company with building sites all over the state has officially been welcomed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Port District</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Columbia River Steel owners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Flodin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Dilbeck</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> have located their base of operation for their regional construction company on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Way</ENAMEX>, with the encouragement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX> commissioners.
</P><P ID="6">   "We're happy to be locating in our hometown and we appreciate the support the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX> and city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> have shown us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flodin</ENAMEX> during a ceremonial ribbon cutting held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> at the new company offices.
</P><P ID="7">   Columbia River Steel, which has worked on a number of large projects in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, as well as in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>, relocated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Port District</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dilbeck</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dilbeck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flodin</ENAMEX> formed the company in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> to build commercial, agricultural and industrial buildings. He said among their larger local projects is the recent expansion at CanAm Steel plant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, a number of large dairy barns in the area, as well as a veterinary clinic on Edison Avenue in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flodin</ENAMEX>, who serves as the company engineer and designer, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dilbeck</ENAMEX>, who labels himself as the builder, employ 20 people in the building trade.
</P><P ID="10">   Officially welcoming the commercial engineering and construction firm were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX> Commissioners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim White</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Grow</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Byam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Wood</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="12">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




