49 35 31 21 1 45
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  All our progress is an unfolding, like a vegetable bud. You have first an instinct, then an opinion, then a knowledge as the plant has root, bud, and fruit. Trust the instinct to the end, though you can render no reason.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Waldo Emerson</ENAMEX> (1803 - 1882)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>