48 35 37 46 2 38
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  You despise books; you whose lives are absorbed in the vanities of ambition, the pursuit of pleasure or indolence; but remember that all the known world, excepting only savage nations, is governed by books.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Voltaire</ENAMEX> (1694 - 1778)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>