


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> calves slaughtered
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">More than 450 bull calves, an entire operation belonging to a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area family, were euthanized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> as a precaution to stop the spread of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>).
</P><P ID="5">   The calves were trucked to a slaughter plant that wasn't being used and were euthanized according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Veterinary Medical Association</ENAMEX> guidelines, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> spokesperson.
</P><P ID="6">   The carcasses were disposed of in a landfill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 7</TIMEX>. None of the calves entered the human food chain.
</P><P ID="7">   Killing the calves is part of an ongoing investigation by the USDA. The governmental agency is still looking into where the more than 80 cows imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow are now at.
</P><P ID="8">   Nine of the cows remain at the Mabton dairy, where the infected cow was milked before it was slaughtered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> after sustaining injuries while giving birth.
</P><P ID="9">   Two additional cows imported along with the infected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX> have been located at a Mattawa dairy finishing facility. Both the Mabton and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX> dairies have been quarantined.
</P><P ID="10">   The USDA is continuing traceback efforts of the other 69 cows unaccounted for. They are also seeking out the 17 cows known to have been in the infected cow's birth herd. It is believed that the 17 cows were also shipped to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, according to USDA officials.
</P>   
<P ID="11">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




