
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary</ENAMEX> speaker stresses that if people are going to be attracted to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> those living here must take active role
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Taking an active role in the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is an important part of "continuing to keep the ball rolling," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daybreak Rotarian Bill Flower</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> served as the club's speaker <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, talking about the responsibility Rotary members and other people in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> community have in coming together and moving forward.   "We're 30 strong, we can do a lot. But we've got to do it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> told Rotarians. "All of us here are responsible for the future of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> said the community is surrounded by gems, like the local museum, as well as its many parks and the community center. He said it's things like these that can help attract people to the community, both as residents and business owners.   He explained that coming into a community that takes pride in what it has to offer can play a part in making people think they might want to become part of the community.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> also told fellow Rotarians that he feels the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is in the middle of an economic development opportunity that it needs to take advantage of - the growth of the local wine industry.   "It's happening all around us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> said, noting the tourist industry could be a boost to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   He said the community has to start working to attract people, not only to visit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, but to stay.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> noted that one of the best gifts given to the community in recent years was the gift of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> property by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don and Karen Seeger</ENAMEX>. The downtown property is now home to Centennial Square.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Greenway</ENAMEX> were present at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> meeting, as was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>, who leaves for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX> soon to take on a new job there.   "We're all wishing you the best in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>, before turning his attention back to the group of Rotarians.   He told those in attendance that with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> soon leaving for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>, it is important that people in the community talk to members of the city council about the importance of keeping the momentum going started by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>.   "We need to get a city manager who understands we need to keep going," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> said.   Ultimately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> said he feels that good things are happening throughout the area and that good things can happen in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, as well.   "I think there's a great hope for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flower</ENAMEX> said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

