12 40 34 47 5 28
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  If you don't know what to do with many of the papers piled on your desk, stick a dozen colleagues' initials on 'em, and pass them along. When in doubt, route.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Malcolm Forbes</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1919</TIMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>