


<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">As we enter a New Year, it is clear that the national economy is on a rebound. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2003</TIMEX>, the Consumer Price Index was down <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.2 percent</NUMEX>, the unemployment rate was down to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.9 percent</NUMEX>, productivity was up an astounding <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.4 percent</NUMEX> (from the same quarter of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>); with all being positive indicators of a strengthening economy. A growing, strengthening economy is one that will produce the jobs that will produce the next round of growth in the economy. This positive-feedback cycle is encouraging, and coupled with the good news from the international arena, it should gather strength <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this next quarter</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   Locally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing Company</ENAMEX>'s announcement to produce the next-generation 7E7 in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX> will keep this state from being decimated by the loss of a substantial portion of its aerospace industry. This event has direct impacts upon <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX>, as the difficulty of improving the local economy increases in direct proportion to any increases in the weakness of the economy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puget Sound</ENAMEX> region.
</P><P ID="5">   Even closer to home, the effects of the hirings at the Wal-Mart distribution center will soon be felt. This will help offset anticipated losses we will experience in some of the agriculture sectors. The long-term net will be a more diversified local economy, one goal that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Incorporated has been working on for almost two decades, and has had considerable success with.
</P><P ID="6">   At this time, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Incorporated is actively pursuing new opportunities to continue improving the local economy, and to attract new employers into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. Additionally, we are working on ways to help local employers remain competitive in this tough business climate. We accomplish this through offering business counseling, consulting and through bringing educational resources to where the need is. We are not a political party ready to assert agenda into every issue that businesses encounter. We recognize that there is a proper venue and level of regulation that assists businesses to thrive, while protecting the health and safety of employees, customers and society in general. We take stands against excessive regulation, not against every regulation solely by virtue of its existence.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Incorporated has led efforts to renew the downtown district in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for many years. The primary beneficiaries have been those businesses that are located within the downtown core. Tens of thousands of dollars have been spent on this effort. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> for the Community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was formed solely for the purpose of making community improvements.
</P><P ID="8">   The Centennial Park Square in the core of downtown was accomplished through the efforts and gifts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> family, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Incorporated, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the downtown merchants, Uptown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, and many, many others; as well as all of the private donors that have their community patronage commemorated within the stonework in the park. You can still be a contributor to this ongoing project, as redefining the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> downtown core is a continuing need. This project has cut across all racial and cultural lines, and is recognized as providing a unifying, central, positive focal point for community gatherings, and is an icon demonstrating what this community can accomplish when all work together. This is the result of what happens when inclusiveness is the main focus of all the diverse groups that have a presence in this city.
</P><P ID="9">   The community center is ready to open, one other positive project for this community, one that has been accomplished in like manner through the inclusion of all parties.
</P><P ID="10">   There is substantial recognition that this community is interested in continuing to foster an atmosphere of inclusiveness and acceptance. It is up to each one of us to support the organizations that represent this community, and to bring our strengths and talents to these groups to help them serve the interests of all the residents. Just as the Centennial Park Square project and community center have been realized through the combined efforts of all, future projects also will have success through combining the talents of all parties.
</P><P ID="11">   Get involved, meet your fellow community members, add to the whole, and be a part of the positive. The national economy is strengthening, the state has retained a major economic generator in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> has a new employer ready to kick out paychecks to be spent locally, and the community has accomplished some substantial positive projects. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This next year</TIMEX> could be very good for the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, this community invites you to be a part of it.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Doak</ENAMEX> is Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Incorporated, an economic development organization dedicated to promoting economic growth in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




