


<P ID="1">Landscaping ordinance OK'd despite opposition
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/15/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A new landscaping ordinance for commercial entities the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> has wanted to implement has been controversial since it was first introduced a couple of years ago. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX> was no different, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> went ahead and approved a condensed version of it anyway.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voted 4-2 to pass the landscaping ordinance, with Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> going against the measure. Shortly following the vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> inexplicably left the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="6">   "This is the product of several months of hard work," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> on redefining the landscaping ordinance, which was about 25 pages in length when it was initially proposed.
</P><P ID="8">   The ordinance approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> is just under five pages in length, outlining specific criteria new commercial development in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will have to meet.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said that the ordinance does have a provision that would make existing businesses that undergo an expansion or alteration to meet the new landscaping requirements. This would only apply when a remodel or expansion would be equal to or greater than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the value of the existing business.
</P><P ID="10">   The ordinance also outlines the general landscaping requirements for parking areas at a business. The ordinance was modified from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> landscaping of parking areas to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>. The landscaping ordinance also outlines such areas as building perimeters, plant materials, fencing and walls, and enforcement.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the ordinance is scheduled to take effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> noted one of the differences with this ordinance before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and past ones is the amount of flexibility it provides. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said during the public hearing process, the planning commission kept hearing from business owners and the rest of the public the need to have a flexible ordinance, which allows developers to try different things. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said he believes this ordinance provides the needed flexibility.
</P><P ID="13">   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> didn't share the same enthusiasm <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> had for the ordinance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she didn't see the need for such an ordinance, a stance she has taken in the past with the issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the businesses that are coming to town are doing a fine job of sprucing up their place. She suggested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> not pass the ordinance because of the shape of the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> added that she is more worried about bringing new business into town then necessarily having them meet a set list of landscaping standards.
</P><P ID="14">   "I really feel strongly this is not the time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>. "We are living in hard times right now."
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s opinion met with some opposition from her fellow councilmen.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> said the ordinance holds a high standard for businesses to meet. He noted that such businesses as Jack-in-the-Box didn't bat an eyelash at meeting city landscaping requirements before. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he would actually like to see the landscaping ordinance before council more stringent to help meet the future commercial development needs of the city.
</P><P ID="17">   "In the next five to 10 years, this community is going to see huge growth," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> touched on the need for a landscaping ordinance. He said a new business is going in along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway. The business is constructing a new building, but developers didn't put in enough frontage to develop landscaping. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the new building will be in the community for several decades to come, but there are no landscaping requirements in place to make that an attractive location. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said landscaping is such a minimal expense when starting a business and in the end it will only help the owner.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> jabbed back, disagreeing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   "The good thing is there will be a business there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> felt burdening business owners with additional requirements will only diminish development.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> voiced no opposition to the ordinance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said it is a very minimal ordinance, asking developers to meet few standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said it doesn't help the community to not have in place any standards for business owners to meet.
</P><P ID="23">   "I am a businessman and to be in business it costs money," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> asked what other cities are doing concerning landscaping requirements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, who was on the planning commission when the landscaping ordinance was initially proposed, said communities such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> have in place similar landscaping ordinances which the planning commission reviewed at the time.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> felt the city wasn't ready for a landscaping ordinance.
</P><P ID="26">   "I can't get past the bump in the road that this is government regulating landscaping," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he thought such measures should be regulated by the commercial sector of the community.
</P><P ID="28">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> agreed with the mayor, but said the city does need some sort of guidelines in place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said businesses with banners, overflowing garbage dumpsters and bars on their windows don't make the community attractive for further economic development.
</P><P ID="29">   "These are things telling people <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> isn't a good place," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   Local business owner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Bliesner</ENAMEX> said hadn't read the entire ordinance, but from what he scanned it seemed like a much more workable solution than previous proposed ordinances.
</P><P ID="31">   Another local business owner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sartin</ENAMEX>, unloaded on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> took the mayor to task, saying that he had promised there would be a public meeting before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the matter before a vote was taken. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> also said his request to have business owners and developers before the planning commission was denied. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with a list of 14 local business owners who weren't in favor of the ordinance and would like to have further discussions with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and planning commission.
</P><P ID="32">   "We don't want you guys telling us what we have to do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="33">   Business owners on the list include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tire Factory</ENAMEX>, C Speck Motors, R.E. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Powell Distributing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Curfman Steel Corp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrus & Roberts</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="34">   The mayor apologized for not having an official public hearing notice on the issue, but did add that citizens were being given the opportunity to comment on the matter now.
</P><P ID="35">   Local resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Campbell</ENAMEX> encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to not pass the ordinance without receiving more public input. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX>, who doesn't own commercial property, said he has always heard during various discussions that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> who wanted the landscaping ordinance, in particular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilmen George Greenway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="36">   "We (the citizens and business owners) were never able to debate the city councilmen who were pushing this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="37">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="38">Webmaster
</P><P ID="39">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




