
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> leaders discuss ways to work together
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/18/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> marked the regularly scheduled meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX>, the first official words of the meeting were uttered by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Schools</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mathis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX>, as well as other members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School Board</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX>, who was recently hired to take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX>' position when he retires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, were all on hand for a joint meeting of the city council and school board.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> said when the meeting was first scheduled, it was done so with the idea that his replacement would have already be found. And that assumption was correct. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> introduced the city council to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, who is currently working as the superintendent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> was officially hired by the school board during its last meeting.   "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX> is just going to do an outstanding job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> said, noting that the programs that have been implemented during the last few years are sure to continue to grow and flourish under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>'s guidance.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said one of the things that drew him to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> position was the teamwork he saw between the school board and the city council. He added that in his opinion the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> has done some really great things, things he doesn't plan on changing when he takes over in the coming months.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that something else he would like to see remain the same are monthly lunches he regularly has had with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX>.   "I want to continue that with you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> also welcomed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, noting that it is nice to see someone from the area, be able to stay in the area and continue to grow.   After being introduced to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> brought up several areas of concern the city has in order to see how both city council and the school board can work together to tackle them. The first issue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> brought up for discussion was trying to curb juvenile crime by offering different after-school programs. He asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> what type of after-school programs the district currently has, and if they are programs with which the city's parks and recreation department are familiar.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> began by talking about the school district's three <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> Learning centers. The centers are located in each of the district's three elementary schools and offers after-school programs to elementary-aged students. He explained that the learning centers focus on three components, education, recreation and parent involvement.   At the middle and high school levels, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> said the district has the Gear-Up program, which they received a grant for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>. He said the program is currently offered to students in sixth, seventh, eighth and ninth grades. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX>, Gear-Up is mostly an education program that does include a small recreation component.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said youth violence and drug use is another area of concern for the city council. He explained that at this point it is something the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX> is working on.   "This is a real priority," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said. "It might be an area where the school district could come into play."   The two entities also talked about the Cops in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> program, which was ended in the district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> said that although the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX> does have a very fast reaction time to any incidents at the schools, the Cops in Schools programs offer other benefits.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> suggested that although the program may no longer be available in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, there are other ways the schools can work with the police department. He noted that simply having the police out in the school zones before and after school and at lunch could be helpful. He also suggested that the school's administrators have a monthly meeting with local law enforcement to talk about things that are going on in the community.   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said one of the city council's goals is to try to make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> one of the best communities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> to live.   "We're looking for ways we can continue to make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> look good," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said, noting that the city's entrances have already been transformed.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the city is also looking toward growth. He noted that they are already beginning to search out businesses that would complement the new Wal-Mart distribution center, as well as tourism related businesses, such as hotels and restaurants.   "We're looking at things for increasing our sales tax revenue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

