


<P ID="1">Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/23/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Fishing show auditions to be held at local fair
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Ever thought it would be fun to just fish all the time, and be the star of your own fishing television show at the same time?
</P>

<P ID="6">Well, that possibility awaits one lucky person,thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Outdoor Channel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">The Outdoor Channel will have its Moose Bus at the fair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 25-26</TIMEX>, and will be holding auditions, in front of the camera, for folks who think they might make a good fishing television show host.
</P>

<P ID="8">One semi-finalist will be chosen from video auditions during the two-day fair stop. Five finalists will then be selected from all the semi-finalists from around the country. The public will then vote for their favorite finalist at the Outdoor Channel's website.
</P>

<P ID="9">The winner will film their show in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 2005</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">The Moose Bus will be at the Oak Park Stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, Matheson plan three debates
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S. Fourth District</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>) is making good on his commitment to face off with his challenger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra J. Matheson</ENAMEX>, in a series of debates across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">Immediately following <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s primary election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> challenged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX> to as many as four debates. A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX> aide responded to the challenge, saying she accepted without question.
</P>

<P ID="14"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> accepted invitations to participate in three joint appearances. The first will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 18</TIMEX>, in a televised debate in the Tri-Cities. The second will be during a live radio show on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KIT Radio</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 20</TIMEX>. The third debate will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 21</TIMEX>, at a candidates' forum in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15">"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX> is looking forward to these debates because he believes the voters deserve to know where the candidates stand on the issues that matter most to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>' campaign manager, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Howe</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> added that he is eager to have details on a fourth debate nailed down in the next few days.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




