


<P ID="1">Estimated 2,500 turn out to support <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s beef industry
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Nothing could stop beef eaters from enjoying the juicy burgers and ribs at the "Eat Beef" rally held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Although the weather was cold and dreary, the hearts of those in the beef and dairy industry were warmed as an estimated 2,500 supporters of the beef industry gathered at what emcee <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Ettle</ENAMEX> referred to as "ground zero," for a free barbecue and rally.
</P><P ID="6">   The eat beef rally was sponsored in support of the beef industry in the wake of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> case found at a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dairy.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Eon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van de Graaf Ranches</ENAMEX>, one of the organizers of the event, likened the rally to county fair barbecues, similar to those like when he was growing up.
</P><P ID="8">   "It was nice to see local people support you and realize that what we're fighting here is an emotional perception," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eon</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Although he spent most of his time with a metal spatula in his hand, he said that the mood he saw was a festive one.
</P><P ID="10">   He said that a lot of people understand that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> doesn't pose a risk.
</P><P ID="11">   "We still have the safest food supply known to man," he added.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Taylor</ENAMEX>, vice president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Cattlemen's Assoc.</ENAMEX>, one of the sponsors of the event, said, "While several governmental organizations scrambled to investigate how the Holstein cow contracted the disease and where the animal came from, members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Cattlemen's</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> began a campaign to educate the public as to the facts known by the scientific community."
</P><P ID="13">   He said that education on the science of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> has been crucial in allaying public fears of beef.
</P><P ID="14">   Also showing support for the beef and dairy industry was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   "We're in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> support of the beef and dairy industry here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   "I like my beef and I like it <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> grown," he added.
</P><P ID="17">   Also showing support for the beef industry was Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>), who has been in contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann M. Veneman</ENAMEX> since the mad cow disease case in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> was first discovered.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said even with a case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>, consumers are continuing to purchase beef.
</P><P ID="19">   "We have said over and over that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> free. Now that it's conclusive that this came from outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> we have a good argument (for our beef importers)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   Also in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> to show support for the beef industry was gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sammamish</ENAMEX>), whose platform is one of turning the state's economy around.
</P><P ID="21">   The former state senator learned of the event the day before and trekked across a mountain pass just to support the beef industry.
</P><P ID="22">   "I think showing support for the cattlemen and their families here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> is important," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   He said farming and the cattle industry is the centerpiece to the state's economy.
</P><P ID="24">   "The bottom line is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> beef is safe to consume," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>. "I wouldn't be here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and eating if it wasn't."
</P>   
<P ID="25">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




