21 28 44 2 34 18
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Death is the enemy. I spent 10 years of my life singlemindedly studying, practicing, fighting hand to hand in close quarters to defeat the enemy, to send him back bloodied and humble and I am not going to roll over and surrender.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Frolov</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Schneider</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Exposure</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">First Snow</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>