


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> explores regulating scooters
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - For the second time in just a matter of months, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> is looking at regulating the use of motorized scooters on city streets.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> took its first look at an ordinance drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maxwell</ENAMEX>. The ordinance limits where the vehicles can be used, the need for safety equipment while riding the scooters and puts an age limit on how old a person must be to operate a scooter on city streets. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell</ENAMEX> told council members that the ordinance was based on the one recently passed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, though ordinances from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> were also looked at during the process.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> first looked at passing an ordinance regulating the scooters during its meeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>, but decided at that time that it wasn't something the city needed.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX> said that although there are children riding motorized scooters in the community, there haven't been any real problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the city is trying to be proactive and pass an ordinance before someone gets hurt.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said he had a chance to look at the ordinances adopted in other communities and felt like the one drafted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell</ENAMEX> covered everything of significance, including that scooter riders must follow the rules of the road, wear a helmet and have a valid driver's license.
</P><P ID="9">   "That's an important one, because it means they have the basic training," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said of the driver's license requirement.
</P><P ID="10">   The ordinance being looked at by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> requires motorized scooter operators to follow the rules of the road, restricts the vehicles from being operated in the downtown business district, as well as in parks, on sidewalks and on streets with a posted speed limit of more than 25 miles per hour. The ordinance also requires scooter riders to have a valid driver's license, therefore putting an age limit on who can operate the vehicles. The ordinance requires riders to wear a helmet, and have their vehicle equipped with lights and reflectors. When it comes to equipment requirements, the ordinance makes brakes and mufflers a necessity.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Joan Souders</ENAMEX> said that despite limiting the scooters to roads with no higher than a 25 mile per hour speed limit, she thinks the scooters might still be operated at too fast of speeds. She pointed to the section of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Road</ENAMEX> that runs past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>, noting that with the hill she is worried scooter riders could get going too fast.
</P><P ID="12">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> said he feels that the scooters could end up being a problem, because the people operating them don't always use common sense.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> will take another look at the proposed scooter ordinance during its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 4</TIMEX> meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said he is hoping to receive input from the public in regards to the proposed ordinance.
</P>





 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




