



<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Lab breakthrough in mad cow disease
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

 

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton Lab</ENAMEX> spokesperson <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurel Sulfate</ENAMEX> told a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that
a team of biophysicists at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton Laboratories</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> have
developed a treatment for diseases such as Mad Cow and Kreutzfeldt-Jakob.
</P>
<P ID="5">Led by laboratory director Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Boynton</ENAMEX>, and his chief scientists Drs. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. VonRyker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Sanderson</ENAMEX>, the scientists state that by
exploiting a unique quality of these so-called "prion diseases"--that
they do not infect all species equally--a prion inhibitor has been developed that stops the progress of the disease. The treatment has successfully been given to infected cattle in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brazil</ENAMEX>, where infections have been kept quiet until now.
</P>
<P ID="6">Caused by infectious, deformed proteins called prions, illnesses
such as Mad Cow Disease encompass a wide array of troubling,
mysterious "spongiform encephalopathies," so named because they
frequently cause the brain to become riddled with holes.
</P>
<P ID="7">Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX> originally characterized these diseases in
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. He stated that mammalian cells contain prion proteins of
two types: normal, cellular prions that don't cause disease; and
abnormal, misshapen prions that arise from normal prions and do cause
disease.
</P>
<P ID="8">Prion diseases exhibit an unusual quality--"species asymmetry."
For instance, while diseased mice infect hamsters well, diseased
hamsters infect mice poorly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VonRyker</ENAMEX> uses a computer to simulate this
asymmetry. Using hamsters and mice as one example, he claims the
simulation shows that normal hamster prions, if injected into a mouse
with prion disease, block the disease in the mouse.
</P>
<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, speaking at the press conference with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulfate</ENAMEX>, stated, "This is truly an amazing development for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX>. They have illustrated why they are the world-leaders in bio-technology, and we are extremely proud of their work."
</P>









<P ID="10">Webmaster
</P><P ID="11">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




