


<P ID="1">Torch scandal?
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/30/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Political wags in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> are excitedly discussing the impact of steamy photos taken of Mayoral democratic candidate John Torch with an unidentified young brunette woman late one evening at a Tri-Cities Starbucks. Torch,  married with 4 children, has not commented on the incriminating pictures. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press</ENAMEX> has obtained copies of these pictures, but following company policy, will not publish them. 
</P>
<P ID="5">Incumbent mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luther</ENAMEX> characterized the scandal as "unfortunate". "Moral values are key to anyone wishing to assume a position of leadership and responsibility," he added.
</P>
<P ID="6">Sources have identified the woman as an employee of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton Laboratories</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurel Sulfate</ENAMEX>, spokeswoman for the laboratory, was unavailable for comment, currently vacationing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Switzerland</ENAMEX>. An assistant to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulfate</ENAMEX> stated that she "will look into the matter upon her return."
</P>





<P ID="7">Webmaster
</P><P ID="8">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




