
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> appointed to finance committee
Newly sworn in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was selected to serve as a member of the city's finance committee.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> replaces former Councilman Alex de la Cruz on the finance committee, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> also replaced on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> will serve on the finance committee with Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX>.
Among the duties of the finance committee is to keep track of the city's financial expenditures.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves interlocal agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX>
This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved an interlocal agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Bellevue</ENAMEX> for the purchase of city supplies.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX> officials approached the city about joining a group of other cities that would be able to bid on supplies and services.
"It does not bind us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. "It simply is an opportunity."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> thought the idea <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> presented was outstanding, but wanted to keep local merchants in mind first as long as they were within <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of the asking price.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s suggestion and asked city staff to keep local merchants in mind when looking at supply orders. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of all sales tax revenue goes back into city coffers.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

