
<P ID="1">What's Happening
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">What's Happening
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">friday</TIMEX>
Yakima Folklife Concert Series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guitarists Jenn Adams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Floridis</ENAMEX> in concert at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for children, available at the door.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sunday</TIMEX>
Live Western Swing band and dancing at Fraternal Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> lodge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3-8 p.m.</TIMEX>
Public reception for artists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Loomis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Dryburgh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Wilbur</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland's Allied Arts Gallery</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1-3 p.m.</TIMEX>
coming events
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">17 & 24</ENAMEX> - "Happi-time Band" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Senior Center</ENAMEX>, 9:<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-11:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">18 & 25</ENAMEX> - Bingo for Fun, open to the public, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Senior Center</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10-11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> for six cards.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 11</TIMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Wells</ENAMEX> in concert at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>'s Legends Casino, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets available at Ticketmaster outlets and at Legends Casino box office.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX> - "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intimate Red Wine & Chocolate Affair</ENAMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Community Center</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7-9 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets, available at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice office at 3920 Outlook Rd., priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> for couples.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX> - Public dance to the music of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hap</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> Band" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Senior Center</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> debuts its "Traditional Arts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morelia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s Sister <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX>" exhibit. Arts and crafts items to remain on display through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14-16</TIMEX> - Third annual "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chocolate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pinot Party</ENAMEX>" at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>'s Maryhill Winery.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>, 20, 21, 27, 28 - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> drama club's performance of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat." Curtain rises at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> each night.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20</TIMEX> - "Beatlemania! America Meets the Beatles, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>" opens at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Center</ENAMEX> and will remain on display through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of 2004</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29</TIMEX> - All-you-can-eat morning pancake feed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Senior Center</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> for children under 12.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 5</TIMEX> - Yakima Folklife Concert Series: "The Suffering Gaels" in concert at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for children, available at the door.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX> - Comedy show featuring Sinbad at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>'s Legends Casino, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets available at Ticketmaster outlets and at Legends Casino box office.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 12</TIMEX> - Fifth annual Hospice Talent Show at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets available at the door that evening.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 18-21</TIMEX> - Fifth annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Horse Fair & Expo</ENAMEX> in Albany, Ore. Ticket information available on-line at: coastalfarm.com.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19</TIMEX>, 20, 26, 27 - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Theater Company</ENAMEX> production of "Guys and Dolls," at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21</TIMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Theater Company</ENAMEX> production of "Guys and Dolls," at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX> - Yakima Folklife Concert Series: "How's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bayou</ENAMEX>" in concert at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for children, available at the door.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brown</ENAMEX> in concert at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>'s Legends Casino, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets available at Ticketmaster outlets and at Legends Casino box office.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17-18</TIMEX> - Apple Cup (Late Models, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sportsman, Streets & Hobby</ENAMEX>) at Yakima Speedway.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>, 27, 28 - Toppenish Creek Players' performance of "Anything Goes" at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakama Heritage Cultural Center Theater</ENAMEX>. Additional performances slated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3-5</TIMEX>. Show times not yet announced.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX> - Late Models, Hobby and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hornets</ENAMEX> at Yakima Speedway.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX> - Late Models, Streets and Bump to Pass at Yakima Speedway.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29</TIMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Tour</ENAMEX> (Hobby) at Yakima Speedway.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18</TIMEX> - Extreme Motocross at Yakima Speedway.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

