
<P ID="1">Sunny Valley Saddlers hone their riding skills during first ever 4-H gaming day
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/3/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> 4-Hers spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX> taking it back to basics for their first ever 4-H gaming day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Tucker</ENAMEX>, leader of the Sunny Valley Saddlers 4-H group, said the gaming day brought the kids together to try their hand at western-style riding games.   "They are done really fast on horseback," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> explained.   The gaming day offered the club members a chance to participate in seven events, ranging from fitting and showing to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> barrels.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said in preparation for gaming day members of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunny Valley Saddlers</ENAMEX> brought in an instructor from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wiley City</ENAMEX> to teach them how to do the different horse-related events. She explained that the 4-H students, who range in age from 12 to 16, were able to learn the basics before they were asked to step into the arena and compete.   "They practiced a lot before that one day," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said.   When it came down to it all of their hard work paid off with some great performances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said all the members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunny Valley Saddlers</ENAMEX> took part in the gaming day, with most members participating in each of the seven events.   "Everyone wanted to try something different," she said.   Taking first place in the fitting and showing event was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimber Tucker</ENAMEX> for the senior division, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX> took first place in the intermediate division and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> took first place in the junior division. Second place honors went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Contreras</ENAMEX> in the intermediate division and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Alter</ENAMEX> in the junior division. Third place went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Contreras</ENAMEX> in the intermediate division.   Results in the pole bending competition included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimber Tucker</ENAMEX> in the senior division, who finished with a time of 37.038. In the intermediate division <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> finished with a time of 34.54, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Contreras</ENAMEX> finished at 36.894, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX> finished at 39.369, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Contreras</ENAMEX> finished at 56.180, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Saam</ENAMEX> finished at 58.907. In the junior division <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> finished at 34.20, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Castilleja</ENAMEX> finished at 38.182 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Alter</ENAMEX> finished at 61.995. Parents and leaders who took part in the event included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Glover</ENAMEX> who finished with a time of 36.79, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Saam</ENAMEX> finished at 43.362, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Contreras</ENAMEX> finished at 45.552, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Castilleja</ENAMEX> finished at 63.369.   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> figure eight competition <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Glover</ENAMEX> finished with a time of 25.123 in the intermediate division, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> finished at 27.712, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Contreras</ENAMEX> finished at 30.978, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX> finished at 33.616, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Contreras</ENAMEX> finished at 41.719 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Saam</ENAMEX> finished at 42.051. Junior competitors included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> who finished at 29.566, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Castilleja</ENAMEX> finished at 31.918 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Alter</ENAMEX> finished at 43.331. Parents and leaders who took part in the event included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Contreras</ENAMEX> who finished with a time of 29.371, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Glover</ENAMEX> finished at 30.038, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Saam</ENAMEX> finished at 34.430 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Castilleja</ENAMEX> finished at 37.646.   In the barrel flags event <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX> finished with a time of 26.946 in the intermediate division, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Glover</ENAMEX> finished at 30.155, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Contreras</ENAMEX> finished at 45.367, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Saam</ENAMEX> finished at 62.75, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Contreras</ENAMEX> finished at 70.580 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> finished at 86.266. Junior competitors included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Castilleja</ENAMEX> who finished at 32.25, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> who finished at 36.85 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Alter</ENAMEX> who finished with a time of 59.891. Leading the parents and leaders who took part in the event was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Glover</ENAMEX> who finished with a time of 29.823, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Castilleja</ENAMEX> finished at 36.714 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Saam</ENAMEX> finished at 109.234.   In the pole key event senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimber Tucker</ENAMEX> finished with a time of 17.042, intermediate finishers included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> who finished at 13.402, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Glover</ENAMEX> at 13.405, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX> at 16.117, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Contreras</ENAMEX> at 16.170, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Contreras</ENAMEX> at 18.556 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Saam</ENAMEX> at 22.276. Junior division finishers included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> with a time of 14.562, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Castilleja</ENAMEX> at 17.759 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Alter</ENAMEX> at 20.978. Parents and leaders who took part in the event included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Glover</ENAMEX> with a time of 15.303, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Saam</ENAMEX> with 17.592, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Castilleja</ENAMEX> with 24.392.   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> barrels competition senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimber Tucker</ENAMEX> finished with a time of 25.885. In the junior division <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Glover</ENAMEX> finished at 19.398, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> at 24.076, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Contreras</ENAMEX> at 24.618, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Contreras</ENAMEX> at 26.352, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Glover</ENAMEX> at 28.326 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX> at 29.991. In the junior division <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> finished with a time of 24.069, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Castilleja</ENAMEX> finished at 24.777 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Alter</ENAMEX> finished at 28.170. Parents and leaders who participated included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Glover</ENAMEX> who finished at 21.487, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Contreras</ENAMEX> at 22.707, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Saam</ENAMEX> at 28.135 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Castilleja</ENAMEX> at 28.486.   In the speed barrels event senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimber Tucker</ENAMEX> finished with a time of 22.452. Intermediate division finishers included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> who finished with a time of 19.825, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Glover</ENAMEX> finished at 22.314, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Contreras</ENAMEX> at 23.965, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Contreras</ENAMEX> at 24.599, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX> at 29.727, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Glover</ENAMEX> at 29.981 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Saam</ENAMEX> at 32.18. Junior division finishers included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> at 24.084, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Castilleja</ENAMEX> at 26.483 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Alter</ENAMEX> at 28.690. Parents and leaders who took part in the event included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Contreras</ENAMEX> who finished with a time of 21.477, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Glover</ENAMEX> at 23.010, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Saam</ENAMEX> at 24.931 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Castilleja</ENAMEX> at 28.795.   High points awards went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimber Tucker</ENAMEX> in the senior division, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Glover</ENAMEX> in the intermediate division, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX> in the junior division and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Glover</ENAMEX> in the parents and leaders division.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

