
<P ID="1">Activities director looks to improve quality of life for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheffield Manor</ENAMEX> residents
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/15/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Small</ENAMEX>, every day is a picnic as she develops activities, events and shows for the residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheffield Manor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX>, the activities director and director of marketing for the retirement center, shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> some of the activities that are held at the center on a daily basis.   She said after 20 years in the wine industry, she found herself more and more isolated with her computer and decided to look for a new career. It was her mother that inspired her to begin looking into positions at retirement centers.   With little experience, she was hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheffield Manor</ENAMEX>, where she has developed a program that has been described as one of the best in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. Mostly, she said, she listened to the residents and designed a program around what they wanted to do.   "I've found that these people are wonderful people and they have so much to offer," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX> said of the residents in the facility.   She said it's important to keep the elderly physically and mentally active and it is her job to make sure they are.   In the mornings she motivates residents to go for a morning walk on one of the pathways. They also have sittercise classes and tai-chi for residents, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX>. Indoor or outdoor golf putting and bowling are also slated activities for residents.   "They will compete in golfing or bowling tournaments," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX>. "We find things to keep them active and to keep them moving. We want them to continue exercising and we encourage them to walk."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX> said that 100 steps make 1/10 of a mile, something she often tells her clients to get them motivated.   Often after breakfast the residents will go on a bus excursion, shopping or on a mystery drive.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX> said in the past the residents have gone to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University Extension</ENAMEX>, to see the murals in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> or on a scenic mountain trip on a mystery drive. The residents also enjoy country drives, which allow them to get out and enjoy the day.   "Now we're doing bird watching," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX>. Residents will go on walks in the back yard of the manor and look for different kinds of birds.   "We believe continued senior education is so important," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX>. "These people have so much to offer."   To encourage learning, Small plans afternoons of reading and poetry at the manor's fireside. Local authors have also visited the residents to speak about their books.   A few residents have even expressed an interest in learning French and Spanish, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX>.   Also planned into the activities schedule are travel slide shows of different places <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX> and other people she knows have visited.   "I usually have a lecture to go along with it," she said.   For those wanting to participate in church services there are Bible studies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> afternoons. She said the residents gather to sing hymns on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Small</ENAMEX> added that they also have a program called "church hopping" that allows residents to visit different churches in the area as a part of the program.   The facility currently has 27 apartments, but in the near future cottages will be added to the property, for those who desire a bit more independence. The facility has independent living residents and those requiring assisted living services.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

