


<P ID="1">Federal grant will upgrade <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> firefighting gear
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - New firefighting equipment and portable radios for use in the field are among the items the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Volunteer Fire Department</ENAMEX> will be purchasing with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,968</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> of Homeland Security Assistance to Firefighters Grant.
</P><P ID="5">   "We're excited to learn <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s fire department has received the grant," said Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX>. "I'm sure they (the firemen) will be using the money for much needed protective equipment," he said.
</P><P ID="6">   In fact, that is exactly what the department plans to do with the windfall, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Volunteer Fire Chief Bill Roettger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>, who applied for the funds from the Homeland Security's web site, was pleased to learn that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> had announced this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> was among the thousands of the nation's small fire departments to receive federal assistance.
</P><P ID="8">   "We're happy to be getting the money in one lump sum," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   "It would take us a long time to raise the funds for the safety equipment we need for the safety of our volunteers," he said.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> said the 21-person <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> department will be using the money to purchase six self-contained breathing apparatus units, which cost about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> each.
</P><P ID="11">   "We also plan to buy three portable radios and four pagers for use in the field to help firefighters stay in contact at fire scenes," he explained.
</P><P ID="12">   All told, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> provided <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$744 million</NUMEX> for the Assistance to Firefighters grants <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   He said the grant money can be used for such safety issues as training, equipment, and fire station and facility modifications.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> said he is glad he took the time to seek the federal grant via the Internet. "We took a shot hoping we would get a piece of the pie," he said. "And it paid off."
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Mabton</ENAMEX> will be kicking in a portion of the necessary funds to fully fund the department's improvement project.
</P><P ID="16">   While the bulk of the money will be coming from the grant, the city will be contributing more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX>, he explained.
</P><P ID="17">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="18">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




