
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> team plays a numbers game
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For the past several months a group of 15 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> students has been working under the guidance of teachers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brianne Carmody</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thalyne Carey</ENAMEX> to learn the ins and outs of math competitions.   All of their training led up to the Mid-Valley Math Competition, held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 28</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Middle School</ENAMEX>, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> seventh grade team took second place honors.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> explained that in a math competition students are divided up into teams of four-people each. For <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, that meant there were two seventh grade teams and two eighth grade teams from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMS</ENAMEX> competing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. The teams then work together to compete in six different categories, including arithmetic, algebra, geometry and mental math.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> said each of the teams is given grade-level tests, so seventh grade students aren't taking the same test as eight grade students. However, all of the teams are working on a certain part of the test at the same time in the same room.   The math competition was held after school, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, and finished with the awards ceremony at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX>, the eighth grade math team coach, said she started working with her students perparing them for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> competition in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>. In order to get the students ready she gave them large packets of math problems to work through. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmody</ENAMEX>, the seventh grade math team coach, said she started working with members of her team just after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> break.   "They worked on their own," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carey</ENAMEX> said, noting that several members of the eighth grade team would come into her room during their lunch period to work on math problems.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmody</ENAMEX> said the math competition is something the students seemed to be very excited about.   "They were all smiles when I saw them on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> (after the competition)," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmody</ENAMEX> said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

