
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Library a place you can count on
Why is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Public Library important to me? It is one of the most important places in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Other kids and I can go there because I can find information I need for school. I can also check out a book or video and bring it home. If there is information in an Encyclopedia I cannot check it out but I can make a copy.
Other useful things the library has are computers and lessons, videos, newspapers from many places, puzzles and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> programs.
It's also a safe place. I know the library is a place I can count on.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Hernandez</ENAMEX>, sixth grader, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Thought of no library frightening
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> has chosen to fund only half of its normal contractual amount with the Yakima County Regional Library System for the running of our local library <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
It is now imperative that the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and all city patrons of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library take issue with this regressive decision by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VOTE</ENAMEX> in favor of forming a library district.
With enough yes votes, the regional library system will be in charge and hopefully the many maintenance improvements to the building that have been needed for years will be accomplished.
At this writing, there are no contingency plans to keep the library open in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, unless this library district proposal receives a majority favorable vote on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX> with the poll vote and the returned mail-in ballots.
Please try to visualize what a city the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, or in fact any city, would be without a library! It is incomprehensible and just plain frightening.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cloe Garrison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Security liaison will be missed
I'm writing this on behalf of Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX>, the security liaison at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>. Recently, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> was transferred from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX>. I would like to tell you how much of a helpful friend and adult he was to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> is a fun person. He is like a student himself...just a little older. He is friendly with everyone. He is funny, too. He always has the best jokes. He always brightens someone's day.
Also, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> did his job. He solved many conflicts within the school. He is someone you can turn to when you have witnessed or have been involved in an accident. He is the kind of person you can trust and know a conflict will be handled.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> will be missed very much by students and staff. We hope his time at Outlook goes well.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thailee L. Paxon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> student
</P> 
<P ID="6">Must see movie
I would like to strongly recommend "The Passion of Christ." I went to see it and it was the best movie I have ever seen.
When I left the theater, I was thinking—hard.
I hope that everyone will go and watch this movie. You will never think of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> the same way again.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Seifert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

