
<P ID="1">Recycling should be part of spring cleaning efforts, say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> leaders
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/1/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Each weekend as the days get longer and the weather gets a little warmer, the urge to get outside and begin spring clean-up grows stronger.   But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, when you begin your annual cleaning out of flower beds, garages and spare rooms, don't forget to recycle, urge officials at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Solid Waste Division</ENAMEX>.   "We are urging county residents to reuse and recycle as much of their refuse as possible in celebration of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Zammarchi</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solid Waste Division</ENAMEX>.   We are encouraging residents to adopt recycling as a year-round family project, she said   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> is making big strides towards increased recycling efforts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zammarchi</ENAMEX> said.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> residents boast a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> recycling rate and the trend toward recycling seems to be growing," she explained.   The distribution of recycling bins throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> has greatly added to the trend, she said. The county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Solid Waste Division</ENAMEX>, in conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Waste Services</ENAMEX>, has bins for plastics, papers and glass located at strategic places throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area.   And even if the bins are stuffed after a weekend of cleaning, creating something of a mess around the bins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zammarchi</ENAMEX> is pleased to see people separating their recyclable items. She said simple projects such as recycling leaves and lawn clippings, rather than disposing the vegetation in the garbage cans, can also help the environment. She said her office annually hosts composting and recycling workshops which will give residents the necessary tips for the disposal of recyclable items.   She said simple projects such as composting yard wastes, in addition to recycling family plastics, papers and glass, will go a long way toward helping to make the environment cleaner and safer for generations to come. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22</TIMEX> is annually recognized as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day</TIMEX> and will be celebrated throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zammarchi</ENAMEX> said.   "We have a full calendar of activities scheduled through the month of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>," she said.   She said the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day</TIMEX> type activities include such things as riding bicycles or walking to work several days a week, attending good bug seminars and starting compost bins in the back yard. Other home activities may include planting a tree, she suggested.   Community activities planned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Arboretum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sarge Hubbard Park</ENAMEX> and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> schools, she said.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> her office will be working with AmeriCorps volunteers to train them to be trainers in recycling, she explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Solid Waste Division</ENAMEX> representatives will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 5</TIMEX> to host a workshop in recycling paper with the volunteers who plan a community <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day</TIMEX> project, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zammarchi</ENAMEX> said.   "It's all part of our countdown to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day</TIMEX>," she explained.   "We will also be working with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> schools to create <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day</TIMEX> messages on brown paper grocery bags," she added.   Students at Pioneer, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Outlook Elementary</ENAMEX> schools will aid in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day</TIMEX> message project, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zammarchi</ENAMEX> said.   "While we won't begin our count-down to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earth Day until April 1</TIMEX>, we know county residents are eager to get started with spring clean-up," she said.   She urged residents to dispose of household hazardous wastes at the local transfer station on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snipes Mountain</ENAMEX> and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cheyne Road</ENAMEX> landfill near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>. Hazardous waste items include such things as car batteries, leftover paint and antifreeze. Other items such as tires must be taken to the Terrace Heights Landfill in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zammarchi</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX> is the date for the annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Arbor Day</TIMEX> family festivities to be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Arboretum</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22</TIMEX> is the date for the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Greenway Eagle Earth Day</TIMEX> to be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sarge Hubbard Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

