
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GHS Follies</ENAMEX>
On behalf of all the students, teachers and volunteers involved in the first annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School Follies</ENAMEX>, I would like to thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> for the excellent coverage of our debut production that took place this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past May</TIMEX>. An incredible amount of time and work was put into our show and we appreciate the publicity of the local newspaper.
We also owe endless gratitude to all of our supporters and contributors, which are comprised of the following: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gayla Boast</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Bennett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Closner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Bones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurene Contreras</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Dalton</ENAMEX>, GEAR-UP, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Grow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Guillen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arcella Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Herrera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tracy</ENAMEX> King, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John LaFever</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lupe Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen Mathews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick and Vicki McLean</ENAMEX>, Mid-Valley Chrysler, Genoveva Morales-Ledesma, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Movie Gallery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny</ENAMEX> and Joci Nelson, Pizza Hut, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Ray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, Safeway, Travel Connection, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WSU-Tri Cities</ENAMEX> Latino Outreach, and the judges—Mike Carpenter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dottie</ENAMEX> and Sil Cervantes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gretchen Chronis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Desserault</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen and Joe Veloz</ENAMEX>.
Thank you, parents and community members, for attending our Follies production. Our tremendously talented group of students who participated in the production should be very proud. Because of extraordinary support we received, we surpassed our monetary goal by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX>.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danika Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GHS</ENAMEX> class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> president
</P> 
<P ID="4">Public encouraged to get involved with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4th of July</TIMEX> celebration here
I am an active citizen who enjoys participating in local activities, as well as getting others involved in doing the same. I recently helped coordinate a fund-raiser for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> celebration. We had donation jars at businesses all around town, asking for money to help pay for the public fireworks display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football field. This display is free to the public.
This was a success, however, we need to start planning for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Our fireworks display could be a lot bigger if we all pitched in and helped fund this project. We need to turn in funds for this project by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 2005</TIMEX>.
Our proposal is you, the public and the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, help fund this project by donating all your aluminum cans. If everyone donated their cans we could raise enough money to have a spectacular one-hour show for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005 Fourth of July</TIMEX> display. We know that if we all work together we can accomplish anything.
I spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dave's Recycling Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and I have opened an account for this project. If you recycle your items at this location and would like to donate all or part of your profits for this project, just let them know at the counter and they will take your donation and deposit it into the "Citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX>."
We will furnish the containers for the aluminum cans, as well as monitor them and pick them up as often as needed. Currently, we have secured one site at the law and justice center, on First Street, near the recycling dumpsters. We are presently trying to secure more sites where citizens can drop off their aluminum can donations around town.
We need your help. Won't you please help by providing a container site? Won't you please help by donating your aluminum cans and drop them off at the designated site near the law and justice center? Won't you please help by donating some or all of your recycling profits at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dave's Recycling Center</ENAMEX>? Won't you please help by hosting a donation jar at your business to raise funds for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s fireworks display?
If you are able to help with this worthwhile community project we would greatly appreciate your support. Please contact me at 837-6340.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Casino night
It's a shame more people didn't show up for the casino night on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 13</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Center</ENAMEX>. The ones who came certainly enjoyed the evening.
When we entered the center we were given <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> in play money. The kitchen counter was filled with all sorts of goodies, including delicious sandwiches. After eating we chose games we wished to play to earn more money so at the end of the evening we'd have enough play money to bid on items offered in the auction.
All in all, it was a fun evening for all us seniors.
The emcee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Stiles</ENAMEX>, makes us all laugh and he did a great job as usual. All of us send a great big thank you to those who helped make casino night possible for all of us. Also, thanks to the young man who carried out my winnings to the car in the dark.
We had a wonderful evening.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernice Seward</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">Fairs threatened
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Fair & Rodeo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> recently concluded another delightful year, with dedicated kids entering food, craft, clothing and livestock exhibits—all while figuring out ways to stay cool.
And it would be a shame to lose this fair, disappointing a lot of kids and parents who count on participating every year. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s fair is just one of three community fairs held annually in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, besides <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>'s and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>'s.
How are these fairs threatened? Because the county budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$390,000</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County WSU Extension</ENAMEX>'s match is in jeopardy. While about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the county's nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 million</NUMEX> budget for law and justice is essential in keeping our communities safe, it is also essential to keep the positive impacts that Extension brings to the residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">4-H</ENAMEX> is based in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extension Service</ENAMEX>. If Extension was eliminated, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">4-H</ENAMEX> program in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> would be eliminated. Hundreds of youth in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">4-H</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> participate in county fairs, yet 4-Hers participate about 10 to 1 over those in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">FFA—which</ENAMEX> means the fairs would probably collapse due to lack of participation. This is exactly what happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Multnomah County</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">4-H</ENAMEX> is just a tip of the iceberg of the benefits of Extension. Extension agents in horticulture and livestock advance those industries with information in cutting edge technology and research. Agriculture is a foundation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extension Service</ENAMEX> is exemplary in using volunteers to improve lifestyles of residents by teaching food safety, improved nutrition, sewing, gardening and living on a budget, to name a few.
<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$390,000</NUMEX> is a small portion, creating a huge positive impact, of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55 million</NUMEX> county budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> receives approximately two times the match in resources for its investment in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU Extension</ENAMEX>. If the money is not approved for Extension, it will be sorely missed, and cause a "trickle down" effect with a loss of valuable industry information, household education and community fairs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karin Argo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="7">Vote for righteousness
Yes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> (Story), you are correct, when you said, "who do we vote for?"
Regarding the U.S. Senate, I would like to share the following: the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX> says, "righteousness exalts a nation." Here is our chance to vote for righteousness (www.bradklippert.com). Be sure to click on the link "Sound the Alarm."
This man's brochure and web site make no bones about his Godly stance. It states, "a God-fearing, Bible-believing, Ten Commandments-honoring evangelical Christian."
Oh, that God fearing people would vote their conscience.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mortensen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="8">Softball tourney
What a great weekend we had in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with a 20-team softball tournament at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>.
For those who think <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView</ENAMEX>'s ball fields don't get used, you are very wrong. With 15 of the 20 teams being from out of town, just imagine what kind of revenue <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> generated. Players and their families stayed overnight and ate at various restaurants, or shopped at local stores.
Fifteen teams times 14 players per team, plus families, makes for a lot of money spent in town.
I, myself, spent the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,200</NUMEX> for tournament expenses here locally.
I want to thank the city park staff for its excellent work all week to prepare the fields for use. We had quite a few compliments. Also, I want to thank our sponsors: Aztlan Sportswear, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Valle Restaurant</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s Market. Thanks also to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre and Bobby III Sarmiento</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rene and Yolanda Montelongo</ENAMEX>, for all their hard work. Without everyone's help this success wouldn't have taken place.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Sarmiento Sr.</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="9">Guard rail efforts
I want to especially thank one individual who has taken on several projects and volunteered all her time and effort. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX> has done an excellent job in organizing the plantings along the guard rail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX> organized all of the volunteers to plant the hundreds of bulbs and starts in this area in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She donated most of the items and received donations for the rest.
After this project was completed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX> then came to me with a new idea to paint the guard rail and have multi-color handprints decorate the guard rail. Again, she organized this effort and did a great job. Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX> this area is much brighter and more colorful for all of us to enjoy.
It is good to know that we can count on individuals to volunteer their time and energy to make our community a better place to live.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Stiles</ENAMEX>, Director, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

