
<P ID="1">Grizzlies maul Falcons for first league victory
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football team got on the winning track in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with a 24-6 thumping of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>.   "I was really pleased," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Mark Marro</ENAMEX>. "We controlled the ball the entire game. I thought we played a total game."   A lot of the success for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s victory can be attributed to the offensive line of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, which opened the running game of the Grizzlies. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s offensive line allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX> to run all over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> had a very impressive night for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, racking up 211 yards on 26 totes and two rushing touchdowns, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> had 155 yards on 21 carries.   "They ran the ball well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> of his two backs. "I am real happy with how they performed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> scored in the opening quarter when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> scampered in for a touchdown from seven yards out. The Falcons also got on the board in the first quarter when a Grizzly fumble gave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> a short field to work with for a touchdown. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was able to block the extra point attempt by the Falcons to lead 7-6 at the end of the first quarter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> had his second touchdown of the night in the second quarter when he scored on a 15-yard run.   The Grizzlies took a 14-6 lead into the locker room at halftime.   The second half opened with a quiet third quarter as neither team could find the back of the end zone.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, though, exploded for 10 points in the fourth quarter to put the game out of reach. Grizzly kicker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX> nailed a 23-yard field goal in the fourth quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s final score came off a 25-yard interception return for a touchdown by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies didn't put the ball in the air very much <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> as quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cantu</ENAMEX> completed only 3-of-5 passes for 20 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't throw the ball much because the ground game was working so well.   "We were getting five to 20 yards a run," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said what was key for the Grizzlies on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was they were able to control the line of scrimmage, which he said dictated the pace of the game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> also gave credit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s defense for its efforts on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in shutting down the Falcons.   The Grizzlies (1-2, 3-3) will be hosting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Homecoming game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said despite <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>'s less than stellar record, he isn't going into the game underestimating the Wolfpack.   "They have nothing to lose," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "I am hoping for a good game. We are not taking anything for granted."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

