
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves contract with consultantsfor MSDR
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved a contract for personal services with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Management Consultants Inc.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mercer Island</ENAMEX>.
The contract calls for the company to help facilitate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Student Data</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recruitment</ENAMEX> (MSDR) office with activities that are related to preparing the request for proposal regarding making the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> branch of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSDR</ENAMEX> the national data bank.
According to the contract, the company will earn <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX> an hour for their services. The contract is effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1, 2004 through Aug. 31, 2005</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Contract approved for gifted and talented program
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> has approved a contract for personal services with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Chambers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chambers</ENAMEX> will be coordinating the Javits Gifted and Talented Program enrichment clusters. The contract is effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2004 through Sept. 30, 2005</TIMEX>. The contract totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Contract approved for language translations
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members have approved a contract for personal services with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centerpoint Language Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
The contract is effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 1, 2004 through Aug. 31, 2005</TIMEX> and notes that a consultant with the firm will provide verbal translations and written translations to the Migrant Education Program. According to the contract, the Migrant Student Data and Recruitment office agrees to pay the consultant <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$275</NUMEX> a day for verbal translation and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> an hour for written translation.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves contract for Corrective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reading</ENAMEX> consultant
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved a contract for personal services with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tara Ebey</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.
The contract calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebey</ENAMEX> to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chief Kamiakin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> with the implementation of the Corrective Reading program. The contract will also provide for training and mentoring for all fourth grade teachers in the district who are working with students who are not seeing success with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Open Court</ENAMEX> reading system. According to the contract, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ebey</ENAMEX> will also continue to guide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> in its second year of the Corrective Reading program.
The contract, effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1, 2004</TIMEX> though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30, 2005</TIMEX>, is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX> a day for up to 29 days, plus expenses.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves contract for review of PASS math course
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> has approved a contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Weron</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> for work to review and revise the PASS math courses.
The contract, effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1, 2004 through Aug. 31, 2005</TIMEX>, is through the office of Secondary Education for Migrant Youth (SEMY). According to the contract, SEMY will pay <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weron</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> an hour, not to exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX>, to review revisions to the curriculum.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Contract for occupational therapy approved
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> has approved a contract for professional services with occupational therapist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan S. Scott</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.
The contract, effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 26, 2004 through June 10, 2005</TIMEX>, calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> to provide occupational therapy for students with disabilities in the district.
According to the contract, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> will be paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55</NUMEX> an hour, for a maximum of 392 hours.
</P> 
<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> schools
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members have approved a memorandum of understanding with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton School District</ENAMEX> to provide the services of a certified school psychologist to the neighboring district.
According to the agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> district will pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> a day, based on a seven-hour school day for the services.
</P> 
<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves sale of surplus property
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> has approved the sale of more than six pieces of surplus property for a total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,234</NUMEX>.
The property sold includes a paint sprayer, a Palm III holder, a Cummins engine, an Orbit drill press, a large <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockwell</ENAMEX> band saw, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockwell</ENAMEX> jointer and scrap metal.
</P> 
<P ID="11">Two travel requests approved by board
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> approved two travel requests, one that will send several DECA students to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> leadership conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> and another that will send <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hughes</ENAMEX> and one student to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>.
The DECA students, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin Ferguson</ENAMEX>, will attend the conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 21 through Oct. 23</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> and the one student will be attending the Effective <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Communities Regional Forum</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Oct. 3 through Oct. 6</TIMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

