
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
S’side High has report cards, diplomas available
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> graduates of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> can pick up their diplomas at the school now, between <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> and 1 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> Mondays through Fridays.
The end of school year report cards are also available to be picked up by local prep students.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Driver’s license law changes
As of a week and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a half ago</TIMEX>, the state has introduced changes that may allow individuals to drive under certain circumstances when their license is suspended.
A new type of license, called an occupational/restricted license, replaces the occupational driver's license that allowed an individual to drive to and from work while serving the terms of a driver's license suspension or revocation.
The new law makes more drivers eligible to drive while their license is suspended. The occupational/restricted licenses will be issued for the following uses:
• to drive to and from an individual's place of employment;
• for an occupation or trade that makes it essential to operation a motor vehicle;
• to undergo continuing health care;
• to attend an educational institution or course of study that leads to a diploma, degree or other certification;
• to undergo substance abuse treatment or for participation in 12-step group meetings;
• for an apprenticeship, Work First, on-the-job training or welfare to work program; and
• to provide continuing care for another who is dependent upon the applicant.
The new law also increases the fee for obtaining this type of restricted driving privilege, from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX></NUMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">American Legion Auxiliary installs 2004-05 officers
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unit</ENAMEX> #73 of the American Legion Auxiliary installed its 2004-05 officers at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> meeting.
The newly installed officers include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lila Furukawa</ENAMEX> as president, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Taylor</ENAMEX> as first vice president, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Maynard</ENAMEX> as second vice president, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beverly Ice</ENAMEX> as secretary, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Schaneman</ENAMEX> as treasurer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Atherton</ENAMEX> as chaplain, Floy Hansen as sergeant-at-arms and Terry Morrow as historian.
As the president, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Furukawa</ENAMEX> will be the unit's delegate at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Washington American Legion Auxiliary</ENAMEX> state convention, to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12-17</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX>.
The Auxiliary's primary project of offering poppies to the public was completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. Procceds from the poppy sales benefit veterans who are hospitalized. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s poppy days chairman was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Playground program taking registrations
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> is now accepting registrations on a first-come, first-serve basis for its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> playground program.
The day camp is open to boys and girls ages 6 to 12. Due to limited space and resources, the program is open only to the first 50 youths who register. Mail-in registration will not be accepted.
The program begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July 7</TIMEX>, and lasts until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 13</TIMEX>. It is held Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> The day camp will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Park</ENAMEX> on Mondays and Wednesdays, and at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Westside Park</ENAMEX> on Fridays. A free lunch will be provided thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> food service program.
The registration fee is set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> youngsters, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37.50</NUMEX> for those youths who reside outside the city limits.
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

