
<P ID="1">Elizondo accepted to play in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">All-state</ENAMEX> game
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/26/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior R.J. Elizondo has been accepted to play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">All-state</ENAMEX> football game on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 26</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX>.   Elizondo is the first <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football player to be accepted to play in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">All-State</ENAMEX> game since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Wells</ENAMEX> in the mid-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990s</TIMEX>. Elizondo was a standout for the Grizzly football team as a running back this past season, leading the Grizzlies to the playoffs.   "It is a great opportunity for him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> football Coach Mark Marro.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

