


<P ID="1">School board backs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s outreach program
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> in the end wanted nothing to do with the community outreach program instigated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>. But at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s monthly meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> was all for keeping the program going, even opting to expand the coverage area of the monthly meetings.
</P><P ID="5">   At the request of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, representing the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of Directors, addressed the board <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> about the outreach program.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the program is designed to bring city services to the community. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the purpose of the program is to bridge the gap that exists in some areas of the community with such entities as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> voted a few weeks back to discontinue support of the outreach program, withdrawing the services of city staff at each of the monthly meetings in designated areas of the community.
</P><P ID="8">   Prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opting out of the program, the city, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> partnered to bring the monthly meetings to the public, which were also designed in part to give the public a place to voice concerns or ask questions.
</P><P ID="9">   "Our attendance kind of varied," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   The up-and-down numbers at each of the meetings had to do with where and when the gatherings were held, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> told the school board.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said that after each meeting she would talk with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Resources Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX> to evaluate the outreach program and work on areas that needed improvement.
</P><P ID="12">   Her long-term goal with the outreach program is to promote neighborhood collaboration. One project <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> is working on right now, she told board members, is getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Auditor</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> involved with the monthly meetings to promote voting.
</P><P ID="13">   Bones asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> what the school district can do to be a more active participant in the outreach program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> encouraged a school board member to attend the meetings with Carrera.
</P><P ID="14">   While the city has backed out with its personnel and any financial support of the program, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Mana</ENAMEX> will still be sending staff to the monthly meetings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the meetings go along with some of the outreach efforts the police department is trying to do in the community.
</P><P ID="15">   The outreach program is currently being funded through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> is working on obtaining a grant that would allow staff to be hired to continue the efforts.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> member Arthur Wells encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> to set up meetings for all local school district patrons, as opposed to outreach meetings for just those neighborhoods within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city limits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> said the school district serves residents outside of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city limits and he would like to see the program boundaries include the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> service area.
</P><P ID="17">   The school board backed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s program and offered the services of the district informational telephone line, school newsletter and monthly newsletters to get the word out about the date of each outreach meeting.
</P><P ID="18">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




