
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/3/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Vote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> on library annexation
I am writing this letter to express my thoughts about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library. We live in the county, so I can't vote on this. If I could, I would vote yes to annex with the Yakima Regional Library.
I go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library on a regular basis, and I love to go. The staff members are very nice. It is a great joy to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library.
It would sadden me greatly if it closed!
According to the information I have read, people who live in the county have been paying the library levy rate since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. I can't remember voting on it. If we who live in the county have been paying (I am happy to pay to have the library), why haven't the people in the city been paying?
I urge the people in the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to vote a huge <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda L. Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Library important
There are many reasons why the library is important to me. There are almost as many reasons as there are books in the library.
One reason is that they have lots of books on different topics. There are books on animals, fairy tales, people and history.
Another reason is their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> reading program. In this program you get little prizes like bookmarks, fun bags and stickers.
Finally, they don't just have books. They have videos and books on tape.
Hence, I think the library is important to me because they have lots of books, a good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> reading program and lots more.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marielle Abbott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> fifth grader, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Security liaison will be missed
I would like to take this opportunity to thank Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Partida</ENAMEX>, security liaison for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, for his outstanding commitment to the safety and welfare of the students, staff and parents at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> has been instrumental in curbing gang activity, violence and drugs at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>. He is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s finest role models for our youths.
Recently, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> was transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX>. I know Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> will be an asset to the Outlook community and will be instrumental in curtailing the growing concerns of gang activity in Outlook.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX>, your presence will truly be missed by students, staff and parents at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>. Outlook, you are gaining one of our finest!
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Engel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> teacher, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

