
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pierce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bodine</ENAMEX> earn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> honors
ELLENSBURG - Four Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> students have been named to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004 summer</TIMEX> quarter honor roll at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>.
To qualify for the accolades, the students had to maintain at least a 3.50 grade point average while carrying a minimum of 12 graded credit hours of study.
The academic achievers include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabitha S. Sanders</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiffanie D. Bodine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger and Shannon L. Pierce</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> veterans groups  to host cancer fund-raiser
A seafood dinner to raise funds for cancer aid and research will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 17</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SunnyView VFW Post</ENAMEX> #3482, 615 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Ave.</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> A silent auction will also be a part of the evening's activities, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Hallman</ENAMEX>, president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW Ladies Auxiliary</ENAMEX>.
She said the dinner of oysters, salmon, cod and trimmings is available at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX>, for all you can eat.
The dinner is being sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SunnyView VFW Post</ENAMEX> #3482 and Ladies Auxiliary, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Am-Vets Post</ENAMEX> #3733 and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW Men</ENAMEX>'s Auxiliary.
The event is open to the public.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

