
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Councilman promises sound fiscal decisions
As a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>, I listened intently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> as many citizens stepped up to the podium and made it clear that they are against privatization. A few of those individuals made very poignant arguments, however, the fact of the matter is this, for every city that has had a bad experience with privatization, there is another that has had a good experience.
Now, I am not saying that I am either for or against privatization. What I am saying is that the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> elected me to be their watchdog, to make sure that I make sound fiscal decisions when it comes to using the city's money. In order to do this, I need to be able to look at all aspects of the city's budget. This includes possible privatization.
Good citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, I will promise you this, whether or not I vote in favor of privatization, I will never vote for less quality or poorer standards regardless of the cost.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sarducci</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City Councilman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Untruths about teachers don’t help fix schools
I have had the privilege of getting to know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> over the past couple of years in the capacity as a tennis and basketball coach. He does a great job covering our local teams and I find him very likable on a personal level. I was, however, disappointed at some of the things he said in his personal column titled "Election night headache" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11-3-04</TIMEX>).
I also voted against I-884 because I don't think throwing more money at the education problem is the answer. I would like to see the education system use existing money more effectively. In that sense I agree with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX>.
However, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX>'s discussion of teachers wanting more pay is very off base. He notes that teachers "work a six-hour day, only work 180 days out of each year, and get to work with children." One part of that statement is true, we do get to work with children. This can be a great joy, but it can also be a tremendous struggle to have 150 kids that you are responsible for on multiple levels.
As a teacher, I take issue with Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX>'s comments regarding teacher work hours. The contract for teachers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> requires that we be at work from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> daily. If my math is correct, that's seven and a half hours a day, not six. I don't know very many teachers who keep that schedule. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> might want to look at the sign-in sheet at the high school, or others for that matter, so he can see the hours that teachers come in to do work for which they are not paid. As a teacher, a 50-hour work week is not uncommon. I have had many full time jobs in my life. Teaching is the most time consuming, mentally taxing and rewarding job of them all!
When I got into this profession, money was not a deciding factor. I wanted to have time in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> to spend with my family. What a dream that was! Not only is my <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> taken up with preparing for the next school year, I am required by the state (at my expense) to increase my education. When do you think that is done? So why is there a teaching shortage in many parts of this country?
The way Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> described it, you'd think everyone would want to teach. So, here is an open invitation. If being a teacher, advisor and mentor to 150 students daily on a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> a year salary appeals to you, then this is a great job. Oh, you have to use your summers to continue your education on your dime (about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> for me so far in my fourth year).
I love my job and wouldn't trade it for any career. I chose it over law school because of my passion for it. It's just frustrating to read misconceptions like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>'s, because teachers give their all to a system that has rules that they must live under. Fixing the system should be a priority, but promoting untruths about a teacher's job doesn't help.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Whittle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> social studies teacher
</P> 
<P ID="5">Don’t destroyour rec programs
I was dismayed to hear that the city manager plans to eliminate the position of parks and recreation manager and divide the responsibilities of that job between the park supervisor and the secretary of the parks and recreation department. Do you believe these two individuals can handle their own duties, plus supervise the community center, museum, senior center, swimming pool, organize the children's soccer and baseball teams and organize the special craft and recreation programs for adults?
As an example of one event, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> I volunteered to help with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> track meet. There were 300 participants. This event was held on a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. Would the parks and recreation secretary or park supervisor be able to organize and run all of these track events and also do their regular duties?
The parks and recreation manager is responsible for the swimming pool programs, events at the senior center and the management of the sports leagues by assigning fields and organizing games. Will the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">department secretary</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> and park supervisor be able to know what strokes should be taught in the different classifications of swimming classes? Besides their regular duties, will they be able to check on all the sports leagues and their field assignments and organize the league? Will they be present at the senior citizens casino night and participate as dealers?
The citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> deserve a well organized recreational program that meets the needs of all ages. These activities provide outlets to many who would otherwise not have these advantages. When these programs decline, we will have more juvenile problems and associated negative behaviors.
Please join me in opposing the decision of the city manager to destroy our progressive recreational program for all people in the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy L. Aiken</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Evanswill</ENAMEX> be missed
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> will certainly miss Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Evans</ENAMEX>, a long-time member of the police force.
My family and I had the pleasure of meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> when he came to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph's Hospital</ENAMEX> here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX> to witness the birth of his first grandchild, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coven M. Evans Olivas</ENAMEX>. During his visit he spoke often of "his town" with great pride. He exhibited to the community he loved the same caring that he showed his oldest daughter during the difficult birth. His strength, kindness and love helped us all, and we join the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> in their fond farewell.
We will all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> him very much.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalinda and Ron Olivas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="7">Gubernatorial candidate offers thanks to voters
Although the governor's race isn't yet decided, I want to take this opportunity to thank the readers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> for their involvement in the democratic process, whether or not they voted for me. It was a long campaign, and I truly enjoyed getting to know the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
I also want to express my good wishes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Gregoire</ENAMEX> and her family. No matter what the outcome of this race, I feel blessed to have had this wonderful experience.
If I do win, I'll start putting in place my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forward Washington</ENAMEX> agenda to get our economy going again and help get people back to work. If I don't, I'll consider it one of the greatest honors of my life to have had the opportunity to run for our state's highest office.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="8">Blood drawing very successful
Sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Blunk</ENAMEX> as chairperson, we had a very successful blood drawing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>.
The quota was 70 units. We had 87 presenters and three first-time donors. Ten were unable to give, leaving 77 units collected. Because of their efforts, 231 people will have another chance at life.
Many thanks to the sponsors for donating the cookies and juice, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> for the use of its hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX> for the great publicity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington Corrugators</ENAMEX> for displaying the banner at Centennial Square.
I would like to thank the following volunteers: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ella Mae Lochner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtis Lang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Benedetti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trude Meadowcroft</ENAMEX>, Letha Grubb, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lu Ann Roach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Coleman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lila Furukawa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Stark</ENAMEX>.
A very special thank you to the donors, who are the lifeline for the flow of blood in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. We hope to see you at the next blood drawing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Handy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

