45 36 36 37 44 20
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  If you neglect to recharge a battery, it dies. And if you run full speed ahead without stopping for water, you lose momentum to finish the race.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oprah Winfrey</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> - ), O Magazine, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2003</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>