
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Credit Service</ENAMEX> manager brings agricultural heritage to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> 
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">As one of the newest members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Crum</ENAMEX> is learning his way around the group of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> business owners and community professionals. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the club members had an opportunity to learn a bit more about the third generation <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Oregonian</ENAMEX>, who is now the manager of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> branch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Credit Service</ENAMEX>.   A recent graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon State University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crum</ENAMEX> has been in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past nine months</TIMEX>, offering lines of credit to area farmers and agriculture-related businesses.   "I come from a long line of farmers," he told the group, saying his grandfather and father are wheat farmers in the small community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ione</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermiston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>   "It's a town of 250 people and I graduated with 10 people in my high school class," he said.   "I know ag-communities," he added. "But my father discouraged me from becoming a farmer," he added.   But unable to stay away from agriculture, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crum</ENAMEX> decided on a career that offers financial aid to farmers like his dad.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crum</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Mountain Community College</ENAMEX> before transferring to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon State</ENAMEX>, where he earned a degree in agriculture business. "I like crushing numbers and going out and kicking tires with farmers," he said.   He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Credit Service</ENAMEX> has a long history of offering farmers low interest loans. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crum</ENAMEX> said he sees his job as a way to help maintain the security of the nation's food supply.   "We help to keep agriculture in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crum</ENAMEX> said.   He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> branch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Credit Service</ENAMEX> is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Farm Credit Service</ENAMEX>, which is one of five credit unions located throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crum</ENAMEX> said in addition to offering farmers low interest lines of credit for their farming operations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Credit Service</ENAMEX> also offers farm business classes for young farmers, incentives for staying in farming and low interest housing loans.   "Our agency has been around for 85 years, setting the lending standards for dealing with farmers. They know we will be there for them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crum</ENAMEX> added.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

