
<P ID="1">Curriculum developed detailing how Americans were forced from their homes and locked away in concentration camps
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kara Kondo</ENAMEX> was a young girl she was taken from her home, forced to give up nearly all of her possessions and was escorted to a train by armed soldiers for a long trek to a concentration camp she would call home.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> was not a criminal. She had done nothing wrong. The only crime she committed was living on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west coast</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> during World War II.   When the Japanese bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7, 1941</TIMEX>, the world changed for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> and others like her. People who had moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> decades earlier were suddenly being accused of spying for their home country.   "You're a traitor, more like a spy. Why, because you're Caucasian or African American or Asian or European or Middle Eastern. There have been allegations against 'your people,' not Americans, but the people [who] share your skin color, of spying. You might not have known, but it's safer to put all of 'you' away, just in case, since color and ancestry, not personality, determines whether you are trustworthy or not.   "This is basically what President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roosevelt</ENAMEX> said to all people with at least 1/16 Japanese blood living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">western Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">western Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">southern Arizona</ENAMEX>, citizen or not, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February of 1942</TIMEX> in Executive Order 9066," writes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Elizabeth Church</ENAMEX>, a student in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene Wells</ENAMEX>'s class at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Discovery Lab School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   The students in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>'s class spent an entire school year researching the experiences of Japanese Americans during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>' involvement in World War II. The middle school students interviewed Japanese Americans who lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> during that point in history, read books about relocation centers and visited museums to learn about the experience.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX>, one of the women interviewed by the students for the project, said during the taped interview that she remembers calling the relocation centers, concentration camps.   "Relocation center is a nice term for concentration camps," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said in the tape.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX>, who was born in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> and grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, told the students that her father came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX>, with her mother following in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>. She said her mother grew up in a privileged family in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kobe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX>, leaving it all to live with her husband in the brush land of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern Washington</ENAMEX>.   "You can't imagine what it was like in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said. She explained to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>'s class that it was all sagebrush, with dirt roads meant for horse and buggy traffic.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> added that making the adjustment was difficult for her mother, who couldn't speak English.   "I'm not sure how she got through it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said.   However, her mother wasn't the only Japanese immigrant working to adjust to life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> explained during the interview that in the 1920s the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> became a popular area for Japanese immigrants to settle. She noted that once the Japanese began to arrive in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, they started to isolate themselves. She said the Japanese immigrants couldn't speak English, ate different foods and had their own traditions. She told the students that isolation meant they could speak to each other in their own language and eat familiar foods, making it feel more like home.   "It was a small community within a larger community," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students that the Japanese community in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> had their own clubs and churches. She said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese Methodist Church</ENAMEX> was established in the early 1920s and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Japanese Buddhist Church</ENAMEX> was established in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1930s</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>.   One of the reasons Japanese immigrants settled in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said in the tape, was because people coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> were not given the right of citizenship, which meant they were unable to purchase land. She explained that it ended up being easier for them to lease land from the Yakama Nation.   "That is why many of them lived on the reservation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students.   One of the students in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>'s class, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Antonio</ENAMEX>, said after hearing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> talk about the isolation of the Japanese in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> and after reading the book "Farewell to Manzinea," several class members got together to talk about whether or not the students had ever felt isolated from society because they were different.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio</ENAMEX> said during the discussion it became apparent that many of his classmates felt that at some point in their lives they had been bothered because they were different. He said there were a wide range of things that came up during the discussion.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio</ENAMEX> said one thing the entire group agreed on after the discussion, is that although they may have felt singled out or different at some point in their lives, it was nothing like what happened to the Japanese living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years ago</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students that she can still remember the day <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> was attacked. She said on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7, 1941</TIMEX>, she remembers going to church but not hearing the radio announcement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> base had been bombed.   "My father looked very, very troubled when we got home," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students. "That was when we realized that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> was bombed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said in the taped interview that she remembers her family being uncertain as to what would happen to them.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX>, it was just days after the attack that many of the leaders of the local Japanese community were picked up by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>. She said this meant there were families who didn't know where their fathers were taken.   "In a way, the community was without their leaders," she said. "That was the first reaction."   However, in the days and weeks that passed after the attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> life for the Japanese living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> became more and more restrictive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students that the government first confiscated their guns, swords, radios and cameras. She said they were then given an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> curfew, meaning that no one of Japanese ancestry could be out of their home after that time each evening. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said in the interview that another restriction meant Japanese-Americans could not travel more than 15 miles from their homes and if they did, they had to be back by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> that evening.   "Day by day these orders came down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students. "You knew you could not be as free as we were before."   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> wrote in her Japanese internment essay that what other Americans didn't understand about the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> was that it also affected Japanese Americans, because they lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   "The Japanese of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> were just as affected as others after the bombing of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> because they, too, were Americans," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> wrote. "Still others automatically convicted people of Japanese ancestry of being spies because they were afraid and wanted all measure of safety to be taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> government to keep them safe...But no one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> was actually convicted of spying before, during or after the two years the Japanese internment lasted. In fact, Japanese- Americans themselves were shocked when they were accused of spying for a country that they didn't even consider theirs."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said during the taped interview that she remembers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX> as the date the government sent down orders for exclusion. She explained to the students that at first the order stated that all people of Japanese ancestry living within 150 miles of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> coast of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> be sent to relocation camps.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said for Japanese living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, it made life more uncertain because they lived just outside that 150-mile mark. She told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>'s class that people in the area were told to continue living their lives as usual and to keep farming.   "For a long time we weren't sure whether the people from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> area would be taken and put into camps," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said during the interview.   Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1942</TIMEX>, the area of those to be sent to camp was enlarged, with the entire area from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> being established as a military zone. She said that was when the Japanese in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> were notified that they too would be evacuated.   "What does that mean?," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> asked the students. "[It means] you will be taken from your home."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said this meant that people had to prepare to only take with them what they could carry. She said by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late May</TIMEX> people had either sold or stored most of their possessions.   When it came to time to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students she can still remember soldiers coming to town from Fort <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, taking their names and telling them when to board the train for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Portland</ENAMEX> assembly center, which had previously served as a livestock center.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said there was an old train that left for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX> at sunset on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX>, carrying 1,300 Japanese from throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said during the taped interview that she can still remember the soldiers who put them on the train, then stood two soldiers per train car for the entire two-day trip.   Disembarking the train, carrying all she had in the world, she told the students she remembers seeing a tall barbed wire fence running along the perimeter of the center.   "I still remember the sound of the metal gate clanging behind me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said of entering the center. "Then you knew you were in this [camp] and [had] no more freedom."   When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX>'s family arrived at the center what they found was a livestock center that had been converted into a rudimentary assembly center. She told the students that the center had been prepared by simply putting down plywood floors and putting boards up every few feet to serve as a place for families to sleep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said each unit was large enough for two or three cots and not much else. There were about 3,000 people housed at the assembly center.   "It was noisy, there was a lot of confusion," she said during the interview. "It was very uncomfortable."   Despite being torn from their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said those housed at the assembly center tried to maintain some semblance of an ordinary life. She told the students that at the center there were different clubs for people to take part in and the Japanese children attended classes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> and her family spent the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> at the assembly center, moving from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heart Mount</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said it took her family two nights to get from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, arriving to find construction workers still building parts of the facility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said during the interview that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heart Mountain</ENAMEX> relocation center, which housed 10,000 to 12,000 Japanese, made the community the third largest city in the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX>.   The relocation center consisted of rows and rows of barracks, long buildings that were divided into six apartments housing two or three people each, to larger apartments that housed up to five people. She said when her family arrived at their apartment all they found to greet them was a single bed and a large pot-bellied stove.   Also making up the relocation center were several mess halls, a laundry room and a latrine with toilets and showers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students that this meant regardless of the weather, people had to stand outside in long lines waiting to use the bathroom.   Despite being torn from their homes and moved to an unfamiliar place, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said the Japanese-Americans living in the camps tried to maintain some semblance of normality. She said over the first few months churches were established, schools were started for the children and clubs were organized.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said during the interview that the camps also had their own doctors and camp police officers.   "We tried to live as normal a life as possible," she said.   One thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> did to help make the transition to camp life easier, was to get a job at the camp newspaper, The Heart Mountain Sentinel. She told the students she worked her way from being a reporter to serving as the society editor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said when she tells people she was the society editor of the camp newspaper, no one can imagine that there were society events to be published. She said she would write about weddings, club meetings and church events. She said the newspaper was published once a week in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cody</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Iseri</ENAMEX>, who was also interviewed by the students and lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> before being relocated to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heart Mountain</ENAMEX>, was a young boy when his family moved to the relocation center.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> said in a videotaped interview that he can remember being forced to say the Pledge of Allegiance every day at the school located at the camp. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> said the children would recite the entire pledge, ending it by saying, "...with liberty and justice for all, except us."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> told the students that at first teachers at the school tried to make the children stop ad-libbing at the end of the pledge, but then one day they just stopped. "Because they realized we were right," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> told the students that when he and his family first arrived at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heart Mountain</ENAMEX> he attended school in a barracks that was furnished with nothing more than chairs and notebooks. He noted that later a school was built for the children.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX>, some of the people living at the camp were also hired to work at the camp. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX>'s father served as the assistant cook in the mess hall.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students that there was a store at camp where people could buy little trinkets and items they needed for everyday life. She added that most of the people in camp opted instead to spend the little money they earned to order items through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Roebuck</ENAMEX> catalog.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> said in the interview that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heart Mountain</ENAMEX> relocation camp was in existence for several years before the government decided it was time for those living in the camps to be let go, between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>.   However, the residents of the camp weren't simply released and sent home. Instead, freedom came just as slowly as imprisonment had. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students that at first the young men in the camps were sent outside the camp walls to work at farms in the area. She said the next people granted permission to leave were students who were allowed to attend colleges on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">east coast</ENAMEX> and in the mid-west.   "Gradually they encouraged families to leave the camp," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students. She noted that it wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> that most families were allowed to return to their homes.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> and his family, being given permission to leave the camp wasn't enough. Instead, he and his brothers and sisters were forced to pick potatoes in fields outside of camp to raise the money needed to make it back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>. Even once the money had been raised, it wasn't an easy trip for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> family.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> told the students that his father and other siblings left camp during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer of 1945</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX>, his mother and his grandmother stayed at the camp until later that fall. He said the reason they stayed back is because he had gotten very sick once he had come back from picking potatoes and was unable to travel.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX>, permission to leave the camp came early. She said she left in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1943</TIMEX> to get married in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>. She said during the interview that together she and her husband lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX> until after the war, when they moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>.   "That was the place that was home," she said.   However, when she returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> she didn't find the same welcoming community she had left behind so many years before. Instead, she told the students she remembers there being "No Japs wanted" signs posted in many of the store windows in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> community.   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> was a very hostile place," she said.   In fact, she noted that of the 1,300 Japanese who were forced to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> was attacked, only about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2 percent</NUMEX> of them returned to the area after the war.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>'s class that he feels one of the reasons so many Japanese never came back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> is because before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>' involvement in the war, they made their living as farmers. He said after the war farming was no longer lucrative.   When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX>'s family moved back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> after they were given permission to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heart Mountain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> said during the interview that instead of living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, as they had before, his family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>.   "We had nothing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> said.   He explained to the students that before boarding the train that would take them to the assembly center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, his father had leased someone the family business with the understanding that the family would get it back when they returned. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> said his family returned to find the business condemned.   The family business wasn't the only thing that had fallen victim to the politics of war during the absence of the Japanese in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> told the students that when his family returned they found the Japanese language school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> had been burnt down.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> told the students that the subject of what his family went through during World War II was one his parents simply never talked about.   "They just held it inside," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iseri</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> told the students that gradually the Japanese had their civil rights returned to them and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> Japanese immigrants became eligible for citizenship.   Although it's been nearly 60 years since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kondo</ENAMEX> first boarded the train that would take her away from her home, it's an experience that will in live on in her mind forever.   "The memories are still there," she said.   And it's those memories that students in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>'s class are working to ensure don't get lost over time.   "We really want to share this experience with others," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> said.   The students recently donated two large boxes filled with an entire curriculum that outlines the Japanese experience in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> after <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> bombed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX>. The curriculum boxes were donated to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

