
<P ID="1">Sports Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Coeur d'Alene Resort course to host senior amateur tourney
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">COEUR D'ALENE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">IDAHO</ENAMEX> - A new event for senior amateur golfers will be staged at the Coeur d'Alene Resort Golf Course in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late August</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Dodge Dealers Senior Amateur Classic</ENAMEX> is a two-day handicapped stroke play tourney that is open to all male golfers over 50 years of age and all female golfers over the age of 45. The competition will feature handicapped flights for males 50 to 64 years old, females 45 and over and males 65 and over. The event is open to the public. The entry deadline is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>.
"With a healthy prize fund and a capped field of 124 players, we're expecting a great turnout for a first year event," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Delong</ENAMEX>, director of golf at the resort.
Prizes will range from Henry-Griffitts drivers to a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Dodge Viper. In addition to the many extras included in the tournament, registration fees include two nights in Premier <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Tower</ENAMEX> accommodations at the Coeur d'Alene Resort.
To register, contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Pearl</ENAMEX> at (800) 935-6283, or visit the web site: www.floatinggreen.com
</P> 
<P ID="4">Opening night tickets for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Single game tickets for opening night and all regular season Yakima Bears baseball games go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 5</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> minor league baseball office, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bears</ENAMEX> open the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> season on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 18</TIMEX>, with a three-game series at Tri-City. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bears</ENAMEX>' opening homestand, a five-game series against the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett AquaSox</ENAMEX>, is slated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21-25</TIMEX>.
Opening night in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County Stadium</ENAMEX> will feature quarter hot dogs, magnetic schedules for the first 1,000 fans and fireworks following the game.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to host track & field night
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The annual youth track and field night, sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>, will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 12</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rich Leenhouts Stadium</ENAMEX>.
Parents must register their children on-site, between 6:30 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> The event is open to youngsters 1 to 12 years of age, and the cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> per participant. Ribbons will be awarded to the top finishers. Events will include 100, 200 and 400-yard dashes, a softball throw and long jump.
Those interested in volunteering to stage the track and field competitions are urged to call the Grandview parks office at 882-9219.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Grand Hoops Fiesta 3-on-3 tourney <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 7</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The 11th annual Grand Hoops Fiesta 3-on-3 Youth Basketball Tournament will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 7</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s event will be held adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Middle School on West</ENAMEX> 2nd Street. Registration forms are available now at the Grandview Parks and Recreation office. Girls and boys ages 9 to 18 are eligible to compete.
The team entry fee is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>, and parent signatures are required for each participant. Deadline to register is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 27</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> junior golf camp scheduled
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Adams Country Club</ENAMEX> will host a junior golf camp for youngsters 5 to 17 years of age, beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX>.
Golf professionals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Galbraith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Hunsaker</ENAMEX> will provide camp participants with instruction on fundamental golf skills, golf etiquette and the basic rules of golf.
"And, it's about having fun," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunsaker</ENAMEX>.
The camp for 5 to 11-year-olds will be staged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29</TIMEX>, 30 and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2</TIMEX>, from 9 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> each of the three days. Youths 12 to 17 years of age will be in camp on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6</TIMEX>, 7 and 9, from 9 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> each day.
The registration cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunsaker</ENAMEX> urges all youths to register as soon as possible (865-4440).
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

