
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> legislators begin work anew <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> legislators <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> are going to have their hands full. The two Republican state representatives joined their cohorts in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> session.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s gathering in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> for the state's elected officials will be a short 60-day session. Both men say much work must be crammed into the short period of time.   Besides trying to thwart the attempts of Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> to siphon money from the state's reserve funds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> say legislators' plates will be filled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> with several issues that need to be addressed immediately.   One of those issues is reforming the state's medical malpractice guidelines. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area legislators say the current costs of malpractice insurance, in terms of both premiums and settlements, are bankrupting the medical profession and driving physicians out of the state.   "It's at a point of total meltdown," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, presently serving his first term in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Representatives.   "We're losing doctors, especially in our smaller communities.   "Right now there are 21 doctors in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> who can't get malpractice insurance. It's either too expensive or it's not offered," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> explain that one of the reasons the premiums for medical malpractice insurance are not affordable is because claims are so high. The two political allies say caps must be implemented on all medical malpractice claims.   "One of the ideas being talked about is assigning an amount of responsibility," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>.   In essence, that means setting a percentage or a ceiling on the amount of money a claimant could collect. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> are quick to point out that advocates of this idea aren't trying to limit the insurance payout to people who successfully file claims for such things as actual medical bills and time lost from work.   "What we're talking about is a pain and suffering cap," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, explaining that instead of millions of dollars being awarded by courtroom juries, a more sensible ceiling for such settlements might fall in the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> range.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> is a sitting member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> judiciary committee, which ensures that at the very least the topic of medical malpractice reform will be addressed this session.   Also apt to be tossed around in legislative chambers this session, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, is the issue of health care costs.   "We've had double-digit growth in health care costs for several years," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>. "Health care costs are affecting everyone...business, you and me, state government."   Changes that are needed, say the two legislators, include Medicaid reimbursement rate adjustments, redefining small group insurance rates and having more flexibility in insurance coverages.   Reforming the way the state adjudicates water rights is bound to come up in discussions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> this session, too. The two men said the state's "use it or lose it" measure needs to be changed so that farmers and ranchers aren't penalized for not using irrigation water.   "After all, if you don't need irrigation water one season and you leave water in the stream, it's benefiting fish," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>.   Under current state law, those holding water rights must give up their water to the state if they haven't utilized their rights for five successive years.   Reform to the state's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor and Industries</ENAMEX> division is also badly needed, say both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>.   "We need to look at how the L&I trust fund is managed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>. "And, L&I has to do a better job at getting people back to work.   "Accountability is needed-both in minimizing fraud and in doing a better job of getting people's claims approved in a more timely manner," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said they are also unhappy with the news that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>, who is giving up his seat as governor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, has indicated that his supplemental budget will draw down the surplus funds that have been stored away by legislators.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> is abandoning the (budgetary) principles that were established <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>.   He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> went on to explain that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> is proposing to expand on the state's existing programs, in areas such as increasing the enrollment counts at state universities.   "If we deplete our reserves and abandon our budget approach, it will make for more difficult times," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>. "What's being proposed in this supplemental budget will amount to a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> deficit."   Both men say now is not the time to put <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state into further economic peril. They said the sound financial principles that were adhered to in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s legislative session need to be continued this session, in hopes that the state's economic climate continues to rebound.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

