
<P ID="1">Grid Kid sign-ups <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/29/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The tenth year of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Grid Kid football is about to get underway. Team sign-ups will be held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 30</TIMEX>, from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football field.   To be eligible players must be between 9 and 12 years old, have a copy of their birth certificate and pay a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> registration fee.   There will be a football camp in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> that will stress fundamentals and teamwork. The exact days of the camp have not been set yet.   Questions can be addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max Saldana</ENAMEX> at 839-2968.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

