


<P ID="1">Animals rights group uses mad cow disease scare to promote its belief in not eating meat
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The reaction was predictable. The subject of mad cow disease in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> is a very touchy one, and three representatives from the People for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ethical Treatment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animals (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PETA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> touched a nerve when they arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> just in time for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> rush <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Carrying signs reading, "It's Mad to Eat Meat, Go Veg," and "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, the Mad Cow Capitol of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PETA</ENAMEX> special projects coordinator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Chorush</ENAMEX> and volunteers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudine Erlandson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Pennington</ENAMEX>, all from the Seattle area, waved to motorists from their post on Sixth Street in front of Safeway. The trio, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorush</ENAMEX> dressed in a cow costume, held up signs and passed out literature on vegetarianism to anyone who showed any interest.
</P><P ID="6">   Many drivers slowed to pass the three demonstrators, however most of them did not offer any support. Instead, several motorists pulled into the grocery store parking lot and loudly announced they were going to go in specifically to buy cuts of meat, particularly beef.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorush</ENAMEX> said he knew coming to the area where the first case of mad cow disease was discovered less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a month ago</TIMEX> the group was not likely to receive a warm welcome.
</P><P ID="8">   "It's a bit friendlier than we thought," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorush</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   He said the group's objective in coming to the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> was not necessarily to change people's attitude toward eating meat, but instead to make people think about the current situation.
</P><P ID="10">   "People want everything to go back to normal, but it's not going to happen," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorush</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlandson</ENAMEX> said the group braved snowy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> passes to come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> from the Seattle area <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, going over Stevens Pass due to the closure of Snoqualmie Pass. She said the trip took the trio about 10 hours.
</P><P ID="12">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlandson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chorush</ENAMEX>, before coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> they had gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> to take a look at the cows in the area and planned on returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> before heading back over the mountains.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlandson</ENAMEX> said for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 10 years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PETA</ENAMEX> has had a campaign to ban downer animals from the human food supply. However, it wasn't until the first case of mad cow disease was discovered that the ban was put into place, she said, pointing to the recent announcement made by Agriculture Secretary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Veneman</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   "It passed very quickly then," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlandson</ENAMEX> said of the ban on downer animals.
</P><P ID="15">   She explained that many people don't understand the disease and the danger that eating meat can pose, which is why <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PETA</ENAMEX> has been staging similar demonstrations at grocery stores and restaurants across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erlandson</ENAMEX>, a 15-year member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PETA</ENAMEX>, said while in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> promoting vegetarianism a lot of people walking or driving by were docile and unresponsive.
</P><P ID="17">   "But this is where it all happened," she said.
</P><P ID="18">   For <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Uberuaga</ENAMEX>, having <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PETA</ENAMEX> show up in his community promoting vegetarianism was like a slap in the face.
</P><P ID="19">   "These folks...are insulting us as a community, our families, our friends," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="20">   It was this feeling that led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> to react to the demonstration in front of the local grocery store. He said when he first noticed the group and its signs he didn't feel good about it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> said he found that when he got back to his house he simply got angrier and then decided he was going to do something about it.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> pulled into the Safeway parking lot, pulled out a bag of hamburgers and proceeded to stand in the bed of a truck while he chomped away at the burgers in front of the PETA demonstrators.
</P><P ID="22">   "[It's a] show of support for our community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> said, who gave hamburgers to six other supporters. "It's one thing to promote vegetarianism, it's another to come in and say hurtful things about the community," he added.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorene Perez</ENAMEX>, who came out to show her support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX>, said she shares his feelings on the PETA demonstration.
</P><P ID="24">   "Our community is a victim," she said.
</P><P ID="25">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PETA</ENAMEX> representatives demonstrated in front of Safeway for a little over an hour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="26">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="27">Webmaster
</P><P ID="28">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




