


<P ID="1">City Studies Plan for New Voting Machines
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/17/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">With national attention riveted on how chads in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> have thrown the nation into an electoral morass, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> officials are thinking about ditching punch-card machines and spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> on the newest in paperless technology.  
</P>
<P ID="5">The mayor and three of the five members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> say the city needs to upgrade its voting machines, although they said any move might have to be made in small, more affordable steps.  
</P>
<P ID="6">"You can't keep the same system after what we've been through," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX>
</P>
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> briefed his colleagues about the city's creaky election machinery. He also reported on an experiment at nine locations with 38 high-tech voting gizmos called touch screens. 
</P>
<P ID="8">They can count in seven languages, talk to blind people and spit out answers faster than a politician's spin machine. 
</P>
<P ID="9">Many computer scientists strongly urge caution. 
</P>
<P ID="10">They vehemently debate the vulnerability of electronic voting to tampering, but election officials say the machines have won voters' trust.  Conceivably, the city could slog along with its punch-card Votomatics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said. "But I don't think voters would stand for it. This is a national issue now," he said of election methods nationwide. 
</P>
<P ID="11">If financing appears and no other major obstacles arise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> thinks they could outfit the entire city with touch screens by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. 
</P>

