
<P ID="1">New school property eventually to be annexed into city limits
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Palacios</ENAMEX> has always been one for forming partnerships, even during his days as mayor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   So when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> passed a bond/levy this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past February</TIMEX> that will allow for the construction of a new school in the northeast area outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> saw an opportunity he couldn't resist.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> has been spearheading an effort for the past several months to partner with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> to help upgrade the area in the northeast section of town around <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cemetery</ENAMEX> roads. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX>' plan calls for residents in the area, where there is between 75 and 80 homes, to hook-up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> utilities, eventually annexing into the city.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> asked for a meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> officials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> to see what sort of partnership the three entities could form to help make improvements the county commissioner has been aiming for in the area to the northeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   Where the school district fits into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX>' plans is that with the construction of a new middle school, the county commissioner is hoping the school district will help with some of the expenses of extending water lines out to residents in the area. The school district purchased 56 acres for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$360,000</NUMEX> to construct a new school, in the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> roads. The property sits just outside of the city limits near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>'s meeting helped clear up some issues for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> officials.   One of the reasons for the meeting was Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> about some concerns he had with the property the district purchased, which is entirely in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>. Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Plesha</ENAMEX> said the mayor was concerned about whether the property fell in the Urban Growth Area of the city.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s meeting was a productive one, as the school district learned the city will be willing to connect utilities for the new middle school that will be constructed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said the school district will incur a slightly higher rate for water and sewage disposal as a result of being outside of city limits.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braven Bendzak</ENAMEX>, director of facilities for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, said the city will connect the new district school to its utilities through an outside utilities agreement. Through the city allowing the school district to utilize its wastewater treatment facilities, the property on which the new school is to be built will eventually be annexed into the city, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bendzak</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bendzak</ENAMEX> also said all but 15.8 acres of the 56 acres of property the district purchased falls within the city's Urban Growth Area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bendzak</ENAMEX> also said the city is talking with the school district about possibly placing a new water well on the school district property. The city currently operates a well on school district property, alongside the high school football field.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said while most cities have their schools within city limits, the local school district did nothing out of the ordinary by purchasing property in the county. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> is outside of the city. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> also added when the property for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> was purchased it was also outside of city limits.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bendzak</ENAMEX> said during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s meeting, county officials talked about partnering with the school district for improvement work they are looking at doing in the areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beckner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McClain</ENAMEX> roads.   Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bendzak</ENAMEX> said the school district is open to any sort of partnership with either the city or the county and will be exploring different options down the road.   "We want to make sure what we are trying to do with this new school is what the city and the county is trying to do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bendzak</ENAMEX>. "It is going to be a partnership with everybody involved."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said he is hoping a partnership can be formed between the three entities to provide a better way of life for people living in that area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said people there are running a health risk because of the lack of utility services, such as sewer and water. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said there have been reports in some areas in the northeast section of town that septic flow is coming up out of the ground.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said in the next few weeks there will be another meeting of the different groups involved in the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said the next meeting will involve engineers with the project, which he views as a step in the right direction.   "It will be a really neat thing if we can bring some improvement into that area," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

