
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/13/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaSalle</ENAMEX> open house <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNION GAP</ENAMEX> - Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> families interested in providing their children with an educational opportunity in the tradition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Brothers</ENAMEX> are invited to attend an open house at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaSalle High School</ENAMEX>.
Those who attend the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, April 19</TIMEX>, open house will have the opportunity to visit with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaSalle</ENAMEX> students, parents and faculty about the college preparatory classes offered there, Christian values, personalized education and the campus ministry.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaSalle High School</ENAMEX> is located just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ahtanum Road</ENAMEX>, off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goodman Road</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>. The open house hours will be from 4:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">College information available at family event  
Information about college applications and financial aid will be made available to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> families during a special family night to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 13</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
Organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> GEAR-Up program, the two-hour program will include representatives from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Learning Center</ENAMEX>.
In addition to information about post-high school education, a variety of math and science activities are being planned, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luz Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, Yakima Valley GEAR-Up parent liaison.
Additional activities include a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Science Center</ENAMEX> technology exhibit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> family night event, she said.
For more information about the evening call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> at (509) 961-9894 or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lino Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> GEAR-Up site director at 830-2149.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

