
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU's Orchesis Dance Company</ENAMEX> to take the stage
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University's Orchesis Dance Company</ENAMEX> will present its 37th spring concert next week-April 29, 30 and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> 1-in McConnell Auditorium on the Ellensburg campus.   Titled "Extensions," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s annual spring performance will include classical ballet, modern, jazz, tap and ethnic dance.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Therese Young</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> dance program coordinator, will direct the performance by the 40-member group, half of whom are dance minors at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX>.   The featured works will include:   ? "Forests in Flight," choreographed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Holden</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> senior from Auburn, which incorporates unusual movement with exotic masks;   ? "Snake Food," choreographed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Galey</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> senior from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX>, which "resonates an earthy, tribal feeling," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young</ENAMEX>;   ? "Trials and Tribulations," which pays tribute to Holocaust survivors who are each forced to deal with the reality of death. This piece was co-choreographed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ott</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mill Creek</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Pitts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kirkland</ENAMEX>.   The performances will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> each evening, with doors opening at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> General admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX>. Pre-sale tickets are now available in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU Student Union Building</ENAMEX> and at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s Downtown Pharmacy. Tickets will also be sold at the door.   The Orchesis spring concert is being co-produced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> health, human performance and recreation, and theatre arts departments.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

