
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> tables sheriff's sales tax proposal
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/14/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima County Sheriff Ken Irwin</ENAMEX> has a plan to generate additional revenues for the county and cities to combat funding problems with law and justice. While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> sees his proposal to implement a 3/10th of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> sales tax in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> as a viable solution, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> sees things a bit differently.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> came before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> with a presentation of his 3/10th of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> sales tax to help generate money for criminal justice programs. Groceries, medical services and automobile sales are the only items exempt from the tax. If voters passed the measure, which is anticipated to be on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election ballot, the county is expected to generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.7 million</NUMEX> in the first year. The county would receive <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the money gained under the tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> would receive an anticipated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$279,873</NUMEX> from the tax in the first year.   At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was discussing the idea of whether or not to draft a letter of support for the sales tax.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> recommended drafting a letter of support for the measure, but recommended one change. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> wanted to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> commissioners do away with the six-year sunset clause. The sunset clause for this measure says the county will bring the matter back before voters for approval in six years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the sunset clause was a part of the ballot measure that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> recommended doing away with the sunset clause because cities are already having enough trouble finding funding for programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> didn't want to hire additional personnel with the money and then voters not renew the measure in six years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said this would mean having to eliminate positions or finding additional funding in cash-strapped times to support any new programs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also voiced concerns over the wording in the sheriff's proposal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said from his understanding state law does not allow the money generated from the proposed sales tax to fund existing programs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$280,000</NUMEX> the city would receive from the tax is needed, as it represents <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s law and justice budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he would recommend approving a letter of support with the removal of the sunset clause.   "We would figure out how to deal with the rest," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, saying there is no reason for the city to hire any additional personnel without some sort of funding guarantees to keep the new positions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> also agreed on removing the sunset clause.   However, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> wasn't in favor of drafting a letter of support. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>, who wasn't in attendance for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s presentation, said he wanted to see it a bit more defined on where the money is going to be spent.   "In view of the way the county does business, I would like to see it (the ballot measure) better defined," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>.   Councilman John Torch also wanted to explore ways where the city could use the money from the tax to fund existing programs. Torch also wanted to explore the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> operating its own juvenile justice facility.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> cautioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that if it didn't adopt a resolution of support with the one change about the sunset clause it was unlikely the city would have much of a voice on the matter at all.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> interjected and told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that at a meeting of the Yakima Valley Conference of Governments all three Yakima County commissioners-Jesse Palacios, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay-said</ENAMEX> they wouldn't move forward with the ballot measure if all of the cities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> weren't aboard.   With that, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opted to postpone discussion on the resolution of support until the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19</TIMEX> meeting.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

