
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/18/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> to host Scottish Festthis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - Everything Scottish, from Celtic music to Highland games such as an anvil launch to sheep dog trials, will be out in plain view <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> at the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benton Wine & Food Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
Gates to the park open for the annual Scottish Fest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, June 19</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX>
Organizers say festival goers will be treated to Celtic music and pipe bands while watching primitive arts and crafts exhibitions. Also scheduled are a sheep dog trial, Highland games, an anvil launch, Celtic story tellers and numerous children's activities. Theme foods and beverages will be available for purchase, as well. In addition, organizers have arranged for a U.S. Stick Dressing championship <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
Admission costs range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for adults to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for senior citizens and children.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Health career camps for youths scheduled
There's no reason for your children to be bored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. Parents are being encouraged to check out several health career camps for their youngsters, two of which are offered here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen O'Brien Saunders</ENAMEX>, executive director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Workforce Training and Education Coordinating Board</ENAMEX>, said a health career camp will give youths an opportunity to learn first-hand what it's like to be an emergency medical technician, doctor, registered nurse or cardiovascular technician.
In a series of week-long career camps being held throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, students will observe operations, participate in mock emergencies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">practive CPR</ENAMEX> and wear actual scrubs as they find out what it takes to work in health care. They will also attend lectures, visit labs, hospices, hospitals and various emergency medical services. In addition, information will be provided on financial aid packages that are available to youths, and how to plan the remainder of their high school career more effectively.
"It's an opportunity for them to explore jobs in health care, and find out first-hand what additional classes they need in high school to make the most of their postsecondary education," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX>.
She said camps normally are free to participants who are between the ages of 13 and 21.
The two health career camps being offered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> are scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21 through July 30</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5-9</TIMEX>. The first is a six-week <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> vocation health career program for high school students. The second is a math and science institute for health careers for middle school students, to be held at YVCC. The contact person for both camps is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Benavides</ENAMEX> (509-865-7630, extension 204).
</P> 
<P ID="5">Early Music Festival planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LEAVENWORTH</ENAMEX> - Early music performed on period instruments will fill the air of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17-22</TIMEX>.
The first ever Icicle Creek Early Music Festival will be held those six days. Beneath Ponderosa pines beside the glacier-fed Icicle Creek in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cascade Mountain</ENAMEX> foothills near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX>, four performances of baroque and renaissance chamber music will be presented. There will also be daily lectures, demonstrations and workshops at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icicle Creek Music Center</ENAMEX>.
Internationally known performers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Stubbs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> on lute and baroque guitar, Hans-Jurgen Schnoor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lubeck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> on fortepiano and harpsichord, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susie Napper</ENAMEX> of Montreal on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">viola da</ENAMEX> gamba and baroque cello, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Haynes</ENAMEX> of Montreal on baroque oboe have committed to performing at the event.
The festival performances will include "Cristofori in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX>" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at Canyon Wren Recital Hall, "The King's Own Music: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louis XIV</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frederick</ENAMEX> the Great" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at the Grunewald Guild, "War and Peace: Renaissance and Baroque" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at Canyon Wren Recital Hall, and "The Baroque Piano and J.S. Bach" on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sleeping</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chapel Theater</ENAMEX>.
Billed as an artistic retreat, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Icicle Creek Music Center</ENAMEX> is an educational facility and performance venue. Completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, the facilities include workshop and practice rooms, cabin lodging and two ideal sites for early music performances.
The cost to attend the six-day program is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$420</NUMEX>. Inquiries should be directed to (800) 281-8026 or icicleearlymusic@hotmail.com.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Hop Rod Brew Fest returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> area
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Puterbaugh Farms, located between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, will again be the site of the Hop Rod Brew Festival.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s fest, as tradition dictates, will again feature beer and wine sampling, a hot rod show and shine, and hot food grilled by the Knights of Columbus. Children's activities will also be set up so families can attend.
A special treat at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fest, scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 10</TIMEX> from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>, will be the guitar and vocal talents of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Fortier</ENAMEX>.
Admission costs will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for everyone under 21 years of age. All proceeds will benefit the Knights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>.
Puterbaugh Farms is located on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley Road</ENAMEX>, just off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midvale Road</ENAMEX> that runs south from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Monster trucksat fair racewayall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The major league of monster trucks returns to the State Fair Raceway in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18-20</TIMEX>.
Headlining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s show is Grave Digger—six-time World Monster Truck Champion Tom Meents, driving Maximum Destruction. Also scheduled to appear are El Toro Loco, Obsession, local <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tuff</ENAMEX> trucks, the Quad Warriors and the State Fair Raceway Hornets.
Each performance will feature Monster Truck racing, as well as Monster Truck freestyle.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, gates open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> with racing at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, gates open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> with racing at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, all kids 12 and under will be given a free toy Monster Truck. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, all dads will get in free for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Father's Day</TIMEX> with a paid family member admission.
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Rawls</ENAMEX> to perform in Seattle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Rawls</ENAMEX> will take the stage five times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8-11</TIMEX> at Dimitriou's Jazz Alley in Seattle.
With a voice as distinctive and instantly rcognizable as any in music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> will perform an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> set on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8</TIMEX>, a pair of 8 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:15 p.m.</TIMEX> sets on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9-10</TIMEX>, and two more 6:30 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:45 p.m.</TIMEX> sets on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX>.
Throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX>' career there has been one constant—a voice that critics call sweet as sugar, soft as velvet, strong as steel and smooth as butter. In his 40-some years as a recording artist, spanning an astonishing 70-plus albums, three Grammy awards and 13 Grammy nominations, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> has epitomized theultimate song stylist.
His television and movie credits include being the singing voice of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garfield</ENAMEX>, one of the Rugrats in the film "Rugrats: The Movie" and numerous cameo appearances on such shows as "Norm," "Baywatch Nights" and "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> is currently touring to support his latest release, "Rawls Sings Sinatra."
Tickets, priced at about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>, are available by calling Dimitriou's Jazz Alley at (206) 441-9729.
</P> 
<P ID="9">‘Roar in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Core’Labor Day</TIMEX> weekend
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">COEUR D'ALENE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">IDAHO</ENAMEX> - Motorcycle enthusiasts and rock-n-roll fans need to pencil in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> weekend on their calendars.
"The Roar in Core" will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 3-6</TIMEX> at the Kootenai County Fairgrounds in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coeur d'Alene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>. The event will entail all aspects of the cycling lifestyle, including bike displays from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, interactive exhibits, vendors row, tattoo artists, custom bikes, poker runs and charity rides.
Organizers also promise top notch musical entertainment for rock-n-roll fans. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 4</TIMEX>, on stage will be Shades of Purple, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jude Bowerman</ENAMEX> and The Fabulous Thunderbirds. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 5</TIMEX>, No Quarter and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Frampton</ENAMEX> will entertain what is sure to be a capacity crowd.
The four-day event also offers on-site camping, a saloon and NASCAR simulators. The Roar in Core will be held the same weekend as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coeur d'Alene</ENAMEX>'s Balloon Fest.
Tickets for The Roar in Core are available at any Tickets West location.
</P> 
<P ID="10">‘Fun in the Sun’ figure skating championshipson for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18-19</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KENNEWICK</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Figure Skating Club</ENAMEX> is hosting its annual "Fun in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX>" figure skating championships <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 19</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s event brings together two competitions in one—an endorsed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ice Skating Institute</ENAMEX> recreational competition and a sanctioned U.S. Figure Skating competitive event. Nearly 100 skaters are expected to take part.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Figure Skating Club</ENAMEX> invites the public to come and enjoy watching the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic</ENAMEX> hopefuls compete. Admission to all events is free of charge.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s performances at the Tri-Cities Coliseum rink B will be from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

