
<P ID="1">25-year-old woman named assistant principal at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> school
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Loffer</ENAMEX> was a senior in high school she wrote a paper on how she wanted to be an administrator in education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>, who still has the very paper she wrote, didn't have to wait all that long to fulfill the very words she wrote about less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> formally approved the hiring of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> as the new assistant principal at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>, 25, will replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Diddens</ENAMEX>, who will take over as principal at Pioneer for the retiring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Davis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddens</ENAMEX> is the current assistant principal at Pioneer and she will be taking over the top spot at the end of the school year.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> was one of 25 applicants, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddens</ENAMEX>.   "The pool (of candidates) was really strong," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddens</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer</ENAMEX> rose to the top."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddens</ENAMEX> said she very impressed with the performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> during the interview process. The initial pool of 25 applicants was narrowed down to eight. The remaining applicants then went through a three-hour interview process. Based on those findings, the application pool was narrowed to four. Those four then came back and went through an interview process with district administrators, including Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>. The four applicants also went through the Ventures interview process, which every administrator in the school district has had to do, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddens</ENAMEX>. The Ventures interview is done by an interviewer asking questions that were asked of top notch administrators throughout the country. The applicants' answers are compared to those of the prized administrators. The information was then compiled from the interview process with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> being hired as the new assistant principal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddens</ENAMEX> said some of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>'s duties as assistant principal will be improving the parental involvement at Pioneer. She will also be working with special education and will help oversee disciplinary issues.   "We have really big shoes to fill with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX> leaving," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diddens</ENAMEX>. "I think we found the right person."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> has quite a resume for not being in education all that long. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> is currently teaching third grade in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snoqualmie Valley School District</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puyallup</ENAMEX>, graduating in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rogers High School</ENAMEX>. As a result of being in the Running Start program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> was able to graduate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> with a Bachelor of Science degree in psychology. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> obtained a Master's degree in teaching from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitworth College</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> will have by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this June</TIMEX> her principal's credentials from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Pacific University</ENAMEX>.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, as part of obtaining her Master's degree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> had the opportunity to teach at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International School of Paris</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">France</ENAMEX> for a month. While in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> had an opportunity to work with students from all over the country.   "It was so much fun," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>. "It was hard to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paris</ENAMEX>."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> also can boast of work she has done in shelters with victims of violence while attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> also has experience in working with children who have autism.   One of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>'s most prized accomplishments just might be the black belt she holds in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tae-Kwon-Do</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>, who is planning to become an accountant, currently have no children, accept for an African gray parrot and a "spoiled cat."   Working with children has always been a goal of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>.   "From a very young age, I knew I wanted to work with kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>.   At her current school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> takes a leadership role with the staff. One of the areas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> is looking forward to being involved in at Pioneer is staff development.   "As a teacher my biggest passion is literacy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>.   Working with elementary school children is something else <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> has always enjoyed.   "I love their excitement about learning," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>. "So many things are brand new to them."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> said she is impressed with some of the reading programs implemented in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "They are doing some wonderful things here for kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>. "I am so excited to be part of that."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> found the job posting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on a website. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> said she did a lot of research on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "It looked like a great community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX>. "I am just thrilled to be here. I am really excited to move in and get the opportunity to know everyone."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> won't have to wait long to assume her new administrative duties. Her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of work teaching third grade will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25</TIMEX>. She will start work at Pioneer on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

