
<P ID="1">No TV...no problem for these families
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The idea of giving up television for two weeks might make some people a little crazy. Questions such as what will we do until bedtime or how will we entertain the kids would plague most families.   But not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott and Tonya Marquez</ENAMEX> nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The two young families recently took part in a two-week ban on television watching, just to see how their family would react.   "What we learned is that we really aren't a television family," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonya Marquez</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> family and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> family were among the families to take part in "TV Turnoff Week."   The week was extended to two weeks for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> families to see if they could kick the television habit.   The concept of TV Turnoff Week was established <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX> by the TV Turnoff Network, a non-profit group that encourages families to watch less television and spend more time together exercising, reading and talking to one another. According to research, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of American families have the TV on before sitting down to eat dinner and continue watching it through dinner. The turnoff event is designed to encourage families to have a meal together without television at least three or four times each week and hang out together, sharing the events in each other's lives.   "When we work with families that is one of the things we request in family counseling," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jody McClellan</ENAMEX>, a family counselor with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran Community Services</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   A local organizer of the TV Turnoff event, she said turning off the television doesn't mean tuning out the world.   She said a TV-free evening is a good chance for families to talk together about world events, rather than just watch them unfold on the TV. "It helps the youngsters to develop some of those critical thinking skills educators are hoping children will develop," she added.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> families are among seven million American families who switched off their televisions for the temporary ban on TV.   With their busy schedules that include a near daily routine of work, school, as well as after school latchkey sessions, religious classes, dance lessons and soccer games and practices, the families found their evenings packed with more conversation and more meal times spent around the dinner table.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> family kept a small journal of their experiences.   "We did well on the first several days keeping track of every little activity. But soon we saw a pattern emerging," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> said.   Daily routines varied little from school programs and homework. The parents found themselves spending more time together.   "I found I didn't sit down until after the evening chores were all done and it was time for bed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonya Marquez</ENAMEX>. "We got a lot done every day," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, who is a single mother of three and a college student, said her daily schedule doesn't allow for much television watching.   "We're out of the house by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 a.m.</TIMEX> and sometimes don't get back home until after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>," she said of her schedule.   "That doesn't leave much time to sit in front of the television," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> smiled.   "We watch television at Grandma's," said her son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcel</ENAMEX>, 9.   Watching television at the babysitter's was another place the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> youngsters found time for a quick 30 minutes of cartoons, said their mother   But on the whole, the children didn't seem too upset about not being planted in front of the television.   "They never asked about watching television," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> said. But when they did it was to see a special show," she added. So we recorded it for viewing at a later date," she added.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> family, who spent some of their TV-free evenings going for bike rides, also had plenty of other activities with which to keep them busy.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madison</ENAMEX>, 8, has weekly dance classes while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mathew</ENAMEX> is involved in soccer and little <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>, 4, is always hurrying to keep up.   "The kids are usually in bed by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, so we spent a few minutes every night reading to them after baths," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> said.   When the youngsters weren't on their way to soccer games or practice, they rode their bikes, played outside or did homework.   A similar pattern was developing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> household.   "The kids spent time at latchkey after school most weekdays, where they get their homework done until I pick them up," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>.   "They also have extra soccer practice and soon they'll be active in softball and t-ball," said the young mother.   In addition to finding time to study for her English and education classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>, where she is an education major, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> coaches her son's soccer team.   "We're all in bed by about 9 each night," she said. "Then up again at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to start all over," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Marquez</ENAMEX> said watching television has never been a big priority for his family.   "I think it steals your creativity," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX>, who works at Marquez Manufacturing. His wife is employed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> in the business department. "We have very busy schedules so the time we spend with the family is very important," he added.   He enjoyed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past week</TIMEX> of spending extra time playing with the kids. Their evenings included a lot of family cycling, games, such as dominos, and reading books.   So far, neither family has plans of increasing their TV time. While admitting a little bit of television is a great way to unwind, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> family likes the idea of keeping television turned off. It may remain a special treat for their family. "We taped "Survivors" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and saved it for a family night treat with popcorn to celebrate the end of our no TV experience," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said she also likes the idea of her children having more time to do extra reading or working on creative projects.   "I think they get along better this way as well," she added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

