


<P ID="1">Herriman Grandview's 'Person of the Year'
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, 22 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> residents and business people were honored for the hard work and dedication they put into the local community. They came away from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Community Awards Banquet</ENAMEX> with engraved plaques commemorating their contributions and the realization that what they do for the community is important.
</P><P ID="5">   Among those winners was Person of the Year award recipient <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> has been a very active member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> community since he returned to his hometown recently. He currently serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> president, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> he helped work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Fair and Rodeo, served as parade chairman and organized Band and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cheer Day</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "For the first time in many years, we had a band in our annual parade and it was great," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bradshaw</ENAMEX>, who presented the award to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradshaw</ENAMEX> added that there are many organizations in the community that have been made better thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>'s involvement, noting that he is always willing to help.
</P><P ID="8">   "He's a hands-on person who wants to get the job done," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bradshaw</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>, who served as the emcee for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s event, realized that he had been named person of the year, he beamed.
</P><P ID="10">   "This community is the best thing that has ever happened to me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said. "This town kind of took me by surprise."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>, who grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, said he has always loved the community. He told those in attendance that when he lived on the west side of the state people would get tired of hearing him talk about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "No one could understand why I love this town so much and the reason is you guys," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said, pointing to the audience. "We have a sense of community."
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said he is excited to see things happening in the community, and is proud to be able to be a part of it.
</P><P ID="14">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the President's Award, which is selected by the president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, went to local businessman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Boast</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boast</ENAMEX> recently purchased the historic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX> building in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and has been working diligently to restore the structure.
</P><P ID="15">   Upon receiving the award, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boast</ENAMEX> said he is hoping that the work he is putting into his building will help spark a transformation of the community's downtown area.
</P><P ID="16">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orrin Dybdahl Youth Service</ENAMEX> award was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Jimenez</ENAMEX>, who wrote the grant that ensured the purchase of the new playground equipment at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimenez</ENAMEX> was the recipient of the award, she was quick to point out that she wasn't the only person involved with the playground project.
</P><P ID="18">   "It was a community effort," she said. "It was a collaborative effort."
</P><P ID="19">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Past Service</ENAMEX> award was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> has served as president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> and has been active in both the chamber and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Rotary Club</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> was unable to attend the banquet, so <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assistant Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armando Martinez</ENAMEX> accepted the award on his behalf.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> noted that as long as he has known <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>, he has been someone who was always willing to lend a helping hand.
</P><P ID="21">   The Outstanding Volunteer award went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianne Torres</ENAMEX>, the manager of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview U.S. Bank</ENAMEX> branch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torres</ENAMEX> is active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Rotary Club</ENAMEX> and has been chairman of the United Way campaign in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   "We've been told that this lady can be relied on to do anything," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torres</ENAMEX>. "That's a good definition of an outstanding volunteer."
</P><P ID="23">   The Economic Development award went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen and Dennis Byam</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   "This couple has served on numerous city and county boards and commissions, and have been very active in the economic development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said of the couple. He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Byam</ENAMEX> currently serves as president of the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Byam</ENAMEX> is on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Planning Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the Outstanding Business award was presented to a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> business, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown's Les Schwab Tire Company</ENAMEX> and its owners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac and Gail Brown</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> noted that the couple has made a firm commitment to the community and have put in a lot of time and effort into improving the highway corridor where their business is located.
</P><P ID="27">   Members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police and fire departments were also honored during the banquet.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Assistant Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armando Martinez</ENAMEX> presented the award for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outstanding Police</ENAMEX> Officer to officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Hopp</ENAMEX>. The recipient of the Outstanding Firefighter award, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Glasenapp</ENAMEX>, was unable to attend <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s event.
</P><P ID="29">   Someone else who was honored for their service to the community during the awards banquet was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Councilman Norm Childress</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Childress</ENAMEX> was the recipient of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Mayor's Beautification award.
</P><P ID="30">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> noted that he chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Childress</ENAMEX> as the award recipient because of his work on the slide show presentation that is given every year during the awards banquet. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Childress</ENAMEX> has added a lot to the presentation over the years, showcasing all of the good things about the community.
</P><P ID="31">   Many others were also recognized during the banquet, including a teacher and student of the year from each of the schools in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="32">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClure Elementary School Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jared Lind</ENAMEX>. Student of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego Arroyo</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="33">   "He's a good role model," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClure Principal Steve Kaufman</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arroyo</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="34">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur H. Jones School Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Novak</ENAMEX>. Student of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Curtis</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="35">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones Principal Diann Zavala</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curtis</ENAMEX> is a student who follows through on every task given to him and shows good leadership, noting that he has a kinder-buddy.
</P><P ID="36">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harriet Thompson Elementary School Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kara Dykstra</ENAMEX>. Student of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jocelyn Rodriguez</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="37">   "We're so proud to have her here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Thompson Principal Connie Davis</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="38">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Middle School Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Miller</ENAMEX>. Student of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krystal Valle</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="39">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle School Principal Brian Anderson</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valle</ENAMEX> is the kind of student that makes a teacher excited to come to school every day.
</P><P ID="40">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compass High School Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Diaz</ENAMEX>. Student of the Year is Merced Guerrero.
</P><P ID="41">   "I have a lot of respect for you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Compass Principal Mike Closner</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guerrero</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="42">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School Teacher</ENAMEX> of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Bardwell</ENAMEX>, who works at the school as the junior and senior class counselor. Student of the Year is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Desserault</ENAMEX>, who serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASB</ENAMEX> president.
</P>





 










<P ID="43">Webmaster
</P><P ID="44">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




