
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> youths attend conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/30/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Three of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> students who attended the national Community Anti Drug Coalition of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CADCA</ENAMEX>) Conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> spoke to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> about their trip.   Seven students from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> attended the conference, which was funded though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration</ENAMEX> and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD 105 Drug Free Commission Grant</ENAMEX>. The students' trip was sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise.   The students who attended the conference are members of Leaders <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">In <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>, Reducing Under Aged Drinking (RUAD) and local church youth groups, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Wells</ENAMEX>, one of the seven teens selected.   As a part of the conference, the students joined a group of 40 students who lobbied Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> on drug and alcohol issues on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX>. As a part of "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Capitol Hill Day</TIMEX>" the students were taken on a tour of the U.S. Capitol and shown the underground tunnels and they rode on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> train. They also were given passes which allowed them into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> gallery.   As a part of the week-long conference, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> students <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jilliann Stroh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Spilles</ENAMEX> participated with 20 other students in a presentation to more than 2,000 adults. The presentation was entitled "What We Say that Adults Don't Hear."   The presentation used drama, power point and speakers to show adults that stereotypes of who uses drugs aren't always true.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stroh</ENAMEX>, the presentation showed that every kind of kid, from jock to gangster, use drugs.   "Any kid can do drugs and any kid can not do drugs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stroh</ENAMEX>, who, due to the conferences, is considering a career in drug abuse prevention.   While on their trip the youths were able to take in a few of the sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. One of the most impressive places for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stroh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spilles</ENAMEX> was impressed by the Capitol building. The students said that meeting people from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> was also impressive.   While at the conference the youths accepted a national award from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CADCA</ENAMEX> for the Leadership in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Action</ENAMEX> program, which involved students at the high school taking voluntary drug tests. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the group is starting a mentoring program in the elementary schools, since studies show that younger and younger students are being faced with drug and alcohol choices, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.   The award was presented the week of President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s State of the Union address, which mentioned the importance of drug testing in schools.   The teens who attended the conference were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stroh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spilles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercedes Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique Villa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Lozano</ENAMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

