
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> fire chief attends national academy
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Ever since 31-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Damron</ENAMEX> became the Grandview Fire Chief he has been applying to attend classes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Fire Academy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emmitsburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Md.</ENAMEX>   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, he was accepted to attend the Volunteer Incentive Program training class, which he attended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Fire Academy</ENAMEX> offers classes in 10 different areas that are geared toward volunteer fire departments and combination paid and volunteer fire departments. The classes for volunteer or combined departments are held three times a year.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Fire Department</ENAMEX>, with 26 volunteers and two paid staff, is a combination department.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> was accepted to attend the leadership and administration class at the national academy.   As a student of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Fire Academy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> learned recruitment techniques, skills to keep and maintain a volunteer base, planning, human resources and managerial skills.   The academy wasn't limited to fire departments in smaller communities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> said one of his instructors was from an all-volunteer fire department in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> community of 80,000 people. That department is in a state that has a state run retirement system, making it possible for an all-volunteer department.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> explained that most of his training was learning how to meet the needs of volunteers and helping them better be able to meet the needs of the community.   Courses offered by the Volunteer Incentive Program include challenges for local training officers, command and control of incident operations, community education leadership, fire cause determination, advanced safety operations and management and presenting effective public education programs.   "I'm hoping over the next few years to take all the classes at the fire academy," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> native. "It's a place to learn new ideas and it's also a place to network with different people from across the country."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> has been a paid firefighter with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Fire Department</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>. He became captain in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> was hired as the fire chief.   Attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Fire Academy</ENAMEX>, which is run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Emergency Management Agency</ENAMEX>, cost the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> a minimal amount of money, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX>.   Those accepted to attend the academy are provided a travel stipend and stay in housing for the six days of training.   "All we have to pay for is meals," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

