
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High student registration begins <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first of April</TIMEX> 
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Registration for the 2004-05 school year will begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 1</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   Registration for the next school year will coincide with parent-teacher conferences to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> and 2, according to school officials.   Registration for seniors, juniors and sophomores will be held in staggered sessions beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> for the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. The class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> will register beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> and the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX> will register from 12:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX>   "We will be using an arena format, which will allow students to choose the classes, teachers and periods they most prefer," according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Birr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> principal.   "This format allows students to design a school day schedule that best fits their needs," he explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX> said all staff, administrators and counselors will be available during the registration process to assist students.   He said students received pre-registration materials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to aid them in pre-determining what classes they will be wanting to take <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> freshman class of 2004-05 will register for high school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following spring</TIMEX> break (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5-9</TIMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> parent-teacher conferences will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX>, from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX>, from 8 until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX>   Parents interested in learning more about the two events may call the high school at 837-2601.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

