
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/16/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Public reception scheduled for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> artists
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - A public reception is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 8</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland's Allied Arts Gallery</ENAMEX> to honor three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> artists whose artwork will be on display throughout the month of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>.
The 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> reception will give art lovers the opportunity to meet artists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Loomis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Dryburgh</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Wilbur</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> All three artists will have their work on display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> gallery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Feb. 3 to Feb. 27</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loomis</ENAMEX>' mixed media works represent the nuclear age of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>, showing her feelings about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> from her artistic viewpoint.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dryburgh</ENAMEX>'s artwork utilizes totemic images that come from the darkest recesses of consciousness. Her drawings are populated with running dogs and inky forests, as well as black crows.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilbur</ENAMEX>, an internationally known artist from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, will present his metal works at the gallery. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Gallery</ENAMEX> officials say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilbur</ENAMEX>'s elegant simplicity of his recent Asian-inspired sculptures brings a harmony to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> show to balance the mood of darkness implied in both the works of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loomis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dryburgh</ENAMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> gallery is located at the entrance of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Howard Amon Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> (89 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Blvd.</ENAMEX>).
</P> 
<P ID="4">Sweet Adelines' ‘Laugh-in, Sing-out’ coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
The Rolling Hill Chorus of Sweet Adelines will present "Laugh-in, Sing-out" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 30</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
The barbershop-style singers will be joined by the Peanut Butter Conspiracy, an internationally known comedy barbershop quartet.
Tickets will be available at the door at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> for seniors and youths. Also available is a special <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> family ticket.
Two more performances are planned at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>'s Chief Joseph's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Middle School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 31</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
For more information call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Eakin</ENAMEX> at 882-3335 or (509) 943-ARTS (2787).
</P> 
<P ID="5">Dinosaurs returnto science museum
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PORTLAND</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - Was T. rex a scavenger? Or a murdering predator?
Special guest Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Horner</ENAMEX>, curator of paleontology at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of the Rockies</ENAMEX> and technical advisor for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Spielberg</ENAMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jurassic Park</ENAMEX>" films, will be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Museum of Science & Industry</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 27</TIMEX>, to offer his conclusions on the scavenger vs. predator theory.
The exciting, new exhibit, " T. rex on Trial," features the suspect T. rex, a triceratops victim and seven other animatronic dinosaur "witnesses." Full-size dino skeletons and rare fossils, along with hands-on activity stations, will help visitors analyze the data and reach a verdict.
Tickets are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for the general public (503-797-4661), and includes admittance to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horner</ENAMEX>'s evening lecture on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

