
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> graduate joins Lincoln Ave. Family Medicine
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">An advertisement in a job search newsletter led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Mattern</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Billings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, and an opportunity to begin practicing medicine in a rural setting.   She said she has long had a desire to work on the front line of medical care, working with families in rural settings.   As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattern</ENAMEX> has the chance to fulfill that dream as a member of the staff at Lincoln Avenue Family Medicine Clinic in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   A certified physician assistant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattern</ENAMEX> is a recent graduate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rocky Mountain College</ENAMEX> physician assistant program in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Billings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> Prior to entering the physician's assistant program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattern</ENAMEX> worked as a phlebotomist and as a clinical research assistant in Seattle.   "My husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>, and I were interested in relocating back in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> seems to be a perfect location for us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattern</ENAMEX> explained.   She said before becoming a phlebotomist, she was pre-med student earning her Bachelor's degree in chemistry.   "I've always been interested in rural medicine and I looked to the physician assistant program as a way to work directly with patients," she explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattern</ENAMEX> said she hopes to continue working in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> for the long term.   "We like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. It feels like it will be a good spot for us," she said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

