34 29 24 47 5 11
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  There is surely a piece of divinity in us, something that was before the elements, and owes no homage unto the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sun.</TIMEX>  Sir <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Browne</ENAMEX> (1605 - 1682), 1642
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>