
<P ID="1">Local grape prices drop as harvest hits midway mark
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/23/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Drive past any grape vineyard and the sweet smell of ripened grapes fills the air, but not all is sweet in the grape market.   Recent surpluses in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> grape market are reaching out to impact local growers, who are now in their second week of harvest.   On top of the surplus in the grape market, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> grape growers are looking at a smaller yield, an estimated 130,000 tons, due in part to freezing temperatures <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX> and a cool spring.   Despite the small yield, the quality of the grapes being harvested is excellent, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Concienne</ENAMEX>, general manager at the Grandview Welch's plant.   "We are getting good sugar and the wood for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s crop is also looking very good," he said.   However, the yield appears to be down this harvest, averaging only about five tons per acre in most areas. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the yield was slightly over eight tons per acre," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concienne</ENAMEX> said.   While <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Welch</ENAMEX> bases its prices over a 20-month contract, he said other growers may be experiencing a drop in prices. "We've heard that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smucker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Milne</ENAMEX> have both set prices at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105</NUMEX> per ton for cash growers, he said.   "We're trying to be optimistic that prices will hold steady," he added.   Meanwhile, cash contract growers like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Sylling</ENAMEX> of Outlook is concerned about the drop in the grape per ton prices. In an email to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>, he said a number of growers recently received word that some of them would be receiving lower prices for their Concord and Nigrara grapes after thinking their prices were locked in.   Now growers are asking the question, "What's up with cash grape prices?"   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">J. M. Smucker Company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Milne Processing</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> are both paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105</NUMEX> per ton. Yet just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smucker Company</ENAMEX> was quoting prices of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> per ton.   In letters mailed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smucker</ENAMEX> growers, company officials said they had originally set prices too high and were adjusting the prices per ton to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105</NUMEX> to be reflective of the current marketplace.   "It sounds to me like price fixing," said Sylling, but company officials said the prices just reflect the grape marketplace.   Milne Processing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> announced its contract prices as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105</NUMEX> per ton for grapes with 16 brix, a number which refers to the sugar levels in the grapes.   "We are giving premium prices for grapes with higher brix levels," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Hagman</ENAMEX>, general manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milne Processors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>.   A depressed Concord grape market is being blamed for the lower prices, which means there is a cut in the demand for the grapes. "It's pretty competitive out there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX>, a grape grower in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emerald Valley</ENAMEX> area.   "The surplus of grapes coming out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> is making it harder for us," he said.   Juice companies are buying more wine grapes to blend into their juices, making it tougher to sell the Concords," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> explained.   Grower payments are based on sales and movement of the crop, agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concienne</ENAMEX>.   "The prices are just lower <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

