


<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - When you ask <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Librarian Linda Dunham</ENAMEX> how long she has worked at Bleyhl Community Library, she has her answer down to the exact day. As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> had been on the job for 24 years, one month and two days. Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> has been working at the library for some time, it's the story of how she came to be a community librarian that is unusual.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">south Texas</ENAMEX>, moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arkansas</ENAMEX> at the age of 2 1/2. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> turned 14 she moved again, this time to attend a boarding school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri</ENAMEX>, which was called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> of the Ozarks at the time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> explained that the school included a four-year high school and a junior college.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said when she started attending the junior college, she was working toward being an English major. However, when all was said and done she ended up getting her undergraduate degree in food technology and animal husbandry.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said the reason for this sudden switch was that after attending two years of college at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School of Ozarks</ENAMEX> she had to make a decision regarding where she would continue her education. She said the school offered full ride two-year scholarships to several colleges in the area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> admitted that she chose to attend the college she did because it was where one of her relatives was attending school. The only snag was the one subject she could major in and still use her scholarship was animal husbandry.
</P><P ID="8">   Needless to say, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> is qualified to be a butcher. After graduating from college she was offered a job working as a meat inspector for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> explained that she didn't take the job because it would have meant living in one place no longer than 30 days at a time.
</P><P ID="9">   After interviewing for several other jobs related to her degree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> found that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Missouri</ENAMEX> had just opened a library science school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> immediately enrolled and was a part of the first library science class.
</P><P ID="10">   However, she later married a man who was working on his doctorate at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rutgers University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said she decided it would be a good idea if she started attending classes there as well, but she ended up having to fight to go to school there. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said at the time the school was looking for liberal arts majors and not science majors, which technically she was. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said she scheduled a meeting and explained to university administrators that she had a strong liberal arts background and deserved to go to the school. It took a little convincing, with the administrators asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> if she would be willing to take an oral exam on library science from one of the leading professors in the field. If she passed she would gain entry.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> started classes there immediately, graduating after about a year and half.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said the first job she took out of college was at a pharmaceutical library in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Jersey</ENAMEX>. After working there for awhile she took time off to raise her children, then her family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Michigan State University</ENAMEX>, where her husband was doing research. From there her family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Texas</ENAMEX> and then on to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, where her husband had gotten a job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Irrigated Agriculture Research</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Extension Center</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   The fall after her family had moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> got a job working as a reporter and photographer for the Prosser Record-Bulletin. She didn't hear about the library job in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> until about a year and half after taking the reporting job. She said she was at the Prosser library one day when one of the librarians told her about the opening.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said she immediately went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> and learned that the position was closing that day. So she stood there and filled out the application, while her six-year old son waited.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said she remembers not hearing anything about the job for a long time. Then one day she was called in for an interview in front of the library board. Then it was another two months before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> was offered the job.
</P><P ID="16">   "I had given up even getting the job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said her job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> community library provides for a lot of variety. She said she was a little surprised how much her research background has helped her in the public forum. She said a lot of younger people don't realize that one of the best ways to do research still involves using books and not the internet.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said working at the public library has also forced her to confront her shyness. She said she has found that she enjoys people. In fact, she said that after working at the library for so long, there are a lot of people she has met through the library that are like old friends.
</P><P ID="19">   In fact, the library is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> met her second husband. She said the two first met at the circulation desk.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said the thing she has found the most challenging in regards to her job, is trying to run an up-to-date library that has what users are looking for and doing it on less and less money. She noted that the library currently has only half of the money it previously did to purchase books.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> said generous donors are helping ensure that the library is able to keep up with book purchases. She noted that the Friends of the Library group has also proven to be an essential element to the library.
</P><P ID="22">   In the end, even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunham</ENAMEX> always envisioned herself has a research librarian, she has found her niche at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> community library.
</P>





 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




