


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber</ENAMEX> to spearhead downtown revitalization project
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Picking up the ball and running with an idea. That is what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> is hoping the local chamber <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of</ENAMEX> commerce will do with his suggestion.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> was on hand at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> to offer members the lead role in beautifying <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s downtown area, which has been an area of much discussion lately.
</P><P ID="6">   "There is nothing to attract any of us to go to downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>, who runs a business in the downtown sector.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> told chamber members there has been a lot of economic positives going on outside of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, such as the newly opened Wal-Mart distribution center. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> mayor, though, added no major business has ventured into downtown.
</P><P ID="8">   In hopes of turning the misfortunes of the downtown area around, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> offered a partnership of sorts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> chamber.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said the city obtained <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> from the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>), that has been earmarked for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s downtown area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> suggested the chamber take that money and utilize it to find ways of improving the downtown area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> also said the city would work with the chamber on finding additional money for downtown improvements.
</P><P ID="10">   "The chamber, we feel, kind of needs to run with this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>. "We are committed as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to find money to clean-up the downtown. It is horrible. I think it is a chance for us to improve the downtown area."
</P><P ID="11">   With the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> suggested the chamber use <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> of that to map out a plan and budget to go towards downtown revitalization. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said the planning portion would basically outline the objectives of the program and put in place a time line for achieving those goals. With another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> mayor suggested hiring a staff member to conduct a neighborhood outreach program to help with the implementation of the downtown revitalization plan. The remaining <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> would be used for implementation of the program.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said all money the city obtained from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has to be used by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "The downtown is not like it used to be," he said.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said that is something he hears quite often from residents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> pointed out the changes in the downtown area, which at different points in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s history was thriving, can be traced back to its residents.
</P><P ID="15">   "The downtown is not like that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> because we got in our cars and drove to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and the Tri-Cities," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX> asked members to volunteer for the task of working with the city to improve downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "Ask yourself what you can do for this community to make it better. To make it shine," stated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>. "It is a very easy task (to do) for many people."
</P><P ID="18">   During a special meeting the chamber board held following the regular gathering, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> talked more about what needs to be done to improve downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   "It just needs to be a pleasant place to go," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>. "We want to make it inviting."
</P><P ID="20">   Chamber board member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bradshaw</ENAMEX> asked what kind of ordinances the city has in regards to beautification. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said he didn't want to see any more city ordinances implemented, but rather felt it would work out better if the downtown business owners and residents bought in to the idea of making positive changes.
</P><P ID="21">   Chamber member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dottie Cervantes</ENAMEX> suggested holding public forums to receive the input of business owners. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> wanted to have translation services available in hopes of getting Hispanic business owners involved.
</P><P ID="22">   The chamber voted to take the lead role, utilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> money, to tackle the issue of downtown revitalization in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. The chamber formed a committee to move forward with the project.
</P><P ID="23">   "We are going to have to do this piece by piece," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




