4 34 48 34 10 3
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Watch out for the fellow who talks about putting things in order! Putting things in order always means getting other people under your control.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denis Diderot</ENAMEX> (1713 - 1784), Supplement to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bougainville</ENAMEX>'s 'Voyage,' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1796</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>