
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> Christian swamps Knights, 7-2
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">MOSES <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LAKE</ENAMEX> - Imagine the surprise and the looks on the faces of the powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> Christian boys soccer team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> when they found themselves in a 1-0 hole just five minutes into the game against lowly <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian.   To the shock of the unbeaten and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> leading <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> Christian club (8-0), <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan Haak</ENAMEX> headed in a corner kick from his cousin, junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Haak</ENAMEX>, for a goal to give the underdog Knights an early 1-0 lead.   "You start to think some pretty exciting things when you're ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> just five minutes into the game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Smies</ENAMEX>, who's in his first year of coaching the Knights but is still looking for his first conference victory.   The early shock <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> Christian experienced quickly wore off, though.   "They went on a tear against us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX>.   Three minutes after the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haak</ENAMEX> cousins combined their efforts to put <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian ahead, the home team struck with a goal off the foot of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendon McCornack</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> Christian then rattled off four more goals in the next 15 minutes to forge a 5-1 advantage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCornack</ENAMEX> added a second goal in that four-goal run, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Bassett</ENAMEX> providing the other three.   Another goal just before intermission from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Friehe</ENAMEX> put <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> up 6-1 at the half.   "They were ripping right through the middle," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> said of the well oiled machine his Knights went up against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.   "They pass the ball extremely well, they make precision cuts...they're very intense.   "It's obvious <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> puts a lot of work into it. They're an amazing team. That's why they're leading the league," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> added.   The second half was a slightly different story. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> Christian could only find the net one more time, mostly to the stepped up play displayed by the visiting Knights.   "They subbed a bit towards the end of the game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX>, "But we definitely turned it up in the second half."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> credits the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haak</ENAMEX> cousins for most of the increased intensity after intermission.   "The two of them were working very well together in the second half," he said. "They had some very nice give-and-gos," he added.   The sparkling teamwork paid off for the Knights in the 15th minute of the second period. The older <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haak</ENAMEX> swept in a pass from senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah Koopmans</ENAMEX>, sped down the field while juking a couple of defenders and cleanly booted in a goal to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>'s lead to 6-2.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Townsend</ENAMEX> countered the score in the 68th minute of the game with a goal of his own to account for the final 7-2 score.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian actually had a couple of golden opportunities to cut into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>'s lead even more. Unfortunately for the visitors, two wide open shots taken by the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haak</ENAMEX> careened off the top bar of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> goalpost.   "After awhile, you kind of scratch your head and wonder when the shots are going to start going in the net for you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> said. "It gets to be frustrating after awhile."   All in all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> Christian only outshot the Knights by a 13 to 9 margin. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">goalkeeper John Bosma</ENAMEX> was credited with six saves.   The Knights (0-8, 5-10), who have already been eliminated from the postseason, close out the season this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> at home against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trout Lake</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

