


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>'s 3-on-3 tournament gains <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX> support
</P>

<P ID="5">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> Jam 3-on-3 Basketball Tournament, set for the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24</TIMEX>, has received a substantial contribution from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">The commissioners voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX> to donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> to the two-day tournament, annually
</P>  
<P ID="7">sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8">This is the second year the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Commission</ENAMEX> has supported the tourney, which will be held at the Mid Valley Mall parking lot in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="9">Vacated house
</P>    
<P ID="10">to be moved
</P>   
<P ID="11">from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX> property
</P>

<P ID="12">A vacated house on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port District</ENAMEX> property north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alexander Road</ENAMEX> will be removed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downing Construction Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">The house, which was vacated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> after being deemed unsafe, will be moved from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North McLean Road</ENAMEX> site by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell Downing</ENAMEX>'s crews. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> contractor has agreed to fill in the building's basement and level the area, making it suitable for future industrial needs, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Hansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX> manager.
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX> had originally considered burning it until <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downing</ENAMEX> suggested moving the building.
</P>

<P ID="15">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McLean</ENAMEX> property is located on a part of the 38 acres of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX> property which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX> commissioners hope will soon be annexed into the city limits, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> added.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




