29 6 10 32 26 7
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Let me have men about me that are fat,
Sleek-headed men, and such as sleep o' nights:
Yond Cassius has a lean and hungry look;
He thinks too much: such men are dangerous.  William Shakespeare (1564 - 1616), "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julius Caesar</ENAMEX>", Act 1 scene 2
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>