


<P ID="1">Low income housing proposal hits snag
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">After nearly two hours of public testimony surrounding an annexation and land use request from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> property owners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Burns</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Burns</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> voted this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to approve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>' annexation into the city limits.
</P><P ID="5">   However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> denied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>' land use request for their property, located at the southeast corner of North 16th Street and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> members said it didn't conform with surrounding land uses located on the west side of North 16th Street.
</P><P ID="6">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> sought to have their property zoned R-3, high density residential, which allows for the development of multi-housing complexes.
</P><P ID="7">   "We've discovered our original plan for development of the land is unworkable," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Burns</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>. He said the family had been contacted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Housing Services</ENAMEX>, which wants to create a 51-unit housing complex on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> property, as well as an office that would oversee the operations of all its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> housing complexes.
</P><P ID="8">   However, despite the attractiveness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX>'s proposal, which is similar to an existing housing complex recently completed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> determined that R-2 was a better match for the area in question. The commissioners felt the area should not be used for professional offices, which is allowable under the R-3 zoning codes.
</P><P ID="9">   Representatives for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese and Beacon Development Group</ENAMEX>, the project developers, told the commission they supported the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>' request for an R-3 designation.
</P><P ID="10">   They took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s public hearing as an opportunity to outline how their affordable housing proposal could enhance the community. The developers expect to not only provide rental property for low income families, but education programs to help families stabilize with the end goal being home ownership. Their plan for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX> property include a park-like play area, as well as street, curb and gutter improvements, as well as covering the SVID ditch located nearby. The developers had also hoped to build a professional family counseling services office on the property to further enhance the new neighborhood.
</P><P ID="11">   "The area in question is listed as a transitional residential area on your existing comprehensive land management plan," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Probst</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX>'s development coordinator.
</P><P ID="12">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX> property is flanked by CanAm Steel, an auto wrecking yard, a farm shop, businesses, a school, a church, as well as some residences.
</P><P ID="13">   "The area is of the proper size for our proposal," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX> said, adding the funding is in place for what the housing service expects will be a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> development.
</P><P ID="14">   "It has the potential of creating a neighborhood style environment," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Carmody</ENAMEX>, an attorney for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   However, after asking many questions regarding the scope of the project, and even agreeing it was an attractive proposal, the planning commissioners decided the proposal didn't suit the neighborhood in question.
</P><P ID="16">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> voted 4-2 for the annexation, but chose to recommend the R-2 designation as being more in keeping with the city's development needs. The commissioners encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX> to continue with its proposal under the R-2 zone requirements.
</P><P ID="17">   "It is better for the community that the proposed annexation area be zoned R-2, medium density residential," said Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Weaver</ENAMEX>, who made the motion for the annexation and zoning use.
</P><P ID="18">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX> developers will however, have to seek a variance from the city's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> in order to allow it to proceed as currently proposed.
</P><P ID="19">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> had suggested the area be zoned ranchette, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> felt the area is more suited to the medium density designation.
</P><P ID="20">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>'s annexation and zoning recommendation now goes before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Boundary Review Board</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   It may be several months before the commission learns of the board's decision, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




