
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> each score three TD's in win over Bulldogs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - Getting three touchdowns apiece from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Villanueva</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Cantu</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> freshman football team rolled to a 53-0 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s freshmen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> improved to 6-2 on the season with the resounding win.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> scampered 31 yards in the second half on a TD run, and also tossed two touchdown passes earlier in the game-the first a 5-yarder to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Salcedo</ENAMEX> and the second a 66-yarder to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Cornelius</ENAMEX>. He completed 5-of-8 passes in the game for 120 yards, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> also rushed for 61 yards on three totes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX>, who led all rushers with 158 yards on 11 carries, had two touchdown runs, the longest a 49-yard burst into the end zone. He also returned an interception 30 yards for a TD.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Montelongo</ENAMEX> also inflicted some damage on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. He broke off a 42-yard touchdown run in the first quarter and picked up a fumble in the third quarter, returning it 56 yards for a score. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX> tallied 51 yards rushing the ball, coming on just three touches.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Martinez</ENAMEX> also gained 21 rushing yards for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on three carries.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Glenn Braman</ENAMEX> said his defensive squad only forced <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> into one punting situation all night long.   "They had the ball for a lot of the game," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said. "Our defense bent but we didn't break," he said of the shutout.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

