


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> pulls away from Lady 'Hounds in the fourth
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/14/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> gave it their all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and found they could run with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> girls' basketball team was able to keep pace with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> team, and despite the Lady 'Hounds finishing behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Adolfo Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said he was happy with what he saw.
</P><P ID="5">   "It was a great game," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said. "Now we know we can run with them and play with them."
</P><P ID="6">   The final score in the match-up was 41-30, with the Lady 'Hounds staying within a bucket or two until the fourth quarter.
</P><P ID="7">   "As good teams do, they hit some shots at crucial times," he said.
</P><P ID="8">   Despite falling to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>, the Greyhounds still managed to gain some small victories over the visiting team.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said one of the things the team wanted to do against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> was control the tempo and take away the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX>' inside game, both of which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team was able to do <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> also managed to press the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> team throughout all four quarters.
</P><P ID="10">   "Defensively we did really well against them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> was forced to work the ball around.
</P><P ID="11">   On the offensive side of things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the Lady 'Hounds were able to convert some key steals into points, and also managed to successfully set off its transition offense.
</P><P ID="12">   "Offensively we did what we wanted to do," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>, a key player in the match-up against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> was junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danelle Cowan</ENAMEX>. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cowan</ENAMEX> worked hard during the game, and managed a double/double with 12 points and 10 rebounds. Also scoring for the Lady 'Hounds was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Rodriguez</ENAMEX> with 8 points and seven rebounds.
</P><P ID="14">   Despite playing well against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> team, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said he did see some things the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls will have to work on during the week. He said the Lady 'Hounds (2-1, 6-3) need to work on keeping their composure and not running the ball without thinking about it. He said the team also had some key turnovers that led to key points for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> team.
</P><P ID="15">   "That really put us on our heels," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said of the turnovers.
</P><P ID="16">   He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team will also have to work on not giving teams "second chance points." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> noted that during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> game the Lady 'Hounds gave away too many second chance points, and said that not blocking out was one of the reasons why.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will have a few days to practice before taking on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> on the road <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




