


<P ID="1">Scotties take advantage of 10 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> miscues
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/30/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">COWICHE - Ten errors cost the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> baseball team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The only good thing about all the Viking miscues <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> is that they came during a non-league game. Playing at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Class</ENAMEX> 1A Highland defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Class B Vikings</ENAMEX>, 12-2. The non-league contest was stopped after the fifth inning because of the 10-run rule.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> got to the Scotties' starting pitcher, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX>, early. In the top of the first, the Vikes' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Elizondo</ENAMEX> opened the game by slapping a double. A walk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Magana</ENAMEX> and a bloop single by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Galvan</ENAMEX> loaded the bases. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balli</ENAMEX> then lofted a fly ball to center, scoring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizondo</ENAMEX> on the sac fly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> reloaded the bases when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos Zepeda</ENAMEX> singled sharply, but Highland got out of the inning cheaply when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> fanned a batter and then induced the last out of the inning with a groundout.
</P><P ID="7">   The Scotties all but ended the game in the bottom half of the first, pushing eight runs across the plate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balli</ENAMEX>, the starting pitcher for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>, was touched for three hits in the opening frame. He also gave up two walks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balli</ENAMEX> could have survived that, but three errors on the part of his teammates ended up doing him in. He was lifted from the mound without a single out being recorded.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zepeda</ENAMEX>, pitching in relief, finally got the Vikes out of the inning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zepeda</ENAMEX> only allowed one more run until turning the pitching chores over to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizondo</ENAMEX> in the fifth inning.
</P><P ID="9">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zepeda</ENAMEX>) kept us right in there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Coach Kerry Snodgrass</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   "The story <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> wasn't pitching," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snodgrass</ENAMEX> continued. "We didn't field the ball. We just can't make these kinds of errors and expect to get away with it."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> accounted for its second run of the game in the top of the third. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balli</ENAMEX> singled, eventually scoring on an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBI</ENAMEX> single by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zepeda</ENAMEX>, who had the lone multi-hit performance of the day for the Vikes, going 2-for-2.
</P>   
<P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at
</P><P ID="13">   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him
</P><P ID="14">   at bstory@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




