
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Linde</ENAMEX> crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Linde</ENAMEX>, 18, of Outlook has been selected as the Yakima Valley Dairy industry's youth ambassador for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.   The daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaDon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Linde</ENAMEX> of Outlook, she was awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess crown during ceremonies held this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Convention Center</ENAMEX>.   Sponsored by the Yakima Dairy Women, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> was one of two candidates vying for the crown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   Named as alternate was Carly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeGroot</ENAMEX>, 17, a junior at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> replaces reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendra Golob</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, who will now advance to seek the state dairy princess title.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX>, a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, is a member of a fourth generation dairy family. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> family owns and operates an 800-Holstein dairy near <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>.   The second oldest of six children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> is active in Leaders in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX>, as well as being a former legislative page in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Representatives and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.   She is a recipient of the Hugh O'Brian Youth Leadership award. In addition, she attends classes through Running Start at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>, where she expects to receive her Associate of Arts degree at the same time as her high school diploma in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.   During the coming year, she will represent the dairy industry at ribbon cuttings, parades and at other dairy industry-sponsored events.   Named as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alternate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeGroot</ENAMEX> is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn DeGroot</ENAMEX>.   She is a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Honor Society</ENAMEX> and has received honorable mentions in the National Guild Piano auditions. She is the vice president of her school's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> chapter and is a class officer.   In addition to the dairy princess announcement, the Yakima Valley Dairy Women presented two <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> scholarships to students pursuing careers in agriculture. Scholarship recipients are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Boogerd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa DeJong</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Brooks</ENAMEX> of the Udder Guys <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dairy Service</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was named the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dairy Women</ENAMEX>'s "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Friend of the Dairy Industry" during the banquet.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

