


<P ID="1">Stitler appeals censure case to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/13/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Stitler</ENAMEX> is back dispensing rulings from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Municipal Court</ENAMEX> bench, while waiting to hear if the highest court in the land will hear his case against the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Commission on Judicial Conduct</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> is contending he was treated unfairly by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> during its investigation of his time as a judge pro-tem in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Municipal Court</ENAMEX> between 1996-2001. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> took nearly three years to conduct its investigation charging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> with serving as both lawyer and judge in numerous cases in the neighboring community.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> has filed a writ of certiorari with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> to review and evaluate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s methods. He maintained throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s investigation and the subsequent censure that any violations of the state Judicial Code were unintentional.
</P><P ID="7">   "We are hoping the Justices will look at his case and agree to evaluate how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> conducts its future investigations of lower court judges," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip Talmadge</ENAMEX>, a former state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court Justice</ENAMEX>, who is representing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> in his appeal.
</P><P ID="8">   "We believe the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s actions were questionable," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmadge</ENAMEX> said. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s procedures need to be examined."
</P><P ID="9">   Saying the length of time over which the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX>' case was investigated violated his rights to a speedy conclusion of the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmadge</ENAMEX> is hopeful the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will see the inequities in the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> deals with lower court judges.
</P><P ID="10">   "It took nearly three years for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX>' case to come to a conclusion even though he immediately took steps to remedy so-called violations," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmadge</ENAMEX>. "We feel the end result was incredibly unfair."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX>, who has served his 120-day suspension from the bench, lost his censure appeal in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2003</TIMEX>, when the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> voted 8-1 to concur with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>'s recommendation to censure Judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> for having violated the state Code of Judicial Conduct.
</P><P ID="12">   The state court's ruling concurred that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX>' actions while serving as a visiting judge in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Municipal Court</ENAMEX> denied numerous defendants their constitutional rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> was accused of having failed to disqualify himself as a judge in matters where he had previously served as the lawyer of record.
</P><P ID="13">   While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> made immediate changes to his conduct upon being made aware of the conflict, what is at question is the length of time and method in which the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> conducted its lengthy investigation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmadge</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> waited a little more than two years to hear what punishment the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> would have for him. He, in the meantime, took steps to remedy the situation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmadge</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="14">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> discovered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> might have been in violation of judicial ethic rules, but waited until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> to offer its ruling.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX>' case should have been handled in a more timely basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmadge</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> had at least the same rights as a criminal to a speedy trial," he added.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talmadge</ENAMEX> said he is hoping the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> justices may find the case intriguing enough to consider examining, noting it may be several months before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> announces which cases it will hear in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> said he is ready to again serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city court bench, having abided by the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling.
</P><P ID="19">   "I've done what they wanted me to do," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="20">   As part of his suspension, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX> was required to attend judicial training before being allowed to return to the bench.
</P><P ID="21">   His four-month without pay suspension came to an end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 2</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="23">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




