


<P ID="1">Fond farewell bid to Fonfaras
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/2/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A bronze statue of a lanky cowboy will accompany former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX> to his new post as city manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The statute was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy</ENAMEX>, during a farewell party held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>, who was praised for his many civic and economic contributions to the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, was presented the statue in recognition of nearly 24 years of service to the community.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>, who came to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> to become the city's first parks and recreation director, also served as the community's first director of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, the local economic development agency.
</P><P ID="8">   While serving as the agency's director, he is credited with encouraging such companies as Darigold and Valley Manufactured Housing to construct plants in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Among other projects on which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> played a major role is the completion of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Centennial</ENAMEX> park and pathway, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> statue project.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> resigned as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s city manager in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early January</TIMEX> to become the city manager of the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> resort town.
</P><P ID="11">   Hosted by members of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s reception was attended by more than 70 people, who shared anecdotes about and praises for the long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> couple.
</P><P ID="12">   Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Schuler</ENAMEX>, who shared master of ceremony duties with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Jones</ENAMEX>, reminded the couple they left once before for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX>, only to return a few years later.
</P><P ID="13">   "We're hoping that happens again," he said.
</P><P ID="14">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> board of directors presented the Fonfaras with the table top bronze statue of pioneer cattleman Ren Ferrell, one of the first statues to be placed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="16">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




