
<P ID="1">New manager named for livestock identification program
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For nearly 70 years the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSDA</ENAMEX>) has been recording brands and therefore recording ownership of livestock.   The WSDA Livestock Identification Program was taken over by the department in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>, and just several weeks ago the program was taken over by a new program manager.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Rude</ENAMEX> began serving as the manager of the state's livestock identification program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> holds a Bachelor's degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Lutheran University</ENAMEX> and a Master's degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX>, who grew up on a family farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Roy</ENAMEX>, has extensive agricultural experience, which includes working with livestock quarantines, transportation, branding and identification concerns.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> comes to the WSDA after spending 14 years as executive director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Rehabilitation Riding Program</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eatonville</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> said the role of the program is to maintain official records on the approximately 7,000 livestock brands registered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>. She explained that once a brand is registered with the state, the livestock identification program maintains the records of the brand, including its history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> explained that although the state keeps records on the brands, the brands themselves are actually owned by the farmers and ranchers who register them.   "They have title to that brand," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> said.   She said the livestock identification program also conducts inspections of cattle and horses at public markets, slaughterhouses, certified feedlots, before change of ownership and prior to movement out of the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> said inspectors go in and inspect the animals hands-on for proof of ownership. There are livestock brand inspectors located throughout the state.   "Our staff is everywhere," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> said, including the Toppenish Sales Yard. She said there are livestock brand inspectors located on-site in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, working to ensure proof of ownership for all of the animals bought and sold at auction.   Another role the livestock identification program fills is dealing with missing or stolen animals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> said whenever there is question of ownership, inspectors are called in to help take part in the investigative process.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX>, serving as the manager of the livestock identification program will mean providing leadership for the inspectors, as well as working hand-in-hand with both the director and assistant director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> said so far she has found herself stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, although once she gets settled into her new position she said she will be traveling throughout the state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> will also be meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livestock Identification Advisory Board</ENAMEX>, which is made up of six members who represent different areas of the livestock industry, from beef producers to meat processors. She explained that the advisory board allows representatives from the livestock industry to come together with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> to voice concerns they may have or issues they want to address.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rude</ENAMEX> said two issues the advisory board is currently discussing are the Country of Origin Labeling law and animal identification.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

