
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Politics
I swore to myself I would never write another letter to the editor. But, I read "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Open Mike</ENAMEX>" in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX> issue and couldn't hold back. I, myself, am just like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX>. I vote for the man regardless of the party they are affiliated with, providing they are Republicans. Then, after I go to the polls and cast my vote I kick myself the rest of the year for voting that way.
But the reason I do this is because a friend of mine is a die hard Democrat. He will vote Democrat if they run a yellow dog. I keep trying to tell him that their Democrat yellow dog this time has rabies. But he won't listen. All George Bush needs done is to be wormed. Now, which way would you vote?
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> saying Wild Bill Clinton was a good president is going way too far. He had the ability of being a great president, except for his ignorance.
As far as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> recount, it saddened me that there were so many weak Democrats that couldn't push the chads out. Next time they should take a Republican to the polls with them. let them push out the chads.
And as far as saying Bill Clinton only made a few mistakes, wow, that makes me think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> did not get very good grades in mathematics. Giving away secrets to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX> for campaign financing is a huge mistake. No, not for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, but for our freedom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, we do know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> was going to do next. He was going to do whatever was good for him. Not what was good for the American people.
Then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> stated he would like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX> as president. If that happens, it will be the first time you have such a close family who would both be president. It may be as interesting as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> says.
But let's get to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>'s favorite, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX>. I approached him once about voting for something. Exactly what, I can't remember. I have the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> memory virus. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>' response was, I can't do that because the Republican party doesn't want it. That at the time proved he is working for the Republican party, not the constituents.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Padelford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Medical care
I want to make known to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> my heartfelt thanks to the ambulance crew of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Blumer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Price</ENAMEX>.
I was stricken with a heart attack on the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14</TIMEX> and needed to be transported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Heart Center</ENAMEX> for a life-saving procedure.
I am recovering and very thankful for the ambulance service that was available to assist in my situation. I strongly urge the council to NOT consider taking this life-saving service away from our fire department. This is a valuable part of our community and is very much needed to provide this form of health care to our citizens.
I wish to thank Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Evans</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ER</ENAMEX> staff at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> for their expedient and professional help. I was in the midst of a heart attack and I was properly diagnosed and stabilized for transport to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, where I underwent a three-stint procedure to restore my heart to good working order. The actions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ER</ENAMEX> staff and ambulance crew saved my life.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Durbin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Mayfest
Many thanks to the wonderful volunteers who helped with Mayfest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
Thanks to our sponsors: McDonald's, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX> King, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s Drive-In, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George and Margaret DeRuyter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX>'s Security, Campos Music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palateria Nortena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Radio</ENAMEX> station La Maquina and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pepsi Corp.</ENAMEX>
A special thank you to the booth chairmen: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario and Angela Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mays</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Heitstuman</ENAMEX>, Scorro and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge Bazaldua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio and Nina Ramos</ENAMEX>, Zenaida and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Herrera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy and Fidel Partida Jr.</ENAMEX>, Nuestra Casa, Lino and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda Guerra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike and Sue Wedam</ENAMEX>, the Hispanic youth group, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trina Alvarez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille Cullen</ENAMEX>.
Thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Luis Zesati Jr.</ENAMEX> for handling the children's races, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Luis Zesati Sr.</ENAMEX> for help with the entertainment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Gastelum</ENAMEX> for being emcee and DJ, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Garibay</ENAMEX> and his youth group for all their help, Father <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandro</ENAMEX>, our wonderful clown, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose and Pete Garza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariana Zesati</ENAMEX> for all their help in everything.
Also, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry Turley</ENAMEX> for help ordering stuff and getting our booths up, and to the musical groups that participated: the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> mariachi band and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sleater</ENAMEX>, Father <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto</ENAMEX> and Azucena Pimentel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Alan Turley</ENAMEX>, Smmoth da Messenger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrel Greg</ENAMEX> and Commonwealth, Preacha Paul, Los Bagantes, Promesa, Mariachi Caporal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra y Alegria Nortena</ENAMEX>, Panda Bear Cubs, The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magic Man</ENAMEX>, and all the singers and dancers from the talent competition, including the judges: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracie Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esteban Zambrano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Hernandez</ENAMEX>.
A big thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> for its generous coverage of Mayfest. Also, we appreciate all the donations from parishioners who were so generous with food and money.
It was a wonderful event enjoyed by all!
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelda Gastelum</ENAMEX>, Mayfest coordinator, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

