


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds getting close to another perfect season
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">MOXEE - The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> are on their way to their third consecutive undefeated season. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team played tough against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX>, walking away with a 3-0 victory.
</P><P ID="5">   The Lady 'Hounds defeated the Red Devils by scores of 25-14, 25-17, 25-14.
</P><P ID="6">   "They played well when they needed to," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said of his team's performance.
</P><P ID="7">   He said although his team wasn't on top of their game <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, they were still able to stay ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX>, which was a team that didn't bring any surprises to the court.
</P><P ID="8">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> was what we would have expected," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   The Greyhounds played tough both offensively and defensively against the Red Devils. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said junior Tonhya Wysong and freshman Kealey Johnston did a good job on defense for the team.
</P><P ID="10">   "Their digging has been really good and it's important," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Johnston</ENAMEX> also stepped up her game, with four or five kills in a row against the Red Devils during the second game of the night.
</P><P ID="12">   He added that senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> had a good night against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX>, noting that she did a nice job for the team.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Johnson</ENAMEX> finished the night with 6 kills, 27 digs, 7 service points and 2 blocks; Wysong had 32 digs; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> had 13 kills, 5 digs and 2 aces; Danelle Cowan had 8 kills, 8 digs, 5 service points and 3 blocks; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> had 3 kills and 8 digs; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> had 8 kills and 7 digs; Chante Bottineau had 29 assists and 12 service points; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX> had 3 service points and 1 dig.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said at this point his team is in a good position going into the postseason, adding that they will likely host the first round of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   However, before the team can look forward to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX> they have two matches left to play in the regular season. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> the Lady 'Hounds will play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> at home.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




