
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">PAID <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OBITUARY
AMELIA KLEINGARTNER
Amelia “Molly” Kleingartner</ENAMEX>, 87, a long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> resident, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 5, 2004</TIMEX>, at Prosser Long Term Care.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14, 1916</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, the eldest of eight children, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia Ruth</ENAMEX> (Lorenz) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Martin</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1918</TIMEX> her parents moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and later to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emerald District</ENAMEX> south of town, where she received her education at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell Phillips</ENAMEX> schoolhouse. Her parents being farmers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> learned at an early age to be a hard working farmer’s daughter, which remained with her throughout her life. She seemed to have an endless amount of energy and stamina, enjoying work and a job well done. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Kleingartner</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. They moved to Outlook, where they were row crop farmers. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> and owned and operated a dairy farm. For many years she worked at a local packing plant and retired as a floor lady. 
Up into her 80s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> enjoyed dancing, pinochle, canning from her garden, embroidering and crocheting. She loved to cook and feed anyone stepping across her threshold. She spent time going to garage sales and bartering for good deals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> cherished time spent with family and friends. 
She was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX>, and the Moose.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX> is survived by three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Pappas</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, of Seattle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Kleingartner</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bayview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>; 11 grandchildren; numerous great-grandchildren; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Martin</ENAMEX>; four sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Price</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Prescott</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Booher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port Angeles</ENAMEX>.
She was preceded in death by her parents; her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Kleingartner</ENAMEX>; one great-granddaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber</ENAMEX>; and a sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elsie Mattingley</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Feb. 9, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 10, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 10, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. We will always remember her smile, the twinkle in her eyes, endless energy and her outgoing and fun loving personality. 
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

