


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> folks asked to help buy satellite telephones for soldiers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - When Sgt. 1st <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Class Michael J. Davison</ENAMEX> alerted his parents that he was headed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, he told them there was only one thing he really wanted them to do for him.
</P><P ID="5">   "He told us he wanted a satellite phone so he could keep in touch with his wife and children," said his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Davison</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret (Ermey) Davison</ENAMEX>, checked into the cost of purchasing the communication device, they found the cost of the phone to be more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,300</NUMEX> for a single unit, not counting the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> per minute calling time.
</P><P ID="7">   Undeterred, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> couple decided the best thing to do was to establish a fund to raise money for what is now being called "Operation Call Home."
</P><P ID="8">   The project has taken on a life of its own, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX>. With the help of a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> residents, including former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Hubert</ENAMEX>, the family has formed a non-profit agency to collect more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> for the purpose of purchasing satellite phones for each platoon now stationed overseas.
</P><P ID="9">   "When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> said he planned to share his satellite phone with the men in his platoon, it got us to thinking. Why not raise enough money so every platoon would have access to a satellite phone?," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> and his wife will travel to Fort <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, where their son, a platoon leader with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">81st Armor Brigade</ENAMEX>, is now awaiting deployment to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Their son and his fellow soldiers will be taking part in a troop send-off ceremony to be held at the Tacoma Dome, before leaving for specialized training in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>. From there they, along with 3,000 members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">81st Armor Brigade</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington National Guard</ENAMEX>, will face a year's separation from their families.
</P><P ID="11">   "It's our plan to present a satellite phone along with a calling card good for 3,000 pre-paid minutes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>'s commanding officer, Brigadier General <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillman</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillman</ENAMEX> and Brigadier General <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Toney</ENAMEX>, the commander of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Army National Guard</ENAMEX>, have been very supportive of Operation Call Home. "They see it as a way to boost the morale of their troops," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   He is now encouraging other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> families of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> military personnel to help purchase more of the costly phones and calling cards for the young soldiers.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> said a 10-minute call home, via satellite, can cost as much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> has set up an account at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> branch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of America</ENAMEX> for Operation Call Home.
</P><P ID="16">   "But people interested in donating toward the cost of the phones or calling time may leave donations at any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank of America</ENAMEX> branch," he said.
</P><P ID="17">   Donations may also be mailed to "Operation Call Home" at 101 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearne St.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>. 98948.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davison</ENAMEX> has also established a web site at platoonphone.com with more information about the program.
</P><P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="20">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




