
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>
<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> volleyball team was commended by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> read a letter from the father of a Selah volleyball player that noted how impressed he was with the class shown by both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s volleyball team and the student body as a whole. The father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Graf</ENAMEX>, noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> had played <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> during the Grizzly's senior night and he appreciated that not only were <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s seniors honored, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>'s as well.
</P> 
<P ID="5">547 participated in Best SELF program
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members learned that 547 students participated in this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past summer</TIMEX>'s Best SELF program.
Over the course of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> those students received 112 hours of study time, as well as a chance to take field trips, play tennis and paint murals for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> commends <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jensen</ENAMEX> for her work at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook
Outlook Elementary School Nurse Colleen Jensen</ENAMEX> was commended by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outlook Principal Cathy Mears</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> for the way she recently reacted to a situation involving a sick child at the elementary school.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mears</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jensen</ENAMEX> quickly realized the child was very sick and needed immediate medical attention. The child was transferred to the local emergency room and was then taken for further care in the Tri-Cities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mears</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jensen</ENAMEX> didn't stop at sending the child to the hospital. She also got to work hunting down the boy's parents, as well as an older brother to accompany him to the emergency room.
"Every school nurse would have done the same thing," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jensen</ENAMEX> said.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Parks and rec thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VICA Club for Harvest Dance</ENAMEX> success
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> offered their thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School VICA Club</ENAMEX> for the success of the recent Harvest Dance.
During the Harvest Dance VICA students served as hosts and hostesses and danced with the seniors who were in attendance.
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Perkins</ENAMEX> budget
 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved the budget for the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Perkins</ENAMEX> funds.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Ohler</ENAMEX> said the school district has received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$97,276</NUMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Perkins</ENAMEX> funds. She said the money will be used for a variety of things, including updating the software in the school's business labs, training counselors in career guidance and paying for field trips for the different vocational classes.
</P> 
<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves contract for gifted and talented program
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> approved a contract between the school district and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington Center</ENAMEX> for the Study and Teaching of At-Risk Students (C-STARS).
The contract will help provide support services and technical assistance for the district's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob K. Javits</ENAMEX> Gifted and Talented Students Education Program.
The amount of the contract is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$129,882</NUMEX>, and the period of the contract is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from Oct. 1, 2004 through Sept. 30, 2005</TIMEX>.
</P> 
 
 


 




<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

