
<P ID="1">Dutch WWII resistance member visits <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/6/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sixty-one years ago</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Amundson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wietze Eizenga</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leiderdolp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX> met in a hayloft.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. It has been about two years since the two last saw each other when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX> to the field where his plane crashed nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">61 years ago</TIMEX>.   But the two had seen each other before. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>, a doctorate of economics, who has taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX>, among other prestigious schools in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, has met with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> several times over the years.   The two have kept in contact since the end of World War II, which started when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> sent food and clothing, products that were in short supply after the end of the war, to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>.   When they first met they didn't know much about each other. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> knew he needed help, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> was in the business of helping those hiding from the Nazis.   In hiding himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> joined the Dutch underground forces in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940</TIMEX> and ruled the country banning anything that was anti-German, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>.   "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX> the Germans were looking for me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>, explaining that all Dutch aged 15 to 45, were forced to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX>, because with the war workers were a scarcity.   Not wanting to work for the Nazis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> fled.   "If you did not go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> you were a criminal and had to hide," he said.   His father took him to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Friesland</ENAMEX> where he hid in a barnyard. Ration cards were stolen for him and he was invited to join the underground forces, a sabotage group in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, which eventually became a part of the internal forces of the Dutch military in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> after the war was over.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> specialized in the portion of the organization that acquired weapons, ration cards, cars, bikes, whatever was needed by the members of his group.   "When our friends were in prison, we liberated them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>, adding that his group had German and Dutch police uniforms.   "We did all kinds of things that God had forbidden," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>.   "I worked in a very special group," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>. "It was very small."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> had been in the countryside of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX> working the "drop fields" when he first met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX>.   At the time there was an elaborate underground system to return officers to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> and to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> front against the Nazis. The underground went from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Belgium</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portugal</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spain</ENAMEX> back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>.   "It was very difficult to go through the German-occupied countries," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>.   The B-17 bomber <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX>, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Air Force</ENAMEX> officer, was in had just been shot down and landed in the Dutch countryside.   "I told the crew, we might just as well scatter rather than all get caught together," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> and his fellow crew members split up to hopefully avoid capture.   "I ran across a turnip field of some sort and the Dutchmen were waving me down," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX>.   Finding refuge in a hayloft, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> was visited by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> in the middle of the night.   "He brought me food and clothes," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> remembers.   As a member of the Dutch underground forces, who worked on the drop fields of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Netherlands Eizenga</ENAMEX> was in the area when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX>'s plane crashed. He went to where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> was hiding and questioned him before taking him further on the underground system.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>, who usually didn't help individuals on the underground route, was in a branch of the underground forces that focused on supplying resistance members.   "When I met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les</ENAMEX> our first problem was what to do with him."   Within a few days of the plane crash, the four officers were located and reunited. The other six members of the crew were taken in by local farmers and some were hidden for as long as six months, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> and his fellow officers were on their way back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> when they were eventually captured, about a month after the plane crash.   The officers were in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amsterdam</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> waiting for a vehicle to pick them up.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> said they got off the train and what appeared to be a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> Dodge Victoria stopped to pick them up.   "We didn't know it when we got into that car; we were caught," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX>, adding that the Germans had infiltrated the Dutch underground.   They officers were taken to a room and soon German officers were pointing guns at them, letting them know they had been captured.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> was taken to a work camp for military officers, where he stayed until the end of the war. He said when he arrived at the camp there were about 600 prisoners and there were almost 10,000 when he was freed.   "My main business was not taking care of pilots," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>. "I was in the group that was gathering the weapons that were parachuted into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>."   His group also raided offices for ration cards and other supplies needed by the rebel group.   "We took care of everything that was needed," he said.   As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> was sent on his way by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>, he couldn't make notes to stay in contact, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> asked his helper to contact Amundson Hardware in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> after the war.   After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amundson</ENAMEX> returned home from the war, he shipped clothing and food to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> to show his appreciation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX> said the supplies were needed following the war.   "The Germans stripped <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eizenga</ENAMEX>. "There was even a clothes shortage."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

