


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> in three
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> kept their winning streak alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, defeating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> in a three-game match. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team has yet to lose a game in league play.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> by scores of 25-7, 25-18, 25-11.
</P><P ID="6">   "We played well enough to win," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said of his team's performance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. "We've probably played better."
</P><P ID="7">   Despite not playing up to their fullest potential, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team was able to easily put away the Huskies.
</P><P ID="8">   Playing well for the 'Hounds was sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">setter Chante Bottineau</ENAMEX>, who finished the night with 17 assists, 2 aces, 13 sgeer said senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> also did a good job for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "She did a very good job at the net," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX>, who finished the match with 7 kills and 2 aces.
</P><P ID="10">   Also with 7 kills for the Lady 'Hounds was senior Danelle Cowan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> had 9 digs against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tonhya Wysong</ENAMEX> had 24 digs, Kealey Johnston had 7 digs, 2 kills and 9 service points, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> had 3 kills and 2 service aces, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Penwell</ENAMEX> had 1 kill.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Clapp</ENAMEX> also played well for the 'Hounds.
</P><P ID="12">   Despite having one more regular season match coming up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team is already looking ahead to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> play.
</P><P ID="13">   "We're looking forward to playing tough matches at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="14">   He noted that the team is already working on its game, getting ready for the postseason.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will take to the court again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at home against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>. The match will serve as senior night for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>. The Lady 'Hounds will play their first <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> match in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 4</TIMEX>, against Cascade.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




