
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> regional teacher of the year
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara Steen</ENAMEX>, an English teacher at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, has been selected as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> 105's regional teacher of the year.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Gutting</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105 Superintendent, made the suprise announcement at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>'s staff meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> has 22 years of teaching experience, 21 of them at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. She teaches all levels of students-from remedial reading to advanced placement English, a program she helped establish for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> she will take on the role of literacy coach for the district.   As a teacher and neighbor to many <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> students and their families, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> is well aware of the challenges facing those in her school district and community.   "Teaching children of poverty is my life's work, an avocation and not a vocation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> said. "A passion and not a job.   "I have made connecting with my students a primary focus at work. Until they (students) feel someone cares, it is hard for them to concentrate on academics, or even see the reason why they should. I try to get to know every student, letting each know that he or she is valued," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> said.   Hosting "coffee house" poetry readings, developing new programs to engage students in a higher level of learning and connecting with students and their families at school and other social activities are some ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> works to get to know her students, and encourage their success.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">This year</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105 regional teacher of the year selection committee cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX>'s effectiveness as a teacher and her community involvement. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> members also noted her ability to inspire other teachers and her ability to adapt to educational progress.   "I was overwhelmed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara</ENAMEX>'s determination to meet adversity and speak to it in such a challenging and encouraging way," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Merriman</ENAMEX>, a retired businessman and member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105 teacher of the year selection committee.   "She is really determined to make a difference in the lives of her students," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merriman</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX>'s name, along with eight other regional teachers of the year from throughout the state, will be forwarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction, which will then select a state teacher of the year. The nine regional teachers of the year will be honored at a celebration at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum of Flight</ENAMEX> in Seattle on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 28</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

