
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Thanks for the great seasons
Due to a career change I will not be able to coach the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> basketball team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. First thank you to all of the parents of the student-athletes I was able to coach over the past five seasons. Your dedication to your daughters was awesome.
For the players, I have enjoyed my years at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and thank everyone for the wonderful memories that I will cherish for a lifetime. I hope that you have learned as much from me as I have from you over the years. Your desire to improve yourself and to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> basketball competitive was awesome to be  a part of.
This desire was never more evident than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX> at Soap Lake Team Camp. Due to unforseeable circumstances, five girls - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alida Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriana Cardenas</ENAMEX> and Talisa Sotelo showed everyone at the camp what hard work, desire and guts were all about. These young ladies played 11 basketball games in four days. They competed in every game and took most teams to the very end. It was truly an honor to coach you five Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> one last time. The future of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viking</ENAMEX> basketball is alive and well.
I wish all returning players and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Roettger</ENAMEX> the best of luck this upcoming basketball season, as well as in all of their seasons. I hope that each of you get to taste the success each of you deserve.
Ladies my bags are always packed.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Simpson</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls basketball coach.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Seniors thank party sponsors
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> would like to extend a special thank you to all of the following individuals for their help in making the senior graduation party a great success:
First to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margie Ramirez</ENAMEX> for the donation of a handmade Grizzly quilt for the raffle; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Pina</ENAMEX> for being our cook and to all of the junior class parents who donated food; to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Karen Cullen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary and Cori Visser</ENAMEX> for the casino (even though they didn't have any seniors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>); and to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miles</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezell</ENAMEX> for helping with the games (all greatly appreciated; to Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ohler</ENAMEX>'s leadership class for the help with decorations; Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauro</ENAMEX> and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulus</ENAMEX> and the boys for their muscles; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Schilperoort</ENAMEX> for helping at the door and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha Soto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Rollinger</ENAMEX> for their help with decorating; and also to the school administration folks that helped out.
And last, but not least, to all of the senior parents who were there to help plan the event and helped at the party as well. We couldn't have done without you.
We also greatly appreciate the financial and merchandise donations from the following community businesses. Without their donations we would not have had such a great party. So a great big thanks you to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Lanes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Hall</ENAMEX>, Pepsi, The Battery Store, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randall J. Schuler DDS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MS</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Investment Properties Real Estate Inc.</ENAMEX>, R.F. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Strain Insurance Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Fire Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harold</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Repair and Rental LLC</ENAMEX>., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Orange Dairy Services Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Chiropractic Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ganser Enterprises Inc.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Physical Therapy and Sports Rehabilitation Services</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golob Family Trust</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MS</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Properties</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX>., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LLC</ENAMEX>., JCPenney, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Racquet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitness Center</ENAMEX>,  Costco, El Conquistador, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Auto</ENAMEX>, Arbys, Taco Bell, Eastway Video, Burger Ranch, Wal-Mart, Homestretch Espresso, Pizza Hut, Dominos's Pizza, Slam Dunk, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX>/A&W, McDonald's, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'d <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Footwear</ENAMEX>,  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Catalina</ENAMEX>'s, Jump Start Espresso, Daily Buzz, BiMart, New Image Hair Design, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Dental</ENAMEX> and U.S. Cellular.
 If we missed anyone we are truly sorry. It took the combined efforts of everyone to make it happen and to give our kids a safe place to celebrate their enormous accomplishments for this particular part of their journey. To them we say congratulations and to you again, we say thank you.
From the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS Senior Class Parent Booster Club</ENAMEX>
</P> 
 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

