
<P ID="1">Two innings cost <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girls
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">With the exception of two innings, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> girls fastpitch softball team gave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> all it could handle this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>.   But, the two letdowns-the fifth frame of the opening game and the sixth inning of the nightcap-both proved to be costly. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> utilized the two bad innings on the part of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> to pull out a pair of 7-4 and 9-5 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> victories.   "The first game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Kris Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, "we had a mini-meltdown in the fifth inning." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> rallied from a 4-2 deficit in the top of the fifth, plating four unearned runs to take control of the game. The major miscue in the fifth was an outfield error that let in two runs.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> opened the first game by plating a single tally in the first inning. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> increased its lead to 4-0 with a three-run uprising in the bottom of the second. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monique Montelongo</ENAMEX> started the second inning rally by drawing a walk, working her way around to third on a passed ball. She scampered home easily on a single by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacey Yanez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Cruz</ENAMEX> was then issued a walk, and both she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanez</ENAMEX> moved up a base on a passed ball. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanez</ENAMEX> scored when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Taylor</ENAMEX>'s grounder to second was misplayed for an error, the only miscue Ellensburg committed in the opening game.   The Bulldogs, after taking a 6-4 lead in the fifth, added an insurance run in the sixth. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't score again after the second inning.   The first game loss spoiled a fine pitching performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viri Pasillas</ENAMEX>, who limited the Bulldogs to just five hits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> had three strikeouts in the game.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viri</ENAMEX> pitched a great game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. "She was hitting her spots."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> actually outhit Ellensburg in the opener, 7 to 5. Two of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> came through with two hits apiece-Taylor, who was 2-for-4 with two singles, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devina Martinez</ENAMEX>, who was 2-for-3 with a double in the bottom of the fifth.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> jumped all over the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> in the twin bill finale, scoring three runs in its first at-bat. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> wasted little time, though, in responding, answering with a four-run explosion of its own in the bottom half of the first.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> initiated the first inning rally by laying down a bunt single, one of two hits she had in the game. She proceeded to swipe both second and third, two of the three stolen bases <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> was credited with in the nightcap. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, who turned in another two-hit performance for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>, drove in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> with her first single of the game. An error of the bat of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celeste Loffer</ENAMEX> scored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. Following a walk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Wells</ENAMEX> lashed a single to plate both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loffer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX>.   The Bulldogs came back with two runs in the top half of the third, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> squared the contest at 5-all by plating a lone score in the bottom half of the frame.   Neither club could get much of anything going after that, that is until the top of the sixth, when the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> committed three of the six errors they had in the game. The three sixth inning miscues led to four <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> runs crossing the plate.   "We had those three errors, plus <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> started hitting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>) that inning," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. "We couldn't come back from that."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> was lifted midway through the sixth, making way for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>, who finished the pitching chores for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The two losses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> dropped <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s conference record to 0-3, 0-7 overall. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> are scheduled to take on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> on the Red Devils' field for a single non-league game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>), with game time set for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

