
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> makes the shots to win Banana Belt title
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/14/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Stotz</ENAMEX>'s hobby is collecting birdies. Not parrots or canaries, the types you keep in a cage in your living room. Rather, he picks up his birdies on golf courses.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past weekend</TIMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Banana Belt, Black Rock Creek's most prestigious golf tourney of the year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> collected nine birdies. They helped him to soar to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s title.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX>, who's attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> and is scheduled to graduate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this December</TIMEX>, knocked down five birdies on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> enroute to posting an opening day best one-under 71. That gave him a slim one-stroke lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hall</ENAMEX> heading into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s final round.   The eventual winner, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> graduate, was still clinging to his one-stroke lead over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> through 12 holes of play on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> went birdie-birdie on 13 and 14, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> could only muster a par and double-bogey on the two holes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> widened his gap over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> from one stroke to five.   Parring three of the four final holes, absorbing a double-bogey hick-up on the par-3 17th, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> cruised to the easy win. He finished the 36-hole affair with a one-under 143 (71-72). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, the runner-up, was five strokes back with a 148 (72-76).   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Grace</ENAMEX> and Robi Raab, both playing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s final group, tied for third low score of the tourney. They each shot five-over 149's.   Raab, whose credentials include both Banana Belt and Yakima Valley Amateur titles, posted the third low score of the day on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, a one-over 73, but he quickly fell out of contention <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. A triple-bogey on the 210-yard, par-3 second hole put him four shots back of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX>. He slipped back another stroke on No. 3 when he parred the hole and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> birdied it. A bogey on No. 6, the toughest hole on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> course, put Raab six strokes behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX>. Raab played even-par from there, but the damage had already been done.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace</ENAMEX>, a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Adams Country Club</ENAMEX>, opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s Banana Belt with a two-over 74. The three-shot deficit he took into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s play quickly grew to five strokes, as he bogeyed and double-bogeyed the first two holes. The closest he got to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> was four strokes, when he birdied the par-3 12th.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, deemed by many as the best golfer of all the current Black Rock Creek members, fell from one shot back of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> to three behind at just past the midway point of the opening nine on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> opened the three-stroke lead by posting a par and birdie on 6 and 7 while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> took a bogey and par, respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> rebounded to match <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> with pars on the next three holes, then made it interesting by scoring a bird on the dogleg-right 11th hole. With <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> taking a bogey there, all of a sudden <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> was back to being down by only one.   The two linksters both parred the short, par-3 12th. But when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> posted back-to-back birds on 13 and 14, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> didn't respond accordingly, the handwriting became clear that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> was in control.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Schutt</ENAMEX>, 18, hung with the big dogs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, skating through the first 18 holes with a two-over 74. Perhaps feeling the pressure of his first ever "adult" tournament, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> faltered on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, settling for an 83. His two-day total of 157 left him with the ninth best tourney score.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Campbell</ENAMEX>, a seasoned veteran on many of the state's top golf courses, posted solid numbers in finishing with the fifth low score from the 60-person field. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> had rounds of 75-77 (152). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Porcayo</ENAMEX>, another Yakima area golfer, had the sixth low two-day round (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77-76-153</TIMEX>).   In the Banana Belt's Rainier Flight, for golfers with handicaps of 14 and above, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Luther</ENAMEX> claimed top honors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> carded rounds of 84-85 (169) to best the next closest finishers by eight strokes. The runners-up were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Boge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hicks</ENAMEX>, each of whom had two-day totals of 177. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Ott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Schlenker</ENAMEX> were a stroke back with identical 178's.   Golfers who cashed on the net side (actual score minus handicap) included: (Concord Flight)-1st-Ken Harle 139, 2nd-(tie) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keith Grace & Robi Raab</ENAMEX> 141, 4th-(tie) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tom Diener & Ivan Porcayo</ENAMEX> 143, 6th-Pete Veliz 144; (Rainier Flight)-1st-Bob Barker 141, 2nd-Ken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ott</ENAMEX> 142, 3rd-Dan <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kolb</ENAMEX> 144, 4th-Dan Clark 147, 5th-(tie) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Miller</ENAMEX> & Steward <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX> 149.   Flag prize winners included: (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>) long putt on No. 1-Bob Rice (26-2), KP on No. 3-Willie <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Edwards</ENAMEX> (0-6), KP on No. 4-Joe <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Herber</ENAMEX> (6-5), long drive on No. 7-Rick <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pedee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KP</ENAMEX> on No. 9-Mike <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nichols</ENAMEX> (11-4), KP on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">No. 11-Keith Grace</ENAMEX> (2-4), KP on No. 12-Ty <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX>, KP on No. 17-Jack Syverson (9-3); (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>) long drive on No. 3-Ivan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porcayo</ENAMEX>, KP on No. 5-Dennis <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burke & Joe Herber</ENAMEX> (chip-ins), KP on No. 6-Chad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> (5-9), KP on No. 9-Robi Raab (1-0), KP on No. 12-Ivan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porcayo</ENAMEX> (4-10), KP on No. 13-Travis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> (1-6), KP on No. 14-Dennis <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Burke</ENAMEX> (0-5), KP on No. 17-Ivan <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porcayo</ENAMEX> (3-1).
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

