
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> students holding steady when it comes to ITED
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Students in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> may not have scored as high as the state average when it comes to the Iowa Test of Educational Development (ITED), but students throughout the area are managing to keep their scores in line with not only other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> students, but the school's average in years past.   The ITED tests ninth-grade students in three categories, including expression, reading and quantitative thinking. The test also offers a core total.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX> explained that the ITED is a completely different exam than the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) exam that people have gotten used to hearing about. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said the ITED is a strictly multi-choice exam, where students are not asked to explain the answers they provide. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said when it comes to the WASL students are asked to explain their answers and are then scored on both the answer they gave and the explanation of how they came to that conclusion.   "It's just a different test," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s ninth grade students scored as well or better than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37 percent</NUMEX> of their peers throughout the nation in the category of expression. In the reading category, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students scored in the 25th percentile and in the quantitative thinking category they scored in the 40th percentile. In the core total, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">34 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> ninth graders scored as well or better than other ninth graders throughout the country.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Vegar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> executive director of instruction and learning, said he was concerned when he saw <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s test scores. However, he noted that although as a community many people are in the business of making comparisons - comparing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s scores with the state average or with scores from surrounding communities - what should really be compared is how <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has done in the past with how it's doing now.   "We need to compare ourselves to ourselves," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said. "We need to look at our children and make sure we're improving from year to year."   When looking at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s numbers, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> ninth graders did show improvement. In the core total in 2002-03 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students scored in the 31st percentile. In 2003-04, that number went up by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX>. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students improved by at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> in every category.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, students' scores seemed to stay fairly close to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s scores. In the category of expression, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of students scored as well or better than other ninth grade students throughout the nation, in reading the students scored in the 27th percentile and in the 39th percentile in quantitative thinking. Looking at the core total, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">33 percent</NUMEX> of students scored as well or better than other students who took the exam.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said one of the things he attributes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s scores to is the make-up of the district, noting that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> has a large population of migrant students and students who qualify for free and reduced lunch. He said comparing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> to the state average is like comparing apples to oranges.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> pointed out that when compared to other districts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> students are scoring right where they should be.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> also noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> students have managed to keep their scores holding steady over time.   The state average on the ITED test shows in the category of expression <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX> of students scored as well or better than students who took the exam throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, in reading <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> students scored in the 53rd percentile and in the 59th percentile in quantitative thinking. Overall, the core total for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state ninth graders in 2003-04 shows <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">57 percent</NUMEX> of students scoring as well or better than other American ninth graders who took the exam.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

