
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> karate instructor has 25 years of teaching experience
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Karate. Many people misunderstand the purpose of the mystical sport of martial arts. Some people don't respect it while others have found that it has a place in their lives.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olegario Luna</ENAMEX> is one of the latter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>, 59, studies the system of Doshinkan Karate.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> and came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> when he was 1-year-old. He was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> until he was 12. In 1960-61, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> and his family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, where they purchased property. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>'s family, though, would migrate to different areas in the country to perform farm labor. Being part of a migrant farm labor family, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> was forced to drop out of school because he couldn't keep up with his education.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> would come to meet his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anjelica</ENAMEX>, in his early adult years. The couple has been married for 32 years, living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. They have one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, and one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca</ENAMEX>, both of whom have graduated with college degrees.   "We were very proud to see they finished school," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> took up karate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">35 years ago</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.   "I used to have a friend in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> who got me involved," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>.   The first place that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> trained was in the basement of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Methodist Church</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said the group eventually moved to the Tri-Cities to follow their trainer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> joked that when he first started training people would tease him that he was too old to take up karate at the age of 25, which was considered a late age to start.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said karate has taught him a lot personally.   "It taught me to be kind of a leader," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>. "It gives me a lot of self-confidence.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said when he started karate one part of it he liked was how everyone seemed like a part of the each other's family.   "I have met a lot of interesting people in karate," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> touched on how karate has changed over the years. He said when he first started his teacher didn't believe in attending karate tournaments. He also said there were only three colors of belt when he started, which were white, brown and black. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> is a sixth degree black belt.   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 25 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> has been teaching karate/self defense classes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>.   As an instructor, he focuses on training, not teaching.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said he still remembers his first class.   "We had a lot of young people turn out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>.   He said the large group quickly dwindled down when participants realized it wasn't what they thought it would be. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said a lot of people went into the class thinking they would be flying around doing all the karate stuff they see in movies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said his first class dwindled from 25 participants to two.   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 20 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> and his friend <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jeweler <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Beck</ENAMEX> have been training together, developing a strong friendship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> has obtained a seventh degree black belt.   Karate has taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> many places in life. He has gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> to train with different teachers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said he enjoys teaching karate, but uses the opportunity to train and work on his skills. As a teacher, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said he teaches his students to strive to be a better master of karate than he is. Under the system <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> trains in, students learn to study karate on more of an individual basis.   "The system is to make you stronger," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>. "Make your body as powerful as possible."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> teaches karate classes year round for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said that he doesn't care if he has one student or 20.   "As long as there is one person who shows up, I am here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said he simply enjoys teaching students who want to learn his style of karate.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> tries to teach his students to never start problems and that karate is only to be used to defend yourself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> said he remembers one of his teachers telling him that with karate a person can do two things. First, karate can be almost always used to help a person talk their way out of a problem. Secondly, karate can be used to help a person never get into a situation where they would have to use it.   There are a couple of misconceptions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX> would like to clear up about karate.   "You can't go by what you see in the movies," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luna</ENAMEX>. "It is not that way at all. Karate is more about training than fighting. That is the disciple of it."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

