
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board queried on why funds not allocated for skate park
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">As the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LYVREC</ENAMEX>) board met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to review progress being made by the agencies that received funding from the federally-funded board <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, representatives of a rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city project waited to question the board on its funding decisions.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recreation Department Director Don Stiles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX>, 16, who has championed the construction of a skateboard facility at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>, attended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting asking for a better explanation of why <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s skateboard park proposal had been swept off the funding table.   "How did we go from being at the top of the funding list to being scrapped all together," asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX>, who has been working on the skateboard project for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>.   The skateboard park project, designed to become a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>, located midway between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, was not among the selections which received appropriations from the LYVREC board's final pot of money in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late December</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> requested all of the remaining money left of the LYVREC's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 million</NUMEX> federal funding, about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>, for the development of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> park, a request some feel may have led to its being rejected from funding consideration. Not so, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Souders</ENAMEX>, LYVREC board chair.   "As I've said before, we looked at sustainability and jobs when it came to our funding decision," said Souders.   Receiving the bulk of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds were a Grandview playground project and a grape and wine education center at the Grandview campus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>. Also receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funding were the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX> equipment request, and the Horizon Of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s adult computer, education and language classes. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> also received funding for a health care program for young people considering entering the health field.   All of those projects, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> park proposal, had been among the top projects initially approved for consideration by the LYVREC board in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. But controversy over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>'s request for the entire <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> may have colored the board decision, a claim denied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LYVREC Board</ENAMEX>.   "We only had a certain amount of money to distribute," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Henry</ENAMEX>, a board member from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "We had to look at all of the projects," he said, reiterating that no single community was judged over another.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> said the board was very interested in the skate park, but ultimately the issue of jobs was the determining criteria.   Souders said there were other applicants who were also eliminated.   "All of the applicants were given an opportunity to move to the next level," she said.   Souders told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stiles</ENAMEX> that the board worked hard to make the "best decision with the amount of money we had.   "We had a scoring process and we strictly followed it," she added.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

