
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Indelook Club</ENAMEX> to hear about life in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Argentina</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Indelook Club</ENAMEX> will have a chance to hear about life in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Argentina</ENAMEX> when they get together for their next meeting, set to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 10</TIMEX>, at the home of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie Cullen</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Cocciaro</ENAMEX>, an exchange student from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Argentina</ENAMEX>, will serve as the guest speaker during the event, which will be co-hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Bruhn</ENAMEX>. The program chair for the meeting is Pat Barr.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX>, members will also begin to prepare for the holiday season. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> members are asked to bring a copy of their favorite holiday recipe to share with the group during roll call.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

