
<P ID="1">Victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> no cakewalk for 'Hounds
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NACHES</ENAMEX> - The Naches Rangers know how to put a hit on opposing players. Just ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> football team.   "We had some kids that were sore after the game," confirmed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Dustin Lamb</ENAMEX>.   Despite the bumps and bruises sustained by the Greyhounds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> stole a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX> victory away from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX>' home field. Riding the pinpoint passing of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX>, who tossed three touchdown passes, the 'Hounds eked out a 30-21 win.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s victory squares <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s CWAC South record at 2-2 on the season. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> slipped to 1-2 in league play.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said the win will go a long way in helping the 'Hounds solidify at least the No. 4 seed into the CWAC playoffs. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> (2-2, 2-4) still has league contests remaining against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> (0-3, 1-5) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> (4-0, 6-0).   After playing to a scoreless tie in the first quarter, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> drew first blood in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s game on a 28-yard TD pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX>. A 20-yard field goal by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Alvarez</ENAMEX> later in the second period gave the 'Hounds a 9-0 lead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> cut the deficit to 9-6 on the ensuing play, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dylan Emmons</ENAMEX> outraced <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s kickoff team 95 yards to paydirt. A two-point conversion pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Weller</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Rowan</ENAMEX> drew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX> to within 9-8.   Neither club could get much of anything going in the third quarter. But the final period started off with a bang for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, as the 'Hounds struck quickly twice. The first of the two TD's came on a 32-yard pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX>, the second such scoring hook-up in the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX>, who led all rushers in the contest with 171 yards on 28 totes, broke off a 28-yarder for the second fourth quarter Greyhound score. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>'s two <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAT</ENAMEX> kicks gave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> what appeared to be at the time an insurmountable 23-8 lead.   But the gutsy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> wouldn't go away quietly.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> countered with a 28-yard TD pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weller</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Reese</ENAMEX>, following up the score with another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weller</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese</ENAMEX> touchdown connection-the second one a 40-yard scoring strike.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rangers</ENAMEX> pulled to within 23-21 of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> on the second <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weller</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reese</ENAMEX> hook-up. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> opted to go for two on the conversion in an attempt to tie the game, but the 'Hounds stuffed the running play to preserve their slim two-point lead.   Down the stretch, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> ended any suspense that was left when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> threw for his third TD of the night. The final touchdown toss went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Chester-a</ENAMEX> 24-yarder. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alvarez</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAT</ENAMEX> kick accounted for the final 30-21 score.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX>) had a good game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>. "The best thing we had going was the balance we showed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> does well when he has time, and our line did a great job of giving him time."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> ended up completing 11-of-20 passes for 172 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> were his favorite targets, as they combined for seven catches for 112 yards.   The balance <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> spoke of was provided by the Greyhounds' great rushing attack. With superb blocking from the likes of right tackle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody McMillan</ENAMEX>, left guard J.R. Camacho and center <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Peterson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> tallied 198 yards on the ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX>'s 171-yard rushing performance highlighted the ground attack.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX>) put his <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">ten cents</NUMEX> in," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>.   Heading into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said he knew <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX> were going to provide a stiff challenge for his team.   "We were very impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> on film," he said.   "They bring it right at you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX>' wishbone attack, also praising the 3-5-3 defensive alignment <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> throws at opposing teams.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> hits very hard. They're a touch bunch," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said.   The Greyhounds, though, proved they're not sissies, either. Defensively, Camacho had the standout performance for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, recording 11 tackles and one quarterback sack. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> showed he isn't one-dimensional, as he added nine tackles and deflected two passes to go along with his three TD tosses on the night. Registering four stops apiece for the Greyhounds' defensive unit were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake Carpenter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMillan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Concienne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mejia</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

