
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> will be used to buy books, books and more books at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> library
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - How much does <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83,639</NUMEX> buy nowadays?   Well, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> is hoping it will cover the cost of everything from enlarging its school library book collection to providing for professional development opportunities.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Leos</ENAMEX>, the associate deputy undersecretary and senior policy advisor to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of English Language Acquisition</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Education</ENAMEX>, presented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83,639</NUMEX> No Child Left Behind grant. The grant funds will be used specifically for improving literacy through the school library.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz-Fox Librarian Kris Schilperoort</ENAMEX> explained that the funds can be used for a variety of things, ranging from extending the hours of the school library to upgrading technology in the facility.   However, the thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> is most excited about is the prospect of being able to both update and enlarge the library's book collection. Currently standing at more than 16,000 pieces, including books and other mixed media, the collection contains battered paperback books and some non-fiction selections that could be updated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> laughed, noting that the library has books about basketball that still show players running down the court in short shorts.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> said she realizes there are books in the collection that should have been thrown out long ago, but getting riding of books is not something she is good at.   "I have a hard time because they're still really good stories," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> said. The last time the collection was cleaned out was more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> said receiving the grant is going to require her to go through every shelf in the library and decide which books can stay and which will have to go.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> said just because she decides books are too battered to stay in the collection doesn't mean that they won't be replaced. Instead, she said she is hoping to update a lot of the books that have been well read over the years. She noted that there are certain series the students can't get enough of, and those are the books she plans on replacing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> said some of the popular books include selections from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX> the Cowdog series, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junie B. Wells</ENAMEX> books and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Potter</ENAMEX>.   "They're just fun," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> said about the different series. "I would like to get them all in hard cover instead of paperback."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> also talked about upgrading the technology in the library and maybe bringing in another computer. She added that another computer would mean increased access to Accelerated Reader tests, which students can take after reading a book off of the Accelerated Reader list. The computerized exams test a student's comprehension of the book they read.   When it comes to professional development, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schilperoort</ENAMEX> noted that there are several conferences she wouldn't mind attending. She said the conferences help point out ways librarians can help students with their literacy skills while in the library. She noted that the conferences also deal with updates in circulation systems, teaching librarians about the new technology added to the systems and how to best take advantage of them.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> wasn't the only local district to receive such a grant. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Middle School</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$48,120</NUMEX> grant. Together, the two grants represent only a small fraction of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19 million</NUMEX> in library grants that were awarded to 31 schools across the nation.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

