


<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">by CONGRESSMAN <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DOC HASTINGS</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">People's Republic of China</ENAMEX> has recently stepped up efforts to gain access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> fresh apple market - an action that could have serious consequences for American fruit growers far beyond simple market competition.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX> is home to numerous pests and diseases that have the potential to devastate American agriculture. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>'s (USDA) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX>) has already identified nearly 300 pests present in Chinese apple production areas that do not occur in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. This is an especially significant concern as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX> doesn't have a good track record of ensuring that their native pests and diseases do not enter our country.
</P><P ID="6">   Less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, APHIS halted the importation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ya</ENAMEX> pears from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX> due to the presence of a fungal disease. The initial discovery of this was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state. If this disease had become established, it could have caused significant economic harm to not only the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> pear industry, but also to the entire tree fruit industry, including apples and cherries.
</P><P ID="7">   Another pest native to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Emerald Ash Bore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAB</ENAMEX>), was discovered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Michigan</ENAMEX> and has cost millions in losses. As USDA works to eradicate this destructive tree-killing beetle, taxpayers foot the bill.
</P><P ID="8">   We were very lucky that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ya</ENAMEX> pear incident in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> was discovered quickly, and there were no long-term or large-scale impacts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> tree fruit industry. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> simply cannot afford another incident like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EAB</ENAMEX> infestation.
</P><P ID="9">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> has a well-established track record of using sound science as the basis for determinations on the safety of imported agricultural products. Until scientific experts are convinced that imported apples will not be a pathway for the introduction of a destructive disease or pest, our markets should not be opened to Chinese apples.
</P><P ID="10">   It is very important that APHIS moves only with great caution as they consider requests from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX> to export fresh apples to our country. The USDA's first responsibility must be protecting American agriculture and American consumers.
</P><P ID="11">   I have every confidence that the quality of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> apples means they can readily compete in the global marketplace with Chinese apples. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> growers should not be forced to deal with new pests and diseases from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX>, and the significant costs that would come with them.
</P><P ID="12">   Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>) represents <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>'s 4th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Congressional District</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




