


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> speakers not happy with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> session
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/30/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Disappointment was the common theme among three area lawmakers with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> state legislative session.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Senator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> and area Representatives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> addressed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> to talk about the past session.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> was the first of the three lawmakers to speak on the past 60-day session, which he felt nothing major was really accomplished. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said the session was marred by the fact <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is a major election year.
</P><P ID="7">   "It does tend to flavor some of the bills (introduced)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, who is just completing his first two-year-term, said the state once more spent more money than it has. The good news, felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, was that general taxes weren't increased to cover any shortfalls.
</P><P ID="9">   There was some good news out of the recent budget session. The legislature allocated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$145 million</NUMEX> to address areas such as education and health care.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said the state in the next biennium faces another multiple billion dollar deficit, similar to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.8 billion</NUMEX> the state was in the hole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   The legislature also implemented some regulations concerning the Mad Cow epidemic. It is now illegal to transport "downer" cows to rendering plants. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said the legislature is also looking at addressing prevention of the Mad Cow disease further.
</P><P ID="12">   There were also bills passed designed to help the fleeting asparagus and hop industries.
</P><P ID="13">   The legislature, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, also managed to reinstate several tax incentives that were set to expire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> after being in place for a decade, that will help state business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said these incentives will help spark the state's struggling economy.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> also said more needs to be done to keep doctors, nurses and hospitals, especially in rural areas, from moving out of state because of liability premiums that are too expensive to pay.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said he is excited about this upcoming election year for Republicans. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> is a quality candidate for the Republicans. He also felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> has a good chance of being re-elected president, depending on how the economy and the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> take shape in the next few months.
</P><P ID="16">   "Republicans in this state feel a sense of excitement," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, who is the deputy Republican leader in the house, was also frustrated with the recent legislative session. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said no consensus on issues dealing with such areas as health care and workman's compensation were addressed in this past session.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> spent a majority of his time talking about the failing workman's comp system.
</P><P ID="19">   "It is not adequately serving employers or employees," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said unless something is done to address problems with the state labor and industry department program, another double-digit rate increase can be expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> added the problem with the workman's comp system is that L&I is not adequately managing the program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said the 15th district trio plans to work extensively <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> on bringing meaningful reform to the system.
</P><P ID="21">   Another area of concern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> has deals with the recent changes to the primary election. The state, based on a court decision, recently implemented a new primary election system, where people will vote according to political affiliation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> is concerned the new voting system will keep people away from the polls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> is expecting an initiative on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> ballot challenging the state's new primary system.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said this election year will be one of the most significant ones in recent memory. He said the decisions made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> will impact the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> and the state for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next decade</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   One of the top priorities of the three area lawmakers is to restore the people's trust in their government, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said he wants to see changes within state agencies, where they focus on serving the people more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said business and people continue to leave the state because of the changes being implemented in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   "We really need to change that," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, the elder political statesman of the trio, was equally disappointed with the happenings in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> this past session.
</P><P ID="26">   "(In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>) we really didn't get a whole lot done we could be proud of," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> was disheartened to see no headway being gained on the workman's comp issue. He also wished more had been done to address the state's water issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said Governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> did a lot to slow down progress on both bills.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the problem with the workman's comp issue is the department of labor and industry, itself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> wants to implement legislation that has an outside agency conduct a review of the labor and industry department. Currently, the state agency conducts an internal review.
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> also announced he is seeking the caucus chair position, which is the No. 2 seat in the senate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> currently had 17 votes to give him the coveted position, needing only 13.
</P>





 










<P ID="30">Webmaster
</P><P ID="31">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




