
<P ID="1">14 year old chosen to watch over para-pro's children
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Walker</ENAMEX> asked if anyone would be interested in a job that paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> an hour, many students' ears perked up. However, it was 14-year-old freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolene Merry</ENAMEX> who was chosen to fill the position.   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three months</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> has been spending her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> evenings, as well as her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> mornings, caring for the children of para-professionals who are taking classes through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>.   According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, the classes are being offered through the college in an effort to help para-professionals prepare for the new state assessment test. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> officials said by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2006</TIMEX> all para-professionals throughout the state will either have to have passed the test or have an Associate of Arts degree.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> said she took the after school job because she enjoys working with children. So far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> said she typically watches three or four children during each of her shifts. She said caring for children ages infant to nine years old can be a challenge, although she finds that the older children can be easier to watch.   During the week <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> watches the children for approximately two hours a night, spending three hours with them on Saturdays. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> said during that time she plays games with the children, allows them to watch movies and every now and then they even head down to the gymnasium to play a little basketball.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> said although she has enjoyed the job over the course of the last several months, she will have to reapply for it next semester. In the meantime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> said she is also interested in taking care of other children when she is not working at the school. She can reached at 837-5121.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daily News   Jolene Merry</ENAMEX> has been spending many of her weeknights and Saturdays caring for children at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>, ensuring they are entertained while their parents take classes being offered through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>. Here <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merry</ENAMEX> watches over 3-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene C. Rangel</ENAMEX> and her brother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique</ENAMEX>, 1, both of whom are the children of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucie Rangel</ENAMEX>, a para-professional.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

