
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> drama club play to take stage for five-day run
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A story of jealousy, power and betrayal set to music is the foundation for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Drama Club</ENAMEX>'s presentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat.   Under the direction of Maisy Sylling, with aid from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Hellner-Gomez</ENAMEX>, opening night for the high school singers, dancers and actors will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 19</TIMEX>, on the stage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.   Leading the cast as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Grimmer</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Wells</ENAMEX> as the narrator. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX>'s father, who is devastated when his sons decide to sell their youngest brother to a band of traveling traders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reporting Joseph</ENAMEX>'s death to their father sets into motion one of the most touching stories in Biblical history about family betrayal. The treacherous brothers will be played both male and female actors, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dane Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Esquivel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Spilles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Razey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Harvey</ENAMEX>, Alaina Hull, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Henry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Fuller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Magana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikki Castro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Wells</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Martin</ENAMEX> and Keely <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaCombe</ENAMEX> will play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>'s wives include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurora Weaver</ENAMEX>, Estela Florez, Amber Guy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Clements</ENAMEX>. Ishmaelites will be played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Jetter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard McCardle</ENAMEX>.   Dancers include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherran Martinez</ENAMEX>, Heather Van Cobach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dione Cohan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Zamorano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kat Bingham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marika McNerney</ENAMEX>.   The brothers' wives will include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa McMinimee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Cohan</ENAMEX>, Keely <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaCombe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jillian Jetter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Matson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizzy Shehata</ENAMEX>, Brionna Hughes, Erendida Manzo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marika McNerney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabitha DeRuyter</ENAMEX> and Heather Van Corbach. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Whittle</ENAMEX> will be the lone adult actor in the production, playing the Pharaoh. The nearly all-student production is aided by musical director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Haney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Cohu</ENAMEX>. Student stage managers are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Kilian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Thomas</ENAMEX>. Lighting technicians include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Webster</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Martin</ENAMEX> handling sound. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Schilperoot</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Lopez</ENAMEX> are in charge of make-up.   The lobby crew under the direction of house manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Marin</ENAMEX> includes Abi Anderson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Deaton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meagan Kraxenberger</ENAMEX>.   Also working behind the scenes are students <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaymee Arevalo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina Bobadilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Campbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Cervantes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Hansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatriz Jimenez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joaquin Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kari Mandrell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacie McIntire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perla Ortega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanna Pangle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cami Richardson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Rivera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marissa Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Saunders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Uribe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Valencia</ENAMEX>.   With music by award-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Lloyd Webber</ENAMEX> with lyrics by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Rice</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> drama club production is one families will want to attend.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS Drama Club</ENAMEX> will present the popular Broadway musical in five-performances - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>, 20, 21, 27 and 28, with the curtain going up all five nights at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>   Ticket prices are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for senior citizens and students.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

