
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board approves use of funds to provide certified nurse training
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Those people, young and old alike, who are interested in taking part in training to become a certified nurses assistant (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNA</ENAMEX>) will soon have another place to turn.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) board voted to allow <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,500</NUMEX> of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,500</NUMEX> originally granted to the organization for use in providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNA</ENAMEX> training. The proposal was approved pending a formal written request by the hospital.   The informal request for the use of the funds was made during a report by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Linde</ENAMEX>, who is in charge of organizing and conducting health care seminars through the local hospital. These seminars were what the original grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board was intended to be used for.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> noted that most recently the hospital hosted three health care seminars, each looking at a different health care career. She said they held seminars on what it takes to be an obstetrics nurse, a laboratory technician and to work in respiratory care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said all of the seminars were fairly well attended, especially the respiratory care seminar, which had 14 people in attendance.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said the people taking advantage of the seminars are mostly students from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, although several students from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> did attend, as well as several adults.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX>, when the proposal for the seminars was first brought to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board it was the hospital's intent to create seven different seminars, focusing on seven careers. Instead, she said they have been able to create 12 different career kits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said she plans on dropping off copies of the kits at both the local high school and middle school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said she is also planning on offering a high school senior project day at the hospital. She said the event would serve as a day where those students interested in pursing a career in health care could come to the hospital and learn more about the senior projects and the health care careers that are available for students to study for their projects.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,500</NUMEX> she is requesting would be used to offer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNA</ENAMEX> training at the hospital, and is money that she has been able to save from the original <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,500</NUMEX> that was granted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board. She said the money would be well used, if it was utilized to conduct at least one <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CNA</ENAMEX> class before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX>, which is when all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds have to be spent.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

