
<P ID="1">400 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> fifth graders to be adopted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/15/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Students' parents asked   to attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17</TIMEX> meeting   Adoption proceedings are in the works for approximately 400 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> youngsters who will be in the fifth grade at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.   No, the parents of these 400 or so youths aren't farming their sons and daughters out to new families. Rather, it will be more of a "joint custody" type arrangement.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise group has decided to "adopt" the 10 and 11-year-olds to ensure they all are given access to the organization's five promises. Those promises are intended to help reduce risk factors and support the youngsters as they work toward graduating from high school.   The parents of all the kids who will be fifth graders at Chief Kamiakin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> are being asked to attend a meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday, June 17</TIMEX>, to help address what needs to be done to keep their children in school and prospering. The open house meeting will be held from 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX>. The administrative assistant of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Fairbairn</ENAMEX>, said child care services will be provided that evening. Free food and prizes are also being offered to those who attend.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise is a grassroots coalition of individuals, business people, educators and representatives of social service and faith-based organizations. The group has adopted an initiative to bring the five promises to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s young people.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> said the goal is to remedy the high dropout rate and disturbing trends toward tobacco, alcohol and drug use.   "It's a fact," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>, "that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of our students in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will not graduate from high school."   That means of the 400 or so youths who will be sitting in fifth grade classrooms at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, 100 of them will not finish school before graduating.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise group is committed to working with parents to change that statistic.   Part of the problem, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>, is that the rate of alcohol, tobacco and drug use in this area of the state is higher than in other regions.   She said at the urging of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX>, who chairs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise, the group will adopt the 400 or so fifth graders. Plans are to work intensively with the youngsters throughout their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next eight years</TIMEX> of school to give them every chance to graduate with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> pointed out that based on surveys and research, it has been determined that the fifth grade is the best time to implement positive youth development strategies. She said every year the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX> will receive special age-appropriate prevention and educational services.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> group is asking that the parents of these youngsters become part of the solution, and attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s meeting to help develop strategies that will ensure all 400 fifth graders graduate from high school.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

