


<P ID="1">Water shortage exists in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - As the water pressure in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> continues to drop, the tempers in the small community are on the rise.
</P><P ID="5">   Citizens gathered at Mabton City Hall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to urge the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to cite those citizens not adhering to the recently mandated water conservation efforts.
</P><P ID="6">   The city initiated a city-wide water conservation program in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early July</TIMEX> when citizens began complaining of serious drops in water pressure. Citizens were mailed notices urging them to limit irrigating their lawns and other outside water use to odd/even days. As part of the city's conservation effort, the public water crews began shutting off the city's water supply between the hours of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to allow the wells to refill. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> officials issued the conservation alert again in mid- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, again asking residents to restrict their water use in order to give the city an opportunity to provide enough water for drinking and washing. But as citizens reported <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, there are still too many people not paying attention to the conservation need.
</P><P ID="7">   While most citizens attending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s council meeting were in favor of the city's conservation effort, others were concerned that some residents don't understand the need for curtailing water use.
</P><P ID="8">   In addition to airing concerns about the health and safety hazards, the water shortage and shut-off, residents complained that proper notice hasn't been provided to citizens.
</P><P ID="9">   "The notice was mailed in English. I think it needed to be mailed out in Spanish," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Vasquez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fifth Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Mabton</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   With nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s population of Hispanic descent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasquez</ENAMEX> felt most people weren't complying with the conservation effort because they couldn't read the city's notice.
</P><P ID="11">   "Some may not have even received it," he added.
</P><P ID="12">   They definitely don't understand why there is no water at the tap in the middle of the night, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elsie Sanchez</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Mabton</ENAMEX> resident.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>, who lives on Pine Street, said her concerns with the water shortage deal with health and safety issues. "Plus, there is no consistency about when the water is shut off and when it is turned back on," she told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said she had researched how other towns handled water shortages "But none I found resorted to turning the water off after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>," she said.
</P><P ID="15">   "I think this method is endangering people's health and is a fire risk," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   She cited instances when she had found her water turned off as early as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX> and not turned back on until well after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 a.m.</TIMEX> "Not all of us work 8 to 5," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="17">   "What are the hours the water is to be turned off and why weren't we given better notice of the shut-offs?," she asked.
</P><P ID="18">   Saying the city had looked hard at what measures to take in view of the city wells depleted water supplies, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> chose the shut-off as a stop gap emergency measure.
</P><P ID="19">   "We sent out notices to the residents asking them to voluntarily conserve water during this emergency," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX>. "But we can't force people to stop watering their lawns."
</P><P ID="20">   Not everyone is observing the odd-even water days, noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Palomarez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fern Avenue</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Mabton</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   Saying her children are now calling her the water police, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palomarez</ENAMEX> is worried that not everyone in town is taking the current water shortage seriously.
</P><P ID="22">   "A lot of people don't understand about the city's recent action to cut off city water after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palomarez</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="23">   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> city wells have been shut off after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX> to allowed the wells to replenish, a step the council took in an effort to save the city wells' booster pumps.
</P><P ID="24">   The city, which is in the process of seeking state and federal funds to drill a new city well, noticed a dramatic drop in water pressure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX>, when the first hot spell hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> city crews and engineers have tried several methods of elevating and maintaining the water pressure to no avail, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="26">   "Our booster pumps can't work fast enough to replenish the system," he said.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> has seen a drop in the aquifer during the past several years and is in the process of seeking the approval of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Conservancy Board of Yakima</ENAMEX> for permission to drill a new well. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said in the meantime, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is seeking funds to build a new well, which is expected to cost more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> dollars.
</P><P ID="28">   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> aquifers continue to drop so we will have to drill a deeper well shaft," he told the citizens. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said even if the city isn't able to get a grant to dig the well, it will be seeking a loan to get the well dug.
</P><P ID="29">   "We will have a new well by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>," he said.
</P><P ID="30">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> engineers continue to meet with the conservancy board to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s need for a new well, which is expected to cost between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX></NUMEX> to drill, and install.
</P><P ID="31">   In the meantime, residents can expect to have the water emergency continue as it is until <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> temperatures begin to drop, lessening the demands on the city wells.
</P><P ID="32">   Also attending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s meeting was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, who commended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and the citizens for their patience during the current water crisis. He said he traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> to see how desperate the water situation is and to offer the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Commission</ENAMEX> when the city's grant request comes before it.
</P>





 










<P ID="33">Webmaster
</P><P ID="34">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




