
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Yes votes urged
I have lived in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> for many years and have always supported kids and public schools. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1973 to 1977</TIMEX> it was my pleasure to have served as a board member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>.
I have listened to a presentation from school administrators on the cost of the bond issue and special levy and how the money will be used. The special levy will replace the levy approved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2000</TIMEX>. The bond issue will be used to build new schools and remodel others. The difference in cost of voting yes or no is only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> a year if your home is valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>.
The board of directors have done what they said they were going to do—lower taxes and bring a lot of money into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> with the special levy. The bond issue is needed because we are growing over 100 students per year and we need more classrooms and more teachers to keep up. If a new school is constructed, the state will pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82 percent</NUMEX> of the cost. You can't beat a deal like that.
I urge you to vote "yes" and "yes" on both issues.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Greenhalgh</ENAMEX>, former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> board member
</P> 
<P ID="4">Seeking all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds pointless
I appreciated the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 8</TIMEX> article covering the City Council’s confusion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel’s</ENAMEX> participation on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LYVREC Board</ENAMEX>. I was appointed by the mayor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> to be a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX> and was elected vice-president. I want to assure the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> community and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> that Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> did represent the Council’s proposal for all of the remaining funds. She brought the matter to the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX> at the next meeting, right after it was requested of her to do so.
What the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> does not seem to understand is that it has no authority to control those funds, but merely to have representation for the benefit of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> communities. This seems particularly curious since Councilman John Torch is a former member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX>.
The funds came from a federal grant and are disbursed through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> for the benefit of the two tracts which include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Of the large grant that was originally made available, only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> is remaining. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> is also trying to get back money that was allocated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for the neighborhood outreach program, which cannot be done.
The expectation for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Angel</ENAMEX> to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> meeting and demand all the remaining funds is pointless. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX> is legally accountable to the county and the federal government for appropriate and fair disbursement of the funds. Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> is one member among several, from both cities, who have worked together to establish a criteria by which many organizations can compete for funds through the grant system.  
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunnyview Skate Park</ENAMEX> is a viable project, as are the other six proposals that are under consideration.  It’s too bad that there is not more money to cover all of the requests. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX> is doing a very careful job deciding how to fairly distribute the available funds.    
/s/ Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Henry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pastor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Methodist Church</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Time</ENAMEX> for a new S’side newspaper?
Bob Story’s policy of “front page editorials,” where he unethically presents his opinion in hopes that it will be conceived by the public as fact, has unfortunately left the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with no credible local source of information regarding our local politics. (He does not live in the city and rarely attends council meetings. Where does he derive his information and opinions.)
Some issues that are very important to the decision-making process of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters are misrepresented in his paper due to his unethical, journalistic tactics of attempting to MAKE the news rather than report it. A recent example is his year-ending, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12-31-2003</TIMEX> headline, “Alderwood councilman insists she wants to unite community.”  This article about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> should have been a letter to the editor. But, Story once again gave preferential coverage on the front page to promote his personal agenda. It appears that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> is beginning to campaign early in the election year early and providing expensive space to their chosen candidate.
Strategically, his articles falsely erode the efforts of many of our elected persons who have contributed greatly to our community and conducted the business of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to promote the community in an effort to dig this community out of a hole created by 15 years of “special interest politics” during the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Fancy</ENAMEX> regime.  The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> waged a similar undermining campaign against the outstanding efforts of, then councilman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Werkhoven</ENAMEX>. Those who know of Werkhoven’s commitment to integrity and work ethic, watched in dismay as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> savagely and unjustly painted him as a racist to provide an unfair advantage to his opponent. Similar to Story, most of the community voters do not attend council meetings and have only the front-page opinions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> for information, or misinformation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> is a consistent bright spot in this dark-sided-news reporting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Press</ENAMEX>, owner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>, is located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> The owners are far removed from emotional or ethical responsibility for the activities of their satellite newspapers. Story’s front page editorializing must reflect the policy of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagle Press</ENAMEX> or they would be more prudent about monitoring such violations of journalistic etiquette. As we begin to search for a city manager to fill the big boots of stalwart <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>, maybe it is also time to solicit individuals who would be willing to invest in a news media of accurate reporting, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Osland</ENAMEX> did more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX> when he created the seed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> with a paper consisting of one legal-sized sheet of colored copy paper.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James E. Stevens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DMD</ENAMEX>, Past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Councilman
(Publisher's note: The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> is a part of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press, Inc.</ENAMEX>, a group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> community newspapers based in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore. Contact</ENAMEX> information: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press, Inc.</ENAMEX>; P.O. Box 12008; 4901 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Indian School Rd.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> 97305; 1503-373-1774; President, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James O. Wells</ENAMEX>)
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Becomingan</ENAMEX> American
President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore Roosevelt</ENAMEX> gave an answer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890</TIMEX> in an address before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holland Society of New York</ENAMEX> that I would like to share here:
"We of the Holland blood of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX> have just cause to be proud of the men of note in American history who have come from among us...(but) the point on which I wish to insist is, that the Hollanders could never have played such a part, could never have won honorable renown by doing their full share in shaping the destiny of the republic, had they remained Hollanders instead of becoming Americans...Had they remained aliens in speech and habit of thought. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuyler</ENAMEX> would have been a mere boorish provincial squire instead of a major general in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Revolutionary Army</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Buren</ENAMEX> would have been a country tavern keeper instead of the President of the mightiest republic the world has ever seen, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vanderbilt</ENAMEX> would have remained an unknown boatman instead of becoming one of the most potent architects of the marvelous American industrial fabric."
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Timmermans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

