36 30 39 44 13 21
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  There are people who strictly deprive themselves of each and every eatable, drinkable, and smokable which has in any way acquired a shady reputation. They pay this price for health. And health is all they get for it. How strange it is. It is like paying out your whole fortune for a cow that has gone dry.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Twain</ENAMEX> (1835 - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>