
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">One thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vidi Pasillas</ENAMEX> prides herself in is being able to see the bright side of people. There is one person in particular who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> sees as a shining star, and that is her younger brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX>, who has down syndrome.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> is hoping to see the bright sides of many new people as a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>, 17, who will be a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, is one of eight young ladies looking to represent the community as the 2004-05 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The annual pageant will be held in conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Sunshine Days <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> is a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, having lived in the community her entire life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> credits the strong women in her life with helping her become the person she is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> has particular praise for her mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Rangel</ENAMEX>, and her grandmother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena Zuazo</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> is being sponsored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s pageant by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blueline</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Les Schwab Tire Center</ENAMEX>.   At high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> stays very active. She is involved with Link Crew, which is a group of older students who help incoming freshmen make the transition to the high school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> is also involved with the leadership class and the Leaders in Action program. Her other school activities include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX>, cheerleading and fastpitch softball.   Outside of school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> has volunteered at the Just Like Home retirement center and the local food bank. Another of her loves is working with the Special Olympics program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> became involved with Special Olympics through her brother. After high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> wants to attend college to study to become a special education teacher.   "He (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX>) inspired me to go in that line of work," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.   When working with Special Olympics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said she is at her happiest because she feels she is making a difference.   "I think it is really fun," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>. "They (Special Olympics members) are just funny. They are very honest."   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> will mark the third season <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> has been involved with cheerleading.   "It (cheerleading) was kind of like a little girls' dream," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> explained she's had a desire to be a cheerleader since she was a little girl. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> acted on that dream when she was a sophomore.   "I tried out and I was so nervous," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.   Another of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>' loves is the sport of fastpitch softball. She has been playing softball since she was in middle school.   "When I was in middle school I was kind of the quiet kid," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.   She said none of the other sports such as basketball or volleyball appealed to her much.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> recently found her niche at the prep level on the mound this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past summer</TIMEX>, where she developed into one of the premiere arms for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>.   But being involved with family and friends is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> treasures most. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said she looks up to her mom and brother. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said she admires her mom for being a single parent, but always finding time to still support her children.   "She is going back to school (college)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>. "I am real proud of her."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said her brother also taught her an important lesson about life.   "My brother has taught me not to be judgmental about people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.   Why run for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>?   "I think it is a great opportunity for any young lady to experience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said if she is named to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court she wants to inspire young children. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said she would love to serve as a role model for young girls, inspiring them to compete for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> when they are older.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said she has great respect for the role the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> serves in the community.   "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court members) are making the community a better place," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> did admit she was a bit reluctant at first to vie for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> title.   "I wasn't sure if I would have the time to do it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>. "But then I thought, you only live once, you might as well do it to the best of your abilities."   What <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> enjoys about the community is the people and the diversity.   "Everyone is really friendly," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>. "We are able to get to know each other."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> has several projects she wants to work on if appointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>. Her featured community service project will be working with the Special Olympics organization. She would also like to start a project through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Veterans of Foreign Wars post, sending letters from the community to troops serving abroad.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said she would be honored to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>.   "I would be so excited," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>. "I would be very honored because it is something I have worked so hard for."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX> said being involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant, at the very least, she is hoping to develop friendships and treasured memories.   "It is something to think about when you are 80," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasillas</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

