
<P ID="1">Ten hopefuls vie for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco De Mayo</ENAMEX> crown
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Ten <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> teenage girls will vie for the right to wear the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> crown at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo Pageant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 23</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.   "Corazon Latina" (Latin Heart) is the theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s pageant, which has attracted young Hispanic girls from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, Outlook and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Maya</ENAMEX>, pageant committee chairman.   He said tickets to the pageant, which will showcase the candidates' poise, confidence and physical fitness, are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> per person. Tickets are available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> office, or at the door the night of the pageant.   He said the candidates have spent the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past month</TIMEX> learning what will be expected of them as members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cinco de Mayo Court</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this month</TIMEX>, the young women sponsored a beef industry rally in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as a fund-raiser, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX> said, as an opportunity to get the candidates ready for the public spotlight.   The court, which will include a queen and a princess, will participate in its first official community event at the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> celebration to be held in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 7</TIMEX>, 8, 9, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX> said.   Among the 10 young candidates vying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> crown is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Alvarez</ENAMEX>, 17, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalia Alvarez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, she is a one of four children. A student at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> is active as a member of the high school <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grizzliettes</ENAMEX> dance/drill team. In addition, she regularly volunteers to read to younger children at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> hopes to one day attend college.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth L. Cervantes</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Cervantes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, is a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School</ENAMEX>. The 17-year-old girl describes herself as an outgoing and friendly person, who is a member of the school cheerleader squad during football and basketball seasons. She enjoys music and dancing, and hopes to major in fashion design or business following high school graduation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anabel Diaz</ENAMEX>, 15, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Roberto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maricela Diaz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. A sophomore at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, she enjoys singing and is learning to play piano. She is active in her church and youth group. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> said even though she finds school work hard, she hopes to attend college and major in computer science.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Gonzalez</ENAMEX> is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Carmelo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gomez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. She is a junior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX>, where she is active in drill and dance team. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> loves dancing so much. she hopes to make it a career. One of four children, she hopes to one day go to dance or modeling school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidate Yesenia Jalifi</ENAMEX>, 16, dreams of a career in education, but first she'd like to be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> student is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfredo and Linda Jalifi</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. A volunteer at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX>, she spends her spare time baby-sitting and spending time with her four older brothers and sisters and friends.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidate Maria Elena Macias</ENAMEX>, 18, of Outlook is a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. A student in the high school's nursing assistant program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macias</ENAMEX> hopes to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> to study nursing. One of five children, she is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isidro and Margarita Macias</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidate Rosie Moran</ENAMEX> hopes to attend college in order to major in early childhood education upon graduation from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. The 17-year-old is active in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grizzliettes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clubs TATU</ENAMEX> and SADD, as well as being the senior class treasurer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX> is also the dance team treasurer. In addition to her school work, she holds a part-time job at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Taco Bell. She is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicente Moran</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidate Iris Ruiz</ENAMEX>, 17, is a student at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, where she is a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Honor Society</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club SADD</ENAMEX> and her school's chapter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Future Business</ENAMEX> Leaders of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruiz</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Ruiz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leticia Chavez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is also a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Explorers Post</ENAMEX>. Her association with the police scouting group has encouraged her to study criminal forensics at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidate Maribel Sanchez</ENAMEX>, 16, is a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> student, who enjoys styling hair. One of six children, she is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Sanchez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said she hopes to go to college, but hasn't yet chosen a career course.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathya Quijano</ENAMEX>, 17, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> is the final candidate for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> title. A student at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, she is a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Link Crew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MeCha</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club SADD</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quijano</ENAMEX> is a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grizzliettes</ENAMEX> and plays high school softball. She is also a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> school teacher at her church. One of three children, she is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Lopez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quijano</ENAMEX> hopes to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> to study architecture.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

