


<P ID="1">Another public defender may be added to judicial budget
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">One of the discussion items before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at its budget study session was the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> judicial budget for the municipal court system.
</P><P ID="5">   The proposed judicial budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$239,940</NUMEX>, a slight increase from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$229,140</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The largest expenditure in the judicial budget is for salaries and wages, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$106,810</NUMEX>. This is up slightly from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$106,150</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Salary increases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> are set to be minimal, but the area for personal benefits saw a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,200</NUMEX> increase (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42,740</NUMEX>) from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Finance Director Chad Stotz</ENAMEX> said the reason for the difference between the salary increase and personal benefits is that the city will incur extra costs for such benefits as medical and retirement.
</P><P ID="8">   Another significant line item in the judicial budget is under other services and charges, which as proposed will total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$74,990</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> said this money goes towards paying the retainer the city has for its public defender and prosecutor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he will bring back at a future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting a discussion to hire an additional public defender at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,200</NUMEX> per month. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> wants to use the money the city will receive from the 3/10's of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> sales tax increase <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> voters recently approved for the new position.
</P><P ID="9">   The budget proposal also includes a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> pay increase for the city's municipal court judge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Stitler</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the pay increase will help align <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stitler</ENAMEX>' salary with that of other judges in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   Councilman John Torch recommended the city increase its fee structure for fines to help bring in additional revenue.
</P>





 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




