


<P ID="1">Open Mike
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">I was going to write about all of the gruesome things I have read about pregnancy and why women would want to go through such a process. But instead I am opting to write about another such painful process, but with not quite as a rewarding outcome-the presidential election.
</P><P ID="5">   This coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> we will once again go to the polls to decide many races, most notably the presidency. It was such fun last time with the ever-thrilling, blow-by-blow moment of the heated contest between George Bush and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>. That election taught us one important thing that will make us all better citizens-never leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chad</ENAMEX> hanging. Who didn't enjoy MSNBC's blow-by-blow account of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> recount. I broke out the popcorn and the pop for that one. Honestly, the recount was stupid in concept, but weren't you just glued to your television set?
</P><P ID="6">   I personally liked having Bill Clinton in office. Come on, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> may be an ignorant son of a gun, but wasn't it fun with him in office? We didn't have any of the major issues we have going on now when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> was running things. Sure, he made a few mistakes, but having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> in office was sort of like watching an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MTV</ENAMEX> reality show, you never knew what was going to happen next. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> was a good guy. People had jobs, money in their pocket and lived a decent life.
</P><P ID="7">   The problem with politics is there are too many politicians. Nothing ever gets done. Politicians can never live up to their baby-kissing promises because there are too many of them to reach a consensus.
</P><P ID="8">   I am not a Republican or a Democrat. But, I always vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX>, who is a Republican, because I feel he can get the job done. The problem with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX> is that he has to run every two years for re-election, which takes his focus off what can be done. I will admit I made a mistake voting for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic</ENAMEX> Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> worked four years for the state and then decided to go on vacation the next four. I vote for whomever I feel can get the job done. The problem <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this November</TIMEX> is I am not sure who can get the job done.
</P><P ID="9">   This presidential election we have Democratic front runner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>, who my kids know an awful frightening lot about, and President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. I believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> is also thrown into the mix as an independent candidate.
</P><P ID="10">   Let's take a look at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> for a moment. He is sort of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Munster</ENAMEX> looking individual who can't seem to find his way out of a wet sack. I really don't know that much about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>, except I would rather vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Clinton</ENAMEX> than him. Why not give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> a chance? Could she really do any worse? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> really needs to find his own issues to stand on rather then just picking apart the president. All of us can join the fray to beat a man down. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> seems like he lives in a black and white world, sort of like the Munster TV episodes.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is a little harder for me to judge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had a good idea when he wanted to give people back the money they work hard for. Also, no one can hold the president accountable for what happened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>. Who would have ever thought that would take place? The problem I have with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is that he just never really answers a question. And quite honestly, the country is not a better place since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> took office.
</P><P ID="12">   I don't know who I am going to vote for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this November</TIMEX>. Heck, I might vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nader</ENAMEX>. I might vote for no one. Better yet, I might vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bill</ENAMEX>. Life was good, fun and interesting when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> was the leader of the free world. Wouldn't you like those times back?
</P><P ID="13">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




