
<P ID="1">Story Time
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dear Santa</ENAMEX>, once again, I've procrastinated and haven't yet got off my annual letter to you in the mail. Realizing that it won't reach you by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> Day</TIMEX>, I'm hoping that you are a regular reader of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and will see it here.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santa</ENAMEX>, I wish I could tell you I had a big list of things I'd like you to bring me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Christmas</TIMEX>. But in all reality, there's really not much I want or need. I'm hoping for a pair of new bowling shoes, but you shouldn't worry about that. I think my wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>, picked up on a few pre-Christmas hints I dropped about the shoes and will be taking care of that wish.   Since there's really nothing I want you to bring me <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Christmas</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santa</ENAMEX>, maybe you could take care of a few people on my gift list. Any help you can give in filling my wish list would be appreciated. Here goes:   ? Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones-an</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> approval rating on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>'s bond and levy issues. Should be a cinch since <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents won't be offered such a great deal for years to come.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara-smooth</ENAMEX> sailing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>. And, elected officials in that resort community who don't like micro-managing the day-to-day affairs of the city.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Urrutia-a</ENAMEX> varsity boys basketball schedule that allows him to attend all of his daughter's games.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Anciso-an</ENAMEX> appropriate thank you from the community for the 20 or so years he served <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, showing a sense of fair play for all who live here.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Brown-ditto</ENAMEX>!   ? Lance Den Boer-a red shirt. Fifth year seniors can pack a mean punch.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lathen-a</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> three-bagger.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bender-next</ENAMEX> year a finish that's one step above where he placed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">this year</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington PGA Pro-Am Series</ENAMEX> points standings.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Galbraith-at</ENAMEX> least one round in the 60's, please!   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Greenway-the</ENAMEX> insight to realize that people don't need to attend city council meetings to have an opinion on what the city should spend its money on, just as people don't need to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> to have an opinion on whether or not American troops should be there.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Wagenaar-a</ENAMEX> referee who's not afraid to blow his whistle in the closing moments of a game.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Schlieve-100</ENAMEX> people who want to purchase a bronze plaque at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s War Veterans Memorial. They're a great deal for those who want to memorialize the veterans in their families.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Doak-the</ENAMEX> savvy to take on the lead role in landing the new county jail in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, after county commissioners have it drilled into them that there is too much opposition for the facility to be built at the fairgrounds in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">John Torch-a</ENAMEX> state grant that would give every merchant in town enough money to build a carbon copy replica of the train depot he had renovated. Heck, even enough money to put up a white picket fence around each new business.   ? Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse-a</ENAMEX> second year in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> that reflects the statesmanship and dignity he displayed there in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, making all 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> voters proud that he was their choice.   ? Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford-the</ENAMEX> strength to continue fighting for and representing the business and farming interests of the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor-a</ENAMEX> dinner invitation from the mayor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>. My favorite uncle lays out a mean party spread.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan White-a</ENAMEX> copy of my checkbook register, showing that nearly all of my money is spent in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peyton Manning-a</ENAMEX> five-touchdown performance at Houston <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX>. I need it to have a shot at winning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fantasy League</ENAMEX>.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Seeger-a</ENAMEX> gavel and a black robe. He may as well look the part.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel-a</ENAMEX> steel fortress. I do believe she's under attack.   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Migrant Council-the</ENAMEX> understanding that they're not going to please everyone in town with the way they operate the new community center. They should just strive to make the center as accessible to as many people as possible.   ? To all my golfing buddies-the generosity to give me an additional two strokes every round. My game's getting worse and I need the extra help.   If I've left anybody off my wish list that's deserving, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santa</ENAMEX>, could you please extend my apologies. By the same token, could you send an apology to those who might not have wanted to make my list.   Signing off until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby      P.S</ENAMEX>. The milk and cookies can be found where I always leave them      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

