


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Apology from car show organizers
</P>

<P ID="5">We would like to take this opportunity to sincerely apologize to all who attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Tejano Music Association</ENAMEX>'s car show on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 5</TIMEX>, for the language used in some of the performances on stage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Tejano Music Association</ENAMEX> takes full and complete responsibility for what transpired.
</P>

<P ID="6">There were some performers who traveled a long distance, donating their time and talent to perform. We would like to thank all of our volunteers who gave their time and effort. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Tejano Music Association</ENAMEX> is founded on the premise of encouraging and continuing the exposure of young people to Tejano and other types of music. In future events, we want to personally ensure that performances and/or entertainment will be geared towards our goal and mission.
</P>

<P ID="7">Again, please accept our apologies. If you have any additional concerns or recommendations, feel free to call us at (509) 882-5050 or 837-2236.
</P>

<P ID="8">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florentino Patina</ENAMEX>, President, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Tejano Music Association</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="9">Local librarian appreciates help
</P>

<P ID="10">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> branch library finished another wonderful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> reading program, and would like to thank everyone who helped us Discover New Trails at their library <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, and then helped us celebrate at our Trail's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">End Party</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="11">We first want to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s excellent readers of all ages for joining in the fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. More adult readers signed up than ever before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. We also had a wonderful group of very small library patrons whose big brothers and sisters read to them so that they both could earn reading prizes. And, our thanks go, of course, to all the ages in between who read everyday and collected their rewards.
</P>

<P ID="12">We want to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s Drive-In for generously giving out ice cream cones to all our young readers who finished a whole discovery trail. Our prize winners' gratitude increased as temperatures rose. Thank you very much, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Johnson</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s Market, through its manager, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Aguayo</ENAMEX>, provided delicious munchies for our end-of-summer celebration, as they have every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. Their backing makes our parties possible. We truly appreciate the support of The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s Market.
</P>

<P ID="14">We want to give special thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Nettleton</ENAMEX>, who brought us an adorable miniature donkey and a "lordly llama" for our petting zoo. Our young readers were overwhelmed at their chance to touch animals they had only seen in books. We are very grateful for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill</ENAMEX>'s help.
</P>

<P ID="15">Thank you, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>. You are the best! You have listed our events in your calendars, promoted our programs and celebrated our special occasions. Thank you very much. Your assistance helps make our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> programs a pleasure to offer to our favorite town.
</P>

<P ID="16">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay C. Saunders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> branch librarian
</P>

 


<P ID="17">Register to vote
</P>

<P ID="18">We live in a country built on freedom, liberty and rights. I have been out in my community going door-to-door to register voters. I believe that all persons who are 18 and citizens of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USA</ENAMEX> should be registered. If they then choose to not vote, to go along with what others decide for them, then so be it.
</P>

<P ID="19">I have been able to meet super people in my community, and encourage more participation in decision-making in the process.
</P>

<P ID="20">I do have one concern and thought to share with everyone. I think that anyone who works for and gets paid with taxpayers' money should be registered voters, whether they work for cities, school or port districts, counties, state or the federal government. It takes so little time or effort to be registered and you can even vote by absentee ballot from your home. Please everyone, register to vote, and vote!
</P>

<P ID="21">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




