
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls coach taking his game to a different level
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/4/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - As the head coach of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> girls basketball team, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Simpson</ENAMEX> didn't win a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> title. He didn't win any league titles. In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> didn't post a winning league season until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last year</TIMEX>, his fifth as coach of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> may not have won a championship, but in many ways he did something so much more important than that-he brought life back into what was a dying program and reinstilled pride in Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viking</ENAMEX> basketball.   But now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>, 31, is ready to tackle a new frontier. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> will be leaving his position as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls basketball coach and teacher at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> junior high school at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> and his family are moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX>, where he will be assistant principal at the kindergarten through 12th grade school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> is a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>. After earning his Bachelor's degree in education from what is now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Oregon University</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, where he also played baseball for four years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> found a job interestingly enough in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX>. He taught in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX> for three years, but ended up a victim of budget cuts.   But it was at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX> where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> met his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alli</ENAMEX>. While in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> coached the junior high school boys basketball program and was an assistant coach for the high school junior varsity boys basketball and baseball programs, all in his first year. His second year in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> took on the job of assistant high school football coach.   "I was a single man, I had a lot of free time," joked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>.   It was in his third year at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> and his future wife started to get to know one another. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> was the coach of the junior high school boys basketball program and his wife was coach of the girls program.   "She was in charge of controlling the kids on the bus," recounted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>. "I drove the bus."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> remembered with a slight grin about how the two used to keep one another's stat books and go to the local Texaco for a date after the game.   After leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> decided it was time to come back home to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. He was hired as a sixth grade teacher. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> moved to the junior-senior high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, where he has worked ever since.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> earned his administrative credentials <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University Tri-Cities</ENAMEX> campus. As part of his credentials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> had to go through 720 hours of administrative work, which he had to fill in around teaching, coaching and his family.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> was hired by then assistant principal/athletic director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey Gant</ENAMEX> to resurrect the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls basketball program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> and his wife took over the reigns of the program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s first year saw the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> go 0-20 in the 1A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Central Athletic Conference</ENAMEX>, but the team kept making small improvements each game. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> marked a milestone for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> program. In one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s two most memorable games, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> ended a 31-game losing streak with a victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wahluke</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dropped down to the Greater Columbia 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>, where the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> finished the last couple years with 8-12 records. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> had their first winning league season in a while <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>, going 7-6.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>, though, play in one of the toughest girls 'B' basketball divisions in the state with the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian, Riverside Christian and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaSalle</ENAMEX>.   It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>'s last game that proved to be his most memorable. In what can be easily termed a classic, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian girls basketball team survived <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> on their home court. But it wasn't the actual game that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> remembers most, but rather what happened afterwards, that still sticks with him and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">players-the</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> finally got their respect.   "They stood up and gave us a standing ovation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> of the crowd that filled the gym at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian. "That meant so much to me and the girls. That meant a lot for me for those girls to hear that."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said he walked into the locker room and his players were amazed that the crowd reacted like that to them after so many years of being told that they were a horrible team.   "They applauded for us at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX>," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>. "I will always have that."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said he never thought about leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> until he was approached by people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX> after the basketball season to take the administrative job.   "I honestly thought I was going to be back coaching basketball <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said he is taking the opportunity in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Curlew</ENAMEX> because people don't receive many chances like this one.   One of the things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> hopes he left his players and students with is certain life lessons and the power to believe in themselves.   "You can do whatever you want to as long as you believe it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>. "The mind is a powerful tool."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said he was driven to stay with coaching even through all of the less than stellar years in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> remembers playing for then <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> boys basketball coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Affholter</ENAMEX> and all of the success <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> had under him.   "I wanted these girls to have that same success," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said his players taught him a lot about being able to care about your team and the ability to learn to take small steps when times are tough.   The foundation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls basketball program has hopefully been put into place, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said whomever they hire to replace him ought to be able to come in and experience success.   "If I have done a good job here of laying the foundation for these kids, they should be successful. I am excited for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to see if I left something for these girls," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>.   His advice for a coach who is heading a struggling program is to stick with it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> has etched in his mind a famous quote on a poster of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Jordan</ENAMEX>'s when he played for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bulls</ENAMEX> that he always keeps in mind.   "I've missed more than 9,000 shots in my career," the poster reads. "I've lost almost 300 games. 26 times, I've been trusted to take the game-winning shot and missed. I'VE FAILED over and over and over again in my life. And that is why I SUCCEEDED!"   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX>, I looked at myself as a failure because we weren't winning," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX>. "In all those failings I think to some degree I have succeeded."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

