


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> continues pressuring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to open collective bargaining meetings to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/8/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> brought back an old issue at the beginning of the new year during this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> brought before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> an item he lobbied for extensively in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, namely making everything but the initial strategy session in collective bargaining meetings open to the public.
</P><P ID="6">   At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> officially re-introduced the item for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> consideration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> tried unsuccessfully once <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to get collective bargaining meetings held in the open. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> reintroduced the idea at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting with two new councilman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sarducci</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, aboard. The item will be before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> for consideration and possible approval at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Jan. 19</TIMEX>, meeting.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> provided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with some information on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s proposal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said what the councilman is proposing would create a new section to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s rules of procedure.
</P><P ID="8">   If approved, the new section would state that all discussions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> concerning collective bargaining shall be held in public with the exception of the initial strategy session. "Generally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> strategy for collective bargaining shall be directed to analysis and direction of total costs of proposed employee wages and benefits and proposed policy determinations that may impact and could be applicable to other bargaining units of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>," the new section further states. "Any proposed modification of the established strategy for any bargaining unit will be discussed in executive session prior to the consideration of adoption in open session."
</P><P ID="9">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> said that with the wording of the resolution, if passed, there would be a lot of emphasis by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the initial strategy session.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> asked to delay discussion on his proposal until it was presented for a vote on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 19</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> has been advocating for the past few months on making the collective bargaining process public because he, as stated at past meetings, believes the process will bankrupt cities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> has also stated that he feels the citizens have every right to know where their money is being spent.
</P><P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




