
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Simms</ENAMEX> to open Community Concert Series
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Simms</ENAMEX>, the first performer in the 2004-05 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Community Concert Series, will be singing African American spirituals, as well as Broadway show stoppers on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 4</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simms</ENAMEX>, a Gold Medal winner of the Enmark American Traditions Competition, has been hailed by critics for his "rich luxuriant tone," "energetic performances" and "convincing stage presence." He has performed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Smithsonian Institute</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles African-American Museum</ENAMEX>, Grace Cathedral in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Historical Institute</ENAMEX>, and at many colleges and universities throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   Season tickets for the 2004-05 Community Concert Series, hosted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Concert Association</ENAMEX>, will be available at the door.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s series includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells & Adams</ENAMEX>, a cello and guitar duet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 16, 2005</TIMEX>; Westwind Brass, a brass quintet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 28, 2005</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alpin Hong</ENAMEX>, pianist, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22</TIMEX>; and Baroque Northwest, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16</TIMEX>.   Season adult tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX>, student tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> and family tickets (two adults, two students) are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85</NUMEX>. One night performance tickets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simms</ENAMEX> concert are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> each.   The doors will open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, 30 minutes prior to the concert.   For further information about this concert or the 2004-05 series, call 786-3070 or 837-7054.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

