
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate: arts and crafts buff has plenty to smile about
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">It is rare you'll ever see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Martinez</ENAMEX> without a smile on her face. There is good reason because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> has plenty to be happy about these days. She has a spot she loves on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> cheerleading squad, she is involved with numerous school activities and taking up most of her time recently has been the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, 16, is one of eight young ladies vying for the title of 2004-05 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The annual pageant will be staged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>. The pageant will be held in conjunction with the community's Sunshine Days festivities.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, a life-long resident of the area, will be a junior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. She is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MaryAnn and Joel Martinez</ENAMEX>. She is being sponsored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Valle Restaurant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raquel</ENAMEX>'s Hair Botique.   For the past couple of years cheerleading has been at the forefront for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. She recounted how she had wanted be a cheerleader ever since she was a little girl. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said she can remember going to cheerleading camps as a little girl and always looking up to the older cheerleaders, wanting to be like them. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> marks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>'s second season on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> cheerleading squad.   "It is great," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "Being in front of the entire school you kind of get pumped. If you are pumped up, they (the crowd) are pumped."   In addition to cheerleading, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> is involved with the high school Distributive Education Clubs of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> and the Link Crew, which helps incoming freshmen make the transition from middle school to the high school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> is also an honors biology student.   Dancing is another hobby of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>'s. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> enrolled in jazz dance classes to help prepare her for the talent showcase at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant.   "I like it a lot," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   When she does have spare time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> keeps herself busy with arts and crafts projects. She has been creating different arts and crafts projects since the sixth grade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> found the fun side of arts and crafts when campaigning for a middle school class office. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> explained she utilized some arts and crafts projects for her campaign signs and her love of the hobby just took off from there.   "I have all kinds of things in my room," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "You never get bored with it."   The most difficult crafts project <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> has started is a photo album. Smiling, she said it was hard for her to get it to look like she wanted.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> has long had a desire to represent the community on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said when she was younger she ran for the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "It was a good experience," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said.   Her longing to compete for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> title grew in many ways, from when she ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Little</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. She views her current quest as a valuable growing experience.   Preparing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant has been an interesting experience, so far, she said.   One of the major perks of being involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> program, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, is that it helps teach you about maturity and how to be a more responsible person.   "I am hoping I will grow a little bit more," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   Being a lifelong resident of the area, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said she has always enjoyed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "I like the people," she said. "They are really friendly. They are giving and they do want to help you."   If rewarded with a spot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> would like to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> her community service project.   "I would want to work more with the little kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "That is where it all starts when you are little. It (the parks department) keeps you out of trouble."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said she can remember as a small child having her interests piqued in cheerleading through the camps the parks and recreation department organized.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> describes herself as someone who is determined, funny and enjoys being involved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said she would like to take all of those attributes and put them to use if she was named to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court.   "I would want to be a good role model," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "If (young children) see me as that way they would want to be like that."   After high school, Martinez plans to attend college to study to become a teacher.   "I picked education because I like to teach," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> is named to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court, she sees it as a dream come true, knowing all of her hard work paid off.   "I would see it as a privilege," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is not just something that is given to you."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

