
<P ID="1">Rough night for Grizzly JV
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Simply put, it was a rough night for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> junior varsity football team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>.   The Grizzlies hosted <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s junior varsity squad and the Falcons snatched a commanding 40-14 victory.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Sambrano</ENAMEX> was roughed up a bit by the Falcons' defense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sambrano</ENAMEX> completed 8-of-20 passes for 99 yards but served up three interceptions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sambrano</ENAMEX> also had six carries for 17 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sambrano</ENAMEX> did rush for a touchdown.   Grizzly running back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Peters</ENAMEX> had a decent game on the ground, tallying 95 yards on 18 carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peters</ENAMEX> also had one reception for 10 yards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Bonesman</ENAMEX> had the Grizzlies' other touchdown. He also had four catches for 51 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Dolan</ENAMEX> had two catches for 18 yards for the Grizzlies.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevor Fernandez</ENAMEX> kicked both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s extra points.   The Grizzly JV will hit the road for its next game on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 18</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

