


<P ID="1">Canadian visitors to tour <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">MABTON - Three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX> city mayors will be making a stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> as part of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> tour. The mayors are on a goodwill tour, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   The tour was set up following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX> discovery of a case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> on a local dairy in the small community.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said he had been contacted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the northern delegation, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> also suffered international scrutiny when a case of the fatal cattle disease was discovered in their providence.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said the mayors will be making similar visits in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb. 4</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "They will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> at city hall at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said.
</P>   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




