
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s 'O' line subdues <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manson</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - The story of the game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>' offensive line.   The not so big, but very young and physical offensive line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> had its way with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manson</ENAMEX>, sparking the Vikes to a 27-0 whitewashing of the visitors.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> victory upped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s conference record to 3-2, 4-2 overall.   "Our offensive line played well all night," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Coach D.J</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "We're young on the line, only one senior, but they're physical and very fast. They were opening some huge holes for our rushing attack."   The linemen in question include senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Magana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underclassmen Robert Marquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Monciviaz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Balli</ENAMEX>, Vicente Tovar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Magana</ENAMEX> and tight end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moises Gutierrez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said most of the credit for the 249 yards his club gained on the ground goes to his linemen.   "What a job they did," he said.   Of course, someone had to blast through the holes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>'s offensive linemen were creating. That task went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pablo Sanchez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Zavala</ENAMEX>, who combined for 209 rushing yards and between them scored all four of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s touchdowns.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>, who gained a game best 142 yards on 11 carries, scored the first TD of the game on a 35-yard burst.   "It was a simple lead play," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>, explaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> followed two running backs and hit the hole his offensive linemen created.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> also had a first quarter TD run for the Vikes, capping off a short drive with an 18-yard scamper that came on a counter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Zepeda</ENAMEX> hit one of two extra point kicks on the two first quarter touchdowns to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> a 13-0 lead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> added a 91-yard breakaway TD run in the second quarter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manson</ENAMEX>, on the previous play, went for it on a 4th-and-1 play from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s 9-yard line. Unable to convert, though, the Vikes took over possession of the ball. On the very next call, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> found daylight and outraced everyone to the end zone.   "It was another counter," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "Our offensive linemen had people on the ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pablo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>) found an opening and just outran everyone."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> pitched the ball to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> on the ensuing 2-point conversion and he bounced into the end zone to up the Vikes' lead to 21-0.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> put an insurance TD on the scoreboard in the third quarter, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> capped off a long drive with a 4-yard TD run.   For the most part, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> kept the ball on the ground against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">QB Ryan Harris</ENAMEX>, a senior, did air it out seven times, connecting on five of the passes for a total of 62 yards. It was the second straight week <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> wasn't intercepted.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> went 11-for-16 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and then had a 5-for-7 night <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "Not bad passing numbers at all."   In looking ahead to this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pateros</ENAMEX>, located near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> may throw the ball a bit more than they did against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manson</ENAMEX>.   "We know <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pateros</ENAMEX> jams the defensive line with 10 guys," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said. "So you may see us throwing the ball more.   "On offensive, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pateros</ENAMEX> likes to spread the field on offense. We'll have to play good assignment football to shut them down.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paterson</ENAMEX> is tied for first in our league with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX>. It's a game we need to win," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

