
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood Railroad</ENAMEX> helps make Harvest Fest bigger, better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PARKDALE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood Railroad</ENAMEX> will celebrate Hood Rid (786-2163).ival Weekend by holding an outdoor fine arts and musical festival in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Parkdale</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 16-17</TIMEX>, event will be free to the public, and will feature more than 25 local and regional artists, as well as live music throughout both days.
Harvest Festival Weekend celebrates the bounty of the season.
The event in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Parkdale</ENAMEX> offers a variety of activities, as well as an opportunity to purchase fresh produce with majestic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood</ENAMEX> as the backdrop. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Parkdale</ENAMEX> is located 16 miles from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cooper Spur Road</ENAMEX>, approximately three miles off of Hwy. 35. The event will be held in the town's park.
For visitors wishing to view the fall colors throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood River Valley</ENAMEX> by rail, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood Railroad</ENAMEX> excursion train will depart <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood River</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> both days.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Pioneer eventon tap <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kittitas County Historical Museum</ENAMEX> will host its second annual “Who Wants to be a Pioneer?” event on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31</TIMEX> and again on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 21</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> at the historic Cadwell Building in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.
“Who Wants to be a Pioneer?” offers families numerous opportunities to relax together in a fun and educational environment. Adults and children alike can learn about the rich history of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kittitas Valley</ENAMEX> through fun, hands-on activities.
Activities at the event will include, but are not limited to: candle making, flower pressing, butter churning, ice cream making and various live demonstrations and other historically valuable trades used by the pioneers.
For more information contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin Black</ENAMEX>, museum curator, at (509) 925 3778 or kchm@elltel.net
</P> 
<P ID="5">Kiwanis pioneer picnic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNION GAP</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s Kiwanis pioneer picnic, expected to draw about 700 senior citizens, will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Aug. 18</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ahtanum Park</ENAMEX>.
There is no cost to those over the age of 60. Guests under 60 years old will be assessed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.50</NUMEX> fee to attend the picnic.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s menu includes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ</ENAMEX> chicken, potato salad, baked beans, fresh tomatoes, rolls, watermelon, milk and soft drinks.
Organizers say those who attend will not only enjoy a fine feast, but will be treated to live entertainment and have the opportunity to visit friends they haven't seen for years, as well.
The Kiwanis pioneer picnic is being sponsored by several Upper Yakima Valley Kiwanis clubs, as well as by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Parks Department</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima City Parks Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Department of Food Services</ENAMEX>.
Attendance is limited, so reservations are required and will be accepted beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1</TIMEX> (1-800-572-7354, ext. 2200).
</P> 
<P ID="6">‘Rose' Renaissance’ wine tasting, dinner set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vintner's Inn Restaurant</ENAMEX> will be the site of the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima Valley Rose</ENAMEX>' Renaissance" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
The event will start off with a 'meet the makers' tasting, where guests will sample Roses' made by five of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s premier <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX>' producers, along with matching hors d'oeuvres.
"When I started in the wine business in the early 70's, Roses' were very popular wines, accounting for 25 to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> of all wines sold," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Wallace</ENAMEX>, Hinzerling's winemaker and proprietor.
"Most of the ones being made those days were from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and were fruity, sweet and on the light side," he explained.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> said Mateus and Lancers were probably the most well known. But after a decade or so, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX>, the Roses' began losing ground to light red and white wines, "...like those we produced here in the 80's and to some extent were replaced by blush wines.
"In recent years, a number of winemakers here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> have been making some really fine drier style Roses' from all kinds of grape varieties," he continued. "With lots of the fruity and spicy wine flavors our area is so well known for, these wines are well suited to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> foods, especially barbecue and grilled items."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace</ENAMEX> said after tasting a number of them over the last few years, he and others thought it would be fun to get some of these winemakers and wines together. Hence, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima Valley Rose</ENAMEX>' Renaissance."
Following the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> social hour tasting, attendees will dine on a barbecue of spice-rubbed grilled pork chops and an assortment of salads and sauteed vegetables. Roses' will be available by the glass to accompany the meal.
The participating wineries will include Two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Cellars</ENAMEX>, Vineheart, Hinzerling and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paradisos del Sol</ENAMEX>.
Reservations for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>'s event can be made by calling 786-2163.
</P> 
<P ID="7">‘Dance in the Streets’ event <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 31</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Planned Parenthood of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> will hold its first ever "Dance in the Streets" event <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 31</TIMEX>. It will be held on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Front Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX>, and will include live music, food and drinks.
The music will start at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> with Wayman Chapman, a local favorite, to be followed by the X-Band—a local classic rock cover band.
Providing special menus for the evening will be The Barrel House, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s Keg and Cork, Cafe Melange, Carousel, The Depot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greystone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ Works</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santiago's Restaurant</ENAMEX>.
Organizers will be serving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>'s beer and local wines from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wineglass Cellars</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hogue Cellars</ENAMEX>, Desert Hills, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurston Wolfe</ENAMEX> and Bonair Winery.
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> in advance and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> the night of the event. Those who attend must be at least 21 years of age. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> tables are available. Tickets or tables can be reserved by calling (509) 225-3400.
Proceeds generated that evening will benefit the Planned Parenthood organization.
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

