


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> school levy, bond issues validated, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> measure defeated by a single percentage point
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">In the final count of special levy and bond issue votes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters gave the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> a narrow <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60.9 percent</NUMEX> approval for its $1l million bond.
</P><P ID="5">   According to the latest ballot numbers released by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Election Department</ENAMEX>, a total of 1,396 "yes" ballots were cast while 821 voters said "no" to the bond issue.
</P><P ID="6">   Early numbers showed the measure with a higher approval rate, but the final count of ballots added a few more "no" votes to narrow the approval margin.
</P><P ID="7">   All special levy measures required a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> super majority for passage.
</P><P ID="8">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s count of the remaining absentee ballots gave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s four-year <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> maintenance and operation levy measure an additional 20 "yes" votes. The measure received a total of 1,480 "yes" votes, for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">64.6 percent</NUMEX> approval rate. A total of 787 voters said "no" to the levy.
</P><P ID="9">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger School District</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$515,793</NUMEX> special maintenance and operation levy has failed to gain the necessary votes for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> super majority in the final examination of absentee ballots.
</P><P ID="10">   The small community's M&O measure only received a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59.09 percent</NUMEX> approval.
</P><P ID="11">   Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195,000</NUMEX> special levy gained 40 more votes for a total of 241 "yes" votes and four new "no" votes for a total of 57 negative ballots. The measure, which received <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> approval from the Mabton voters on election night, passed with an <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80.87 percent</NUMEX> approval rate.
</P><P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="13">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




