
<P ID="1">Planned Parenthood hires women's health activist
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gina Popovic</ENAMEX>, B.A., has been hired by Planned Parenthood of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> (CWPPH) as a public policy field organizer to help alert the public to issues surrounding changes in women's health care.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popovic</ENAMEX> will be working with groups in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> clinic areas, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin Fishburn</ENAMEX>, the director of marketing and development of Planned Parenthood of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>.   "It's essentially a public relations job. I'll be responsible getting our services and our message out to the public," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popovic</ENAMEX> explained.   "I'll be working to create bridges between different groups in the community. For example, I'll be meeting with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> student groups offering our educators as speakers explaining exactly what Planned Parenthood does," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popovic</ENAMEX> added.   "She will also be conducting voter registration campaigns at the various sites," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fishburn</ENAMEX>.   She said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popovic</ENAMEX> will also issue information about policy changes that affect women's health care, as well as working with young leaders interested in effecting change.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fishburn</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Popovic</ENAMEX> has experience as an organizer, having organized the Ellensburg chapter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Organization for Women</ENAMEX>. She has been involved in state and local activist activities for more than 10 years.      
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

