
<P ID="1">Fire department starting cadet program
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> firefighter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Roe</ENAMEX> knows first-hand how important a cadet program can be to a community.   A former fire cadet himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> got his first taste of what it means to be in the fire prevention service as a high school student. After he graduated from the cadet program he became a volunteer firefighter and now he is a full-time firefighter/paramedic for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>.   While a cadet, his passion for the fire service developed and he now is a career member of the local fire department.   Wanting to provide local students with the same opportunities, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> is starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> cadet program.   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> is taking applications from those interested in participating in the cadet program, which he said is much like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>'s Explorer program.   The fire cadet program is open to high school students 16 and older who attend school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The program is limited to six cadets, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>.   The program, he said, is a good way to develop and grow the volunteer fire department.   "It's a great way for students to learn if they want to pursue a career in the fire service," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>.   He added that the cadet program is designed to give students an in-depth look at being a firefighter before they have to make final career decisions.   Cadets will not be participating in live fire training or in a capacity that will take them into burning buildings, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>. Rather, cadets will provide support service for the fire department and help with clean-up. Currently, volunteer firefighters are providing the support, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>. The cadets will free them up for more active roles on a fire scene.   Cadets will also be participating in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> trainings at the fire station twice a month. The first thing the cadets will learn will be basic life-saving skills. They will be trained in first aid and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, they will have hands-on fire training, he added.   Cadet applications are available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> has also visited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> to drum up interest in the program.   "I have given out many applications," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>.   So far he has received three back. The applications can be returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>. They are due <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1</TIMEX>.   Applicants will go through a process similar to the firefighter hiring process, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>.   Students will be required to complete a physical agility test, and they will undergo an oral board and a chief's interview.   "We hope to have the students selected by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>'s vision for the group is that it would be self-sustaining.   So far, the cadet program has received donations from several groups in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> said the funds he has collected will be used to pay for a fund-raiser for the cadets. He said the cadets will be making and selling posts with numbers on them that can be placed near the road so that fire personnel can more easily find residences in case of emergency.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

