


<P ID="1">Victory over Cascade sends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> to second round of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> play
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> volleyball team didn't let a little thing like playing in the first game of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX> shake their confidence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Instead, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> pushed forward with their season-long winning streak, sending the Cascade Kodiaks home without a game win.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team swept past Cascade, winning by scores of 25-22, 25-13, 25-19.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said going into the match his team knew they would be faced with some tough competition.
</P><P ID="7">   "We knew they had some really athletic girls and some girls who jumped really well," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said. He added that they also knew that Cascade had beat some teams that were ranked above them and had recently been in some really close matches. He noted that Cascade had beaten <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX> and barely lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Although they knew it would be a hard fought match, the Lady 'Hounds went into it with a plan - play consistently.
</P><P ID="9">   "We want to be really consistent when we play," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   And consistency is what helped the Lady 'Hounds rally past the Kodiaks.
</P><P ID="11">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX>, both Tonhya Wysong and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> kept up their games, working hard against the Cascade team. He said going into the match, the team was also looking for senior Danelle Cowan to step up her serves, which she was able to do.
</P><P ID="12">   Wysong finished the night with 21 digs; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> had 12 kills, 6 digs, 7 blocks and 9 service points; and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowan</ENAMEX> had 13 kills, 11 digs, 3 blocks and 11 service points.
</P><P ID="13">   Also helping out the 'Hounds were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> with 11 digs; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> with 6 kills and 6 digs; setter Chante Bottineau with 30 assists and 6 digs; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX> with 1 ace; and Kealey Johnston with 4 kills, 15 digs and 9 service points.
</P><P ID="14">   The Lady 'Hounds are now just one match away from playing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament. However, before they can look to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team will have to face off against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX> in the second round of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> action.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will take to the court <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX>. The winner of the match will advance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>, which will be played in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




