
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> freshmen sustain first defeat of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> season
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/23/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> freshman football team gave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> a run for its money this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>. But in the end, the vaunted Mustang grid program proved to be too much for the Grizzlies.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> took the early lead on the Prosser freshmen, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Villanueva</ENAMEX> bulldozed his way into the end zone from a yard out. The score came in the opening quarter.   "On our first possession of the game we were forced to punt," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS Coach Glenn Braman</ENAMEX>. "But the ball deflected off a player and we recovered it. We drove about 40 yards, with (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX>) capping it off with a one-yard touchdown run."   The missed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAT</ENAMEX> left <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with a 6-0 lead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s quarterback, in the second quarter, eluded <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s defenders and broke off a 12-yard TD scamper. The successful exra point kick gave the Mustangs a 7-6 advantage.   The Mustang squad increased its lead to 14-6 on its first possession of the second half. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> capped off the drive with a 5-yard TD run. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> scored again in the third quarter, after the Grizzly freshmen gave the Mustangs excellent field position.   "We only got off about a 10-yard punt," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX>. "That gave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> the ball at about our 20-yard line. They punched it in from there," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> cut the deficit to 21-12 in the fourth quarter, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> scampered into the end zone from 10 yards out. The Grizzlies attempted a 2-point conversion pass, but it failed.   Neither club scored again in the game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> doesn't have individual numbers from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s contest, but said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> rushed for close to 100 yards.   In comparing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s game with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s outing against the Prosser freshmen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> was pleased with the effort of his club <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, I think <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> scored on just about every possession," he said. "This time around, they were only able to score on three of their possessions.   "Defensively, I thought our kids played awesome. We made them punt six times. And, we had two fourth down stops against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> inside our 10-yard line," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> recounted.   "All of our kids worked very hard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   "And the good thing is, we get to take on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX> on our home field. It's not every season you get to play a team twice, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we'll get the chance to turn the tables on them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> added.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> freshman squad is now 2-1 on the season.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

