
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Parent info center open house setfor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX>
An open house for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s new parent information and resource center will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>, from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> The official ribbon cutting is slated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
The resource center has been made possible through a partnership with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Community Action Center</ENAMEX>, funded by a grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Education</ENAMEX>.
The new center has been created especially for parents and adults who wish to become more involved in their child's education, in an effort to improve student academic achievement. The center will provide information and resources in conjunction with the local school district's community technology center. While the technology center will focus on teaching computer skills to parents, the new resource center will ensure parents have access to information on a variety of topics important to student achievement.
Yesenia Rodriguez will serve as the new resource center facilitator. She will work to provide assistance to school buildings in their efforts to engage parents directly in student learning, strengthening parenting skills and increasing parents' confidence to communicate more effectively with school personnel.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>'s open house is open to the public.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Heartstrings to perform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gospel</ENAMEX> singing group, Heartstrings, is inviting its listeners to a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gospel</ENAMEX> music jamboree at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser City Park</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 25</TIMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Baptist Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> is presenting the jamboree during the balloon rally weekend. There will be other activities in the park, as well, including a car show.
The scheduled performers for the 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gospel</ENAMEX> music jamboree include the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Gospel Quartet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Covenant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Diamond</ENAMEX>, Joyful Noise and Heartstrings.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fair</ENAMEX> admission, parking free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday, Sept. 24</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - There will be no charge for admission, or parking, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> for three hours <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday, Sept. 24</TIMEX>.
The special promotion will run from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX>
"We've had huge turnouts the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> that we did this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Stewart</ENAMEX>, fair president and general manager.
After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX>, the regular gate weekday admission will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for senior citizens and children ages 6 to 12. Children under the age of 6 will be admitted free at all times when accompanied by an adult. Parking onthe fairgrounds is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> in the main lot and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> for the infield.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

