
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa</ENAMEX> letters arrive at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole...Alaska</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The magic of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> can often be summed up in one moment. For some children, it's the excitement and wonderment that fills their eyes when they receive a letter back from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>.   Every year thousands of children across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> and other parts of the world sit down to carefully pen their thoughts and wishes in the form of a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>, often reminding the jolly old elf that they have been good throughout the year.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> is no different than any other part of the world. Here, children still sit down and write out their thoughts to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa</ENAMEX>, often including a wish list and holiday greetings. However, what happens between the letter being written and the envelope being dropped off at the local post office and that special moment when the child receives their response is almost magical in and of itself.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> offices from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> send their mail, including sentiments addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>, to be sorted at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> facility.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Summers</ENAMEX>, a clerk at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Post Office</ENAMEX>, there is an employee in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> who traditionally responds to letters that come through the facility. However, not every letter is answered at that level.   Other letters continue the journey north to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>, where several post offices receive and respond to the specially addressed letters.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dwight Grimmer</ENAMEX>, postmaster of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Post Office</ENAMEX>, said one of the final resting places for letters addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grimmer</ENAMEX>, who used to work at the post office in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrangel</ENAMEX>, said every year he worked there the facility would receive at least one large mailbag filled with letters addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX>.   "I was surprised we received as many as we did," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grimmer</ENAMEX> said.   He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrangel</ENAMEX> started receiving letters addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa</ENAMEX> when the mail system became automated. He explained many of the addresses on the Santa letters include the highest zip code people can think of and since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrangel</ENAMEX>'s zip code, 99929, is the highest zip code in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, the letters automatically get routed in that direction.   However, the letters that arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wrangel</ENAMEX> weren't necessarily replied to. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grimmer</ENAMEX> said, the letters were given to the local newspaper and many were published.   One of the busiest destinations for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa</ENAMEX> letters and other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> sentiments is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>. According to the branch manager in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Matthews</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the mail facility received 70,000 letters.   "They come in from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> said, noting that letters from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> are also received.   She explained that some of the letters are addressed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>, while others carry no postage and simply have the words <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX> scrawled across them in children's handwriting.   "They barcode them to us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> said.   Once the letters arrive at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX>, a myriad of volunteers work from the day after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thanksgiving through the Christmas</TIMEX> holiday to ensure that each of the letters with a return address are answered.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> said the letters are handed over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Pole Badgers Lions Club</ENAMEX>, with many of them being answered by club members, as well as people involved in other charitable organizations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> said many people in the community get involved with the letter writing project, including students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Pole Middle School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> said in order to ensure that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> and the Santa's Mailbag project continue every year, the organization holds fund-raisers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from January through December</TIMEX>. She explained that the funds are then used to purchase the stationary and postage needed to ensure the letters get back to the children who are eagerly awaiting a response.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthews</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Pole</ENAMEX> branch of the Fairbanks, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> post office was started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, and since then many letters addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Claus</ENAMEX> have been received at the facility. She explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa</ENAMEX> letters arrive at the branch office throughout the year, with the Santa's Mailbag project collecting them and answering them when the holiday season arrives.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

