
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> congresswoman in town promoting Democratic platform
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda Solis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> traveled north <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, spending two days touring the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to the Tri-Cities, promoting the Democratic platform and talking about presidential candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>'s plans for dealing with the rising costs of health care and education.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX>, a congresswomen for the 32nd district of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, which includes all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, was the guest speaker at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Latina Women's luncheon held at El Conquistador in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> was elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, and received the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John F. Kennedy Profile</ENAMEX> in Courage Award the same year. She also serves as the chair of the Hispanics Congressional Caucus Taskforce on Health.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> noted that she represents a diverse area that includes urban and inner city communities. She added that she also represents a wide array of people, explaining that about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of her district is Latino, with another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> being Asian.   "I'm dealing with a very diverse group of people," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said.   She went on to note that she sees the Latino community as an ever growing group of voters who could have a big effect on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election. She noted that Latinos are a minority, majority community. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> explained that Latinos are the fastest growing minority in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   However, despite the community's large numbers, Latinos are not as politically active as they could be, she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said that she is looking to the younger generation of Latinos to change that. She explained that although the population of Latinos is growing, it is still a young population with a large group of people under the age of 18.   "But in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 10 years</TIMEX> I see them taking on some very crucial positions," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said.   She then talked a little bit about her personal background. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said her father came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>, and her mother is originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nicaragua</ENAMEX>. She said the two met in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> and started their family in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">La Puente</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said when she was in high school there weren't a lot of Latino students in her school. However, there was a Mexican American counselor who one day asked her where she was going to go to college.   "I thought he was crazy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said.   She said she told him that her family was raising seven children and there was no way they would be able to afford to send her to college. Her counselor then <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> her down and told her that through financial aid she would be able to go to school.   "That is why we need to support good government," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said, noting that it's because of federal financial aid that she was able to go to school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> then pointed to President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>'s No Child Left Behind act, which is aimed at ensuring that all students receive the education they need. However, she said when the President created the act he didn't provide the funding required for schools to implement the programs they need to comply with the law.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said higher education is also suffering under the current administration. She said the Pell grant program and other grant programs that help students pay for college education are shrinking.   "We need a president who is going to help to put more [funds] in," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said of the grant programs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> has a plan to help middle class families pay for college, noting that his plan includes a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> a year tax credit for parents who are sending their children on to school.   "You don't hear any of this coming from the other party," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said.   When it comes to health care issues, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> noted that she serves on the task force for health. She said it's important that people have access to affordable health care. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said it's not simply the unemployed who don't have the funds necessary to cover the rising costs of health care. Instead, she said it's the working poor who are suffering, those people who are holding down jobs, trying to make ends meet.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said also adding to the health care issues in this country is the lack of nurses. She said there is no incentive for nurses to become teachers at nursing schools, when they can make so much more money working in the emergency room at local hospitals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said something needs to be done to ensure that there are enough teachers out there educating young nurses and getting them ready to fill the needs of hospitals and medical facilities across the country.   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> told the women at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s meeting that she believes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX> ticket.   "I believe that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> believe in diversity and families," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

