


<P ID="1">Grandview rodeo moves to the PRCA
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/6/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Several years ago when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Junior Fair in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> was looking for a way to boost attendance, a new idea was brought forward to coordinate a rodeo that would take place during the annual summertime event. The idea was approved, and now <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years later</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Fair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rodeo</ENAMEX> is planning on taking its rodeo up another notch.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Fair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rodeo</ENAMEX> will host a Professional Rodeo Cowboy Assocation (PRCA) sanctioned rodeo event.
</P><P ID="6">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Fisher</ENAMEX>, who helps organize the annual event, when the idea to incorporate a rodeo into the fair was first brought up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Herriman</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northern Cross Rodeo Company</ENAMEX>, it was with the idea that after a few years of holding a successful rodeo that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> event could move up from being a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ProWest Rodeo Association</ENAMEX> event to being sanctioned by the PRCA.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>, who has always provided stock for the local rodeo, had been wanting to move up to providing stock for PRCA sanctioned events and had said if the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> rodeo was successful he would bring the event up to PRCA with him.
</P><P ID="8">   "He was really anxious for us to go up with him," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   She explained that after the rodeo saw success for three years in a row, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> felt the time was right to apply to the PRCA. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said first <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> went through the process of getting approved to provide stock to PRCA rodeos. Once that happened he approached the PRCA about putting together a new six-rodeo series, which would include the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> event.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said the next step was for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Fair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rodeo</ENAMEX> event to be approved by the PRCA. She explained that this included filling out some paperwork and showing that the rodeo had been successful in the past.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said being a PRCA sanctioned event in the Coeur d'Alene Casino Championship Series will mean a larger cost to put the rodeo on, but will also mean there will be more opportunities for corporate sponsorship.
</P><P ID="12">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, it will cost approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX> more to put on a PRCA rodeo than it has to put on a ProWest rodeo. She explained that the added cost comes from needing larger purses for the cowboys and having to pay the rodeo judges more money, as well as needing to have official rodeo bullfighters on staff instead of rodeo clowns.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said the six rodeos that make up the new circuit are working together with the Coeur d'Alene Casino to gain more corporate sponsors. She said people representing the different events, which take place in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brewster</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tekoa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Mary</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Libby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, have been meeting monthly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coeur d'Alene</ENAMEX> to discuss everything from sponsorships to the promotion of the series.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said she is hoping that moving to the PRCA will also help bolster participation in the rodeo. She explained that in years past the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> event has been scheduled between two PRCA rodeos, one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX> and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermiston</ENAMEX>. She credits this to the reason the local event has been so successful. She said a lot of PRCA cowboys would take part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> rodeo between the other two events, regardless of the fact that they couldn't earn PRCA points.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> is hopeful that with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> rodeo now being a PRCA event that more PRCA cowboys will take advantage of the scheduling and add the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Fair</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rodeo</ENAMEX> to their schedule, especially now that the points they earn there will go toward both the series championship, scheduled to be held at the Coeur d'Alene Casino <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24-26</TIMEX>, and to nationals, which take place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the Grandview Rodeo had more than 300 participants, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> is hoping to see that number grow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   She said she has been happy with the success the rodeo has seen over the years.
</P><P ID="18">   "I think it has helped the fair survive," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said.
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




