
<P ID="1">New water and sewer rates in effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents can expect to see another rate increase on their water and sewer bills at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of March</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved the rate increase at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting. The latest rate increase marks the third time in less than a year the city has raised water and sewer rates.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2003</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approved a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> rate increase for water and another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.5 percent</NUMEX> increase in sewer services. Later in the year in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> implemented another rate increase of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.8 percent</NUMEX> for water and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> for sewer. Prior to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> increase, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had not raised water and sewer rates in a decade.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said the latest rate increase is basically to help bring the city in compliance with the mandated debt for the water and sewer bonds the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> implemented a few years ago. The city is currently not in compliance with the terms of the bond debt.   Beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>, local residents will see an additional <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.86 percent</NUMEX> increase in water rates and another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.89 percent</NUMEX> in sewer rates. City Finance Director Chad Stotz included an additional <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> in the sewer rate charges to help rebuild the depleted sewer reserve funds. The extra <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> will give the city an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37,000</NUMEX> in reserves <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   Local water and sewer users will start seeing the new rates reflected in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> bill.   But the city also faces another challenge in implementing water and sewer rates. The way the city's water consumption billing is cSmarted, residents are rewarded for using more water as a result of paying less for the more they consume. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said this is an issue the city is taking heat on from the state because it doesn't stress conservation.   Under the new rates, customers will begin paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.39</NUMEX> for each cubic foot of consumption between 301 and 1,200. This is the level of consumption most residents fall within. Customers are charged a minimum of 300 cubic feet of consumption at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.39</NUMEX>, resulting in a flat beginning fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28.12</NUMEX>. Presently, the amount then goes down for customers who use more water.   Beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>, customers will be charged a minimum sewer usage rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22.33</NUMEX>. The charge for using between 301 and 10,000 cubic feet will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.98</NUMEX> per 100 cubic feet. The fees then slide down as more sewage is disposed.   The ordinance also covers fees for commercial customers and processing plant users, as well as mobile home parks. There is also a section highlighting the fees for using a grease trap or a sedimentation trap.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> wanted city staff to address the issue of how the water rates are structured as soon as possible.   "This is just not right," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. "People who conserve water get penalized."   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Works</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Ott</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the city is addressing the rate structure as part of updating its water comprehensive plan, which must be completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ott</ENAMEX> is expecting to have a report to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the rate structure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> also wanted to look at implementing a rate structure that would benefit all users, not just provide specific cuts to certain people.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Bliesner</ENAMEX> provided the lone public comment on the water and sewer rate increases. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliesner</ENAMEX>, who owns Valley Processing, told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that large businesses in town, such as his processing plant, subsidize the smaller, residential users. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliesner</ENAMEX> also added that on average senior citizens in the community are some of the wealthiest residents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliesner</ENAMEX> felt no special privilege should be given in regards to fees for water and sewer use to seniors just because of their age.   "It should be based more on their need," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bliesner</ENAMEX>.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> explained there is a qualification process anyone looking for a reduced rate has to go through to become eligible.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

