
<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerri Honeyford</ENAMEX>   I have a friend I would like you to meet. He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 15, 1959</TIMEX>, the youngest of seven children. He grew up on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> in Seattle, where his father was a public school teacher. His father's family had emigrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Diamond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>. to work in the coal mines. His mother's background was Klinkit Indian and Irish.   After graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Woodway High School</ENAMEX> in Edmonds, my friend worked his way through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle University</ENAMEX>. He had various jobs, such as night janitor and construction, but his degree was business management when he graduated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX> he bought his first apartment building and he's been in commercial real estate ever since.   Although he thought he was a confirmed bachelor, he met a girl at the office who, he says, "chased me until I let her catch me!" He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terri</ENAMEX> were married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 8, 1987</TIMEX>. They have four children: Juliauna who is 13; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX> 10; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> 7; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jillian</ENAMEX> who is 3.   Oh, and the family has a dog, G.W., named for our president since the children wouldn't have gotten the dog without President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s intervention! Over and over the children had asked for a dog. But with four children in a very busy household, the parents decided the dog might not receive the proper care. They said no dog. Once after another plea on the part of the children, my friend said somewhat tongue-in-cheek, "Not unless the President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> says you can have a dog!" The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX> when the family was visiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, the children prepared a note to leave on President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s desk. This was accomplished. To their parent's surprise, a letter came from the President saying he thought every family should have a dog to care for and love! I heard that the President asked about the dog when he visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.   In his first election experience, my friend voted for President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Reagan</ENAMEX>. Later he volunteered in King <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> and because of the outstanding work he did there, he was named King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Republican</ENAMEX> of the Year. He was asked to run for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in the 5th district and went to serve in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. In just a short time he became the chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>.   Besides other successful and highly acclaimed accomplishments, he wrote the budget that rescued our state from a deficit without raising taxes. He resigned from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> to put his full efforts into serving us in another position.   My friend is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> and he is running for governor. He wants to bring a fresh start and a refreshing service attitude to public service.   There are so many areas that need new leadership. For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 20 years</TIMEX>, many of the same people have been shifted around in state government agencies and offices. Businesses and jobs have been leaving for other areas. Health care and education are in crisis, but there is no clear leadership for needed change.   We can do better. We can have a state where families can live and work well, where youth can be well educated, and the ill and elderly can be well cared for. We need to change the culture and direction of state agencies who need to understand they are servants, not masters.   I'm sure you will like my friend if you take the time to know him. That's why I have introduced him to you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerri Honeyford</ENAMEX>, wife of Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, provides her "Across our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>" column as her take on the legislative happenings currently underway in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

