
<P ID="1">Sports Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
6-11 Sports briefs
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> Jam returns to S’side
The second annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> Jam will be held at the Mid-Valley Mall the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10-11</TIMEX>.
The 3-on-3 basketball tournament offers numerous divisions of play for youngsters and adults, alike. Registration fees are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> for youth teams and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70</NUMEX> for adult teams. All sign-ups are being handled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> (837-5939).
Tourney organizers report that team packets and t-shirts will be distributed during check-in, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. Each team is guaranteed to play a minimum of three games in the round-robin format.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Nozaka, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowlsby</ENAMEX> grabfirst place finishes
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - Black Rock Creek's golfers found Columbia Point Golf Course to their liking this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>.
Competing at a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA Central Washington</ENAMEX> chapter pro-am series event, five of Black Rock Creek's members scored a first place finish <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>. The winners included Souta Nozaka, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Stotz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly Hector</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Andrews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoff Bowlsby</ENAMEX>.
Nozaka won top honors among all the amateurs, carding a tourney best five-under 67. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> finished in an eight-way tie for low net honors among amateur division #1 golfers by shooting a handicap-aided 66. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector</ENAMEX> was one of three golfers to tie for low net honors among amateur division #2 golfers with a 66. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowlsby</ENAMEX> shared amateur division #3 low net honors with six others, all posting 66's.
The low professional round of the day was turned in by Von Wells of Desert Canyon Resort. Wells posted an eight-under 64.
</P> 
<P ID="5">S’side Boosters stage tournament
Two squads tied for top honors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> in the second annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Boosters Club Golf Tournament</ENAMEX>, staged at Black Rock Creek Golf Course.
The two four-person teams carded 13-under 59's playing a scramble format. The winning teams were comprised of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Rohde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry O'Brian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Phillips</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Shreeve</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zach Wanderscheid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Taylor</ENAMEX>, Juston Bos and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Swinehart</ENAMEX>.
Placing third with a 61 was the foursome of Lance Den Boer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Van de Graff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Stewart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duane Schutt</ENAMEX>.
In the handicap-aided net division, the foursome of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Carr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candice Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chet Terrell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Monroe</ENAMEX> placed first with a 51.75. Second place net finishers, with a 52.75, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Ross</ENAMEX> and Tayana Rogers. The third place net team, with a 53.60, was made up of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rae Ann Goin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Cantwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Goin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kari Hunt</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Swim lessonsstart <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday
Monday, June 14</TIMEX>, swim lessons get underway at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> municipal pool.
Local parks and rec officials report that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents can register for the lessons during regular pool hours.
Lessons are being offered Mondays through Fridays, half an hour at a time, during each two-week session. The cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> for in-city residents and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26</NUMEX> for those residing outside the city limits.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Soapbox derby practice run setto be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26</TIMEX>
All those racers planning to compete in the sixth annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Soapbox Derby are invited to test out their cars on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 26</TIMEX>.
The practice run at the hill next to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX>
The derby, itself, will be held during <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> celebration, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 3</TIMEX>. Three divisions of competition are offered: youths 7 to 14 years of age, adults and the Mayor's Challenge Cup for all city and county officials.
Registration fees range from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX></NUMEX>. Registration forms are still available a the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> parks and rec office. The deadline to sign up to compete is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 21</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Volleyball camp open to girls
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> will sponsor a volleyball camp for girls on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12</TIMEX>, 14 and 16 at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> gym. The three-day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp is open to girls in the 7th through 12th grades.
Seventh and eighth grade girls will attend from 9 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> each of the three days, learning basic skills development in passing, serving, hitting and stragegies.
Girls in 9th through 12th grades can register for the hitters camp (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>) or for the setter/defense camp (12:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>). Sign-ups are being conducted at the local parks and rec office.
Camp fees are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. For high school aged girls who want to attend both sessions, the fee is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX>. All girls who attend will receive a camp t-shirt.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s camp will be directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> varsity volleyball coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Whalen</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="9">Grade school boys invited to hoop camp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15-16</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> varsity boys basketball coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Urrutia</ENAMEX> will be the director of the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> basketball camp for grade school boys.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s camp will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15-16</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> both days. The camp is open to boys who will be in the first through sixth grades <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
Sign-ups are underway at the local parks and rec office. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> registration fee includes the cost of a camp t-shirt.
</P> 
<P ID="10"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> hoop camp for girlsset for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15-16</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and Recreation Girls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> Classic Basketball Camp will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 15-16</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> varsity girls basketball coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Gomez</ENAMEX> will serve as camp director. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> camp is open to girls in the first through sixth grades.
Girls can register at the local parks and rec office, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>, which includes the price of a camp t-shirt.
</P> 
<P ID="11">Golf Fore Life tourney <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX> will host its Golf Fore Life Tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 19</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Black Rock Creek Golf Course.
Participants are invited to set a goal of golfing 100 holes that day.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s event drew 27 golfers to Black Rock Creek for an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> breakfast and a long day of golf. They helped raise more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> through pledges they obtained from family and friends.
Sign-up information on the tourney is available by calling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan</TIMEX> McDonald at 882-1899.
</P> 


 




<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

