


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> rejects <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s funding request for new well
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Losing its bid to receive a state community development block grant has not deterred the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton City Council</ENAMEX> from seeking other funding sources for a much needed new city well.
</P><P ID="5">   The city leaders, who had sought a state community block grant to help with the estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> cost of punching a new well recently learned their application was rejected.
</P><P ID="6">   "We're not sure why our application was rejected by the state, but we are in need of an additional water source," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX>. He said the city's aging water system had given the city a number of headaches the past several years. The city hopes to drill a new well to meet current water needs, as well as future needs in the tiny community.
</P><P ID="7">   "We are now seeking other funding sources," he said.
</P><P ID="8">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton City Council</ENAMEX> approved spending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,600</NUMEX> to fund an engineer's study of the city's aquifers, which is required by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Water Conservation Board</ENAMEX>. The professional study and the approval of the county conservation board are both needed before the city can apply for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> funding, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="9">   He said the study is the first step in seeking a USDA rural development grant/loan package.
</P><P ID="10">   The USDA funding will require the city to pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of the costs putting in the new well, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ildia Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> city administrator.
</P><P ID="11">   The USDA provides funding in <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> grant/<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> loan packages, she explained.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said the city may seek extra funding from the state's public works grants.
</P><P ID="13">   The rejection of the city's block grant application is expected to delay the city water project, by at least six months.
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




