


<P ID="1">Crack in sewer main leads to emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G'view Council</ENAMEX> meeting
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - All of the wastewater in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> at one time or another travels from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Euclid Road</ENAMEX> pump station, under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima River</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> wastewater treatment plant. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Aug. 11</TIMEX>, crews at the local treatment plant noticed wastewater rising in the river during a routine check of the plant's back-up systems.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, it was confirmed that the wastewater leakage was coming from a 10-foot long, 1/2-inch wide crack in one of the two 20-inch water mains that are used to transport wastewater from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid</ENAMEX> pump station to the treatment plant.
</P><P ID="6">   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> called an emergency meeting to discuss the problem and find a solution.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Public Works Director Cus Arteaga</ENAMEX> explained that the damaged east main is currently used as part of the wastewater treatment plant's back-up system. He noted that both 20-inch mains that cross the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima River</ENAMEX> were first installed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, with the east pipe being used to regularly transport wastewater across the river, until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> when improvements were made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid</ENAMEX> pump station.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> explained that the upgrades included the construction of a 100,000-gallon storage basin and the installation of an engine-driven back-up pump, that in case of emergency would pump wastewater from the basin, across the river to the treatment plant. He noted that the upgrades also meant dedicating the east pipe, which already had 20 years of use, to the back-up system.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said that the back-up system is only set to be used when electricity is lost and the back-up generator doesn't kick in to operate the three electric pumps that pump wastewater across the river on a day-to-day basis.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Pooler</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huibregtse Louman and Associates</ENAMEX> told city council members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that the crack was discovered after 5,000 gallons of wastewater leaked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima River</ENAMEX> during a routine check of the back-up system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said the back-up system is checked quarterly.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooler</ENAMEX> said as soon as the wastewater was seen coming up in the river, the pumps were shut down. He added that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX>, it was confirmed that there was a leak in the east main, when dyed water was run through the pipe and showed up in the river.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooler</ENAMEX> told council that on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 19</TIMEX>, a camera was inserted into the main and sent down the length of the pipe. He said the crack was found about 90 feet from the river bank.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooler</ENAMEX> then showed a video of the camera's journey through the pipe to council, pointing out where the crack is located. He noted that at points along the crack it is possible to see the river bottom.
</P><P ID="14">   Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooler</ENAMEX>'s presentation, he introduced four repair options to council. The first option was to replace only the damaged section of the pipe, another option was to insert a pipe liner in only the damaged section of the pipe, and the third option was to replace either one or both of the 20-inch mains that run across the river. The fourth option introduced to council called for the insertion of a pipe liner into the entire length of the either just the east main, or both the east and west pipes.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooler</ENAMEX> noted one advantage of using a liner is that it wouldn't make it necessary to actually get into the river to do the repairs, which would mean dealing with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Environmental Protection Agency</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> asked if it would be necessary to line both pipes at the same time. He noted that since the west pipe has only had about four years of regular use, he would like to see a camera go through that pipe to see if a liner is really needed before council opts to set aside funds to have the second pipe lined at the same time.
</P><P ID="17">   "Sometimes it's different when you're not behind the eight ball," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooler</ENAMEX> estimated the cost of lining the east pipe, which has the crack in it, to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$116,369</NUMEX>. The estimate to line the west pipe is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$111,936</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that the money to make the emergency repair would come from the city's water and sewer fund, which he noted currently has a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> fund balance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that the impact this will have on sewer rates has yet to be determined.
</P><P ID="20">   After listening to the presentation, council voted to line the east pipe, with the option of lining the west pipe if it is determined to be necessary.
</P><P ID="21">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




