
<P ID="1">Shockers blow past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> gridders, 42-7
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Like a knife slicing through warm butter, the Waterville Shockers ran through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s defensive squad <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> enroute to posting a convincing 42-7 victory.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX>, the defending <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> champs, tallied 250 rushing yards in pinning the overwhelming defeat on the Viking football team. The Shockers didn't try to confuse <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> in mixing up offensive plays, as they threw the ball just twice. Instead, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX> just came right at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>, shoving the ball down their throats.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX> had to replace four of their five starters off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s offensive line," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Coach D.J</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "But it was like nothing was missing. They're as strong as ever.   "Their line got off the ball quick. They dominated us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said.   With the huge gaps the Waterville line created, the trio of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Creel</ENAMEX>, Jarod Biggar and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Craig</ENAMEX> ran wild. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Creel</ENAMEX> toted the ball just six times, but totaled 78 rushing yards and scored twice. He busted loose for a 27-yard TD scamper to open the scoring, and found the end zone just before the half on a 40-yard breakaway. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Biggar</ENAMEX> had eight carries for 48 yards, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig</ENAMEX> piled up 45 yards on five totes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> didn't fare all that badly when it had the ball. Unfortunately, whenever a promising drive got started, it stalled. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> did manage to find the end zone once. Trailing by a 35-0 count midway through the third quarter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> got on the scoreboard when freshman fullback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eli Perez</ENAMEX> bulldozed his way up the middle for 9 yards to pay dirt.   The underclassman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX> showed lots of promise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>. He ran for 41 yards on 11 carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s fullback, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Castillo</ENAMEX>, was the leading ground gainer for the Vikes, picking up 75 yards on 14 carries.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> didn't mount much of an attack through the air, as Viking QB Ryan Harris only completed 1-of-5 passes for 28 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> was picked twice by the Waterville defensive unit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Running Mabton</ENAMEX>'s option offense, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> did scamper for 18 yards on six scrambles.   The league opening loss to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX> followed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s 9-0 non-league victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyle two Fridays</ENAMEX> ago. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> look to regroup this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> with a conference game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaSalle</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaSalle</ENAMEX> has a new head coach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "They have a lot of kids out for their team.   "We know they run a wing T offense and a 4-4 defense. To shut them down, we're going to have to play assignment football," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> explained.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

