
<P ID="1">Weekly Bowling Report
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/12/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
WeeklyHonor Roll
</P> 
 
<P ID="4">Valley LanesWeek #23
Early Birds
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-3-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Ewart</ENAMEX> 553 (189), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 497 (179), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Hunter</ENAMEX> 452 (153), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Allison</ENAMEX> 440 (167). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Ewart</ENAMEX> +79. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 169. LL: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>'s Car Store 17-11.
Sunny Valley Women
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-3-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise James</ENAMEX> 557 (244), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcy Carl</ENAMEX> 551 (224), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tami Walkenhauer</ENAMEX> 518 (217), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Tucker</ENAMEX> 512 (179). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annette Watkins</ENAMEX> +78. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Schlieve</ENAMEX> 202. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Cromwell</ENAMEX> 194. LL: Valley Asphalt & Sealing 17-11.
Late Ladies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-3-04</TIMEX>
High series: Krisi Schooley 526 (215), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn Meyers</ENAMEX> 521 (202), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Newhouse</ENAMEX> 511 (201), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Brandmire</ENAMEX> 505 (178). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawn Meyers</ENAMEX> +167. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Buckles</ENAMEX> 231, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Patton</ENAMEX> 211. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Dorsey</ENAMEX> 168. LL: 10-4 Cafe 115-35.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> Mixers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-4-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Tilley</ENAMEX> 663 (257-213), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wilson</ENAMEX> 570 (193), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Pierce</ENAMEX> 553 (233). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Tilley</ENAMEX> +111. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanne Bruinekool</ENAMEX> 528 (194), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 464 (164), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Lopez</ENAMEX> 443 (170). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanne Bruinekool</ENAMEX> +66. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Rice</ENAMEX> 224. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 168. LL: Pinbusters 24-16.
Inter-City
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-4-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 720 (207-268-245), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph LaClair</ENAMEX> 683 (203-224-256), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 680 (247-254), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Poteet</ENAMEX> 671 (234-203-234). Highest series over average: Elray Compo +88. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Carl</ENAMEX> 237, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gress</ENAMEX> 224, Deland Olney 222, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sr. 220</NUMEX>. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 226. LL: Lamp's 179.5-120.5.
Coffee Trio
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-5-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 539 (203), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Ewart</ENAMEX> 513 (196), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixie Heitschmidt</ENAMEX> 495 (172), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Wiley</ENAMEX> 489 (184). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dixie Heitschmidt</ENAMEX> +93. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Falce</ENAMEX> 211. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 176. LL: 410 Market 10-2.
Commercial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-5-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> 739 (267-255-217), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Seifert</ENAMEX> 718 (267-205-246), Brad Morrow 699 (216-258-225), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Spencer</ENAMEX> 672 (245-242). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> +163. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector Fonseca Jr.</ENAMEX> 277, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cavin</ENAMEX> 255, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Huth</ENAMEX> 236, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hill</ENAMEX> 236, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddie Jasso</ENAMEX> 236, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mashburn</ENAMEX> 236, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Davis</ENAMEX> 235, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Schlenker</ENAMEX> 235, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hicks</ENAMEX> 234, Rayburn Borden 233, Dusty Van Hollebeke 228, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gustafson</ENAMEX> 224, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mitoff</ENAMEX> 223. High average: Brad Morrow 211. LL: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Schwab Tires</ENAMEX> 212.5-87.5.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> Fun Bunch
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-6-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: Redfern Mardel 666 (227-258), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Spencer</ENAMEX> 661 (223-207-231), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute Jr.</ENAMEX> 624 (223-212). Highest men's series over average: Redfern Mardel +156. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 600 (234-217), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Lallashute</ENAMEX> 490 (168), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Sequochs</ENAMEX> 467 (166). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Lopez</ENAMEX> +93. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Haggerty</ENAMEX> 245. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Haggerty</ENAMEX> 206. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 200. Winner second third: Beer Dogs 27-17.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preps & Bantams</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-7-04</TIMEX>
High boys series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Rice</ENAMEX> 371 (148), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Zapata</ENAMEX> 371 (140), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Sarmiento</ENAMEX> 370 (149). Highest boys series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Zapata</ENAMEX> +101. High girls series: Jadelynn Howard 380 (150), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Pacheco</ENAMEX> 359 (140), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Cruz</ENAMEX> 341 (135). Highest girls series over average: Jenneil Duran +52. High boys average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Rice</ENAMEX> 128. High girls average: Jadelynn Howard 123. LL: 3 Muskateers 23-5.
Jrs. & Majors
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-7-04</TIMEX>
High boys series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Schaneman</ENAMEX> 630 (233), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joaquin Lopez</ENAMEX> 541 (196), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Huth</ENAMEX> 541 (192). Highest boys series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joaquin Lopez</ENAMEX> +121. High girls series: Aleshia Langworthy 506 (201), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Cruz</ENAMEX> 497 (181), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Rice</ENAMEX> 460 (187). Highest girls series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Guy</ENAMEX> +105. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane Huth</ENAMEX> 210, Kraig Wyatt 200. High boys average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Schaneman</ENAMEX> 203. High girls average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Cruz</ENAMEX> 160. LL: Team #7 99.5-75.5.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> Mixers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-8-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 694 (266-235), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Vigil</ENAMEX> 690 (207-218-265), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 641 (235-201-205). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc Torres</ENAMEX> +104. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Orr</ENAMEX> 594 (203-206), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Hill</ENAMEX> 532 (188), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cruz</ENAMEX> 503 (188). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Hill</ENAMEX> +88. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Webb</ENAMEX> 233, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Newhouse</ENAMEX> 224. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Rice</ENAMEX> 222. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cruz</ENAMEX> 180. Winner second third: H&H Auto Glass 31.5-12.5.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Scratch
(5 games)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-9-04</TIMEX>)
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph LaClair</ENAMEX> 1222 (215-267-225-248-267), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Alvarez</ENAMEX> 1190 (242-236-212-253-247), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 1174 (246-223-278-207-220), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mitoff</ENAMEX> 1137 (236-219-234-257). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> +204. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Poteet</ENAMEX> 276, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 265, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 258, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Huth</ENAMEX> 258, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corey Guy</ENAMEX> 257, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sr. 255</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Snavely</ENAMEX> 236, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Van Boven</ENAMEX> 233, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butch Covel</ENAMEX> 226, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> 225, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Golob</ENAMEX> 223, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Colley</ENAMEX> 222, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Guy</ENAMEX> 221, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deania Guy</ENAMEX> 212. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 221. Winner second third: HAD 200.5-129.5.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

