


<P ID="1">High school singers invited to audition for cash
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolling Hills Chorus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweet Adelines International</ENAMEX> is offering an opportunity to area high school singers to be guests at the Adelines' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2005</TIMEX> show.
</P><P ID="4">   The show, "Hit Me With the Spotlight," will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28, 2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The musical, written and directed by chorus members, is about auditions for a "Broadway" musical, which will feature guest high school performers, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen Duncan</ENAMEX> of the Rolling Hills Chorus.
</P><P ID="6">   The would-be guest performers are now being encouraged to audition for the show, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="7">   Those chosen to perform in the musical are eligible to win a scholarship to further their musical education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX> said. A first, second and third place scholarship will be awarded based on the vote of the audience the night of the performance, she explained.
</P><P ID="8">   Auditions for high school singers will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethany Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>, Second Street and Birch Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   There is no limit to the number of singers who can audition, however only three will be chosen for performing in the show.
</P><P ID="10">   For information about the auditions call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Eakin</ENAMEX>, 882-3335, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Duncan</ENAMEX> 882-1420.
</P>   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




