
<P ID="1">Police seek two would-be robbers
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> is seeking two men who are believed to have gotten cold feet <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> and changed their plans to hold up Highway Fruit.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preston Kelley</ENAMEX>, two men, one wearing a black sweatshirt and one in a brown sweatshirt, were seen near the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Second Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Warehouse Avenue</ENAMEX> walking toward the convenience store.   "One had a rifle and the other had his hand under his shirt and one of the witnesses thought it might have been a gun," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>.   The two men parked their green car at the end of Second Street and started walking toward the market, but people were standing out front. One of the small neighborhood dogs grabbed ahold of the pants leg of the man with the rifle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> said he believes the two men were spooked and left before they had a chance to enter the store.   The two men are described as in their late teens or early 20s. They were last seen driving a green car with a stripe of molding or a decal down the side.   Police are seeking the car in hopes of finding the two men.   Anyone with information is asked to call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, 836-6211.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

