
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JOSE M
JOSE M. Martinez
Jose M. Martinez</ENAMEX>, 95, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 20, 2004</TIMEX>, at Just Like Home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8, 1908</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matias and Maria Anita (Guajardo) Martinez</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. He received his early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX>, where he worked as a farmer and operated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oro y Plata Rodeo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Alvarez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva Sanchez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe Martinez</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Renton</ENAMEX>; numerous grandchildren, great-grandchildren; and one great-great-grandson.
 He was preceded in death by his parents; his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad Martinez</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincente</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matias Martinez</ENAMEX>; three daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adelina Guerrero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Ibbara</ENAMEX> and Hortencia Flores Rebollosa; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matias Martinez</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leticia Perez</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 22, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 23, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of Wells Funeral Home.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JAMES C. SHADWICK
James C. Shadwick</ENAMEX>, 88, a long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> resident, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 17, 2004</TIMEX>, after a short bout with cancer.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 23, 1915</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goodman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Samuel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Jane Saley-Shadwick</ENAMEX>. As a young man he moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kansas</ENAMEX> to live with his sister and seek work. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> he met and married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie M. Gordon</ENAMEX>. Together they had five daughters. He moved his family to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> and then to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>, he purchased a farm, where they had continued to live. He spent his early years in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> working at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Morning Milk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnation Milk</ENAMEX>, both in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and then with Yakima Wine Growers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> until his retirement.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie Shadwick</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; five daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Bryson</ENAMEX>, of Sea Tac, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Breeze</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bev</ENAMEX> and Ken Kite, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen and Doug Hilmoe</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine and Manuel Messick</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hoquiam</ENAMEX>; nine grandchildren; 15 great-grandchildren; two great-great-grandchildren; numerous nieces and nephews; and cousins and in-laws.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 23, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 24, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Prosser Cemetery</ENAMEX>, under the direction of Wells Funeral Home.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CLIFFORD LEROY RETZER
Clifford L. Retzer</ENAMEX>, 69, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 10, 2003</TIMEX>, from his comforting, loving wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol’s</ENAMEX> arms into Jesus’ outstretched, welcoming arms at their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX>. He had suffered a debilitating stroke <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years earlier</TIMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 11, 2001</TIMEX>.  He was able to return home for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX> to care for him and those two years were a precious “bonus time” sent directly from God.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27, 1935</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ashley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.D</ENAMEX>. to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustav</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Buchholz</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Retzer</ENAMEX>.  The family moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1938</TIMEX> and settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX> received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, graduating with the Class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> and continued his education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Institute</ENAMEX> after serving in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>. He was a Korean War Veteran. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Rose Price</ENAMEX> were married <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 22, 1960</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. They lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> the first year and relocated to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbanks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>, where he was associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior Airways</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gene’s Auto</ENAMEX>, returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>. He was employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carnation Company</ENAMEX> until its closure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>. He then became an employee of Darigold in Seattle. He retired as foreman for Darigold in Seattle and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Issaquah</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.
 He and his Boxer dog, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lexi</ENAMEX>, took long walks daily and were well acquainted within a 10-mile radius of home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lexi</ENAMEX> went everywhere with him in the pickup and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> right by his side in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">hospital’s ICU</ENAMEX>. The Retzers owned Boxers for more than 35 years, so each one was well known in the community.  
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford L. Jr.</ENAMEX> “Skip” (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina</ENAMEX>); one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stefanie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cox</ENAMEX>; four delightful granddaughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelli Retzer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabrielle Caprice Cox</ENAMEX>; sister and brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph and Bernice Fennewald</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marvin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reta</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>; three sisters-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Yearout</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> “Tex”) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Stephens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winifred Price</ENAMEX> of Seattle; and many nieces and nephews. Special long-time friends and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol’s</ENAMEX> cousins kept in constant encouraging contact with him, bolstering <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol’s</ENAMEX> spirits. He is also survived by special friends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> vanWyk, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry and Marilyn O’Connor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon and Gail Hedrick</ENAMEX>; and cousins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Linderman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron and Gloria Judd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Berg</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his parents; mother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily Dixon</ENAMEX>; sisters and brother-in-laws, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ella</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel and Irene Fairbanks</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George and Don Dixon</ENAMEX>; two nephews, E.B. “Bud” <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Tunison</ENAMEX>; a grand-nephew, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>; and the beloved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lexi</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX> is remembered for his ever-present bright smile, genuinely congenial personality and the sight of him driving his faithful ’48 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chev</ENAMEX> pickup with a Boxer dog accompanying him in the front seat.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX> loved his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savior</ENAMEX>, the Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>, family, friends, attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>, visiting and enjoying good food. So we will do just that with those that care to join us attending the regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> services <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>, 16th and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>. Graveside services will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 25, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at Outlook Cemetery with Rev. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katy Haney</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX> officiating. We’ll have some good food and enjoy each other’s company at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snipes Mountain Restaurant</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>, after the graveside service.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RENA WERKHOVEN
Rena Werkhoven</ENAMEX>, 92, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> resident passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, April 19, 2004</TIMEX>. Our beloved mother, grandmother, and great-grandmother entered the eternal presence of her heavenly Father, and her Lord and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Savior Jesus Christ</ENAMEX>, whom she loved and was faithful to her entire life.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rena</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 19, 1911</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boyden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred and Nellie Zylstra</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 26, 1937</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Werkhoven</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rena</ENAMEX> and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>, were dairy farmers in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fall</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Duvall</ENAMEX> areas for many years until they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rena</ENAMEX> was also employed by City Bakery and The Palace Café in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> for over 15 years. She recently moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to live with her son and daughter.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rena</ENAMEX> was a faithful member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Christian Reformed Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> for 45 years, actively involved in the Golden Hour circle, various Bible studies as well as actively supporting Cascade Christian Home for the handicapped.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rena</ENAMEX> is survived by her daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Werkhoven</ENAMEX>; three sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leroy</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Libby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Carmichael</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>; five grandchildren; seven great-grandchildren; two sisters; and five brothers.
She was preceded in death by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>; three brothers; one sister; and one grandson.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawthorn Funeral Home Chapel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX>. Memorials can be given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mount Vernon First Christian Reformed Church Memorial Fund</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawthorn Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

