
<P ID="1">Canadian mayors trek to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> stumping to open borders to beef trade
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lethbridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, Can. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Tarleck</ENAMEX> and his colleagues refer to themselves as "the three Canadian amigos."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Weisbeck</ENAMEX>, mayor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, and Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garth Vallely</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Medicine Hat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, traveled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, where the first case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, or mad cow disease, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> had been found, to try and encourage the reopening of the Canadian-American border to trade of live beef.   The mayors know first-hand the kind of impact being labeled a "mad cow" country can have on the economy. Their towns and cities have felt the effects when the first Canadian case of mad cow disease was found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern Alberta</ENAMEX>, across the country from their communities, which are located in the southern part of the province.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> said that when the border was closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last March</TIMEX>, it put in jeopardy 100 years of infrastructure development created to support the beef industry. He said that for nearly 100 years the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> have been trading cattle freely.    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> said there are American slaughter companies that buy Canadian beef, that are waiting for the borders to be reopened. In the meantime they are going out of business. Grain growers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> that sell to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> are also closing shop, he said.   He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> isn't a Canadian issue, it's a North American issue.   When the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> and foreign markets turned their noses up at Canadian beef due to the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, the economy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lethbridge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Medicine Hat</ENAMEX> began to slow.   Prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> finding, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of Canadian beef was exported.   With less discretionary cash, the over-all economy is fading, they say.   Vallely said that people aren't going out and buying things such as shoes and machinery. He said trucks aren't running and people are being laid off of work.   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Medicine Hat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lethbridge</ENAMEX> have somewhat diverse economies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks</ENAMEX>, a town of about 12,500, is what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisbeck</ENAMEX> calls a "two-horse town."   One of the community's economic footholds is employing 2,400 people in the largest slaughter facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>. About <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the cattle slaughtered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> are from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>. About one-fourth of the employees working at the plant are bused in from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Medicine Hat</ENAMEX>, said Vallely. Vallely estimates that about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the jobs in his community are either directly or indirectly affected by the beef industry.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lethbridge</ENAMEX>, a community of about 75,000, known for multiple feed lot operations, has also been hit by the world closing its doors to Canadian beef.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> said one beef producer was told to get rid of 10,000 head of cattle before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States BSE</ENAMEX> case was confirmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He was advised to eliminate another 5,000 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.   Up until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian BSE</ENAMEX> outbreak the country had about 13 million head of cattle. About 6.5 million of those animals were in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>. Annually, the mayors added, 3.25 million cattle are slaughtered, about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of which where in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>.   The three mayors are trying to keep the border issue at the forefront of people's minds, afraid with all that is going on in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> the border issue will be swept under the rug until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   As full-time elected mayors, the men have decided that they can't sit back at their desks in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brooks</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lethbridge</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Medicine Hat</ENAMEX> and fix the situation. This is their second trip to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> to discuss trade issues. They visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> said with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>' war on terrorism and war in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, the presidential election and the focus on their own <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> case there are other issues in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> that can be put above reopening the border to the trade of live cattle.   "The people that are most directly impacted are the middle to small operators," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisbeck</ENAMEX>. "It will be left to the large operators."   "The family operated businesses are being hurt. If that's destroyed I'm not sure it will ever recover to what it was. I think we might have lost the heart and soul of the Canadian west," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisbeck</ENAMEX> added that there are also psychological effects as third and fourth generation farmers are losing their grandfather or great-grandfather's farm.   "We have family businesses that are shutting their doors after 50 years in business," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weisbeck</ENAMEX> added.   But, there has been a bright side in the Canadian beef. The Canadian citizen's support of the beef industry has gone up, say the mayors.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> said beef barbecue rallies have been held in support of the industry and in his community they had "The Great Canadian Cattle Drive" to support the industry.   "The employees in my city alone bought <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> in beef," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX>.   But it's not enough to revive the fledgling economy.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> said the issue should be resolved using science and reason and communication with global partners. He added that a revision to protocols should be made by both countries.   While the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> continues to work on trade negotiations to reopen the exporting of beef to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> and other countries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarleck</ENAMEX> said, "What we need to do is not just shuffle it (the border issue) aside. It's difficult to just open borders when you yourself are not open."      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

