
<P ID="1">Start honing skills, Hospice youth talent show scheduled
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The chairperson of the fifth annual Hospice Talent Show knows first-hand how Hospice can help a family.   "My two grandpas both had cancer and Hospice did wonders for my family," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Durfey</ENAMEX>, talent show chairperson.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> junior is in the midst of planning for the coming talent show, which is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 12</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium. Money raised in the talent show will benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice.   She got involved in the talent show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, helping chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan Visser</ENAMEX> in the planning process.   The Hospice Talent Show is a project sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> leadership class.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Five years ago</TIMEX> there were some people in the leadership class who thought we should do a service project," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>.   With the birth of the talent show has come a way for youths 12 to 19 to show off their talents and also a way to give back to Hospice, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, she said the leadership class has been very helpful in planning the talent show. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX> said members of the class have sought out donations and helped promote the event.   The talent show is open to students ages 12 to 19 from as far away as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and the Tri-Cities.   "We are trying to get more participants <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>.   She is encouraging people to start practicing for the audition, which will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 6</TIMEX>, from 2:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 p.m.</TIMEX>   "We want a variety of talents," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>. "It would be great to see juggling, dancing, singing, gymnastics and art. It will make it more interesting."   There is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> auditioning fee for those interested in participating in the show.   Currently, members of the leadership class are looking for donations of prizes to be raffled off at the talent show and also for cash donations that can be used as prizes for the talent show winners.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX> said they plan to present awards to the top three finishers in the talent show.   "We're looking to raise the most money possible for Hospice," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>. "We think the talent show will be a great way to help Hospice and draw people in our community together."   Tickets for the talent show will be available at the door on the day of the event.   Anyone wanting to donate to the talent show can contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>, 837-4428.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

