


<P ID="1">Commissioners vote to lower card room taxes
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Card rooms operating in unincorporated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, of which there currently are none, are no longer required to pay the county a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> tax of the establishment's gross receipts.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners voted to lower the card room tax. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> officials, card room operations, before the change, were required to pay taxes at a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> rate based on the amount of gross receipts multiplied by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX>. The amendment to the gambling tax ordinance lowers that percentage to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The change in the card room tax was prompted by a request from someone who is in the process of trying to set up a card room in unincorporated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner Tim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> said although the tax was lowered, the amendment is something commissioners plan to revisit when a card room is actually established in the unincorporated area of the county and is in operation. He said at that point, once the impact of the tax is realized, commissioners will have a chance to decide if the tax will stay at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> or be raised or lowered.
</P><P ID="8">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> explained that the taxes levied against card rooms by the county go into the county's general fund. He noted that at this point <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">86 percent</NUMEX> of the county's general fund goes toward criminal justice, so it is understandable that some of the funds raised would ultimately go to help pay for any extra law enforcement needed in regards to a card room.
</P>





 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




