
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/1/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> board discusses possible retreat dates
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members discussed dates for their upcoming retreat.
The board discussed two possible dates, with the final date for the retreat yet to be set. The possible dates include <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 23</TIMEX> and 24, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30</TIMEX> and 31.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves new parent partnership program
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> has decided to take a more direct approach when it comes to working to increase parent involvement through the district. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the board voted to adopt a new Parent Partnership Plan, which includes the establishment of a district task force, as well as the hiring of a parent coordinator that will work to increase parent involvement, as well as work with schools and programs to ensure that parents are satisfied with both.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX>, executive director of school and community resources, told board members that the parent partnership program will work in cooperation with the different programs the district already has in place, including Gear Up, Readiness to Learn, home liaisons, the parent information resource center, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Learning Centers</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Booster Club</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletic Club</ENAMEX>.
The new program will also work to ensure that parents feel welcome when they walk into the different schools, have access to information about parent involvement activities and have a good understanding of what is expected of students at each grade level.
The parent partnership program also includes a component that will give parents more direct access to administrators. Information from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> notes that the program will promote informal meetings between parents and administrators to help ensure open lines of communication.
The parent partnership plan is set to be implemented this coming school year.
</P> 
 
 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

