
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARIA MILANEZ
MARIA MILANEZ
Maria Milanez</ENAMEX>, 73, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 17, 2004</TIMEX>.
She is survived by her husband Elpidio Valencia; a daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Canderia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; two brothers and four sisters; 10 grandchildren and 10 great-grandchildren.
An obituary will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tuesday’s</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> pending at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Hill Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JAMES RILEY CORNWELL JR.
James Riley Cornwell Jr.</ENAMEX>, 61, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> went home to be with his Lord and Savior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, May 12, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kadlec Medical Center</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9, 1943</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Voss</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James R. Cornwell</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> was a passionate hunter, fisherman and outdoorsman. Whether he was hunting in a field in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> or he was on safari in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Africa</ENAMEX>, he was content. He was even happier when he came home and was able to share his outdoor adventures with his family.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> served in the U.S. Navy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1961 to 1965</TIMEX>.
He was a lifetime member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles Lodge</ENAMEX>. He loved to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX> and swap stories with all his good friends.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> worked at Flour Daniel at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> for 23 years as a maintenance manager. He was a much-respected boss, co-worker and friend.
 He loved to attend all his grandchildren’s sporting events – from football, basketball, baseball and wrestling, he was the number 1 fan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> was very well read and was a walking history encyclopedia. Anything his grandchildren couldn’t find on the Internet, they knew grandpa would know it.
He was also a very caring and compassionate person. He, along with his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX>, took care of his mother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace Aukamp</ENAMEX>, for six years making sure she was comfortable in her time of need.
 He was also a master storyteller. He could make a trip into the local supermarket sound like an adventure. He loved a good joke and always had one to share if you asked, and he had one to share if you didn’t. He had a nickname for everyone, and if he hadn’t given you one yet it was only a matter of time. From “Spamburger” and “Norman” to “Duke” or “Buzzard”, no one was safe. Everyone around him loved his sense of humor. We will miss it very much. When he was leaving a family reunion, barbecue or birthday party, he would always say, “I’m sure glad you had a chance to see me again”, leaving a smile on everyone’s face. He will be greatly missed by all.
 Survivors include his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Cornwell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; five sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James R.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>) Cornwell III of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Adam</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwell</ENAMEX> of Warden, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Anthony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornwell</ENAMEX> of Outlook, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickie</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teri</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beckie Cornwell</ENAMEX> of Warden; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Cornwell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Cornwell</ENAMEX>; four sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Schragg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Craig</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Cornwell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky Engles</ENAMEX>; a special friend, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Bancroft</ENAMEX>; 26 grandchildren, one great-grandson; and numerous nieces and nephews.
He was preceded in death by his parents; and two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Mallonee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Cornwell</ENAMEX>.
Viewing will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 17, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at Langevin-Mussetter Funeral Home, 1010 W. Yakima Ave, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 18, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at Langevin-Mussetter with interment to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Hills Memorial Park</ENAMEX>, with full military honors provided by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser VFW Post</ENAMEX> 3207.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

