
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> new principal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanwood High School</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A 17-year career in education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> came to an end at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of August</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX>, who was the former assistant principal/vocational director at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, was hired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2</TIMEX> as the new principal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanwood High School</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camano Island School District</ENAMEX>.   "I am absolutely thrilled to death," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> of her new job.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> recounted with a laugh how she accepted the job on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX> by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stanwood High School</ENAMEX> serves some 1,600 students freshman through seniors.   It is somewhat larger than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said the design of the high school is a bit different than it is here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The ninth grade class is in a different complex than the rest of the school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> has an estimated staff of about 130, including 85 certificated personnel.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> has been working in education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> for a total of 19 years. She spent 17 years in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX>, 13 as an administrator, and another two in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima School District</ENAMEX>.   "It was a wonderful opportunity," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX>. "I have always wanted my own building for years. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX> is an excellent school. They have a very strong staff and a lot of community support."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> saw the opportunity for a change after her daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley</ENAMEX>, graduated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> is excited about being involved with some new changes going on. She explained the district completed a facilities study and is looking at what to do with such district buildings as the high school, which was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said the district is also focusing heavily on the changes in educational requirements and looking at addressing the dropout rate for students.   "This is exciting," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX>. "I am not coming in during the middle of something."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> found out about the job when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Vegar</ENAMEX> accepted the job of executive director of instruction and learning in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> was the former principal at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> has family ties to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX> area. Her sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Burns</ENAMEX>, is superintendent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arlington School District</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX> are big football rivals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said when she went and met the football players a couple of days ago she told them about how important it is to win the rivalry game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   "That is going to be fun," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Principal Dennis Birr</ENAMEX> said he is sad to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> go, but didn't want to hold her back from a promising opportunity.   "She is going to be a real loss to us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX>. "She has been an instrumental part of the high school."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> was key in developing the outstanding vocational program <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has, one of the tops in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX>.   "I am going to miss her a great deal," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX>. "We didn't want to stand in her way. She deserves that opportunity."   Due to the fact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> had to give a short notice of resignation, the high school will be doing some administrative functions differently for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Ohler</ENAMEX> will be let out of a couple of her class periods to assume the duties of vocational director. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ohler</ENAMEX> completed a vocational director internship under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The administrative staff at the high school will be assuming a majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX>'s duties, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX>. However, Birr plans to utilize administrative intern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Maxwell</ENAMEX> to assist with the workload.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said she regrets leaving so late in the school year to accept the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX> job, but is eagerly looking to come back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to visit in the next few weeks.   "I have a lot of ties," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX>. "You can't leave some place after working for so long without saying goodbye. I didn't get to say goodbye."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

