
<P ID="1">Masked man attempts purse snatching
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX> is looking for a suspect that attempted a purse snatching this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>'s restaurant at 813 W. Wine Country Rd.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX>, just before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> an employee of the restaurant was leaving the business and heading out to her car, which was parked on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Fourth Street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the employee had gotten into her car, when a man came running toward her from behind some trees on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Davie Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the man, who is described as being about 5'8" tall and was wearing a gray sweatshirt and black ski mask, grabbed the car door, opened it and yelled at the employee.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>, the victim ended up outside of her car, and the would-be thief attempted to snatch the employee's purse. When the employee refused to give up her purse, the suspect reportedly hit her on the right side of the head, knocking her down before running away without the purse.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the police department is investigating the attempted robbery.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

