
<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">DON <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. BRUNELL</ENAMEX>   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> vetoed legislation that would have raised that state's minimum wage from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.75</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.25</NUMEX></NUMEX> per hour in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.75</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>.   Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor and Industries</ENAMEX> announced that our state's starting wage will increase to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.35</NUMEX> starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s minimum wage is already the highest in the country. It is no coincidence that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s unemployment rate is also among the highest in the nation.   On an hourly basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s minimum wage will exceed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 cents</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">65 cents</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.20</NUMEX>. The truth of the matter is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s new minimum wage is closer to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX> an hour and, for some industries, is now over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> per hour because of employer payroll taxes such as unemployment insurance, Social Security and workers' comp.   Unless <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s Legislature acts in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, our minimum wage will automatically go up again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>. These automatic increases were part of a union backed initiative that passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> which mandates annual cost-of-living increases in the minimum wage based on the federal Consumer Price Index for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Urban Wage Earners</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clerical Workers</ENAMEX>.   In other words, our state's minimum wage is pegged to wage-rates in Seattle without regard for regional differences in rural parts of the state.   Take <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>. for example. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>, the world's largest asparagus processing plant will close after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next summer</TIMEX>'s harvest because it cannot compete with cheaper Peruvian asparagus. Part of the reason is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s high minimum wage. So, while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> voters may have had the best of intentions when they passed the automatic wage increases, our high minimum wage has helped kill 50 full-time jobs and 1,000 seasonal jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>. That's not what the voters had in mind.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, a state with a heavy dependence on agriculture, would also be hurt by a minimum wage hike. In vetoing the recent legislation, Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> rightfully acknowledged that increasing the state's minimum wage makes it too expensive for employers to hire inexperienced workers or provide jobs for young people and seniors. And remember, small businesses create most of the jobs in this country. In essence, raising the minimum wage ever higher forces farmers and small businesses to cut jobs, replace workers with machines, or simply close up shop.   The problem will get worse unless legislators take bold action <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to change the law. They need to do four things to change our state's minimum wage law before it further erodes our state's job base:1) Repeal the automatic cost-of-living increase and raise minimum wage rates only when warranted; 2) Freeze the minimum wage at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.35</NUMEX> until competing states catch up; 3) Treat the minimum wage the same way we treat prevailing wages in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington-tie</ENAMEX> it to local economies; and 4) Establish a lower short-term training wage and a lower minimum wage for anyone under age 18 to encourage employers to offer job opportunities to disadvantaged and young workers.   While increasing the minimum wage may have seemed like a good idea, it has ended up hurting the very people it was supposed to help. That's called "the law of unintended consequences." Legislators need to change the law next session.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don C. Brunell</ENAMEX> is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

