
<P ID="1">Pre-school begins annual aluminum recycling drive
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/14/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Candyce Villalobos may only be 4-years-old, but she is already learning how to help others. Villalobos and her fellow students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran School</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> are again collecting the aluminum tabs from soda cans as a part of a school-wide recycling drive to benefit Ronald McDonald House of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> the students collected enough tabs to contribute <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> to Ronald McDonald House, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Kilian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran School</ENAMEX> director.   She said the children's recycling efforts helps to cover the housing costs of families who stay at the house, while their children undergo medical treatment at the Spokane hospitals, such as Shriners' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital</ENAMEX>.   "We only collect the tabs, not the entire aluminum can," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> of the children's tab drive.   She said the aluminum in the tabs are recycled and net 35¢ to 40¢ per pound. "All of the funds go directly to the Spokane house," she said.   "We started the recycling project in memory of a former student who had cancer," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said. She said the youngsters bring in their tabs in plastic sandwich bags or strung together on strings, necklace style.   She encourages the community to help the children in their efforts by saving their tabs.   Those interested in helping may do so by leaving bagged tabs at the school, located at the corner of Harrison Avenue and South 11th Street, during school hours, she said.   People wanting to know more about the recycling program or other Calvary Lutheran programs may attend an open house set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 15</TIMEX>, at the school. A potluck salad and dessert supper will be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> followed by entertainment by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Buck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> A tour of the classes and a book fair is also planned.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

