
<P ID="1">Turnovers cost <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> in loss to 1A Highland
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">COWICHE - Five turnovers were too much to overcome for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> football team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   The Class 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>, playing up a division against the Highland Scotties, ended up dropping the non-league game by a 27-7 count.   Mabton Coach D.J. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said his team can't expect to win a game coughing up the ball that many times, especially when they're playing a Class 'A' team.   "We had five fumbles and lost three of them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said. "You throw in the two interceptions...well, it was too much for us to come back from."   It appeared from the outset that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> was going to give the Scotties all they could handle. On the opening drive of the game, which started from their own 20, the Vikes marched the ball down to Highland's 42-yard line, from where Mabton QB Ryan Harris hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pablo Sanchez</ENAMEX> on a touchdown throw.   "That was big," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "It was an excellent start."   Highland countered, though, on the ensuing drive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who led all rushers in the game with 163 yards, capped off the Scotties' opening drive with a 21-yard scamper into the end zone. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAT</ENAMEX> that followed squared the contest at 7-all.   The Scotties scored again in the opening quarter, when Highland's punt return squad burst through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s line and blocked the kick. Highland recovered the loose pigskin in the end zone for its second TD of the night.   Highland took a 20-7 lead in the second quarter when one of its defenders picked off a pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harris</ENAMEX> and raced 48 yards to pay dirt.   The only other score Highland could muster against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> was a one-yard TD run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, that coming in the third quarter.   Despite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX>, who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s 1A rushing leader this season, gaining 163 yards on the ground on 29 carries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> felt his club did an admirable job against the scatback type runner.   "Our defensive line actually did a pretty good job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said. "There were seven times we tackled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buchanan</ENAMEX> in the back field."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> also pointed out that his defensive unit limited Highland's quarterback to just 27 aerial yards, on 6-of-10 passing.   Offensively, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> moved the ball at a better clip than did the Scotties. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> gained 207 offensive yards, compared to Highland's 197 total yards. Most of the Mabton yardage came on the ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Zavala</ENAMEX> was the Vikes' leading rusher, picking his way through the Highland defenders for 67 yards on 15 totes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Elizondo</ENAMEX> added a 33-yard rushing performance for the Vikes on eight carries, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> tallied 26 yards on nine touches. Through the air, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> threw for 75 yards on 3-of-14 passing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> gives much of the credit for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s offensive prowess to his offensive line.   "They played pretty well," he said of his linemen.   The bottom line, though, was turnovers. Any time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> got something started, the Scotties somehow came away with a takeaway.   In looking ahead to this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s game at home against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said his team will have to play assignment defense to shut down the visitors.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX> is a lot like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manson</ENAMEX>," he said. "They play a Wing-T offense, where there's lots of misdirection and they pull their guards a lot."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said a victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX> this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, coupled with a win at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Friday</TIMEX>, will give his Vikes (4-2, 5-3) the No. 2 seed into the South/Central 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> playoffs.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

