
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">STEPHEN RISDON PECK
STEPHEN RISDON PECK</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Risdon Peck</ENAMEX>, 62, of Shoreline died peacefully <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 9, 2004</TIMEX>, at home after a courageous five year battle against brain cancer.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was born on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7, 1942</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James and Maxine Peck</ENAMEX>. He grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where he hunted with his dad and brother, played high school football and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX>. After graduation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">U.S. Navy</ENAMEX>, where he represented his country aboard the U.S.S. Stonewall Jackson as a submarine sonar operator. During his service <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was selected as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“Outstanding Navy Man</ENAMEX> of the Month” by his command, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naples</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy</ENAMEX>. He was released from active duty with a Good Conduct Medal for service ending in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1965</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> developed his successful insurance career for over 30 years in insurance sales with Mutual of Omaha and Bankers Life Insurance.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was an active U.W. Husky football fan and enjoyed boating in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puget Sound</ENAMEX>, car racing, travel, fishing, gardening, cooking and entertaining family and friends at home.
Steve’s sense of humor, leadership and ability to inspire the best in others
will be missed.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> is loved and is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane</ENAMEX> and fiancée, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Utterback</ENAMEX>; daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erika</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> and fiancée, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Blackburn</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Melbourne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Australia</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen</ENAMEX>; step-daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Ryan</ENAMEX>; step-son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Ryan</ENAMEX>; brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Peck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adele Francis</ENAMEX>; sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn VanBelle</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Archie VanBelle</ENAMEX>; sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Solts</ENAMEX>; mother and father-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Fordice</ENAMEX>; brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Fordice</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kari Fordice</ENAMEX>; sister in law, Claudia Dennee and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Melroth</ENAMEX>; brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Fordice</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Fordice</ENAMEX>; 15 nieces and nephews; and 11 grandnieces and nephews.
A memorial service celebrating Steve’s life will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 14, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Free Methodist Church</ENAMEX>, 3200 3rd <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Avenue West</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX>, 98119. In remembrance, donations can be made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children’s Hospital</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Medical Center Foundation Guild Association</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

