
<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">One of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Carrillo</ENAMEX>'s oldest child's biggest fears is that she will graduate from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> at the same time he graduates from high school. With at least two years left, she doesn't think he has anything to worry about.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> is currently the secretary for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DK Bain Real Estate</ENAMEX>, but she has dreams of one day becoming a nurse. After 13 years of waitressing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> returned to secretarial work with the help of People for People.   "When I started their program I didn't know how to work a computer. I was really intimidated by computers," she said.   After attending business school in Albany, N.Y., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> worked as a secretary in upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>, where she lived prior to moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>. But as technology advanced and more secretarial work involved computers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> left her secretarial career.   "I was so intimidated by the computer I gave it up," she said.   Eventually she returned to secretarial work, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> said her first days at DK Bain she began freezing up the computers.   "I accurately type 100 words a minute," she said. "The computer couldn't keep up with me."   Since she started at DK Bain <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> has learned many skills on the computer. She now makes brochures and advertisements for the office, as well as updates listings on the computer and the office webpage.   "I work for more than one person in this office. I work for all the agents," she said.   Returning to her secretarial career helped her realize her life-long goal of becoming a nurse, which helped her make the decision to return to college.   "Ever since I was 15 I wanted to be a nurse," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX>. "Nursing is my dream."   To obtain that dream, besides working, she is a full-time student, starting her days as early as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> and taking classes well into the night. She has also taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> classes to help finish her degree. When she is finished, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> hopes to become an operating room nurse.   "I hope I am teaching my children that no matter how old you are you can obtain your goals and dreams," she said.   Although living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is far from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX>'s family, her mother lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> finds it home because it is where her three children and husband of three years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro</ENAMEX>, are living.   "I've never met such a caring community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX>. "I think the community is the best part of living here." But, she added, "The sunsets here are breathtaking."   She said she also enjoys how the orchards and vineyards climb the foothills surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. Occasionally, when she is homesick for upstate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> said she will drive to Chinook Pass to enjoy the fall colors, which remind her of home. Besides attending school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX> enjoys baking, cooking and crocheting. She has crocheted an afghan with a picture of deer on it and even an afghan displaying DK Bain's name and logo.   "I don't know how to follow a pattern, but I figure it out as I go," she said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

