
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Christian charity
This note is regarding verbal and written comments relative to legal and written indiscretions of our children.
The following are some reflections of my mother on the subject:
• Clean up your own house before you start trying to clean up your neighbors.
• Be careful what you say, it will come back to haunt you.
• If you want to be a judge or be judgemental, go to law school and learn the correct way to be a judge.
• In this country you are innocent until proven guilty.
• We all have our flaws and redeeming qualities.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">• Jesus</ENAMEX> said after he drew a line in the sand, if you are without sin, cast the first stone.
Or my mother would say, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Beth</ENAMEX>, are you being a sanctimonious hypocrite or is what I'm hearing misplaced anger?"
My mother was a wise, old gal and tried to practice Christian charity.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Beth Kirk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">YVCC party
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Student Council</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> campus thanks <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>'s local businesses for donating their time and services to our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX> party for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> graduates:
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s Market, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eli</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX>'s, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Herber</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dairy</ENAMEX> Queen, Just Ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rentals</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> from Automat Vending, Papa Murphy's, Pizza Hut, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Hankel</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Beef</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College Bookstore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Church</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nazarene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Valle</ENAMEX>, Domino's, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Schwab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NAPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Hancock</ENAMEX> from the Funny Farm, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tire Factory</ENAMEX>, Commercial Tire, Taco Bell, Ace Hardware and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Martinez</ENAMEX>, our DJ.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne Cohan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Privacy rules
I am the recipient of the trouble that the new medical privacy rules, or their intrepretation, can cause.
I entered (via emergency) the local emergency room, via ambulance, having suffered a stroke, and was unable to give them much information, if any. I had an emergency <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> capsule on my cupboard door and some information was in it, but not all and not all was correct. My son's name and phone number was included, but he wasn't called or informed of my whereabouts until they went to ship me to a stroke center, which turned out to be <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harborview</ENAMEX> in Seattle.
My son lives in Sultan. He was not able to get any information, even though he had durable power of attorney. According to an elder law attorney, that occured because of the medical privacy rules that came about because of two lawsuits. This clearly was not the intent of the broad ruling, to limit health information in cases of life or death.
Had I not been so determined to get better and back home, plus with God's intent, I would not be writing this letter.
Legislators, please, rethink the intent of the medical privacy rules and save us from death, because we will die if this misplaced interpretation is allowed to stand. Our own children, spouses, etc. are not being allowed to find out in time what is wrong with us if we can't tell them. The doctors will be put upon to make a quick diagnosis without information how to start.
Thanks for listening, but please do take heed.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Bird</ENAMEX>, retired nurse, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

