


<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">OMSI to present ‘Forces of Nature’
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PORTLAND</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - The ground moves, mountains explode, the sky turns black and violent—natural forces that helped create life on our green planet are also ready to threaten it. Science buffs are invited to encounter Earth's fiercest powers and the death-defying science behind them when "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces</ENAMEX> of Nature" premieres in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Museum of Science & Industry</ENAMEX>'s five-story Omnimax Dome.
</P>

<P ID="6">National Geographic, in partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Graphic Films</ENAMEX>, delivers an experience 10 years in the making—the awesome spectacle of earthquakes, volcanoes and tornadoes brought to the giant screen. From an active Caribbean volcano to the earthquake-tested antiquities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Istanbul</ENAMEX>, and finally on to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s "tornado alley," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forces</ENAMEX> of Nature" showcases three scientists aiming to improve our odds of surviving these terrifying events.
</P>

<P ID="7">Promoters of the film say National Geographic examines these inspiring and terrifying natural events with the trademark combination of scientific excellence, storytelling skill and human emotion that has defined National Geographic for more than a century. The result, they say, is the perfect combination of subject and medium—nature's grandest phenomenon captured on the world's biggest film format.
</P>

<P ID="8">The film, narrated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Bacon</ENAMEX>, is made possible by Amica Insurance and funded in part by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">Tickets to the show at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> museum are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.50</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.50</NUMEX> for children. The film will be shown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 8, 2004 through March 2005</TIMEX>. Show times will be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX>, and 1 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> Tuesdays through Sundays, with additional shows at 7 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> Thursdays through Saturdays.
</P>

 


<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alpaca</ENAMEX> show
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18-19</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Post FallS</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>
 - The third annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Alpaca Showcase</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 18</TIMEX> and 19, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Templin</ENAMEX>'s Resort in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Post Falls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">Admission is free to the event, which is sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Alpaca Association</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">The showcase is expected to attract more than 100 breeders of the native South American animal, which has been domesticated for more than 5,000 years in the southern hemisphere.
</P>

<P ID="14">More than 300 alpacas are expected to be shown and judged at the two-day event.
</P>

<P ID="15">In addition to learning more about owning and breeding alpacas, visitors will be able to see demonstrations of spinning and weaving of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">alpaca</ENAMEX>'s cashmere-like fiber, as well as a variety of educational displays.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




