
<P ID="1">Black Rock Creek golfers avenge <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> 'Ryder Cup' defeat to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX> linksters
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Score one for the home team!   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Stotz</ENAMEX>'s drive on the fifth hole <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> epitomized the whipping the Black Rock Creek Golf Course team laid on a squad from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Adams Country Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>.   In the second annual "Ryder Cup" style matches between the two Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> men's clubs, Black Rock Creek handily avenged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s defeat. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> golfers won easily, 18-1/2 to 9-1/2.   The Toppenish golfers won the first ever "Ryder Cup" simulated event in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> by a neck-and-neck 14-1/2 to 13-1/2 score. This time around, the Toppenish linksters weren't any match for the high powered Black Rock Creek team.   "We stayed close with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> the first day at our place on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Adams Club Pro Scott Galbraith</ENAMEX>. He explained that his team only trailed Black Rock Creek by an 8-6 score after the first 36 holes of play at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX>.   But when the venue for the match play competitions was switched to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> course on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the Black Rock Creek team stepped to the plate and knocked one out of the park.   "We couldn't stay with them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High grad who once called the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> course home. "The Black Rock golfers kind of ran away from us," he lamented, explaining that his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX> team won only two of the 14 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heads-up</ENAMEX> matches on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.   "I don't want to say <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeff</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>) loaded up his team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> wisecracked, "But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> I think you'll see a few more heavy hitters coming out of our camp."   Unfortunately for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>, he may have to turn to the likes of an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie Els</ENAMEX> or Vijay Singh to get past the Black Rock Creek team in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. That is, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty Stotz</ENAMEX> opts to return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> golf course.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> put the exclamation point on the outcome of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s competition when he stepped up to the No. 5 tee blocks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. A par-4, slightly dogleg right 326-yard hole, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> aced it with a drive that found nothing but cup.   "I know nobody has ever got a hole in one on a par-4 since I've been here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>. "And I haven't had anyone come up to me since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and tell me they've heard of that happening here before, so I've got to think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty</ENAMEX>'s is the first one ever here.   "The longer hitters usually leave themselves with a wedge into the green on No. 5," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> continued. "It's pretty unusual for anybody, even our longest hitters, to reach the fifth green with their drive, because usually the ball doesn't get the roll out in front of the green.   "For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ty</ENAMEX>'s drive to even make the green, then to drop it for an ace, it's pretty amazing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> said.   The golfer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> was pitted against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Inions</ENAMEX>, could only marvel at what he saw. Asked after his round how he fared, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inions</ENAMEX> said he wasn't at all displeased with how he played. Unofficially, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inions</ENAMEX> carded a one-over 73.   "But when a guy shoots a 69 against you, and scores a hole in one on a par-4, what are you going to do?," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inions</ENAMEX> quipped with a shrug of his shoulders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX> and his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud</ENAMEX>, also claimed one team point for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX>, in the best ball format. The father-son duo defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Girard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Jorgenson</ENAMEX> 2&1. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stotz</ENAMEX>'s lost their alternating shot contest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX> by a rather wide margin, 5&3 to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inions</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Comer</ENAMEX>.   Four of the Black Rock Creek golfers posted perfect 3-0 records in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 14-15</TIMEX> match-ups, one of whom was the club pro, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>. He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hall</ENAMEX> didn't have to play past hole 14 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, topping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comer</ENAMEX> by a 6&4 score in the best ball format. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> also teamed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> to knock off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Grace</ENAMEX> 5&4 in the alternating shot match-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heads-up</ENAMEX> match, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> was a 3&2 winner over his club pro counterpart, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, too, won all three of his matches. Besides teaming with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> for two of the wins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> was a 3&2 winner over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Greene</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> at Black Rock Creek.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Souta Nozaka</ENAMEX> was another of the three-time winners for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. A former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzaga University</ENAMEX> men's golf team member, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nozaka</ENAMEX> made short work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smythe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">heads-up</ENAMEX> match, winning 6&4. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nozaka</ENAMEX> was paired with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Stokes</ENAMEX> in both of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s matches. The duo was a 4&3 winner over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smythe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inions</ENAMEX> in best ball, and won by the same score in the alternating shot format against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smythe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorgenson</ENAMEX>.   Black Rock Creek's other three-time winner was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Guerrero</ENAMEX>. He and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Clark</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greene</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Komstadius</ENAMEX> by a 2&1 score in best ball play, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> bested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rogers</ENAMEX> by a 3&1 score in the alternating shots contest. Heads-up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerrero</ENAMEX> ended his match against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Buckner</ENAMEX> on No. 14, winning 5&4.   The Toppenish contingent had five golfers who posted 2-1 records. The two-time winners included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grace</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Barnick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Valdez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Schuler</ENAMEX>.   Besides tying the "Ryder Cup" series at 1-all and winning bragging rights for a year, the Black Rock Creek golfers will get to relish the thought that one of their flags is fluttering in the breeze over the ninth green at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX>.   "That's the payout," laughed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>. "The losing team has to fly one of the pin flags from the winners' home course on one of their greens for a full month."   The Black Rock Creek flag officially went up at the Toppenish course this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Wednesday</TIMEX>. Good naturedly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> to plant the flag on the ninth hole, "...so that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> can look out his pro shop window every day for a month and see our flag waving on his course," chuckled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>.   The bonus to the payout <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>, is that the flag will by flying this coming weekend, when the Toppenish course hosts its biggest invitational of the summer-the annual Round-up tournament for couples.   "When all those couples roll into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Adams</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX> and see our Black Rock Creek flag on number nine, that should generate some questions for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scottie</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> smiled.   "I had to answer a few <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when golfers at our course saw the Toppenish flag flying on number 18," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> added wryly.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bstory@hawkpress.com   Bob Story</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News   Mt. Adams Country Club PGA Professional Scott Galbraith</ENAMEX> (L) grudgingly assists <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Rock Creek Golf Course PGA Professional Jeff Bender</ENAMEX> with attaching a Black Rock Creek flag to the pin on the ninth green at the Toppenish course. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> and his team lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s "Ryder Cup" matches and the payout included flying one of Black Rock Creek's flags for a full month.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Ryder Cup results   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Best Ball   Jeff Bender & Bob Hall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott Galbraith & Ben Comer</ENAMEX> 6&4.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Stokes & Souta Nozaka</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steve Smythe & Eric Inions</ENAMEX> 4&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ty Stotz & Chad Stotz</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Girard & Dean Jorgenson</ENAMEX> 2&1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike Barnick & James Rogers (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Stitler & Pete Veliz</ENAMEX> 2&1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike Clark & Juan Guerrero</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Greene & Kirk Komstadius</ENAMEX> 2&1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keith Grace & Stan Buckner (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack Syverson & Buzz Blake</ENAMEX> 1 Up.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Javier Valdez & Dean Schuler (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randy Boast & Rudy Fernandez</ENAMEX> 5&4.   Alternate Shot   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jeff Bender & Bob Hall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scott Galbraith & Keith Grace</ENAMEX> 5&4.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">David Stokes & Souta Nozaka</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steve Smythe & Dean Jorgenson</ENAMEX> 4&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eric Inions & Ben Comer (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ty Stotz & Chad Stotz</ENAMEX> 5&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Stitler & Les Bender</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stan Buckner & Javier Valdez</ENAMEX> 4&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike Clark & Juan Guerrero</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BR</ENAMEX>) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Girard & James Rogers</ENAMEX> 3&1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Greene & Kirk Komstadius (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack Syverson & Buzz Blake</ENAMEX> 5&4.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike Barnick & Dean Schuler (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Randy Boast & Rudy Fernandez</ENAMEX> 5&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual Heads-up   Jeff Bender</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Galbraith</ENAMEX> 3&2.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Souta Nozaka</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Smythe</ENAMEX> 6&4.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob Hall</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Greene</ENAMEX> 3&2.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pete Veliz</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Girard</ENAMEX> 4&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keith Grace (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Stokes</ENAMEX> 4&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chad Stotz</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk Komstadius</ENAMEX> 4&3.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike Clark</ENAMEX> (BR) halved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ben Comer (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ty Stotz</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Inions</ENAMEX> 2 Up.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrew Stitler</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Jorgenson</ENAMEX> 2&1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Javier Valdez (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Boast</ENAMEX> 1 Up.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">James Rogers (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>)</ENAMEX> def. Buzz Blake 2&1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jack Syverson</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Barnick</ENAMEX> 6&5.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juan Guerrero</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Buckner</ENAMEX> 5&4.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rudy Fernandez</ENAMEX> (BR) def. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Schuler</ENAMEX> 3&2.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

