
<P ID="1">Holiday season brings rash of burglaries to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The holiday season wasn't quite as happy for several residents and business owners in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX> and 28 several burglaries were reported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX> with items stolen ranging from guns to televisions.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX> said seeing burglaries during the holiday season is nothing new.   "Everybody is out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> shopping," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Dec. 23</TIMEX>, a home in the 300 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Fourth Street</ENAMEX> was broken into. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said a small television, VCR and stereo system were stolen from the home. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police also received a call reporting an automobile theft. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> explained that the car was found and had been borrowed by a family friend.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> was a busy one for members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police force. Between the hours of 1:52 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:36 a.m.</TIMEX> three different businesses located within a close distance to each other reported being burglarized. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the owners of the first store, GTM Market in the 100 block of Ash Street, reported that their front door had been broken into and a bag full of cigarettes was found at the back of the store.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blehyl Farm Service</ENAMEX> in the 100 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> was also found with its front door broken in. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said 20 sets of pruning shears were stolen from the local store.   The final business in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> that was broken into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anderson Equipment Company</ENAMEX> in the 600 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the glass door was found broken, but nothing appeared to be missing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said since all of the businesses were broken into during the same time frame and were all located fairly close together the possibility of the same people being responsible for all three incidents is being looked into.   Businesses weren't the only buildings targeted on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> day</TIMEX>. A home in the 500 block of Grandridge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> was also broken into. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the television was stolen. He explained that the homeowner came home to find the sliding glass door open, as well as a window.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Dec. 27</TIMEX>, a home in the 300 block of Elm Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> was burglarized. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the homeowners came home to find their house had been broken into and three guns had been stolen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the guns consisted of two pistols and one shotgun.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

