35 28 12 11 20 42
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  The whole problem can be stated quite simply by asking, 'Is there a meaning to music?' My answer would be, 'Yes.' And 'Can you state in so many words what the meaning is?' My answer to that would be, 'No.'  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Copland</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>