
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> chambers plan spring festival
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Thousands of tourists flood the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> to sample the early release of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> wines during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> wine industry's annual Spring Barrel Tasting weekend.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, in order to lengthen the stay of visitors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Chambers of Commerce are marketing a series of activities designed to capture the attention of the wine enthusiasts.   "We hope to encourage tourists to come to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> a day early and stay a day longer," explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX>, tourism and promotions director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>.   As an encitement, the Valley Chambers have named <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16</TIMEX> through 25 as the Yakima Valley Spring Fling Festival, complete with a list of special events. The activities are designed to whet the curiosity of the influx of tourists and the local residents as well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> explained.   "We know thousands of tourists come into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, and most stay the entire three days of the barrel tasting event at local wineries," she explained.   "We want them to stay longer," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said the Valley Chambers are taking a page out of tourism plans designed by the communities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skagit Valley</ENAMEX>, which for years have hosted month-long Daffodil and Tulip festivals each spring, events which generates millions of dollars in tourism revenues.   "It's astounding the amount of money the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skagit Valley</ENAMEX> event generates, estimated to be in the area of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> annually," she said.   "There is no reason we can't do something similar here," she said.   "We already know the tourists are coming to sample our wines," she said.   "What we propose to do is give them something extra to make their stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> more memorable," she explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said communities that normally don't gear up for tourists until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> will be marketing activities, beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17</TIMEX> as part of the pre-barrel tasting schedule of events. She said events will continue through the barrel tasting weekend.   For example, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> community will dust off the paddle boats in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dino Park</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17</TIMEX> and 24, for those interested in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early spring</TIMEX> water recreation.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Mural Society</ENAMEX> will hitch up the horses to the mural tour wagons for tours of that city's vast collection of historical murals beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 19</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> will be hosting a Spring Fling Golf Tournament at Black Rock Creek Golf Course on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX>.   In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> will sponsor an asparagus extravaganza, to be held at the Black Rock Creek clubhouse.   Yakama Legends Casino will feature the "Godfather of Rock and Rock," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Brown</ENAMEX>, in concert on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18</TIMEX>, at the Toppenish casino.   In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Chamber</ENAMEX> is also involved in a salmon and buffalo feed at Legends on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> will be hosting a warehouse auction and wine tasting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>, and a spring flea market on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24</TIMEX>.   "We've created a special web site (www.springflingfest.com) listing the Spring Fling schedule of events to help visitors arrange their travel itinerary," she added.   "We realize it may take a while to get this event off the ground, but we're already planning events for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>," she add.   Among the festivities to be added to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> festival may be a bike ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> to Columbia Crest, and perhaps a shorter bike ride from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Dairy Fair on the backroads, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> suggested.   "Part of the idea for the festival is to create events not linked to the wine industry but which do involve families," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s event is just a beginning," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said.   For more information about the spring fling call the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> at 837-5939.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

