
<P ID="1">Annual flea market to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BICKLETON</ENAMEX> - Looking for antiques, books to read <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX> or fresh baked goodies? Head for the hills and the fourth annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX> ladies flea market, where a variety of goodies will be available for purchase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX>.   For the fourth year in a row the Goodwill ladies group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX> is holding a flea market on Main Street in the small community.   The main thoroughfare in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> will be blocked off for most of the day, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 11</TIMEX>, while vendors peddle their wares, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte Williams</ENAMEX>, one of the organizers of the event.   So far, 30 vendors have signed up to have booths, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, but more are expected to join the group <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>. The cost of a table is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> said a metal artist from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> and a jewelry vendor from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wash.</ENAMEX> will be part of the flea market, as will local artisans and collectors.   Tables will be lined with antique and collectable treasures, crafts and bird houses, in honor of the host community that is known as a bluebird sanctuary.   She said the local scout troop will be selling wine barrels to be used as planters and a variety of food will be on sale.   The Rebeccas will have homemade pie, doughnuts and coffee available at the lodge and tamales and Indian fry bread tacos will also be available for purchase.   "We have a lady who will be selling books <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> added.   In conjunction with the flea market, The Hen's Nest gift shop will be open that day.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> said that vendors are still needed for the flea market.   "We're hoping to have someone with fresh fruits and vegetables," she said. "Maybe they have apples or pears or fresh corn. Whatever is out now."   "We wanted to sponsor a flea market so it would have a variety of everything," she added.   After having a battle with the weather at the last flea market held more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> church ladies decided to move the annual event to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>.   "It looks like we're going to have good weather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>. "Maybe we won't have the rain and hail we had last time we had it in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>."   The flea market begins at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> and will run until vendors decide to shut down for the day, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>.   "<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Early morning</TIMEX> a crowd comes through and it's very busy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>. "After lunch it begins to slow down."   The flea market was started as a fund-raiser to help build a new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> school building for the church.   Besides the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> fee, which goes directly to advertising, in past years the ladies asked each of the vendors to give <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of their earnings at the flea market to the church. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> said, it will be optional.   Any money donated to the church will benefit the local congregation.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

