
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
State Grangeto administerfarm labor dispute resolution system
The state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> has entered into an agreement that calls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Grange</ENAMEX> to administer a statewide alternative dispute resolution system. Specifically, the program centers on employment disputes between farmers and farm workers.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX> will serve as the lead organization in what some are calling an "historic collaborative effort," which also includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Growers League</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>-based ag organization, the United Farmworkers of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> and two statewide legal aid programs. The aim is to create an alternative to costly litigation for resolving farm labor employment disputes.
"The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX> has a long history of bringing fresh perspectives and new ideas to problems facing farmers and those involved in the agricultural industry," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Hunt</ENAMEX>, president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Grange</ENAMEX>.
"Legal problems regularly arise in the labor-intensive fruit industry," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>. "We have a responsibility to find ways to identify disputes early on and get them resolved in a fair and efficient manner."
Echoing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>'s comments, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Growers League</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Director Mike Gempler</ENAMEX> noted that the cost of litigation of farm labor disputes can quickly reach into the tens of thousands of dollars.
"Our members need an alternative to litigation that can deliver fair outcomes, ensure compliance with applicable laws and minimize the risk of the extraordinary expense of protracted litigation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gempler</ENAMEX> said. "We believe that a collaborative alternative dispute resolution system will help achieve these ends."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick McIntyre</ENAMEX>, executive director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Justice Project</ENAMEX>, which is the state's largest legal aid provider, views the alternative system with optimism. He said his agency's clients seek a prompt and fair resolution of disputes that arise in the course of their employment.
"Living hand-to-mouth as they migrate from location to location, they have no interest in prolonging or escalating the adversarial level of legal disputes," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McIntyre</ENAMEX>. "We are working and will continue to work hard to find common ground with everyone involved in this undertaking."
Funding for the alternative dispute resolution system, totaling <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, was appropriated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state legislature this past session.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> creates register to reach minority farmers
Minority farmers and ranchers may now join a new voluntary register to receive information from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>.
The register was established at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of August</TIMEX>.
"The new minority farm register is an outreach tool to under-served farmers and ranchers who are not currently enrolled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> loan, farm or conservation programs," said USDA Secretary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann M. Veneman</ENAMEX>. "The register will create a shared outreach list that will help <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX>, community-based organizations and minority-serving educational institutions to communicate with minority farmers and ranchers."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veneman</ENAMEX> explained that by joining the register, minority producers will receive outreach materials, newsletters and program announcements from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> agencies and from other outreach partners.
Those wishing to join the register must sign and date an application that provides their name and address. Applications are available at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> service centers.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Air search nets 620 pot plants
Approximately 620 pot plants were seized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> during a marijuana eradication operation that was conducted high above the ground.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Hintze</ENAMEX> of the Law Enforcement Against Drugs (LEAD) task force, helicopters provided by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington National Guard</ENAMEX> and aircraft from the Washington State Patrol were used in the successful operation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hintze</ENAMEX> said seven different growing sites were spotted from the air.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 3</TIMEX>, eradication mission culminated a marijuana spotter training session sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX>. Officers from throughout the state who attended the class, along with detectives from the city/county narcotics unit and LEAD task force, as well as personnel from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> and uniformed officers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakama Nation Tribal Police Department</ENAMEX>, participated in the operation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hintze</ENAMEX> said additional marijuana growing sites are expected to be located at later dates.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

