
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton School Board</ENAMEX> approves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> operating budget
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BICKLETON</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton School Board</ENAMEX> approved an operating budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,565,143</NUMEX> for the 2004-05 school year, which is the same amount of money the small school district spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to educate the community's children.   During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s board meeting the school directors learned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s school budget varies little from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s operating costs.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Business</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Naught</ENAMEX>, the bulk of the budget is designed to provide education for an expected enrollment of 115 students in grades kindergarten through 12.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naught</ENAMEX> told the board the budget also contains an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX> increase for staff salaries.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Palmer</ENAMEX>, district superintendent, the budget provides salaries for 14 certificated staff, one administrator and six classified employees.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> said the budget revenues include the second portion of three-year No Child Left Behind grant money for the Reading First program.   "The budget is basically the same as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s budget," he said.   "Like other school districts, we are headed into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year two</TIMEX> of the federal Reading First program, so funds have been allowed for paying for a reading coach and the necessary materials for that program," he told the board.   He said former kindergarten teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Merfeld</ENAMEX> has been hired as the district's half-time reading coach.   The budget also includes funds to cover the cost of adopting the district's new math curriculum.   The district has also hired a new science teacher, a combination third-fourth grade teacher and a half-time kindergarten teacher.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> said the kindergarten program is a full-time program, even though students go to school all day, three days a week.   In addition, the budget has been adjusted to provide a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.4 percent</NUMEX> increase to cover the district's expanded special education program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naught</ENAMEX> said.   "We are currently seeking to hire a special education teacher for the program," she explained.   In addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> in operating costs, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton School Board</ENAMEX> approved an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Student Body Fund</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32,800</NUMEX>, with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX> placed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capital Projects Fund</ENAMEX>.   Since the district purchased a new school bus <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> is budgeted for transportation costs this coming school year. The district has no outstanding bonds, so no funds were placed into the debt service fund.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palmer</ENAMEX> said the district doesn't plan any capital projects in the coming year, adding that the only major project planned for the new year are improvements to the gym floor.   "That project is already done," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naught</ENAMEX> said the district spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> to replace the gym floor and plans to add some additional storage units later in the year. The money for the gym improvements came from the district's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASB</ENAMEX> fund.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton School District</ENAMEX> will begin its new school year <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

