31 1 10 15 40 38
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Learn to get in touch with the silence within yourself and know that everything in this life has a purpose.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisabeth Kubler-Ross</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>