


<P ID="1">Street racing a problem
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Imagine sitting in your home late at night and all of a sudden the windows start shaking and the foundation of your house is rattling. Then you open the door only to see a group of cars racing down your street in something that resembles a scene out of the movie "Fast and the Furious."
</P><P ID="5">   This was the scenario <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX> presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> also brought with her a petition signed by 41 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents demanding that the city do something about what she views as a growing problem with street racing in residential neighborhoods.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said when she first started coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meetings <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members told her and other citizens to contact the police department when a criminal activity is taking place.
</P><P ID="8">   But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said the local police department has been anything but helpful lately.
</P><P ID="9">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said her mother didn't receive much help from a dispatcher at the police department when she called to report an incident involving street racing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said her mother called the police department to report an incident involving racing cars.
</P><P ID="10">   "The dispatcher told her, lady, you should just go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting (to voice your concerns)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   The problem involving racing cars has continued to increase, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>. She has been trying to get citizens to ban together to address the problem, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said there has been little help from law enforcement personnel.
</P><P ID="12">   "We are fearful of retaliation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>. "We are fearful the police force is actually afraid of the lawbreakers."
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said the issue with the racing vehicles needs to stop before someone gets hurt.
</P><P ID="14">   "These vehicles are going 70 miles per hour plus," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said she has been told by people the drivers involved with racing cars are imitating what they see in the movies. She said the cars have boom box speakers that rattle residents' windows at all hours of the day because they are so loud.
</P><P ID="16">   Several of the incidents have happened in the neighborhood of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   One other resident besides <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> also came before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and spoke about how street racing is a problem in the area of Newhouse Avenue.
</P><P ID="18">   "They do it at night. They do it in broad daylight. This has just become too much," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>. "If any child gets hurt because of these speeders, this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has been put on notice."
</P><P ID="19">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> referred the matter to staff to further research and report back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




