


<P ID="1">Choose right side
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">I have been very pleased to see the overwhelming level of support for President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in our community during this election season. Thankfully, most of us realize the need for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s leadership, resolve and clarity during this critical time in our history.
</P><P ID="4">   While <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">re-electing</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is certainly important, we also need to grab the opportunity to affect some positive change in our state and county. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> has what it takes to solve the serious challenges facing us due to decades of liberal governors and out of control agencies. We need to get every vote we can possibly get in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> to counter King and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pierce</ENAMEX> counties. Make sure that you get those friends, neighbors and family members of yours who only vote once in a while out to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   While we're out banging the drum for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>, let's show our county commissioners the meaning of the word accountability. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Swanson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leita</ENAMEX> will make a dynamic team on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Commission</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX>'s vision, combined with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swanson</ENAMEX>'s common sense no-new-taxes approach will help our county dig out from under the white elephant that threatens to crush <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>'s future.
</P><P ID="6">   Unfortunately, not everyone utilizes logic and intellect when voting. These elections are going to be won by the side that pushes the hardest. Let's make sure it's the RIGHT side.
</P><P ID="7">   /s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Werkhoven</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




