


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Service Commission</ENAMEX> amends lay-off rules for fire department
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Service Commission</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> changed the rules to how a personnel reduction will be handled by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Commissioners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rey Pascua</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Hughes</ENAMEX> cast their votes in favor of making the changes to the rules. The third Alderwood commissioner didn't arrive at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s meeting until after the vote was taken.
</P><P ID="6">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>, there was question as to the language of the rules dealing with lay-offs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Service Commission</ENAMEX>'s last meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said because of budget constraints <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last December</TIMEX> the city was forced to eliminate the deputy chief position in the fire department.
</P><P ID="7">   "This brought up the question, what happens under civil service rules?," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   He said the language of rule 14, which deals with laying off employees, has been described as murky. After working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Hazzard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Dent</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Jones</ENAMEX> of the fire department, a revision was written which will help clarify the rule, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>, who added that an example is also included.
</P><P ID="9">   The rule now states that in cases of lay-off, temporary employees will be laid-off first. Among regular employees, the least senior employee will be reduced in rank to the next lower classification. The person in that classification will be reduced in rank to a lower position until the person with the least seniority in the lowest rank is laid off.
</P><P ID="10">   Written into the rule as an example, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>, is that if the position to be reduced is battalion chief, the least senior battalion chief will be reduced in rank to captain. The captain with the least seniority will be reduced in rank to firefighter and the firefighter with the least seniority will be laid-off.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the firefighter who is laid-off will be added to a re-employment list, which will be valid for two years.
</P><P ID="12">   Originally, the rule dealing with re-hiring said that employees would be able to return to work if their certifications were kept up to date, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said there is a problem with that since when an employee is laid off they lose their ability to maintain certification. Instead, the rule reads that the employee will have to acquire the certifications within six months, or a time approved by the city manager, when hired back. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kunker</ENAMEX> said in some cases there are tests that are only held every few months and an employee could potentially miss the date of the test depending on when they are re-hired. An employee would also be required to pass a physical agility test.
</P><P ID="13">   With the changes to the civil service rules, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> decided to wait until the next meeting to approve the revisited general rules and regulations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Civil Service Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> did approve changing its meeting time to the second <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> of every month, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting the commissioners also approved the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>'s request for an exam for lateral and entry level patrol officers.
</P><P ID="16">   "We're anticipating possible openings within the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX> or two," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "We would like to have a list available if we choose to fill those positions," he added. "We do not currently have an active list."
</P><P ID="18">   The commissioners voted unanimously in favor of holding testing. The civil service exam for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 28</TIMEX>. Sign-ins will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> with the physical agility testing beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX> The oral boards will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX> that afternoon.
</P>





 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




