


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area lawmakers indicate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> session a bust
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Taxpayers may not have got their money's worth with the recently concluded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> legislative session in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   That was the message hinted at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX> by three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area lawmakers-Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> and Representatives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX>. All three Republicans said the lack of action in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> came at a time when changes were needed.
</P><P ID="6">   Specifically, the three Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> legislators are not pleased that issues such as reforming the state's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Labor & Industries Department</ENAMEX> stalled, or that lawmakers couldn't even get a bill designed to curb the state's escalating minimum wage to the floor for a vote. The three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area elected officials also noted that little was done in clearing up questions on water relinquishment and instream flows. Even less was accomplished, said the three, in addressing tort reform.
</P><P ID="7">   So, how did the state's lawmakers decide to deal with all these burning issues? Simply put, said the three, they were all placed on side burners and earmarked to be researched.
</P><P ID="8">   "You might say this was a session where no study was left behind," smirked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, who operates a fruit orchard near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> when he isn't serving his constituents in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "There was no will to act," he continued. The lack of action by their peers "...reflects the frustration we had over the session," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said, with both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> nodding in agreement.
</P><P ID="10">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next year</TIMEX>, to avoid a repeat of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> session, the three said it is imperative that Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX>'s replacement be a Republican. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>, a two-term Democrat, has already announced that he will not seek a third term as governor.
</P><P ID="11">   "The key part of the whole picture is having a Republican governor in there," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> stressed. The freshman legislator, a hop grower who farms just to the south of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will throw its support behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Issaquah</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said is a strong ag supporter, resigned from the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past December</TIMEX> so he could fully commit to campaigning for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>'s position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> calls <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> "...a stellar candidate."
</P><P ID="13">   The three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area politicians also note that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> has identified 12 key races for the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Democrats enjoyed a six-seat advantage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> this past session. Both, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> will be seeking to retain their House Republican seats <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, a retired educator, is not up for re-election to the Republican controlled state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   In terms of what lawmakers did get accomplished in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, the three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area legislators wincingly acknowledge that a compromise was hammered out on the supplemental budget. The budget that was sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> came out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, but none of the three local lawmakers are all that thrilled that the budget includes only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$305 million</NUMEX> in reserves.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, who said crafting a new two-year budget will be a top priority <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, is among many who are concerned that the state will have to deal with a general budget deficit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   Another area of spending that worries <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> is the budget of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Labor & Industries</ENAMEX>. They said it is almost a foregone conclusion that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> employers will face another double-digit increase in the premiums they pay in to L&I.
</P><P ID="17">   The entire structure of L&I needs overhauling, say the three.
</P><P ID="18">   "Internal changes would fix <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the problems," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>. He cites the need for an annual auditing procedure, and such a bill cleared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Unfortunately, he said, the bill died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce and Labor Committee</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, too, sponsored a bill that addressed two recent state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> cases that have increased L&I benefit costs, in essence providing administrative efficiencies. Under terms of the measure, wages would be calculated by using the highest four consecutive quarters in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX>. Fringe benefits would not be included in the calculation of wages, and compensation would be paid for lost wages at <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65.5 percent</NUMEX> of a worker's wage. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> passed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>'s bill, but like the audit measure, it died in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Commercial & Labor Committee</ENAMEX>. Three other L&I reform bills that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> sponsored-stopping the misuse of worker and employer premiums, requiring timely reports for on-the-job injuries and giving self-insurers more authority over their claims-all passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, but all were killed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Commercial & Labor Committee</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   "Major reforms didn't occur," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said. "There was no real opportunity," he added, referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>'s actions to kill his bills in committee.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> calls the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept. of L&I</ENAMEX> "dysfunctional." He said claims are handled too slowly, the process is expensive and the state agency doesn't serve either employers or employees adequately.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> is just as frustrated with the inaction taken on water issues that came before legislators. He blames <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> for doing nothing to push the issue to the forefront. He also said too much compromise was needed to get anything accomplished, "...and then, not even a study was approved on relinquishment," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="23">   The three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area lawmakers are also deeply disappointed that nothing was done to slow down the state's escalating minimum wage. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state has the highest minimum wage in the nation, at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.16</NUMEX> an hour. Again, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> couldn't get a bill dealing with the issue to the floor for a vote.
</P><P ID="24">   "I think it will be addressed eventually," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, "The question is, how many jobs will be lost before it is."
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> vowed the minimum wage issue will be a top priority come next session.
</P><P ID="26">   Also high on the three local legislator's list of priorities is tort reform. Exorbitant insurance premiums and large monetary awards by juries and judges are bankrupting the medical industry, they say. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said the goal is to reign in the skyrocketing premiums and limit the large settlements.
</P><P ID="27">   "If we don't, we won't have many physicians left practicing here in the state," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="28">Webmaster
</P><P ID="29">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




