
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Vote yes for local bond/levy issues
It is our pleasure to endorse the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> special levy/bond issues. We know that the passage of these issues will make a tremendous difference in the education of all of our students. We have seen the positive results of the previous special levy. The purchase of curriculum materials and supplies, safety officers and technology enhancements alone have been a wonderful assistance to our students and staff.
We ask for your consideration and yes vote on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> bond and special levy. Taxes will increase 20¢ (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.41</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.61</NUMEX></NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of home valuation). The district will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,744,357</NUMEX> annually for four years. Also, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> in new construction and modernization projects will occur.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> voters' approval of these issues will support students and building projects for years and years to come. We need your help!
Please vote yes—bond and levy—Feb. 3.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Quigley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Roedel</ENAMEX>, Outlook
</P> 
<P ID="4">Vote yes
Be sure to vote yes on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> levy and bond.
By doing so we improve our district. With the yes on the levy we get matching state funds and this will help with classes and materials.
The bond gives us more and better schools, as we are growing and need the space. A good working area creates a better atmosphere for our kids to learn in.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> has not deceived us on funding before, and is now helping to make the district even better for only a few cents per thousand (of assessed valuation).
As a past school director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I</ENAMEX> have kept an eye on what happens in the district and feel very comfortable saying, "Vote yes on the levy and bond. It really is the cheapest way to improve our district."
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene McIntire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Beef rally
I would like to take this opportunity to thank all the individuals who attended the rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 10</TIMEX>. The outpouring of support given to the cattle industry and the community during this difficult time was greatly appreciated.
We would especially like to thank Clear Channel Broadcasting for its efforts in coordinating this community service event, which brought more than 2,600 visitors to our small community. With the cooperation of the school district, various law enforcement agencies, city staff and the overwhelming positive attitude of the participants, this was a very successful event.
A special thank you to all our local, state and federal representatives and members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cattleman</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> who braved the weather to attend and support this rally. We also want to acknowledge the following participants: Van de Graaf family, Kallenberger family, Lommers family, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s Meats, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>'s Valley Meats, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coca Cola Co.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">M&M Catering</ENAMEX> for donating their time and products.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">Blood drawing
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies Society</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran Church</ENAMEX> sponsored a very successful blood drawing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 6</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karon Kilian</ENAMEX> was the chairperson.
The snow was falling all day and it was very cold. But that didn't stop the people from coming in to donate the much needed blood. We had 66 presenters and two first-time donors. Three were unable to give, leaving 63 units collected. Because of their generosity, 126 people will have another chance at life. Without you this drawing would not be possible.
A special thanks to the sponsors for the delicious cookies and juice, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> for the use of its hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington Corrugators</ENAMEX> for putting out the signs and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> for the wonderful publicity.
Many thanks to the following volunteers: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtis Lang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ella Mae Lochner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Benedetti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Vessey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Slaight</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Reihs</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine Means</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX> to see you at the next blood drawing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 2</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Handy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> blood drawing chairman
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

