


<P ID="1">Minimum wage may go up, but entry level jobs will be impacted say local businessmen
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> restaurant workers will be seeing a slight increase in their pay envelopes as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1</TIMEX>, the date the state minimum wage will rise to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.16</NUMEX>. But the increase, designed to help create living wages for entry level workers, may be more of a problem than a help to restaurant workers, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Restaurant Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WRA</ENAMEX>) President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Vosberg</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vosberg</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> restaurants are in an economic crisis, as costs rise and profit margins fall. Restaurants are being forced to cut labor costs, he said.
</P><P ID="6">   He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WRA</ENAMEX> will propose reforms to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> legislature to give relief to help restaurateurs cope with the nation's highest minimum wages.
</P><P ID="7">   He said because waitresses usually receive tips, in addition to a base wage, the association is seeking to have tips included as a part of the worker's minimum wage.
</P><P ID="8">   "The federal government and 43 states already count tips towards the calculation of minimum wages," he explained.
</P><P ID="9">   Even the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Department of Labor and Industries</ENAMEX> counts tips as wages when calculating workers compensation benefits, he explained.
</P><P ID="10">   "However, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> restaurants are prohibited from counting tips toward the state minimum wage payments," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vosberg</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   "We are proposing the state allow a restaurant owner to pay a tipped employee <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the state minimum wage as their base wage, so long as the employee makes at least the minimum wage in tips alone," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vosberg</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   But while that may work well in Seattle and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> areas, 14-year veteran waitress <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerrianne Mata</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> isn't sure that would be practical in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "We have to claim <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> when we report our tips on our (federal) income tax reports, but we don't always make <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> in tips," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mata</ENAMEX>, who has worked the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past six years</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunny Spot Restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   "It really doesn't average out even though most of our clients are good tippers," she said.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunny Spot Restaurant</ENAMEX> owner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Hooks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> fears the damage of the new wage increase will not be on the existing labor force, but any new hires he may consider.
</P><P ID="16">   Entry level workers' chances of getting jobs will be limited if they are to be paid the same as experienced workers, he said.
</P><P ID="17">   "One good waitress is worth two green waitresses while they are learning the job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hooks</ENAMEX> said. "But you have to pay both the same."
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hooks</ENAMEX> said the increases won't hurt his popular <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway eatery, but he can see where it will hurt fast food restaurants which rely on unskilled labor for its labor forces.
</P><P ID="19">   "Kids trying to get a job may have more difficulty getting the minimum wage job with the increases,"' he said.
</P><P ID="20">   The restaurants will be forced to pay beginning fast food workers the same wage as some waitresses who have been working for several years, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Stokes</ENAMEX>, owner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger Ranch Restaurant</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway.
</P><P ID="21">   "I try to get my minimum wage workers off that spot as quickly as possible," he said.
</P><P ID="22">   "But I also expect more than minimum work before I pay a bit more. I'm very selective about who I hire," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stokes</ENAMEX> added.
</P><P ID="23">   He fears if restaurant owners are forced to pay more for inexperienced, beginning workers, consumers will have to get used to paying a bit more for their meals, he said.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Thompson</ENAMEX>, owner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie</ENAMEX>'s Country Kitchen, said the possibility of using a waitress's projected tips as part of her income may be a good thing.
</P><P ID="25">   "We used to be able to do that," he said. "I hope the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WRA</ENAMEX> will be able to get the legislature to change the minimum wage law," he said.
</P><P ID="26">   "Many restaurants simply cannot continue to incur additional salary costs and hope to say alive," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thompson</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="27">   The increase, which raises the minimum wage of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.90</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.16</NUMEX></NUMEX>, is part of an automatic minimum wage increase which has occurred each of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past six years</TIMEX>. Restaurants will also absorb worker's compensation tax increases of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, in addition to the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">26 percent</NUMEX> increases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="28">   "They are paying more in unemployment insurance tax, in addition to the ever increasing health and business liability insurance premiums," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vosberg</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="29">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vosberg</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WRA</ENAMEX> proposals are similar to those proposed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, which received substantial support from legislators, but were not adopted.
</P><P ID="30">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="31">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="32">Webmaster
</P><P ID="33">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




