


<P ID="1">Pediatrician abandons island life to work at local clinic
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Moving across a large blue ocean from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> wasn't as big a move for Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> as one might think.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX>, a new pediatrician at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Farm Workers Clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Health Services Corp.</ENAMEX> He explained that the organization helps pay for medical school if a student agrees that after graduation they will work in places that are short of doctors. This is how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> came to live in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX>, who is originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX>, graduated from medical school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vanderbilt University</ENAMEX>. He explained that he chose to go into medicine for a combination of reasons, including a sense of idealistic values and an intense interest in science. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbaur</ENAMEX>'s father and grandfather are also doctors.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> said working through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Services</ENAMEX> organization has worked out well for him.
</P><P ID="8">   "What I wanted to do was work in underserved communities," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> said. "It allows me to work in the environment I want to work in."
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> explained that the way <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Services</ENAMEX> works is that hospitals and clinics apply to be put on the organization's list, which doctors who are part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corp.</ENAMEX> look at when deciding where they want to work.
</P><P ID="10">   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX>, the move to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> was one he chose to make because he wanted to bring his family, including his wife and two young children, back to the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   Now that he's worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> for the better part of a year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX>, who started at the local clinic in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2003</TIMEX>, said he has found himself enjoying the experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> said he now has his own list of patients, but also sees walk-ins regularly.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> said he finds it rewarding to work in pediatrics because of the resilience of children.
</P><P ID="13">   "Pediatrics [offers] the opportunity for a child to walk in very sick and in the short term to walk out completely better," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> said. "It's a satisfying population."
</P><P ID="14">   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> works every day at the Grandview Farm Worker's Clinic, he chose to move his family to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. He explained that all doctors from the local clinic admit their patients to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX>, and therefore each doctor spends a fair amount of time at the Prosser facility.
</P><P ID="15">   "It's easier to be closer to the hospital," he said.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gaensbauer</ENAMEX> said even though he is still working through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Services Corp.</ENAMEX>, he will likely be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Farm Workers Clinic</ENAMEX> for at least three years.
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




