
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/24/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
DSN doinga super job
I really enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>. I look forward to each weekday afternoon when my lovely paper girl puts my paper in my screen door handle so I don't have to stoop over to pick it up off my porch. It's not easy to bend over any more.
I enjoy the insert each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> (American Profile) with a new recipe and interesting reading about various subjects.
I'm informed about things that happen in and about our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, good and bad.
Thank you <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and all the ones who make it possible.
Only one fault, though. Wish the crossword puzzle was a little easier.
All of you are doing a super job!
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernice Seward</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Support appreciated
To all who attended the Young Life brunch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Life Committee</ENAMEX> would like to thank the community for its support of our recent brunch. Good food and good friends provided an inviting atmosphere for everyone and we were blessed by your attendance.
Special thanks are gratefully extended to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navarro's Community Center</ENAMEX> for its spacious and comfortable facility, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX> and Ayner Browning and crew from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prudential Valley Investment Properties</ENAMEX> for cooking up a storm, the numerous table hosts who filled our tables with family and friends, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Cromwell</ENAMEX> for singing so beautifully and inspiring us all, students speakers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Clark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Spilles</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Flores</ENAMEX> for sharing their testimonies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Bosma</ENAMEX> and crew for gathering awesome silent auction items and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Van Slageren</ENAMEX> for the star-studded decorations.
See you all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>!
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Life Committee</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

