
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> honor students who go 'above and beyond' recognized
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> students expect to be singled out for honors based on their academics or performance on the athletic field. But few are ever honored for simply being great volunteers. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Assistant Principal</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> has decided that oversight must change.   "We have a lot of students who receive no recognition for being helpful to the point that they go 'above and beyond' what is expected of them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> explained.   In what she hopes will become a regular awards ceremony, four <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High school seniors were honored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> for their outstanding contributions to their school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> seniors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Kellogg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Wells</ENAMEX>, Alaina Hull and Isley Gonzalez were cited as being exemplary examples of young people who, when asked to take on a extracurricular project, go well beyond what is required of them in order to do a good job.   They were honored for special projects on which they organized and created for which they received no grade. "These were projects that will help to improve the climate of their school," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> explained.   To earn the "Above and Beyond" distinction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellogg</ENAMEX> helped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> put together a mini-movie, using school equipment to showcase the high school's diverse vocational-education program.   "It (the film) used "imovie" technology to include sound effects, music and sound for a very professional film presentation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said.   "His efforts were well beyond the traditional slide or power point presentation we've used in the past," she said.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner</ENAMEX>'s work is an incredible example of film making," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said.   She presented a five-minute version of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellogg</ENAMEX>'s efforts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. In addition to the five-minute board presentation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellogg</ENAMEX> created a longer 20-minute DVD of the film, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> gave to the board members to take home to view at their leisure.   Schuette plans to use <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellogg</ENAMEX>'s 20-minute version for school orientation programs in the future.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said the "Above and Beyond" award is based on the work the students did as community service projects. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, Hull and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>, their award was based on work they did in organizing materials in video form for the high school eighth grade transition programs. Included in their "imovie" presentation was a tour of the high school, interviews with principals and teachers. The movie recorded on a DVD will be used at eighth grade transition and parents night programs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said.   "It's a motivational film," she explained.   The girls included information about club and other extra curricular activities available at the high school on the DVD.   "We are excited to be honoring these students, who are leaving a visual legacy of their skills and talents behind," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> said.   "It is also exciting to see them taking advantage of the top-notch technology we have available at our high school," she added.   "All four students deserve our highest praise," she added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

