
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> garbage rates on the rise
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/20/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> residents will soon find themselves paying more to have their garbage hauled away. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted to increase the current garbage rate by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>. This means the residential rate will increase from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.40</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.24</NUMEX></NUMEX> a month.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX>, the increase will still leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s garbage rate as one of the lowest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> garbage rate hike will go toward funding a community clean-up program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Public Works Director Cus Arteaga</ENAMEX> explained that he set up a budget of approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> for the program. The rate increase will bring in approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28,800</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> told council that the new program will include four steps that will help clean up the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. The first step will be to advertise the one-week program, which is currently scheduled to take place during the week of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said he budgeted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> to help pay for posters and advertising.   During the clean-up week people will be allowed to put any debris out near their garbage can for free pick-up by a city crew. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said there will be an additional charge to pick up items such as tires, refrigerators and air conditioners, but that cost will simply cover the transfer station fee and will likely be added to the homeowner's water bill.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said the second step in the implementation process includes the creation of a clean-up committee, which will be made up of representatives from the public works, police, parks and recreation and code enforcement departments, as well as a member of city council. He explained that the committee will be in charge of doing a community-wide survey of local properties looking for potential violators. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said a list of any properties the committee feels needs to be cleaned up will then be presented to the city's code enforcement officer, who will send the property owner a letter with information about the coming community clean-up week.   Another way the program will aim to clean up the community is through the use of volunteers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said the third step in the program is to establish a volunteer work day on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, May 21</TIMEX>. The volunteers will work to clean up the downtown corridor, from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> south to Fourth Street and from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandridge Road</ENAMEX> east to Birch Street.   The final step of the program will include maintenance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said he would like to assign an employee to monitor residential neighborhoods to ensure that clean-up efforts continue in front yards and alleys.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

