
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> deputy secretary treks to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> for chat with farmers
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - Gathering input from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> farmers and agencies working with local farmers, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> Deputy Secretary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Moseley</ENAMEX> listened and tried to answer questions at a specially called meeting held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.   "I have one primary purpose here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX>. "It is not to answer every single one of your questions, but rather to help you find the answers to that question."   He said his commitment to farmers is to have someone to serve those in need, and he invited those who feel they aren't receiving the service they need to e-mail him personally.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> called the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> conference a showing of democracy where concerns are brought straight to the top.   The listening session was dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Better Service</ENAMEX> Through Public Participation."   "From the top of the USDA the message has been sent. Things are going to be different without diminishing services," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> said that some insinuated that the meeting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> was politically motivated, which he added, "...irritates me."   "If we were here for political reasons you'd see a different kind of meeting," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> said the sessions that have been held in other parts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> have already brought changes in the USDA.   For two hours <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> and other USDA officials directly answered concerns raised by those in attendance.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> farmer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melbern Krueger</ENAMEX> questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> on what is going to be done with the shrinking number of farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX> said there are 3.2 million farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> and at the present rate in the next three to five years the number of farmers will be cut in half and another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> will retire.   "We're headed for a crisis in this country," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX>. "Unfortunately, we are now importing food from third world countries."   With the current state of terrorism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX> said he is concerned that ways to poison the country's food supply will be found.   He added that the North American Free Trade Act (NAFTA) has hurt farmers and that water storage is an issue directly affecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX> said there is a need for tax-free exemptions for food producers.   "It costs us more to produce a product than the value we're getting out of it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX> said with the price of apples in the supermarket at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.49</NUMEX> a pound, the farmer is only getting about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 cents</NUMEX> per pound.   "Young people are not going into farming. My son is one of them. I do not want him to go into agriculture," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> responded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krueger</ENAMEX> saying that a great majority of agricultural products in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> are dependent on NAFTA.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> said even <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of his family's pork and soybean operation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> is dependent on trade.   "My grandfather told me something a long time ago," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX>. "His comment to me was the land will always be farmed as long as there are resources available."   One of the resources of major concern, not only in the Western states, but across the country, is water.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> believes there is something that pulls people to agriculture. He said he has a daughter who runs the family farm with her husband, and another son who wants to become a farmer.   Both of his children watched as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> and his wife in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> lost <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the equity they had built over 32 years of farming. He said that year it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">43 cents</NUMEX> a pound to raise pork and they received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10 cents</NUMEX> a pound at market.   He added that even though there are concerns about food being brought into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USA</ENAMEX> from around the world, consumers are still buying imported food.   "Consumers are always right, whether we believe they are or not," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luz Gutierrez</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center for Latino Farmers</ENAMEX> raised concerns to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> that not all farmers, especially those who are minority or disadvantaged, are receiving information on benefits and programs the USDA offers. She said Latino farmers are the largest number of new farmers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and many are not receiving the USDA information or are being represented on county boards. She also requested that term limits be imposed on those serving on county boards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> said that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> the county board rules changed and 300 counties with a high number of minorities were required to have a Latino or women on the ballot for the county board positions.   "Latinos want to be farmers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutierrez</ENAMEX>. "They're knocking down our door."   She asked that an assessment of the USDA's outreach programs be completed.   "If we don't see them, then they're not doing outreach, and we aren't seeing them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutierrez</ENAMEX>.   A beginning Latino farmer who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutierrez</ENAMEX> has been working with said he has been filling out lot of paperwork, but hasn't received any answers from the USDA.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutierrez</ENAMEX> said the farmer asked why there are special loans for beginning farmers, but in the end all the money ends up in the same pot that benefits long-time farmers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> said it is a policy question and one that needs to be looked at.   "Beginning farmers shouldn't be beginning farmers forever," he said, explaining that established farmers should not be eligible for beginning farmer loans and assistance. "I was a beginning farmer and I have a soft spot in my heart for them."   A concern of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakama Reservation</ENAMEX> farmer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Gasseling</ENAMEX>, who raises hops, apples and mint, is that farmers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> can't compete not only internationally, but with other producers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> because of yearly raises in minimum wages in the state.   "We also need to have a fair and level playing field here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>," said Gasseling. "We don't want a hand-out, we just want some kind of fair and level playing field."   Retired dairy farmer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Vanderstoel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> also voiced his concerns about having a level playing field in the dairy industry.   He said that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> dairy farmers were paid the lowest price ever for milk, but the public paid the highest prices for milk.   "That doesn't make sense," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanderstoel</ENAMEX>.   He added that the push is for larger and larger farming operations.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moseley</ENAMEX> said that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s market the size of a farm is based on what it takes for a family to live.   But, he added, contrary to belief, the USDA is seeing an increase nationwide is the number of smaller farms that are being started.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

