


<P ID="1">Story Time
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/4/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">I'm in agreement with President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> on most issues he addresses. The exception to the rule, though, is his stance on opening up our borders to illegal immigrants.
</P><P ID="5">   To put it bluntly, it's costing us Americans too much money.
</P><P ID="6">   What's going on in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> right now serves as a prime example why we need to close down our borders to the hordes that are making their way into this country on a daily basis. A report released recently by the Federation for American Immigration Reform (FAIR), entitled "The Costs of Illegal Immigration to Arizonans," shows a nearly nine-fold increase in the costs of illegal immigration during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decade</TIMEX>. The burden on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>'s taxpayers, growing at a far too rapid pace, is estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700</NUMEX> a year in additional costs to every native-born head of household in that state.
</P><P ID="7">   Right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> is the prime region for illegal immigrants to nestle in and call home. It used to be <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>. I think most everyone knows what the influx of illegal immigration did to that state's budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state isn't affected as drastically as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, but make no mistake, we Washingtonians are also bearing our share of the costs.
</P><P ID="8">   FAIR's report details that Arizonans are paying approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> annually to fund this wave of illegal immigrants. The biggest chunk of that, about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$810 million</NUMEX>, goes towards providing education to the illegal aliens and their children. Health care for illegal immigrants, which is threatening to bankrupt numerous hospitals and clinics in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, totals about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX> a year. It is estimated another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80 million</NUMEX> is spent in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> each year on incarcerating illegal aliens. As we all know from first-hand knowledge here, many of these illegals do not take the time to learn the laws of our country before jumping across the border to take up residence here.
</P><P ID="9">   The report by FAIR also details that only a fraction of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> in annual costs, about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$257 million</NUMEX>, is offset by what illegal aliens pay in taxes to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   What's even more alarming than the total amount of money being spent on these illegal aliens is the rate at which these costs are growing.
</P><P ID="11">   Says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Martin</ENAMEX>, who authored the report for FAIR: "Perhaps even more astounding than the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> a year that uncontrolled illegal immigration is costing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> is the rate at which those costs are increasing.
</P><P ID="12">   "Between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, the illegal alien population of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> grew by a staggering <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">150 percent</NUMEX>, and that rate of increase has not abated," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> continues.
</P><P ID="13">   Simply put, the federal government, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> leading the charge, needs to take steps to stop this flow of illegal immigration.
</P><P ID="14">   "While <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> has become the new illegal gateway to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>, and Arizonans have been forced to bear the staggering costs of our failed immigration policy, the state's elected representatives in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. have, ironically, been at the forefront of efforts to grant amnesty to millions of illegal aliens and their families," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> says.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> predicts, quite accurately I believe, that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 billion</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> taxpayers are paying now is just a taste of what is to come if the nation doesn't immediately begin enforcing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s immigration laws. And it will only get worse if our elected officials enact the amnesty proposals that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bush</ENAMEX> advocates.
</P><P ID="16">   I'm as much an humanitarian as the next guy. But we need to take care of our own first, before spending billions of dollars on folks who legally shouldn't be in this country. Our top priorities should be feeding and educating Americans. Once that has been accomplished, to the extent where poverty has been wiped out in this country, then let's look at our neighbors across the border and try to give them a hand.
</P>   
<P ID="17">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at
</P><P ID="18">   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him
</P><P ID="19">   at bstory@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




