
<P ID="1">City moves forward with Lincoln Avenue upgrade
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Lincoln Avenue in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> should have a new look to it rather soon.   At the recommendation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Engineer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bridges</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> moving forward with a project to vastly improve Lincoln Avenue.   Prior to the discussion, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> asked to be excused because his business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s Auto Clinic, is located on Lincoln Avenue.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said the city, led by Public Works Director Gary Potter, originally applied for a grant to upgrade Lincoln Avenue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2002</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> lost the money for the project with the passage of I-695.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said the state legislature, though, recognized the need to fund the street projects which lost funding with the passage of I-695. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the legislature took the money for the projects out of the collection of fines obtained in school zones.   The project will take place along Lincoln Avenue between Sixth Street and 16th Street.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said he was contacted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Moffat</ENAMEX>, director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Traffic Safety Commission</ENAMEX>, a few months ago about moving forward with the project.   The grant the city is receiving from the state is in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52,000</NUMEX>. Under the terms of the grant, the city will agree to provide <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> in matching funds. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> will also provide <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> in matching funds for the project, since four school buildings are located in that vicinity.   The project will include the installation of sidewalks and ramps to accommodate people with disabilities. There will also be new crosswalks and electronic speed limit signs installed that will make it easier to change the speed limit in school zones.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Resources Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX> was on hand <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> to voice support for the project.   The project has to be completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said he would like to see the city begin work on Lincoln Avenue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> and have it completed by the time school starts in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> related to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> officials are hoping the Lincoln Avenue improvement project can become a model for other school districts across the state to mirror.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

