
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>'s test scores show schools making headway
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Local school districts are making gains on statewide and standardized tests, but they still have a ways to go to catch the state average.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Superintendent of Public Instruction Terry Bergeson said that overall achievement levels on the Iowa Tests of Basic Skills (ITBS), a national test that assesses third and sixth grade students across the state, remain strong. She added that gaps between the highest performing students and their lower testing peers has narrowed.   The state reading score average for third graders has stayed the same, in the 58th percentile. The third grade math scores have also remained the same, in the 67th percentile.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, third grade reading scores dropped one percentile from 27 in the 2002-03 school year to 26 in the 2003-04 school year at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX>.   Math scores increased from the 30th percentile to the 33rd percentile.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, the composite math and reading score stayed the same as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, at the 29th percentile.   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> third grade reading scores were on the rise at two of the community's three elementary schools. Third grade scores at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> went from the 30th percentile in 2002-03 to the 36th percentile in the 2003-04 school year.   Students' scores at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> raised from the 35th percentile to the 39th percentile.   At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> scores sank one percentile point from 28 to 27.   ITBS math scores remained the same at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX>. Students tested in the 41st percentile in the 2002-03 and the 2003-04 school years.   Students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> increased one percentile point, raising from the 45th to the 46th percentile.   At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> students dropped three percentile points from the 37th percentile in 2002-03 to the 34th percentile in 2003-04.   In the composite math and reading scores, Pioneer students went from the 35th percentile to the 39th. Students at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> raised their scores from the 40th percentile to the 43rd percentile.   Statewide, sixth grade students' reading scores remained the same as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> in the 55th percentile. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> language scores for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> sixth graders were in the 56th percentile. They went down one point to the 55th percentile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. For the third year in a row sixth grade math scores have remained the same, in the 58th percentile.   At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, reading scores dropped from the 29th percentile in 2002-03 to the 25th percentile in 2003-04, but the students showed marked improvements in math and language.   Math scores jumped from the 29th percentile to the 33rd percentile, and language scores increased from the 36th percentile to the 40th percentile.   The core total of the three scores raised from the 29th percentile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> to the 32nd percentile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.   Executive Director of Instruction and Learning for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, Deannie Dunbar, said that the students in the local school district have made improvements in scores.   Sixth grade students at Artz-Fox Elementary noticed improvements in the language and math scores. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> sixth graders' scores increased from 36th percentile in 2002-03 to 40th percentile in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. Math scores were increased from the 29th percentile in 2002-03 to the 33rd percentile this past school year.   Reading scores dropped from the 29th percentile to the 25th percentile.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> sixth graders' core total for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> was in the 32nd percentile compared to the 29th percentile in 2002-03.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX> said he is pleased with the ITBS test results.   "We made some good gains <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and we were able to hold those scores," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>.   He said that in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> they are seeing students who once tested low, move into the middle testing ranges and those from the middle ranges moving to the higher testing ranges.   "We're moving kids from the lowest core tile to the middle and those from the middle to the highest," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>.   The ITBS is a norm-referenced test given annually to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s third and sixth graders.   "It is a tremendous compliment to our teachers and other school staff that our students continue to do well on the ITBS," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burgeson</ENAMEX>. "But even with this consistency and gains in many areas, we still have a significant achievement gap for some of our students. We need to continue working together to help all students achieve our state's learning standards and erase the gap."      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

