
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Levy support
As a former school board member for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> and a long-time farmer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area, I would encourage voters to support the special levy and bond issue on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3, 2004</TIMEX>. It will help to keep taxes low and the quality of our school facilities and programs high.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Newhouse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Racist allegations
I was saddened to see the cry of racism in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>. How disappointing it is to hear there are people who want to divide our community. And if they don't get their way, they stoop to playing the race card.
Should Councilmen Torch and Seeger been accused of racism? I don't think so. Let's look at the complaints that were levied against them in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s paper.
The first letter was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel T. Martinez</ENAMEX>. He accused Torch and Seeger of using the "official pulpit to espouse their racist and divisive attitude regarding a positive economic development effort, because Hispanics are promoting a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hispanic Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>." These two councilmen were not trying to divide our community, they were trying to keep it together. It seems to me that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> is the one wanting to tear it apart.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> went on to say "Spanish speaking business people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> want to promote their businesses, as well as promote economic development in our community. It is "our" choice how we decide to do it. It is not the choice of racist leaders to tell us how to promote and develop "our" business." Again, who sounds racist and divisive? I thought that we were one community with diverse ethnic backgrounds. It sounds like Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> want to segregate the community. I thought segregation was illegal.
He went on to allege that our city council has ignored the downtown businesses by not providing infrastructure for them, because they're Latino owned companies. What a crock! The city is providing the same sewer, water, power, parking, roads and other services to the downtown merchants that they provide to every other business in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. If Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> expects the city to renovate the buildings for him, he's looking for a handout in the wrong place. It is the responsibility of the building owners to update them. Perhaps he should look to them for his economic development.
The second letter was written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Maya III</ENAMEX>. Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX> also considered Councilmen Torch and Seeger divisive because they didn't agree with having two chambers in town. He wrote, "I believe that forming a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hispanic Chamber</ENAMEX> is an answer to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Hispanic owned businesses." Again, why would he think the answer is dividing our community?
I have contacted our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> and found that they have done many things to reach out to our Hispanic businesses. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> told our chamber president of her intentions to divide our community, M'Liss Bierlink tried to work with Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> to keep our business core together. But what did Bengie do? She set up a meeting with several Latino owned businesses here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasco Hispanic Chamber</ENAMEX>, herself, and invited several members of our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> board to attend.
Talk about racist and divisive! Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> and her associate from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> informed our Hispanic business owners that they should only promote and do business with other Hispanic people. Racist? Divisive? You tell me.
All of the minutes from that meeting are available from our chamber. You don't have to believe me, you can find out for yourself what really happened.
As a member of the community, I am sick and tired of hearing this kind of rhetoric from people like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> and her cronies who wrote the letters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s paper. We don't need this in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. We have enough problems here without Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> stirring up the beehive.
I have been following Bengie's career since she was elected to the city council. She has done nothing but drive a wedge between the cultures of this city. If therre is a racist on the council, she is it. In the interest of our community, she should step down and shut up. If she wants to help the Hispanics, that would be the best thing for her to do. Then we could get down to the business of uniting and involving all the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in bettering the community as a whole. Let's not attack Councilmen Torch and Seeger, let's applaud them.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Cleghorn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

