10 13 29 21 49 45
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Conscience and reputation are two things. Conscience is due to yourself, reputation to your neighbour.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saint Augustine</ENAMEX> (354 AD - 430 AD)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>