
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> dancer/teacher heading to national competition 
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jazz dance teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristine Gimlin</ENAMEX> is too excited to sit still for very long when she starts talking about her coming trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX>   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">a Martin School of Dance</ENAMEX> ballet and jazz instructor, will compete in a national "hip hop" competition hosted by some of the nation's most important music video choreographers.   "I'm going to be dancing in front of some of my heroes in the dance world," she said of the unusual opportunity.   "It's a dream come true," she smiled.   Making her achievement even more noteworthy is that the 4'11" woman started taking hip hop dance lessons less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX>, who began dancing in middle school, participated on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser High School</ENAMEX> dance team for four years. "I dreamed and planned to go to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> following high school graduation to be a dancer," she said.   But hip and knee injuries sidelined the young woman for three years. She only recently began dancing again and joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin School of Dance</ENAMEX>'s pool of instructors just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. Since that time, in addition to teaching pre-schoolers the rudiments of ballet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> has taught advanced jazz techniques at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> dance school.   In order to improve her own abilities, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> decided to start taking hip hop dance classes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westlake Dance Center</ENAMEX> in Seattle.   She said it was serendipity that talent scouts saw her dancing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-February</TIMEX>. Representatives of national talent agencies, who were in town seeking new dancers, happened to drop in at the center where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> was in a hip hop dance class.   "They asked me to take part in Monster Hip Hop auditions," she explained. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> describes hip hop as a very loose, physical style of dance that combines rigorous and rhythmic jazz-step type moves.   "I was surprised when I was asked to take part in the Monster of Hip Hop auditions," she explained.   Her invitation to compete in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX> came after talent scouts watched as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> moved through three cuts from among the hundreds of young dancers, all hoping to catch the eyes of the scouts.   "It was the best time I've ever had dancing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> admitted.   She said her biggest thrill of the weekend came when she met her idol, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiggles</ENAMEX>, the self-proclaimed founder of the hip hop dance craze.   "He gave me a compliment on my dancing," she said.   The agencies gave out scholarships to the top two dancers at the Seattle "Monster" audition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> said. As one of the top 10 dancers ranked at the event, she rated a special invitation to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denver</ENAMEX> event. "I was encouraged by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiggles</ENAMEX> to participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX>," she explained.   "It's a realization of a dream," the 23-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> woman said. While she doesn't plan to run off to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> now to be a dancer, she does plan to share her newly found expertise with local students. She said the two-day adventure in hip hop has cemented her decision to teach. "I really want to take my students to the next level," she said.   "I feel I can help others realize their dreams," she said.   "But it was a great thrill to be recognized," she added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

