


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharks</ENAMEX> churn through Neptunes
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - A computer printer breakdown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> kept the results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> meet up in the air. But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late Friday morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Sharks</ENAMEX> learned they had handily bested the Grandview swim team, 515-296.
</P><P ID="5">   The win was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s fourth consecutive victory, and boosted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Sharks</ENAMEX>' season record to 7-2. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s win also gave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a season sweep of the Neptunes.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> out-pointed the Neptunes in nine of the 12 age divisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s strength came at girls 18&U, and in the boys 14&U and 16&U races.
</P><P ID="7">   The leader for the 18&U <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danelle Cowan</ENAMEX>, who managed to win two of the five individual races. She also garnered two runner-up finishes and swam on both winning relay squads. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammate Jessica Arteaga</ENAMEX> added an individual race victory, a second place finish and two relay wins.
</P><P ID="8">   Preventing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> from completely dominating the girls 18&U division was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Kresse</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> swimmer won the 40-yard butterfly and 160-yard individual medley events.
</P><P ID="9">   Keagan Christensen was a one-man wrecking crew for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> at boys 14&U. Christensen was victorious in four of the five individual races, and paced the Neptunes to victory in the 160-yard medley relay. The only race Christensen didn't win was the 40-yard freestyle, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Bardell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> laid claim to. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bardell</ENAMEX> easily got by Christensen in that event, besting the runner-up by nearly a second and a half.
</P><P ID="10">   In the other age division <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> dominated-boys 16&U-Kevin Concienne and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Robillard</ENAMEX> were the standouts for the Neptunes. Concienne piled up three individual race victories and two runner-up performances, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robillard</ENAMEX> was a two-time winner and had three second place finishes.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was untouchable in the nine other age divisions.
</P><P ID="12">   At girls 8&U, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Broersma</ENAMEX> and Sydnee Hernandez provided the one-two punch for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Sharks</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broersma</ENAMEX> won all four races, while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hernandez</ENAMEX> placed second in all four.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Castillo</ENAMEX> secured victory in all five girls 10&U races. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammates Marisa Broersma</ENAMEX> nabbed three runner-up finishes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordain Saenz</ENAMEX> had one second place finish. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Grow</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> got the other runner-up placing. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Sharks</ENAMEX> won both of the relay events in that age division. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broersma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saenz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Hutchins</ENAMEX> were on both relay squads.
</P><P ID="14">   At girls 12&U, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Dolan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> stood out from the pack. She won four of the five individual races. In the only event she didn't win-the 40-yard backstroke-Dolan placed second, 1.22 seconds behind <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinzi Poteet</ENAMEX>, who had four runner-up showings that evening. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 12&U girls won both of the relay events. The squad members included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alissa Martin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Schlenker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Siller</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Knee</ENAMEX> cruised through the girls 14&U events. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> swimmer won all five individual races, and swam the third leg on the winning 160-yard medley relay team. Her three relay partners were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Mendoza</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaitlyn Broersma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broersma</ENAMEX> also notched a pair of second place finishes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sydney Mottice and Cheyenne Bank</ENAMEX> combined for three runner-up finishes in the individual events. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mottice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis McLean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinzi Poteet</ENAMEX> won the girls 14&U freestyle relay.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachelle Durfey</ENAMEX> provided the power for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the girls 16&U races. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX> won three of the individual events and placed second in the other two. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammate Hannah Glockner</ENAMEX> scored one victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Sharks</ENAMEX> in that age division. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allison Grow</ENAMEX> was a one-time winner and placed second twice.
</P><P ID="17">   At boys 8&U, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad Tyhuis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> swept all four races. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryce Carpenter</ENAMEX> finished second in all four.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristian Vargas</ENAMEX> nailed down three first place wins for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the boys 10&U races. He also grabbed a pair of second place showings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammates Tim Stiteler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni Rodriguez</ENAMEX> each scored one victory and combined for four runner-up performances.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Hollander</ENAMEX> turned in the best effort for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the boys 12&U races. He won the 40-yard breaststroke and 160-yard individual medley events, was second in the 40-yard butterfly and freestyle races, and swam on the winning 160-yard freestyle relay team. His winning relay partners included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Luff</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Henry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Sharks</ENAMEX> also won the 160-yard medley relay event at boys 12&U. The winning squad was comprised of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Tyhuis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Myer</ENAMEX> and S. McMinimee.
</P><P ID="20">   At boys 18&U, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> didn't field any swimmers. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had two competitors that night-Kaleb Hursh and M. Uribe. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hursh</ENAMEX> won two of the individual races and swam on both of the winning 18&U relay squads. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Uribe</ENAMEX> picked up three individual race victories and had one relay win to his credit.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> hosts the Prosser Piranhas <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Sharks</ENAMEX> will be looking to avenge a 462-376 defeat they suffered at the hands of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> back on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




