
<P ID="1">Five local students earn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EWU</ENAMEX> degrees
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CHENEY - Five</ENAMEX> Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> students earned degrees from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of summer</TIMEX> quarter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EWU</ENAMEX> graduates include Jeffery Monahan of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Master</ENAMEX> of Science degree in physical education; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leticia Chavez</ENAMEX> of Outlook, Master of Social Work; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Rivera</ENAMEX>, Bachelor of Arts in social work; and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corey Phillips</ENAMEX>, Bachelor of Arts in therapeutic recreation; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Thompson</ENAMEX>, Bachelor of Arts in therapeutic recreation.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

