
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> woman claims giant soup ladle in menudo contest 
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - A giant ladle, along with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> in cash, were presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lupe Castro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> after her large crockpot of a spicy Mexican soup was deemed the best at the first annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Menudo Cook-off</ENAMEX> held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX>'s menudo, which is made of a combination of chile, hominy, spices and tripe, was among 10 recipes entered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>'s first ever menudo cook-off.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> cooks of all ages gathered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger City Park</ENAMEX> to compete for cash prizes and to claim bragging rights for making the best menudo . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castro</ENAMEX> was also awarded a trophy. But the ladle was her surprise award, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulbert</ENAMEX>. The ladle, inscribed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Menudo Cook-off</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, was created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Castro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wizard Graphics</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>.   "We had 10 contestants enter their recipes in our menudo contest," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Hulburt</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> spokesperson. Her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX>, and Gracelia Valencia were the chairs for the cook-off, which was organized to celebrate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>'s rich Hispanic/Mexican culture.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Menudo</ENAMEX> is a popular soup which is typically served with lemon slices, onion, oregano and avocado, which add to the flavor, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulbert</ENAMEX>. Warm tortillas are also served with the uniquely Mexican dish.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juana Ibarra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was the first place winner in the junior cook-off division. She received a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> t-shirt and plaque for her award winning entry.   Earning second place in the adult division was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, who received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> cash prize. Third place went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Cardenas</ENAMEX>, who received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> cash prize, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teodora Delgado</ENAMEX>, also of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, was the fourth place winner of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. All winners received a t-shirt.   Judges for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s event were Guadulupe Sotelo of Radio KDNA, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger City Councilman Ernie Guerra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County Auditor Corky Mattingly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Councilwoman Jennie Angel and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Jaramillo</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>.   "The judges took their job very seriously," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Hulbert</ENAMEX>.   He said the judges sampled each entry twice. "We also had four <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger School District</ENAMEX> students helping with the judging," he said.   "We were very pleased with the contest and plan to do it again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>," he added.   In addition to the contest entries, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> members cooked up six pots of menudo, which they had on sale, along with 10 dozen ears of fresh corn. "We sold out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hulbert</ENAMEX>.   He said proceeds from the contest entry fees and the menudo sales will be used to held fund the city's new aquatic center.   Later in the day, following the cooking contest, entertainment was held in the park for an estimated 200 people who attended the fiesta-style event. In addition, the Yakima County Auditor's office had one of its new voting machines set up in the park for demonstrations.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

