
<P ID="1">Still no decision made yet by USDA on 'depopulating<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">' two</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> herds
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The decision on whether or not to kill any or all of the animals in two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> herds, at a dairy which was home to a Holstein that tested positive for bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>) and a calf feeding operation where the infected cow's calf was sent, has not been made. But the possibility that the two herds may have to be killed, or depopulated as the federal government is now calling it, still exists.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzan Holl</ENAMEX>, public affairs specialist for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</ENAMEX>, there is an indemnity program that cattle owners can apply for, which if approved, would provide fair market price replacement costs should the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> decide that killing the cattle is the best option.   Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron DeHaven</ENAMEX>, chief veterinarian for the USDA, announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that 10 of the 82 cows that crossed the Canadian border into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> were found on the Mabton dairy. The other 70 cows are still being traced down, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> believes they are all in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holl</ENAMEX> said she is unsure if the Mabton dairy owner and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area calf operation owner would be compensated for the time to renew operations, if a severe cut is made into either herd population. The dairy is made up of 4,000 cows and the calf feeding operation has approximately 460 calves.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Gordon</ENAMEX>, executive director of the Washington State Dairy Federation, the only model they have for indemnity are for sheep herds that were eliminated in the Northeast due to disease, and cattle that were killed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Baneville</ENAMEX>, an independent consultant working with the dairy and beef industries, said the government has a response plan to contain and eradicate potential threats to the industry.   She said in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> when bovine tuberculosis was uncontrollable, rather than targeting the wild animals continuously carrying the disease over the border from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, the USDA found it more prudent to provide the farmer with indemnification and exterminate the herd.   "All of us in the dairy industry that are watching this don't know those answers yet," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>. "He's got employees and he's got a lot of hard work and effort."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> added that the whole point of indemnity is so the herd can be tested in the national interest. There is no test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> that can be done on live animals. The testing requires a portion of the cow's brain for testing, according to the USDA.   When <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> found mad cow disease in a single cow in an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX> herd, more than 1,160 cattle were killed and tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, according to Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Evans</ENAMEX>, chief veterinary officer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Food Inspection Agency</ENAMEX>. Cows from the herd where the diseased cow lived, where her offspring lived and herds where the infected cow "co-mingled" were all destroyed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> tests on all of the cows were negative, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Veterinary Medical Association</ENAMEX>.   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> said the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> was a shock to farmers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, it's not something they haven't been preparing for.   "For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two or three years</TIMEX> we've had a lot of paper preparation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>, since the foot-in-mouth outbreak in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, came up with an emergency preparation plan."   With the decision of whether or not to depopulate the two Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> farms still up in the air, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> said he believes the USDA is paying close attention to the international standard and making sure that decision will help in reopening foreign markets.   Also not determined if the cattle on the two farms are determined to be a threat is the method of termination.   "Whatever they do determine will be the most humane way by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Veterinary Medication Association</ENAMEX> guidelines," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holl</ENAMEX>.   She added that the animals would be euthanized by the USDA, and the USDA would incur the costs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holl</ENAMEX> said that if killed the animals would be tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> before they were disposed of. The method of disposal is unknown, but she said they would not enter the meat market.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

