


<P ID="1">DNA links <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> cow to Canadian herd
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Tests are back and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow from a Mabton dairy has been positively linked to an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> dairy farm.
</P><P ID="5">   Tissues from the infected cow was compared against semen from her sire, according to Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron DeHaven</ENAMEX>, chief veterinary officer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The DNA information coupled with documents from the Mabton dairy makes USDA certain in the accuracy of the trace-back, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The next step, besides continuing to look for the other cows that were imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> with the infected cow, is determining how the cow became infected, according to Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Evans</ENAMEX>, chief veterinary officer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Canadian Food Inspection Agency</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> said that the herd the cow came from no longer exists.
</P><P ID="9">   "The animals that moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> were in fact part of a dispersal of that herd," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>. "Because of health problems the owner was no longer able to sustain his dairy operation."
</P><P ID="10">   The herd of 86 milk cows and 16 heifers was dispersed. The majority were brought to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> with the infected cow.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said that although the one cow was infected, there is no indication that all 81 cows imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> at the same time were infected. The USDA is continuing to seek out the additional cows that were imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> with the infected cow. Nine of the cows have been located on the Mabton Dairy where the infected cow was located, and one has been located at a dairy finishing facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>. Both the Mabton and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX> facilities have been quarantined.
</P>   
<P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




