
<P ID="1">New Grizzly newspaper advisor lands scholarship to attend workshop
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> will be taking part in a two-week journalism education workshop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX> to learn all she can for her new role.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> will be taking over the role of advisor for "The Grizzly," the school newspaper at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   As part of the training for her new position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> applied for and received a scholarship through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Society of Newspaper</ENAMEX> Editors (ASNE) to attend a two-week workshop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX> starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX>.   "I think it will be a lot of fun," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX>. "I think it will be a neat opportunity."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> is one of 35 teachers from across the country to be selected to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX> workshop.   This workshop will mark the first endeavor into the world of journalism for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX>, who teaches a variety of business-related classes at the high school, including computers and accounting.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> became the new journalism advisor, which is a regular daily class offered at the high school, after the school newspaper came under a different department. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> said the newspaper used to be overseen by the high school English department, but because that department is heading in a different direction, the newspaper now falls under her department.   While she has never taken a journalism class or done anything in the newspaper business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> is going into the workshop with the mind of a sponge, hoping to soak up all she can.   "I really want the experience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX>. "I want the newspaper career to be real to my students."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> is also hoping that she can bring back what she learned at the workshop and relay that information to her students. Her goal for the newspaper is to have it become a publication that the students at the high school take ownership in. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> will have 26 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s newspaper class and she is hoping each of them bring a unique sense of what the school is like to the newspaper.   "I want to give the paper a new look," she said. "(I want the newspaper to have) more of students' reflections on what they believe."   As part of her application process to attend the all-expense paid workshop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX> had to include a biography and write an essay on the need for journalism with students.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Francisco</ENAMEX> workshop will cover a variety of areas, including journalism ethics, different publishing styles, photoshop and editing. There will be hardly any time to rest for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX>. The workshops will run daily from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>   The workshop will feature newspaper editors from across the country, including heads of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Jose Mercury News</ENAMEX>, The Oregonian and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Houston Chronicle</ENAMEX>. Pulitzer Prize winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">photojournalist Kim Mimenich</ENAMEX> will also be on hand.   "They have so much going on," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wiederspohn</ENAMEX>. "I am hoping I can bring it all back."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

