<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Land Grab in the Works?
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">07/02/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Patino</ENAMEX> lives in a lot of places, but he didn't think the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> was one of them. The retired rancher, farmer, car dealer and bank owner splits time among his rural <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">central Washington</ENAMEX> farm and houses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>.
</P>
<P ID="5">But over a five-month span, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parker</ENAMEX> sees 4,151 neighboring acres to the south from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port Park</ENAMEX> and 5,024 neighboring acres to the north past Boynton Labs annexed into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, leaving him adjacent to a land grab that would grow the city considerably.
</P>
<P ID="6">Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patino</ENAMEX> and other rural homeowners would remain residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> on the tax rolls, the inhabitants of up to 16,336 new homes that could be built around him would all be city residents and eligible for services such as trash and recycling pickup.
</P>
<P ID="7">Rather than views dominated by grasses, cows, and trees, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patino</ENAMEX> might soon look out on concentrations of townhomes, condos, offices and storefronts.
</P>
<P ID="8">"Everyone says (not in my back yard), but that's not the issue," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patino</ENAMEX>, who grimaced when discussing the number of homes planned and the community docks slated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River</ENAMEX> near his home. 
</P>
<P ID="9">"You start talking about 2,500 lots with access to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River</ENAMEX> -- c'mon," he said, chomping on a stubby cigar.
</P>
<P ID="10">An annexation bug is sweeping through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">western Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> as municipalities stretch, swell and sprawl across the county to acquire new land when willing owners ask for inclusion and rezoning -- often when they are preparing property for sale to a developer.
</P>
<P ID="11">The bottom line is municipal leaders expect a flood of new homes and scores of new residents interested in waterfront living, reminiscent of early days of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Unconfirmed rumors suggest Swiss developers have expressed acute interest in the new waterfront <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> properties.
</P>
<P ID="12">Brushing off concerns that the annexations were being hastily considered, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said proper planning and precautions are in place with development agreements.
</P>
<P ID="13">"Everyone says the government moves too slow until (it's) not doing something they like," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said. "Then it moves too fast and sells too cheap."
</P>

   
   
<P ID="14">   Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">     Copyright 
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="17">   , 
</P>   