


<P ID="1">Probe into mad cow disease continues
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">It's been a month since the first case of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>), or mad cow disease, was found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, and in that time well over 600 animals have been killed in the attempts to trace the disease and stop it from spreading.
</P><P ID="5">   The infected cow had been part of a Mabton dairy and was sent to slaughter after it was injured giving birth to a bull calf.
</P><P ID="6">   A sample of the brain of the downer <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX>, which was unable to walk due to the birthing injuries, was sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> lab in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of December</TIMEX>, where it was tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>. The test results came back positive for the brain-wasting disease two days before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>, recalls on beef have been issued as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USDA</ENAMEX> officials have worked to trace the 81 cows that were imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> along with the infected cow. They have also sought an additional 17 cows that Canadian Chief Veterinary Officer Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Evans</ENAMEX> believes are of interest in the case.
</P><P ID="8">   Four of the 17 animals have been traced. Three of the cows are in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quincy</ENAMEX> and one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boardman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boardman</ENAMEX> facility is under a hold order to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USDA</ENAMEX> officials in the investigation. Officials are still trying to determine if the other 13 cows entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   So far officials have traced nine of the 81 cows that crossed the border with the infected cow to the Mabton herd where the infected cow was milked prior to slaughter. The cows that were bought with the infected cow, along with 120 other cows, were slaughtered and tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>. All of the test results have come back negative, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USDA</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   Three cows imported with the infected cow were located by investigators at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>, where the infected cow was held until it was sold to the Mabton dairy. To date, 39 cows from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX> dairy have been slaughtered and tested. The results have come back on 20 of the animals. All tests that have been completed have come back negative, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USDA</ENAMEX> officials.
</P><P ID="11">   Also killed were about 450 bull calves that were part of a bull calf feeding operation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The infected cow's calf was sold to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> business shortly after birth. When investigators were unable to determine exactly which calf came from the infected cow, they eliminated all the animals, according to officials.
</P><P ID="12">   Six of the cows that were imported with the infected cow have been located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> and three in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenino</ENAMEX>. There have not been any determinations on what will happen to those cows.
</P><P ID="13">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Late Thursday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>) it was annouced that another three cows that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USDA</ENAMEX> were seeking were located on a dairy in Burley, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   As investigators track down possibly infected animals, there has also been concern about the safety of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s beef industry.
</P><P ID="15">   Early on into the investigation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Sec. of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agriculture Ann M. Veneman</ENAMEX> announced an immediate ban on sale of brains from cows 30 months and older. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veneman</ENAMEX> also announced an immediate ban on "downer" cows for human consumption.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Cantwell</ENAMEX> has been pushing for banning downer cows being used for human consumption since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "The Downed Animal Protection Act would permanently ban downer cows and other downed animals from our nation's food supply," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantwell</ENAMEX>. "It would codify and expand the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USDA</ENAMEX>'s proposed rule and protect consumers and our food supply not for just as long as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Administration</ENAMEX> feels like, but permanently."
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantwell</ENAMEX> said it goes beyond food safety to trade and jobs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.
</P><P ID="19">   "Opening international markets and convincing our trade partners that American beef is safe is an imperative," she said.
</P><P ID="20">   She added that there is talk of passing similar legislation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.
</P>   
<P ID="21">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




