
<P ID="1">Missing animals common in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>' Lucky Penny lived up to her name <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past week</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny</ENAMEX>, as she is known to her owner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Riggs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, was found and returned to her owners <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> after she disappeared this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waneta Grange</ENAMEX> area.   The wire-haired dauchund disappeared <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> while it was being taken out one last time for the night. Fireworks scared the small dog and it ran off, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>, who was on his way back from a family vacation with his wife and two sons when the dog disappeared. The animal was staying with his parents at their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> home.   Checking at a wedding reception at the nearby grange for anyone who had seen the dog, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>' family was unable to locate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX> said his family put up flyers and knocked on doors in search of their missing family member.   They went through the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> looking for anyone who may have seen their dog at the wedding and took it in, but were unable to find their animal, which was wearing a license and tags when it disappeared. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny</ENAMEX> is also microchipped, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX> added.   "We love our four children," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>. "We have two girls, which are the dogs and two boys, which are our sons."   An ad was placed in the newspaper and on radio stations and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, nearly three full days after <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Penny</ENAMEX> disappeared, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX> received a telephone call from a woman living on the Grandview Pavement.   "She said, 'I think your dog is underneath my van'," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>.   The woman had received the newspaper and compared the picture in the advertisement to the dog that appeared on her property. It was a match.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX> between 20 and 25 dogs are reported missing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Tanquary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> animal control officer. Many of the animals are not returned to their homes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanquary</ENAMEX> said one of the best ways to insure a dog is returned to its home is to make sure the animal is licensed. That way if an animal is found it can be returned to the owners, he said.   "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Eighty percent</NUMEX> of dogs aren't licensed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanquary</ENAMEX>. "If a dog is licensed then I can track down where it lives."   He said it is also important that the dog stays on the owner's property.   "The best way is to fence the yard or tie a dog up," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanquary</ENAMEX>.   Bringing an animal inside the home is also a way to protect it from leaving the owner's property or protecting it from being stolen.   "The problem is a lot of families purchase an animal that's too large for the home," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanquary</ENAMEX>.   Animal theft is a growing concern in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX> said when looking for his dog in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, he was alarmed at the number of people living in the community who had faced similar situations.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanquary</ENAMEX> said that many of the smaller mixed breed dogs that are disappearing are being used for bait for fighting dogs. Purebred dogs that are thought to be of value are often sold or kept as pets, he said.   Purebred dogs are often stolen in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> as are puppies, he added.   Microchipping is an option that pet owners can take that can insure an animal is returned if it becomes missing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanquary</ENAMEX> said that every stray he picks up is scanned for a microchip before it is booked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington Humane Society</ENAMEX> shelter in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   Local vets also scan strays that are brought to them.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Ann Ravine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pet Health Clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, about 25 animals are microchipped at their office each year.   The universal microchipping can be scanned by animal control officers and other vets, she said.   Microchipping costs less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60</NUMEX> at most clinics. Microchipping in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> costs between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52</NUMEX> per animal.   But as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX> found out, locating a lost animal takes more than just implanting it with a microchip.   "My recommendation would be to have owner identification tag on the dog, as well as a dog license, and to keep good pictures on hand," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>. "The lady who found her (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny</ENAMEX>) recognized her from the picture."   He added that knowing a dog's distinguishing identifying marks is also important.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>' dauchund is a wheat colored dog with a black tail, he said.   "But," he added, "It's still important to keep a close eye on your dog."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanquary</ENAMEX> said the dog's description, as well as the name the dog goes by, helps him identify and locate missing animals.   For those missing an animal, he added that putting food and water out for them may bring them home.   "We're very lucky that we got her back," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX>. "The Lucky part of her name really came through for her."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riggs</ENAMEX> said he and his family are planning to take their dogs the next time they go on vacation.   "We'll make sure it's a dog friendly place," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

