


<P ID="1">More mad cow cases believed to be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">A subcommittee made up five international representatives said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that although the bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>) infected heifer was found at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sunny Dene Dairy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, it is likely that other infected animals have gone undetected.
</P><P ID="4">   According to the report, presented at a press conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, "infective material has likely been rendered, fed to cattle and amplified within the cattle population, so that cattle in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USA</ENAMEX> have also been indigenously infected."
</P><P ID="5">   The report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Animal and Poultry Disease Advisory Committee</ENAMEX>'s subcommittee on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>' response to the detection of a case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> has already garnered a response from the National Cattlemen's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beef Association</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX> said in a press release <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that the subcommittee reached "inappropriate conclusions and offers recommendations based on the premise that the risk level in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> for this disease is the same as the risk level in European countries."
</P><P ID="6">   "Clearly some members of the panel do not have a full understanding of the systems we have in place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Weber</ENAMEX>, executive director of regulatory affairs for the National Cattlemen's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beef Association</ENAMEX>. "Many of the panel's recommendations are based on the European model and overlook scientific evidence that clearly demonstrates the long-standing firewalls in place in our country have been effective."
</P><P ID="7">   The subcommittee is made up two representatives from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, as well as one representative each from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Zealand</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   In the report from the subcommittee, it is stated that because there are likely to be other infected animals in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, the as yet to be identified animals from the Canadian birth herd do not pose a significant additional risk in the spread of the disease in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="9">   However, the subcommittee noted that these unidentified infected animals have to be considered as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> goes through the process of creating policies for the prevention of the spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> to humans and cattle through feed.
</P><P ID="10">   One thing the subcommittee suggested as an important part of handling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> is better communication between the government and the public. For example, the subcommittee pointed out that placing herds throughout the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> under quarantine led people to believe that the disease could be passed from one animal to another through contact, which they say is not true. In order to prevent this misinformation, the subcommittee suggested clearer communication with the public as to the reason for the quarantines.
</P><P ID="11">   The subcommittee also suggested the creation of more labs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> that could test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> via animal tissue samples. The report recommends that the government approve a number of labs throughout the country to do the testing as part of a "national surveillance program."
</P><P ID="12">   The subcommittee also looked at the North American feed ban that was put in place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> as "insufficient to prevent exposure of cattle to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> agent." The subcommittee recommended that all specified risk material should be banned not only from all livestock fee, but all pet food as well.
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




