
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise in need of reading volunteers
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise "Promise to Read" program is in need of volunteers to spend about 30 minutes a week reading with children in the local community.   To volunteer for the program, pick up a volunteer application at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Teaching and Learning</ENAMEX> at 800 E. Custer Ave. or call 836-8401.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise is also in search of volunteers to serve as reading mentors for students in the Class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX>, which are currently fifth graders.   Volunteers will wok with students on their reading skills by listening to them and helping them read. Those who volunteer will receive training and will be placed in the school district. Mentors can volunteer their time daily, once a week or once a month, whichever fits their schedule.   For more information about volunteering as a reading mentor contact <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise at 836-8417 or 836-8401.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

