


<P ID="1">Classification proposal would change the look of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">There is a proposal that will be coming up for a vote before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Interscholastic Activities Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WIAA</ENAMEX>) members in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> that could change the make-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The proposed amendment, which failed by three votes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, would reclassify schools in the state based on a percentage.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WIAA District 5 Director Bill Gant</ENAMEX>, whose coverage area includes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, didn't have the exact figures that would be used to figure out the percentage based classifications, but said the proposal is designed to make it where there are an even number of schools in each classification throughout the state.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> 4, which is the Vancouver area, is also proposing a measure for classifications just for football. The 'B' classification would be for schools with no more than 133 students. The 1A ranks couldn't be more than 370 students, while 2A couldn't have more than 893 students. The 3A football schools couldn't have more than 893 students in the top three grades, while 4A schools would be everything above the 3A maximum. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gant</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> 4 proposal is just for football and is different than the percentage based allocation.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gant</ENAMEX> said the proposal to lump schools together in classifications based on a percentage of enrollment could have a dramatic effect on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gant</ENAMEX> said under this formula, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> could have just four schools in it, with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> falling under the 2A classifications.
</P><P ID="9">   If the proposal to base classifications on a percentage formula were to pass it would take effect in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>. Also, if the proposal passed no school would be able to take a postseason allocation with them if they opted up to another classification.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Athletic Director Bill Daley</ENAMEX> said there are a lot of issues surrounding the proposal. He said if it were to pass, there would have to be some creative scheduling done to accommodate each sports season.
</P><P ID="11">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




