
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EARL WRIGHT GASAWAY
EARL WRIGHT GASAWAY
Earl Wright Gasaway</ENAMEX>, 57, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Katy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> and a former resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 15, 2004</TIMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17, 1946</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ark. Earl</ENAMEX> grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arkansas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">southern California</ENAMEX>, graduating from high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Centro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18, 1982</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicki O’Meara Hunsinger</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.  
A combat veteran of the U.S. Navy Sea Bees, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> served his country honorably during the Vietnam War. Upon completion of his service <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> earned an Associate degree from Shoreline <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX> in Seattle, and went on to a distinguished career in law enforcement with the Washington State Patrol. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> retired from service at the rank of detective in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earl’s</ENAMEX> second career was in the auto industry, where he was a general manager for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tom Denchel Ford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hood River Ford</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> spent his life in service to others. He was a member and officer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Rotary Club</ENAMEX> and the White Salmon Rotary club for many years.  He was especially active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary International Youth Exchange Program</ENAMEX>.  Whenever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> had some free time, he would spend it as a volunteer doing community service or assisting someone in need. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> loved people and no one was ever a stranger for long with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> believed that the most valuable thing you could give to others was your time, and he spent his life giving freely of his time and energy.  
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> was an active participant in life.  He enjoyed street rods, golfing, skiing, sailing, and was a talented “handyman”.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> was one of the founders of the Prosser Wine and Food Fair.  He traveled the world, but was always glad to come home to family and friends.  His greatest enjoyment came from his grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper</ENAMEX>.  
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> had a great joy for life, with a quick wit and a sparkle in his eye.  He enjoyed sharing stories and laughter with good friends.  He will always hold a special place in our hearts and will be missed from our daily lives.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> fought a long a gallant battle against a terrible disease.  We know he is with God and ever <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX>, he is watching over us all.  
A beloved son, father, brother, uncle, and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicki O’Meara Hunsinger</ENAMEX>; his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernell Gasaway</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heber Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ark.</ENAMEX>; his daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trisha Lyons</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>; granddaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessa Lynn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Katy</ENAMEX>; his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will Hunsinger</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX>; and grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermosa Beach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>; his sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Horn</ENAMEX>; and brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>.  
He was preceded in death by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eulas Gasaway</ENAMEX>.
In celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earl’s</ENAMEX> life, the Rev. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Maycock</ENAMEX> will conduct a memorial service <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 26, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Porsser</ENAMEX>, with burial at Prosser Cemetery.
If you wish, in lieu of flowers, please consider a donation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Earl’s</ENAMEX> name to Pancreatic Action Network, 2221 Rosecrans Ave., Suite 131,  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Segundo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>  90245.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

