


<P ID="1">Mad cow disease investigation complete
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/10/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron DeHaven</ENAMEX>, Deputy Administrator of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterinary Services</ENAMEX> for USDA's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</ENAMEX>, announced that the field investigation of the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, or mad cow disease, in a cow that once was being milked at a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dairy is complete.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said the epidemiological tracing and DNA evidence proves that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> positive cow slaughtered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9, 2002</TIMEX> was born on a dairy farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calmar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 9, 1997</TIMEX>. The Holstein was moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2001</TIMEX> along with 80 other cattle from that dairy. A brain sample collected from the cow at slaughter tested positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The epidemiological investigation to find additional animals from the source herd led to a total of 189 investigations. That led to complete herd inventories on 51 premises in three states: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>. The inventories involved the examination of the identification on more than 75,000 animals. All herd inventories have now been completed and appropriate analysis of those inventories performed, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>. There are no premises remaining under hold order.
</P><P ID="7">   A total of 255 "Animals of Interest" were identified on 10 premises in the three states. "Animals of Interest" are defined as animals that were - or could have been -from the source herd in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>. All 255 animals were destroyed and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> testing was negative on all of them. The carcasses from all of the euthanized animals were disposed of in landfills in accordance with all federal, state and local regulations, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Included in the 255 animals of interest were 28 positively identified back to the group of 80 cattle that entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> with the index cow, as well as seven heifers out of a group of 17 heifers which were also known to be from the source herd. It is not believed that all of these 17 entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>, but all of them would be considered minimal risk and not significant to the investigation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   Guidelines on bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>) issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Organization for Animal Health</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIE</ENAMEX>), the international animal heath standard setting organization, state that animals born on a premises within one year (before or after) of a BSE-affected animal should be considered of greater risk to the country reporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> detection. As such, USDA focused on 25 of the 81 animals also born into the birth herd of the index animal. Based on normal culling practices of local dairies, APHIS estimated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agency</ENAMEX> would be able to locate approximately 11 of these animals. APHIS definitively located 13 of these animals, plus the index cow, for a total of 14.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said USDA feels confident that the remaining animals represent very little risk. Even in countries like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United Kingdom</ENAMEX> where the prevalence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> has been very high, it is very uncommon to find more than one or maybe two positive animals within a herd, he said. Any of these animals showing nervous system disorder - or any that are nonambulatory at the time of slaughter - will be condemned and not allowed into the human food chain. USDA officials said animals slaughtered after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</TIMEX> would have the specified risk materials removed and not allowed into the human food chain. Specified risk materials are those tissues or portions of the carcass likely to contain the infectious agent in an infected animal.
</P><P ID="11">   Over 2,000 tons of meat and bone meal being held due to potential contamination with protein from the positive cow is on hold and will soon be disposed of in a landfill in accordance with all federal, state and local regulations.
</P><P ID="12">   Of the 255 animals that were destroyed, 28 were part of the 81-cow herd that entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> with the infected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX>. A total of 220 of the destroyed cows could have been part of the original herd.
</P><P ID="13">   Of the 81 that came in from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, 29 of which have definitively been accounted for, one is the BSE-positive cow that was located in the index herd in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, eight were located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> herd, three were located at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenino</ENAMEX>, six were located at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX>, one was located at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quincy</ENAMEX>, three were located at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>, one was located at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>, three were located at a facility in Burley, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, one was located at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX> and another cow was located at a different facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   The USDA destroyed more than 700 cows, including 449 bull calves at a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area feeding operation, a total of 134 animals in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, 39 cows in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>, 15 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX>, 20 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boardman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, 18 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quincy</ENAMEX>, four in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenino</ENAMEX>, 15 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>, three cows in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX> and seven in Burley.
</P><P ID="15">   All adult animals that were killed were sampled and tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>. The bull calves depopulated at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> were not sampled because they were too young for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> agent to be detected. There have been a total of 255 samples taken from the animals depopulated in the Mabton index herd, the herds in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quincy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX>, and the second <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> facility, as well as facilities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boardman</ENAMEX> and Burley. All samples have tested negative for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   The report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Review Subcommittee</ENAMEX> was delivered to the Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisory Committee for Foreign Animal and Poultry Diseases</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Wednesday</TIMEX>. That same afternoon, the co-chairs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisory Committee</ENAMEX> and members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> provided the Secretary a copy of the report and briefed her on its content.
</P><P ID="17">   The report identified several positive findings and actions taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> since finding this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> positive cow, including:
</P><P ID="18">   ? They commended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> on the comprehensive and thorough epidemiological investigation, and suggested all relevant information had been obtained at this point. Their recommendation was to conclude the investigation.
</P><P ID="19">   ? They stated that the tracing and recall of the rendered meat and bone meal that may have been contaminated with specified risk materials from the index case was effective and appropriate.
</P><P ID="20">   ? They indicated that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> ban on specified risk materials from cattle over 30 months of age removes the highest risk tissues from the human food supply and is in accordance with international standards.
</P><P ID="21">   ? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> confirmed the action taken by the Secretary in her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30</TIMEX> announcement to prohibit air injection stunning for slaughter animals.
</P><P ID="22">   ? In addition, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> confirmed the validity of the Secretary's announcement to prohibit Advanced Meat Recovery and mechanically separated meat from cattle over 30 months of age.
</P><P ID="23">   ? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> recognized the food safety merit of prohibiting nonambulatory cattle from entering the human food supply.
</P><P ID="24">   ? They confirmed that the testing of all normal cattle slaughtered for human consumption to be scientifically unjustified, both in terms of protecting human and animal health.
</P><P ID="25">   ? They recommended the adoption of rapid screening tests, which is consistent with the USDA's announcement to accept applications for licensure of such tests.
</P><P ID="26">   ? The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> acknowledged the importance of effective animal identification and traceability systems.
</P><P ID="27">   ? The subcommittee acknowledged the efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">US</ENAMEX> government to follow a science-based approach to policy formulation.
</P><P ID="28">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> also made several recommendations, all of which are being fully analyzed by USDA and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> colleagues.
</P><P ID="29">   These include a recommendation for a very aggressive surveillance program that tests all high-risk animals. The results from that intensive surveillance could then be considered in an evaluation of the overall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> program. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> also suggested that consideration be given to random sampling of animals greater than 30 months of age at slaughter, to encourage disease reporting at the farm level.
</P><P ID="30">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Subcommittee</ENAMEX> also recommended that a number of laboratories throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> should be approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Veterinary Services Laboratories</ENAMEX> to conduct screening tests as part of the national surveillance program.
</P><P ID="31">   The subcommittee, too, urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> to collaborate with the global community in the evaluation and validation of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> diagnostic tests.
</P>   






 










<P ID="32">Webmaster
</P><P ID="33">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




