


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> ponders ways to fund ambulance service
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The discussion at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting concerning the city implementing an ambulance utility fee went many different directions. But by the time everything was said and done, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> reached a consensus of sorts that the public will eventually decide what kind of ambulance/fire department service it wants.
</P><P ID="5">   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 15 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents have been paying a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per month fee to help fund the city's ambulance service. Residents were billed the fee along with their water and sewer service, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX>. The fee generated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140,000</NUMEX> per year. The city has been supplementing the service to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600,000</NUMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The problem for the city in collecting the fee came this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past May</TIMEX> when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled an ambulance service fee the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Kennewick</ENAMEX> was collecting was illegal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said since <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> adopted the same fee structure <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> did it meant the city's fee was also illegal. This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> officials suspended collecting the ambulance utility fee from residents.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> presented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with an ambulance fee the city could implement that he believes could pass the legal requirements of the courts.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the major difference between the fee he is proposing and the former one is it is not only assessed to residents, but businesses, as well.
</P><P ID="9">   "It is set up as a utility fee," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. "It has some of the characteristics of our water and sewer utility."
</P><P ID="10">   The fee would assess a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per month charge to all households on the basis 3.6 residents are living at each home. Businesses would then be charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per month for every 3.6 employees they have up to a maximum of 101 employees.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> explained residents in the city limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> would be charged a city rate for services provided while residents out of city limits would be charged a higher fee to utilize the local ambulance service. Out-of-town residents will roughly see a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> increase in prices for city ambulance service.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> added that with the addition of the businesses having to absorb the monthly fee, the city will raise an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$72,000</NUMEX> for the ambulance service.
</P><P ID="13">   Another part to the discussion centered around raising the Medicaid/Medicare rates to where the city is being reimbursed appropriately. The city currently charges Medicaid/Medicare extensively lower reimbursement rates than it should, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> was proposing across the board increases for everything from mileage to medical care, estimating the city would receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> in additional funding from Medicaid/Medicare.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> must have some sort of ambulance service to offer its residents.
</P><P ID="15">   "To some extent a fire department is an insurance policy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   He said in going out into the community he has heard continuously from residents how much they like the ambulance service the city offers now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the key for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is to agree on a structure for the ambulance service that the city can depend on for revenue.
</P><P ID="17">   "The ordinance we feel will pass the mustard in court," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he wants to continue discussion in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the proposed ambulance fee. He also wants to hold an open house to invite local business owners to offer input on how the fee would affect them.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed unanimously to change the Medicare/Medicaid reimbursement rates to the higher amounts. A public hearing with expected adoption is set to take place at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Sept. 13</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="20">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> couldn't quite agree so whole-heartedly about the ambulance service fees.
</P><P ID="21">   Councilman John Torch was concerned about shifting costs to businesses. Torch wanted to open up discussion with other cities about how they handle ambulance services before agreeing to any set fee.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>, who has been adamant about how the ambulance service is a drain on the current expense fund, expressed his opinion on the matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of cities statewide provide an ambulance service with their fire department.
</P><P ID="23">   "There is a reason," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. "They are black holes that suck money. It is nice to have a Cadillac service, but we are paying a Ferrari price tag."
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> wanted to do a comparison with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> on why that city can maintain a fire insurance rating of five while only having two paid firemen.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> wants to leave the choice to local residents on whether they fund the ambulance service or not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> suggested putting the measure before voters during a special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> ballot issue. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> wanted to remind residents that if they vote to keep the present ambulance service with the monthly fees that have been suggested then they are going to have to pay for the construction of a new fire station down the road. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said with privatizing the ambulance service residents would not have to pay for a new fire station. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he didn't believe the fee that was being proposed to fund the ambulance service would be enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said the city would need to charge residents and businesses <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX></NUMEX> per month to see any economic benefit.
</P><P ID="26">   Council members brought into the discussion regionalization of the ambulance service and how a business fee for the service might deter economic growth in the community.
</P><P ID="27">   "The only way it is going to pass the mustard of the court is (if we) charge residents and businesses," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. "By applying it city-wide we pass the mustard of the court."
</P><P ID="28">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="29">Webmaster
</P><P ID="30">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




