
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAX</ENAMEX> barbecue, ice cream social to benefit local kids
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The barbecue is free, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Biehl</ENAMEX>, owner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE/MAX First Advantage</ENAMEX> located on Yakima Valley Highway, is hoping those who attend will donate money to help local children with special needs.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE/MAX</ENAMEX> office will be hosting the barbecue to benefit Children's Miracle Network <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at its office, 1220 Yakima Valley Hwy.   Since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX> opened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE/MAX</ENAMEX> office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, all of the agents working in the office have been "miracle agents," meaning they donate part of their commissions to the Children's Miracle Network.   Recently, the office stepped up and every agent donated at least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per side of a sale. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX> explained that if an agent has the listing and then sells the house themselves, at least <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> will be donated to Children's Miracle Network.   "All the money we donate stays for local families," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebekah Padgham</ENAMEX>, office manager for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAX</ENAMEX>.   She said the money benefits children in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> with cancer, leukemia, birth defects and other diseases.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE/MAX</ENAMEX> held a pizza party at the Children's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Village</ENAMEX> located in the Mid Valley Mall and the agents were able to meet an autistic boy who benefits from Children's Miracle Network.   The boy, who doctors said would never walk, is beginning to crawl and also showing signs of communication, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Padgham</ENAMEX>.   She said money donated to the cause not only directly benefits the youngsters, it also helps provide support groups for families and arrange travel to hospitals. Clinics with specialists are available at the local Children's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Village</ENAMEX> because of funds raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX> in Seattle are Children's Miracle hospitals.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX> said that the 13 agents in his office decided they wanted to take their support of Children's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Village</ENAMEX> further by holding a benefit barbecue.   Hamburgers and hotdogs will be grilled up and given away, and ice cream and root beer floats will be served for free. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX> is hoping that those attending will give donations to the Children's Miracle Network.   "All the food has been donated so all of the money will go directly to Children's Miracle Network," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX>.   The office will also be having a raffle. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX> said that a 27" color television has been donated by TV Towne for the raffle. Net Access donated Internet access, and gift certificates have been donated by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scissors City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cromwell Radiator</ENAMEX> and Automotive Repair.   The raffle tickets are currently available at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE/MAX</ENAMEX> and will also be available the day of the barbecue. They are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> each.   "This is our first fund-raiser," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX>. "We hope to make this an annual event."   Nation-wide, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RE/MAX</ENAMEX> is the second largest contributor to Children's Miracle Network. Donations from sales are made on behalf of the buyer or seller, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biehl</ENAMEX> added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

