


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> retains U.S. Senate seat
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> voters must still like the message of the lady who made a name for herself wearing tennis shoes and being a working mom.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>, a Democrat, was overwhelming re-elected to a six-year U.S. Senate term <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, as she defeated Republican challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Election results <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">53.9 percent</NUMEX> of all ballots cast (1,020,470 votes), compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, who had 832,527 votes (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX>).
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> basically took the election with her win in King <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, where she had 344,702 votes compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s 174,495 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> also won big in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snohomish County</ENAMEX>, beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> by a little less than 26,000 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thurston County</ENAMEX> by nearly 14,000 votes.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> was a winner in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> (26,236 votes). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> garnered 21,204 votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> also won huge in his native <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane County</ENAMEX> with 94,930 votes compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s 61,998.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fourth District</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> fended off a surprisingly strong challenge from political newcomer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Matheson</ENAMEX>, a Democrat. In <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>'s tallies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.6 percent</NUMEX> of all ballots cast (110,579 votes), compared with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX>'s 65,998 votes (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">37.7 percent</NUMEX>).
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> with 27,623 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX> had 20,520 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, a Tri-Cities native, also won heavily in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton County</ENAMEX>, taking 29,415 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX> had just over 17,000 votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton County</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> didn't lose one of the 10 counties in his district.
</P><P ID="12">   "It's my privilege to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>'s voice in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and I'm honored that the people have chosen me to represent them for another two years," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>. "I plan to build upon my record of service to families and communities so that our children and grandchildren can enjoy a happy, healthy and prosperous future right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> vs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="14">   It looks as if the race for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state governor between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Christine Gregoire</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> will go down to the wire. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX>'s vote totals had the two running neck and neck, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> holding a slight edge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> had 908,077 votes (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48.96 percent</NUMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> so far has 907,691 votes (<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48.94 percent</NUMEX>).
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> has so far won 30 of the 39 counties in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> is well ahead in the crucial King <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> counts with 305,281 votes compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>'s 211,266 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> easily defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> with 30,592 votes to her 16,892 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> also won huge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton County</ENAMEX> with 32,118 votes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX>'s 14,258 votes.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> 15
</P><P ID="17">   In other election results, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> was re-elected to his 15th legislative district seat. He ran unopposed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> was a big winner in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> over Democratic challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kepcha</ENAMEX>. The 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> representative tallied 8,866 votes in the county, compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX>'s 4,023 votes.
</P><P ID="18">   County commission
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leita</ENAMEX> is the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County commissioner. The Republican took nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the votes in his bid for the district No. 1 seat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> replaces long-time Commissioner Tim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, who decided not to seek re-election. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay</ENAMEX> won his re-election bid, as he is more than 6,000 votes ahead of his nearest challenger, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul George</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   In other state election news, voters re-elected Lt. Governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Owen</ENAMEX> and Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Murphy</ENAMEX> won his bid for state treasurer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Sonntag</ENAMEX> will continue as state auditor. It looks as if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob McKenna</ENAMEX> will be the new state attorney general.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Superintendent of Public Instruction Terry Bergeson won her re-election bid, easily defeating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Billings</ENAMEX>, who was looking to reclaim the position she once held.
</P>





 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




