
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> woman celebrates 100 years of life
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/7/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha Curfman</ENAMEX> has been waiting a long time for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident is now officially 100 years old.   One hundred years old <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, April 7</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX> celebrated her centennial with about 50 family members at her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hillcrest Manor</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   Family from as far away as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX> for her celebration, which has spilled over into the week as well wishers have sent cards or dropped by to say hello.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX> was born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha Bates</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>'s Indian Territory in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> to cotton farmers.   She moved with her family to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, where her father filed for a homestead adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX> family, which she later married into. The Santa Fe Trail divided the two homesteads.   On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> Day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1921</TIMEX> she was married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Curfman</ENAMEX>.   They moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1930's</TIMEX> during the Great Depression. Drought drove them from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX>'s family located in the Outlook area in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>. They leased 160 acres of Indian land for a dairy and later an egg business.   After her husband's death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX> moved into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   She is now a resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hillcrest Manor</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX> has five children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bemma Lou</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy</ENAMEX>. She has 16 grandchildren, 41 great-grand children and 15 great-great grandchildren.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

