
<P ID="1">Mustangs make it two in a row over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> frosh team
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser High School</ENAMEX> freshman football team is plenty tough. Just ask the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> frosh squad.   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> wore down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> freshmen enroute to scoring a 28-7 victory. It was the second such win for the Mustangs against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two weeks</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s lone score came in the fourth quarter on a 25-yard TD pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Cantu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Cornelius</ENAMEX>.   "We were dragging a bit at the end of the game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Glenn Braman</ENAMEX>. "We weren't as conditioned as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>."   Despite sustaining the defeat, which squared the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> freshman team's record at 2-2 on the season, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said he is optimistic his club can bounce back against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>'s freshmen <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.   "The kids realized they needed to be in better condition, and even asked to run more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> in practice so they're in the kind of shape they need to be in," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said.   Against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, the Grizzly players had their opportunities to score early on, but were unable to punch the ball into the end zone.   "We had lots of long drives in the game," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said. "But we couldn't sustain the drives once we got inside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s 10-yard line.   "In fact, we had three drives that ended on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s 1-yard line," he added.   "Our kids have to learn that the motto is to win every snap. We need 11 guys going hard on every play. We're getting close to that, but we're not quite there yet," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> scored two of its touchdowns on passing plays, the other two scores coming on rushing attempts.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

