


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state politicians respond to convention remarks
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth District United States</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eighth District United States</ENAMEX> Congresswoman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Dunn</ENAMEX> were selected to lead the Republican response in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state to the opening day of the Democratic National Convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>'s teleconference by disputing claims from Democrat presidential candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> about how <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s Democratic National Convention would focus on him and not President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "We really have not seen a lot of discussion about Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> and his background," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> said she would like to see Democrats let the public know more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> as opposed to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> bashing."
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> added that the message being delivered by Democrats at their national convention hasn't been an optimistic one, so far.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> addressed some comments about health care and prescription benefits that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> made right before the convention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> commented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> is using fear tactics in his campaign to scare voters, in particular senior citizens, about the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> health care plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s health care plan will work. She particulary cited the need for the new prescription benefit card that is now available.
</P><P ID="10">   "The fear campaign is not a good one for him to put out there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> also commented on how the President's tax relief efforts have benefited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> residents. She said 2.3 million taxpayers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> are benefiting from the President's tax cut packages. She also pointed out 780,000 married couples in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> are benefiting from the tax relief measures the President put into place. Unemployment in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> has also dramatically dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7.7 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.1 percent</NUMEX>, she said.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has also made it a priority to increase funding for programs, such as education, which has seen a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">49 percent</NUMEX> increase in funding under the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> administration</ENAMEX>. The budget for homeland security has tripled and funding for providing medical care for veterans has been increased by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> said during the forthcoming budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> veterans will see a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6 percent</NUMEX> increase in funding for health care in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state, alone.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> said she would like to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> camp acknowledge some of the accomplishments of the President.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said he wants to see Democrats talk more about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>'s record. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> pointed out Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> has voted in the past to cut funding for the military, intelligence and to promote higher taxes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> also highlighted some of the contradictions in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> campaign, noting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> has said he fully supports funding the recommendations of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> commission.
</P><P ID="15">   "His track record has been to cut our intelligence spending," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> needs to be acknowledged for his pro-growth stance that has helped boost the economy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s stance has helped promote the economy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state, both from the agriculture and industrial stand points.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> also commented on a remark from former President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clinton</ENAMEX> on the opening night of the Democratic convention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, remarked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has squandered the budget surplus he left the Republican President.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, who was voted to office during <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s first term, said none of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s budgets were balanced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said it was through a cooperative effort that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was able to build a surplus. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said, many people don't realize as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was leaving office the economy was headed towards a recession.
</P><P ID="19">   "Were it not for the President's (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>) tax relief, we might have been in a deeper recession," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said the President hasn't squandered the surplus, despite the Democrats claim. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said the President spent the money on needed tax breaks for Americans. The money was also spent on improving national security at home and abroad after the unexpected attacks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




