
<P ID="1">Gonzaga Bound
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/18/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">There may not be too many people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> who have heard of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Heytvelt</ENAMEX>.   But there are two who know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> quite well, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George and Carol Johnson</ENAMEX>, his grandparents.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> is a man among boys on the prep basketball court. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX>, who weighs 215 lbs. and stands 6'10", has been the centerpiece of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarkston</ENAMEX> boys basketball team for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last three years</TIMEX> and will now be taking his talents to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzaga University</ENAMEX> to play for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Few</ENAMEX> and the Bulldogs on a full-ride scholarship.   "He is quite the player," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarkston Coach Brendan Johnson</ENAMEX>. "He is legite. The talent is bar none. He has got that mix of talent that not a lot of big guys have."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> recently finished his senior year playing for the Bantams basketball team. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> was named the most valuable basketball player of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Spokane League</ENAMEX> this past season. The senior center helped the Bantams to a 23-5 record, and league, district and regional titles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> was also instrumental in the Bantams' seventh place finish at the 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX>'s mother, formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Johnson</ENAMEX>, is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. His grandfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> Grizzly graduate.   "We are happy for him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX>'s grandfather. "Everybody is anxious for him to get started (playing college basketball)."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said his grandson has always been quite the basketball player.   "I think he was born with a basketball in his hand," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> comes from quite a tall family, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>, who stands 6'0" himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX>'s father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolin</ENAMEX>, who is a captain with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clarkston Fire Department</ENAMEX>, stands 6'5". <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said his two granddaughters come in at 6'3" and 6'4".   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>, who has coached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>, said he hasn't seen a big man like the 6'10" senior who can play both inside and out like he does.   "He has been a big part of our success here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX> said his star center really didn't come into his own as a player until after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> break his sophomore season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> moved up to varsity his sophomore year and led the team in rebounds and blocks, while averaging eight points per game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> helped the Bantams to their first <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament appearance since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> was named the newcomer of the year in the then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Border League</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> was later selected to play for a Seattle Rotary Select basketball team and broke through as a star player that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, taking part in some 50 games.   "I think that is when he realized his potential," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX>'s shining performance this past season had to be during senior night. In a 76-28 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Shadle Park</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> scored 36 points, hitting 14-of-17 shots, including 5-of-6 3-pointers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX> said the leadership <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> brought to the Bantams was what has really stood out.   "The offense is just the icing on the cake," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>. "We kind of thrived off his energy."   This season, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> led the team in charges, which is unheard of for a big man.   "There are not many big men who lead a team in charges," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>. "He just knew when the right time (to take a charge) was."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> also has a sense about him on the floor on how to stay out of foul trouble. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarkston</ENAMEX> senior fouled out of just three games all season.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX> said when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> decided <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last June</TIMEX> he was going to sign with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gonzaga</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldog Coach Mark</ENAMEX> Few nearly fell out of his chair.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> told me he has the most skill of any big man they have recruited at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gonzaga</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>. "That is an amazing statement coming from someone like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Few</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX>'s youth is about the only downside, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> will be joining the 'Zags in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to play basketball. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> will still be 17 when he is playing college ball. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> also said Few has plans to start <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> as a freshman.   "The next level is going to present some growing pains," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Johnson</ENAMEX>. "I think he (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX>) still has to get that killer instinct. Hopefully at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gonzaga</ENAMEX> he can get that. If he can get through his freshman year, I predict good things for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh</ENAMEX>."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> had an opportunity to see his grandson play at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament a few weeks ago.   "I have only seen two games this season," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. "But we are kept informed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said when his grandson was younger he never thought he would grow up to play for an elite college program such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gonzaga</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said his grandson had five to six big binders full of scholarship offers from colleges to play basketball.   "You name it, he has had an offer," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson   Johnson</ENAMEX> said his grandson is also quite the baseball player, standing out as a pitcher.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said he can't wait to see his grandson play for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gonzaga</ENAMEX> and said he will watch him as often as he gets the opportunity.   "We just hope he remembers us when he is making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>," laughed the proud grandpa.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daily News   George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Johnson</ENAMEX> hold a picture of their grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Heytvelt</ENAMEX>, following his 36-point performance on senior night during this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past winter</TIMEX> basketball season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heytvelt</ENAMEX> earned a full-ride scholarship to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzaga University</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> and is expected to start as a freshman.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

