
<P ID="1">Gubernatorial candidate stops off in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Working as a member of the private sector, gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> feels he has a different perspective to bring to the office. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>, who is a commercial real estate investment banker and has served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state senate, is the leading Republican candidate for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state governor.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said he feels one of his top priorities, if elected, will include looking at ways to improve the state's economy and job market.   "People are broke and out of work," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said, noting that it is clear that the situation is not getting any better.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said he feels one key to helping solve this issue lies in helping small businesses in the state grow and prosper.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said one of his goals, if elected, is to show people that it is possible to be both fiscally conservative and civically responsible.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said he is also concerned about the state of the region's health care situation. He noted that malpractice insurance is out of control and is driving highly qualified physicians out of the state.   "We have to keep our doctors here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said. He added that it's nice to have health insurance, but it's not much value if there are no doctors to go to. "It's an issue, especially in rural areas," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>, who was chairman of the budget writing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>, said he was proud of his work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this last year</TIMEX>, which included balancing the budget without implementing new taxes.   Working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> also had a chance to include funds in the budget for certain projects, including the Black Rock Reservoir project.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said he feels water storage is an important issue on this side of the state, noting that money was set aside in the budget to support the storage project.   "No matter what happens, we need more storage in this basin," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said. "Water is going to be key."   When it comes to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> tests that are on their way to becoming a graduation requirement for students throughout the state, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said he feels it's important to keep standards high throughout the school system. However, he added that it is something that needs to continually be re-examined.   "We need to look at if we're measuring, what we want to be measuring," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said in regards to the WASL.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>, who is the youngest of nine children and was raised on a school teacher's salary, said he worked hard to get pay raises for first through seventh year teachers during the budget session.   "The lowest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> of teachers get a raise because of me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> said. He noted that first through seventh year teachers should now make no less that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> a year.   He said he also managed to include a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> increase in per student spending for schools in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> also noted that if elected he plans to be "governor of the whole state." He added that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> marked his 13th visit to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

