
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFW</ENAMEX> co-founder encourages <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Latino voters to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> for president
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For Marisela Guzman of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, attending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s public meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> that was geared towards Latino voters was more of a curiosity.   The 18-year-old will be voting for the first time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this November</TIMEX> and she wants to make an informed decision, she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flora Lucatero</ENAMEX>, 25, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> just to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolores Huerta</ENAMEX> speak.   "She's one of my heroes," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucatero</ENAMEX>. "I agree <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> with what she says."   Issues that concern both Guzman and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucatero</ENAMEX> are education, health care and jobs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucatero</ENAMEX> said the job issue is especially important to her since her father-in-law was laid off from the Goldendale aluminum plant after 25 years of service.   "That was partially because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucatero</ENAMEX>.   The young women were among about 100 attending a dinner at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navarro's Community Center</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National</ENAMEX> Chair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Farm Worker</ENAMEX> co-founder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolorez Huerta</ENAMEX> spoke.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>, who co-founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFW Union</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Chavez</ENAMEX>, spoke in support of presidential candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriel Portugal</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Steering Committee for Latinos</ENAMEX> opened the evening's events by telling attendees there is power in the vote.   He compared voting to going to the store.   "The vote is like money," he said. "When you go to the store and buy tortillas, do you buy them because everybody else is or because you want and you need them?"   He said voting is the same way, explaining that you go to the poll to place your vote not for, who your friends vote for but for who you want and need.   "When we have Hispanic issues, we need to have Hispanic representation who knows what our needs are," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portugal</ENAMEX>, adding that they shouldn't just vote Democrat.   "You want to see who is available, who you can purchase with your vote," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Kenney</ENAMEX> introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>, but first said that Latinos of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state are important to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s election.   "Latinos in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> know they can make a difference," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenney</ENAMEX>.   The Latinos for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kerry Committee</ENAMEX> was formed to help bring unified support to the presidential candidate, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenney</ENAMEX>, who added that it also brings the Latino community awareness of the differences between the two candidates and which ones are speaking for the Hispanic community.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenney</ENAMEX> introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>, an icon to farm workers across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, to the crowd.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> is a civil rights leader, a parent, a grandparent and great-grandparent, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenney</ENAMEX>.   "She has played a major role in all our communities," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenney</ENAMEX>.   Arrested 22 times, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> was involved in the Delano Grape Strikes and helped pass the first laws protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> farm worker rights. She was also instrumental in lobbing against federal guest worker programs and spearheaded legislation granting amnesty for farm workers who had lived, worked and paid taxes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> for many years, but were not able to enjoy the privileges of citizenship.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenney</ENAMEX> also noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> was one of three named the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> Ms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magazine</ENAMEX>'s "Women of the Year." She was also listed as one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies Home Journal</ENAMEX>'s "100 Most Important Women of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20th Century</TIMEX>," and has been inducted into the National Women's Hall of Fame and has received the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Civil Liberties Union</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACLU</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Baldwin Medal</ENAMEX> of Liberty award.   With the crowd shouting "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viva Dolores</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> took the stage.   She introduced a group of Snokist strikers who were attending the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> event. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> encouraged those attending the meeting to support the strikers in their efforts.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Chavez</ENAMEX> always said we need to continue the fight and never give up," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>.   She said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s election is important to the whole country.   In the war against terrorism, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s reasons for going to war were not valid.   "The message isn't clear," she said. "People are confused."   In recent months <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ads have been played on Spanish television.   "Oh, yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> loves Hispanics now," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s plan for immigration is not a good plan," she said. "The proposals <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is making are not good for Latinos."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> also criticized <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> for his refusal to increase minimum wage.   Not only in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, but nation-wide the number of people who are living in poverty has increased, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>, adding that more than half of them are Latino.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> does not care about poor people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>. She added that his immigration proposals aren't good enough.   "Anybody who comes and works and pays their taxes has the right to pursue their citizenship," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>.   She said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is making a lot of promises and has not created a single job, although many have lost their jobs.   "The secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">labor</ENAMEX> is taking jobs to other countries. That's not good," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>. "Jobs need to be here for Americans."   Another issue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> said is important is the financial aid issue.   "Financial aid is slowly going away," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>. "Financial aid is not available for our students."   She said decisions made in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United State</ENAMEX> affect the world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> said the big corporations receive big tax breaks.   "When everyone got taxes back that's nothing compared to what the corporations are getting back," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>.   Health care is also an issue that concerns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>.   "How is it we are one of the most powerful countries in the world and we don't have health care for all the citizens?" questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>.   She said that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cuba</ENAMEX> is a small, poor country with a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> embargo and yet people have access to medical care.   "How is that possible?," she added.   Quoting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> said, "All Americans should have the same health insurance that our congressmen and women have."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> said that Republicans tell people that Democrats want big government while Republicans want small government.   "The only reason they want small government is because they want corporations to run the government," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>. "Corporations want to privatize everything and it's going to affect everyone."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> said that Republicans will tell farm workers that Democrats have no family values since most of them support gay marriage.   "I am a Catholic woman and I have really high morals and I have 11 children, but that doesn't mean everyone should have 11 children to have family values," she said.   "If two men get married how does it affect our pocketbooks," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>. "It doesn't affect us, period. What affects us as a family is the pocketbook, which is affected by no jobs."   "Get out and vote," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> encouraged those at the rally. "We have a lot of power and we can do it."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

