
<P ID="1">Drug sniffing canine demonstrates talents for students
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">His clear, blue eyes watch every move the man makes as he crosses back and forth across the room. It's not that he is particularly interested in the man. He is, however, interested in the round, green object the man has concealed in his right hand.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> might be getting older, but there is still plenty of spark left in his heavy set frame.   Even though he is nearing retirement from his job, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX>, a blue Australian Shepherd, is always eager to play ball with his <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">handler Joe Glossen</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County LEAD Task Force</ENAMEX>, an agency charged with stopping drug traffic in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   The pair took part in a classroom demonstration held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> during Drug and Alcohol Awareness Week. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> demonstrated how the partners search for drugs, which as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nick</ENAMEX> is concerned, the drugs are just an excuse for him to get to play ball. "It's his reward, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> explained   "We use the ball as part of his training," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> said. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> is ball obsessive. He'll look for anything as long as he gets to play ball," he said.   Sniffing out the drugs is a game for him, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX>.   It's a game <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> is very good at. But the friendly dog is getting older and will soon be allowed to play ball as much as he wants too, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> has worked sniffing out drugs for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>. "We are already training a new dog to take over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nick</ENAMEX>'s job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> said a dog like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nick</ENAMEX> undergoes more than 240 training hours learning to search out illegal drugs, such as marijuana, cocaine, heroin and meth.   "He is usually pretty mellow, " said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX>. "Until it's time to go to work, then he is all business," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> said about any kind of dog can be trained to search out drugs. He said a dog chosen for the specialized work must have the ability to follow directions and as in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nick</ENAMEX>'s case, be just a little obsessive about playing ball.   During the course of his career Nick has searched out drugs in homes, cars and one time he found drugs on a person's body, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> said.   But now that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nick</ENAMEX> is getting to be well past age 10, it's harder for him to get up on counters or tables where he may need to search out the contraband.   "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> is looking forward to relaxing around the house and playing ball with my little boy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glossen</ENAMEX> said. "He'll finally get to have a few more treats too," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

