
<P ID="1">School superintendent candidates meet <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> parents
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/25/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - The two <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent final candidates spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> in the community answering a litany of questions, touring the facilities and meeting with the public.   The candidates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pasiero Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luz Juarez Stump</ENAMEX>, each spent a day in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> getting a feel for the community, its needs and the role they would like to fill in it.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, who currently is the director of the migrant education regional office at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX>) 105 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, listed in her objectives for obtaining the position that she wants to provide leadership in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> so the teachers and administrators are supported and students are successful. She said it is also important that parents are partners in their children's education.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> has been the director of the migrant education regional office since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. She coordinates and assists 32 school districts in south <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">central Washington</ENAMEX> develop, implement, monitor and evaluate effective programs for Title I/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LAP</ENAMEX>, migrant and bilingual students of all ages.   Prior to being hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> served for 10 years as the bilingual/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESL</ENAMEX> coordinator for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Angeles Unified School District</ENAMEX>. She authored a Spanish language curriculum and has hired and supervised bilingual aides.   She has also served as a reading specialist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junipero Serra High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Compton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Calif.   Davis</ENAMEX> has a Master of Arts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loyola Marymount University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and a Bachelor of Arts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barry University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX>. She has also completed some of her doctoral studies at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>.   She also holds her initial administrator superintendent and principal credentials from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stump</ENAMEX> is the principal of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Elementary School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. A native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, she worked in the Mattawa, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kirkland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> school districts before taking the principal position at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX>.   She said it is her desire to work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, and the good things she has heard about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> schools has drawn her to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>.   The mother of five, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stump</ENAMEX> has an 18-year-old special needs son and a daughter who will be a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisenhower High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. She also has an eighth grader, a fourth grader and a three-year-old.   She has recently been accepted to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> to pursue her superintendent credentials, which will take her away from the schools one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> a month.   A former high school basketball coach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stump</ENAMEX> said she is dedicated to being at the both school and community oriented events.   She also has plans to involve the parents and encourage them to participate in their children's education.   The decision on who will be the next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> superintendent will be made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 2</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

