


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s Republican precinct caucuses to help mold <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> local, national platforms
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Republicans will soon have a chance to help mold the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> platform, taking an up-close look at everything from national issues affecting the country to local issues taking place right here in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 9</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Republicans will gather at 26 locations throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> to discuss platform issues and select delegates to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Republican Convention, which will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 24</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Werkhoven</ENAMEX>, third district commissioner for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Republican Party</ENAMEX>, explained that the precinct caucuses serve as a way for people to have input on the political party.
</P><P ID="7">   "You just can't miss the opportunity to set the agenda," he said.
</P><P ID="8">   All registered voters are invited to attend the precinct caucuses, with the only restrictions being that a person must attest to being a Republican and must not have attended caucuses for any other political party. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX> said once a person has signed in at the precinct caucus they will be given a questionnaire to fill out. The questionnaire, which is sent to the local precincts from the state Republican party, deals with national, state and local issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX> explained that the results from the questionnaires are compiled and then used to decide what the state Republican platform will be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Once the questionnaires have been filled out by all attendees, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX> said delegates are selected to take part in the upcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> convention, which is where the official county <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> platform will be adopted.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX> explained that each precinct is allowed to send a select number of delegates to the county convention.
</P><P ID="11">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> instead of each precinct conducting its own caucus, several different precincts will gather together for their meetings. For example, registered voters in precincts 1701-1703, 1705-1706, 1708, 3209, 4109, 4303, 4615, 4618, 4628 and 5001 will gather together for a meeting in the gymnasium at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Elementary School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The Grandview meeting, which includes precincts 301-306, 3101, 3105 and 4105, will take place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carl L. Stevens Senior Center</ENAMEX>. The Mabton meeting, which includes precincts 901, 3601 and 4002, will take place at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Administration</ENAMEX> building, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> meeting, covering precincts 501, 3002, 3303 and 3902, will take place at in the library of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelt Elementary School</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   For information on which meeting to attend contact Republican headquarters at (509) 972-0631 or 1-800-972-7545, or call the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Auditor's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> at (509) 453-1340.
</P><P ID="13">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




