


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">MARTIN G
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARTIN G. ARREGUIN</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin G. Arreguin</ENAMEX>, 33, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX> died suddenly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 1, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 3, 1971</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX> (Godines) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Antonio Arreguin</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22, 1992</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modesta Sandoval</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. Following their marriage they made <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> their home until moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">He is survived by is wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Modesta Arreguin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>; three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, Yesenia and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX>; his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose and Isabel Arreguin</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>; three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agustin Arreguin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candelario Arreguin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Antonio Arreguin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>; three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adelaida Saucedo</ENAMEX> and Marcelina Mata, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX> and Esperanza Abundiz of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 7, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be recited at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 8, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="9">WILLIAM <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EARL SHENYER</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Earl Shenyer</ENAMEX>, 80, long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> resident died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 2, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> Terrace in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="11">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1924</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pateros</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vera</ENAMEX> (Housden) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Fredrick Shenyer</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brewster</ENAMEX>. He served in the U.S. Navy during World War II and the Korean Conflict. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 5, 1946</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Spence</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermiston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, later making their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. He worked at the Hanford Project for 22 years.
</P>

<P ID="12">He was active in the development of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terrace Mobile Court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. He also sold real estate in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. He later owned and operated Green/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Insurance</ENAMEX> and Realty in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Following his retirement he owned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX> store in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Shenyer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Shenyer</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Young</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; five grandchildren; four great-grandchildren; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil Shenyer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pateros</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ada Jensen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brewster</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="14">He was preceded in death by his parents; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Dadisman</ENAMEX>; one grandson; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie Shenyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Shenyer</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX> services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 11, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bethany Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Inurnment will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 25, 2004</TIMEX>, at Packwood Cemetery, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewster</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DAVID PRESTON MCCLURE</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Preston McClure</ENAMEX>, 50, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 4, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13, 1954</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtle Irene</ENAMEX> (Wattenbarger) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur David McClure</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> served in the U.S. Navy as a jet mechanic during <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> and was honorably discharged as an E-6.
</P>

<P ID="19">He enjoyed camping, hunting, fishing and jeeping with the Timber Wolves.
</P>

<P ID="20"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> is survived by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtle and Carl McDonald</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy-June McClure</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara and Brian Hoffmeister</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina and David Barnes</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>; six grandchildren; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry C. McClure</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug L. McClure</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="21">He was preceded in death by is father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur McClure</ENAMEX>; and twin daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristeen McClure</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="22">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 8, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 9, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial with military honors will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="23"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DARLINE RUFF PHIPPS</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="24"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Ruff Phipps</ENAMEX>, 92, of Outlook our dear mother and grandmother left this world peacefully to be with her creator <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 1, 2004</TIMEX>, surrounded by her loving family.
</P>

<P ID="25"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darline</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21, 1912</TIMEX> in Orient, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>. She married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne A. Ruff</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Creston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>. They along with their two daughters moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> settling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX> they moved to the Granger area, where they had a small dairy operation and later got into the business of raising asparagus. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> they moved to Darline’s present home in Outlook, where they had a grape vineyard. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> passed away in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darline</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale L. Phipps</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. They continued farming on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruff</ENAMEX> farm until Dale’s sudden death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2003</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="26"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darline</ENAMEX> loved traveling, hunting and fishing trips, gardening and playing pinochle. In her younger years she loved to dance. Darline’s first love was always her family. She was a devoted wife, mother and grandmother.
</P>

<P ID="27"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darline</ENAMEX> is survived by her two daughters and sons-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen and Ollie Dodd</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy and James McCosh</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>; six grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>) Kobes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dodd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>) Ruff-Delgado of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> (Spanky) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bellinger</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nampa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lissa Gile</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bonner</ENAMEX> of Outlook; 11 great-grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Nash</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg LaPierre</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nikki</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nash</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gerrit</ENAMEX>, now serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bagdad</ENAMEX>, and wife, (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica</ENAMEX>) Kobes, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kettle Falls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Dodd</ENAMEX>, J.J., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin and Jacob Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy</ENAMEX>, who served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX>, and wife, (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandy</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>, who recently returned from serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, and wife, (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donaldson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsey Donaldson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Misty</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>, who served in Desert Storm) French of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nampa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, who served in Desert Storm, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gail</ENAMEX> (Jonny) Krowczyk of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kuna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>; and 13 great-great-grandchildren. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darline</ENAMEX> is also survived by four step-children and their families, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leroy</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phipps</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Touchet</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>) Pira of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cox</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grayland</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>) Levins of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pukalani</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="28"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darline</ENAMEX> was preceded in death by her parents; her two husbands; a sister; two brothers; and her most precious uncle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="29">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 7, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 8, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. In lieu of flowers, those wishing to honor Darline’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Assembly of God Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Hospice Services</ENAMEX> or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cancer Society</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="30">Webmaster
</P><P ID="31">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




