
<P ID="1">Grizzly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV</ENAMEX> moves to 7-0 on the season
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> junior varsity boys basketball team truly made it a team effort this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> at home against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies built a 25-16 first quarter lead and never looked back in their 79-69 win over the Bulldogs to move to 7-0 on the season.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV</ENAMEX> will host <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> tonight (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>).   "There are some guys who did some pretty good things," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV Coach Glenn Braman</ENAMEX>.   After trailing at the end of the first quarter, the Bulldogs matched <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s 20-point effort in the second quarter to trail 45-36 at the end of the first half.   The Grizzlies outscored <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> 14-11 in the third quarter. The Bulldogs took the final frame from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, winning the period 22-20.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had four players in double digits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derrick Simmons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Schilperoort</ENAMEX> led the Grizzlies in scoring with 13 points apiece. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX> dropped in 11 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Pacheco</ENAMEX> had 10 points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Plesha</ENAMEX> also scored 9 points for the Grizzlies.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> was a solid 5-for-5 from the free throw line.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX> led the Grizzlies on the glass, nabbing five rebounds.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacheco</ENAMEX> had six assists for the Grizzlies while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> had four dishes apiece. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammate Eric Crimp</ENAMEX> finished with two blocks.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> took good care of the ball in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s game, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX>, committing only 10 turnovers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said he was very impressed with the way his team played together against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.         Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knights JV topples Riverside   YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> junior varsity girls basketball team had a bit more success than its varsity counterparts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riverside</ENAMEX> Christian.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knights</ENAMEX> pounded the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crusaders JV</ENAMEX> squad, winning 56-23.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian opened the game with a 17-5 run and led 26-11 at the break. At the end of the third quarter, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knights</ENAMEX> were up 40-18.   "We started off like gang busters and never looked back," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian JV Coach Steve Martin</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> said his Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knights</ENAMEX> had numerous transition baskets in the game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tori Van Wingerden</ENAMEX> led the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knights</ENAMEX> in scoring with 19 points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abby Berkompas</ENAMEX> had 12 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacquie Roberts</ENAMEX> finished with 10 points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsey Wells</ENAMEX> ended up with 9 points for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knights</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian (8-2) will play <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaSalle</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

