


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police chief retires, but not for long
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">One of the most respected police officers in the state has joined the ranks of the retired.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX> retired from his job on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 15 of this year</TIMEX>, but his retirement didn't last long as he was hired back the same day.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>, 51, retired from his 31-year law enforcement career with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX> due in part to the state retirement system.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>'s retirement is completely different than the retire/rehire state program that gained notoriety over the last couple of years in the state education system.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> falls under a specific retirement program for law enforcement officers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said there are a number of different regulations governing each state retirement plan that would provide a vast, indepth explanation because they are so comprehensive.
</P><P ID="9">   "The rules are different for everyone," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the program allows a law enforcement officer to retire after 30 years without losing any benefits the particular officer has paid into his/her retirement. The difference between the law enforcement retire/rehire program and the one being commonly utilized by the education system is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> is not required to be away from his job for a 30-day period. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said under the law enforcement program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> was allowed to tender his retirement notice to the city and then be rehired immediately.
</P><P ID="11">   The major change concerning the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police chief is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> will only be able to work 150 hours a month, instead of the 160 hours in a normal work month.
</P><P ID="12">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> will work a couple of hours less each week than he did before," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> also wanted to iron out some other areas of clarification concerning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>'s retirement. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX>, the Mayor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX>, has the power to make appointments to positions such as police chief. Even under the state provisions concerning the retirement program, the city was not required to publicly post <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>'s position, as is required in the field of education, because it is not a position protected by a union. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> also pointed out that technically <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> never resigned his position, he just retired.
</P><P ID="14">   "The position never did become vacant," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> continued in the position. The hours he can work were the only thing changed."
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>, whose career spans 31 years with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX>, became police chief on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 3, 1984</TIMEX>. His current rate of pay is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,666</NUMEX> per month.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> will actually save about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX> per year in salaries, benefits and other expenses with having <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> employed as chief in this manner.
</P><P ID="17">   "It is a win-win situation for both sides," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said he was in favor of keeping <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> on because having such an experienced and respected officer on staff will only be a benefit to the city and the residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> is one of the most respected police chiefs in the state," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> expressed much of the same reasoning as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> for wanting to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> on staff. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> was actually approached by another employer with a job offer, but opted to stay with the city. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> at 51 was being hurt by the retirement system because he has put his years in on the job, but is still young enough where he can't afford to retire. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said he feels the city was fortunate to be able to retain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> and wants to assure the citizens they will still have full access to their police chief.
</P><P ID="21">   "We aren't going to see any changes (in the way the police department is ran) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>. "With the experience and knowledge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> has I think we are very fortunate to be able to retain him.
</P><P ID="22">   "We believe <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> has just done an excellent job as police chief," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




