
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School secretary</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> wears many hats during the day
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Answering the phone and making sure things get done in the office at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Elementary School</ENAMEX> are two duties that make up the tip of the iceberg for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">school secretary</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Sacher</ENAMEX> and her numerous responsibilities.   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 12 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> has found herself taking care of everything from ordering supplies for the school to caring for sick children. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> joked that she recently went back to look at her job description and decided that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of what she does falls under the category of others.   "I do whatever has to be done that isn't teaching or administrative," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> said.   Working at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Elementary School</ENAMEX> is something that started for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, before her youngest son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX>, now 16, had started kindergarten.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX>, working at the school is a little different than what she did before she had children. Before she and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, decided to begin a family, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> worked as a certified medical assistant.   However, when the secretarial position at the elementary school opened up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> knew the time was right to jump back into the working world.   "I kind of fell into the job and it worked out perfectly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> said.   She said her combination of experience, including her work in the medical field, has proven useful during her time at the school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> said she wears many hats between the hours of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>, including that of receptionist, secretary and school nurse. During the day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> said she takes care of attendance, is the first contact when someone is interested in sending their children to the private school, orders supplies for the entire school, and writes the school's newsletter, all while maintaining order in the school office.   Despite all of the different duties <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> can take on in the course of a day, she said her favorite part of the job remains the approximately 200 students who go to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Elementary School</ENAMEX>.   "You never know what will happen next with them, or what they'll say," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> said, being an organized person, she also finds that she enjoys the part of her job that includes ensuring that things run smoothly behind the scenes, including different fund-raisers and other activities at the school.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

