



<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Laboratory Groundbreaking</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5 May 2002</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="4">Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> joined Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Boynton</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> in breaking ground for the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25 million</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton Laboratories</ENAMEX> facility. More than 200 people attended the event, held on the site of the new building at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX> campus in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. "This remarkable facility is another example of our overall commitment to protect, preserve and restore the safety of our food and the health of Americans across the land," said Governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>. "Just imagine what this tremendous new facility will mean for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s future. We know the scientific breakthroughs that will be achieved here will further our understanding of fundamentals of biology and help us develop the necessary methods for curing mad cow disease."  </P>