
<P ID="1">Clowning around
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/26/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960s</TIMEX> the secrets of clowning were kept close to a clown's heart.   An amateur clown in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1970s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident Arlo (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waldo</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> couldn't find anyone who would help him hone his basic clowning skills.   "Back in the early 60s you couldn't get the old clowns to talk to you," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>, who was known to many people as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waldo</ENAMEX> the clown that taught fire safety to thousands of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> children before he retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.   Attending a circus at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Expo Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX> when his two sons were young, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> approached one of the clowns at the circus and identified himself as an amateur clown, asking a few questions.   "I was afraid to let little kids hug me because when they rubbed against me I'd lose half my face," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> said.   "He said, you powder don't you?" said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>. "I said no, and he threw his head back and laughed and said he'd be out after the show to talk to me."   That day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> learned the basic techniques professional clowns use to apply make-up (they don't make large smiley faces that engulf the top lip), and tricks of the trade when it come to bringing out the vivid colors and getting them to stay put without running.   Now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years later</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> is taking his skills and teaching a new generation of clowns.   "Clowns are all shapes, sizes and colors," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>. "They're a rainbow of funny faces."   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This winter</TIMEX> he started teaching a clowning class for the students of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School Family</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Career</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community</ENAMEX> Leaders of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FCCLA</ENAMEX>) club advisor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Johnson</ENAMEX>.   "It's an after-school group, so they're there because they want to be, not because they have to be," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> about teaching the students clowning lessons <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. She said about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX> she took a clowning class at St. Elizabeth's clowning association.   A clown emergency was called and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and her fellow clown students drove through the streets of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eschbach Park</ENAMEX>, painted with brightly colored makeup.   "We helped a company out," she recalled. The clowns they had hired didn't show up.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> and her fellow clowns spent the day bringing joy to young children and remembering that day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>, who has been known in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> as the fire safety clown.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> approached <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> about teaching some of her students clowning.   The students have taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>'s leadership and found their niche in clowning.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Trevino</ENAMEX> is one of the students in the class and has taken an interest in stilt walking.   "He found a pair of sheet rock stilts at a thrift store and started learning on them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>. "They must have been too heavy because he made another pair in wood shop."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> said the teen has gotten pretty good at walking on stilts and can even run on them.   "Stilt walkers aren't common. I never learned to walk on stilts," he said. "I tried when I was a kid. I finally learned to juggle."   Another two of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>'s students have mastered balloon twisting, making animals, and all of the students are interested in face painting.   Over the weeks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> has taught the students the basics of make-up, balloons, skits, juggling and costumes, and some of the students are talking about attending the Pacific Northwest Clown Conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. They are also planning to attend a one-day class in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> is teaching through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> on how to use the clown image to teach fire safety.   "It boggles my mind that high school aged kids have such an interest," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   But the students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> aren't the only ones learning clowning from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>. The youths at his church, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of God, are also learning skills from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   He said the church youths have an interest in helping with children's events, skits in church and special projects in the community.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> said what tickled him about teaching the kids from his church's youth group is that once they had the make-up on, they relaxed into clowning.   "Every time one of them would put on a different hat or wig, they'd run over to the mirror to look at themselves," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   In both of his classes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> has taught students, "...you don't have to have expensive stuff to start with. Start small and work up."   It's common for a clown to change his or her face several times before finding one that fits the personality they have created.   And, he said, the personalities of the clowns are sometimes the exact opposite of the person playing the clown.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> said when helping with the Wenatchee Youth Circus one year he met this shy little boy who was a clown in the circus. Once he had his make-up on he was a bubbly, out-going clown, but when the make-up was off he was shy again.   For years <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> was a white faced clown, which is a common make-up style that paints the entire face white before adding colors to make up the facial features.   "Then I learned I was too much of a roustabout to be a white faced clown, so I went to an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auguste</ENAMEX> (a style that uses white and colored make-up as well as skin tones)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   Traditionally, white faced clowns are reserved and are the instigators of antics in clown skits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auguste</ENAMEX> clowns follow through with the antics, such as a pie in the face, and the tramp or character clown is usually the clown that is the victim, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> doesn't have any specific memories of clowns as a child, he does remember entertainment at Dairy Days, an event held in his hometown in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>. The community brings in slapstick and skit performers, which he still remembers fondly. It's that type of humor that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> uses in his skits for groups and when teaching fire safety.   He also has a few slight of hand illusions and gags that he uses and has taught to his clowning students.   "Little kids are so gullible," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said that the skills the students are learning can go beyond community service into a part-time job.   In larger cities clowns can earn up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65</NUMEX> per hour at birthday parties and other events.   "That's not bad for a college job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said.   The sky is really the limit on the types of events, skits and clown personalities.   "The only limitation is your imagination," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX>.   "Clowning is coming back," he added.   With lulls in interest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waggoner</ENAMEX> said clowning almost died out, but, he said, he has done his best to keep the interest alive.   Over the years the attitude of secrecy in clowning has relaxed.   Now there are annual clown conferences held both regionally, nationally and internationally.   The conferences have seminars on costuming, skits, make-up and birthday parties, helping clowns develop their skills.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

