
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> PD trains reservists
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/4/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past January</TIMEX>, 15 people from around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> and as far away as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and the Tri-Cities started making bi-weekly trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to learn the ins and outs of law enforcement from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police officers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Patrol</ENAMEX> troopers and a prosecuting attorney.   In the past those who wanted to be reserve officers have had to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> or the Tri-Cities to attend six months of classes required to be a reserve officer.   With budget crunches in small communities across the state, police departments are depending on reserves to help fill gaps and provide extra police coverage in town.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the reserves have always played a key role in helping with special projects or events the police department has undertaken, whether or not the budget was tight, said Captain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Bank</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>. They were crucial in curbing the downtown gang problem and also helped cut down on cruising in the downtown, he said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> requires active reserves to volunteer at least 16 hours a month.   At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX> no reserve academies were planned, so the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> stepped forward to return the favor and host the classes, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>.   "We have a very good core of instructors right now," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>. "We have spent a lot of time and investment in our officers and we thought it would be a good opportunity to teach."   Class organizer Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Cunningham</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> added, "We've had our own reserves who have needed to go to academy."   The class started with 15 members, but one of the students left when she was hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wapato Police Department</ENAMEX> as a paid officer, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX>, adding that she will now be attending the state academy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Burien</ENAMEX>.   Beside reserves from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, reservists are training to work with the sheriff's office, city police departments throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakama Tribal Gaming Commission</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Victim</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Witness Unit</ENAMEX> for the Yakima prosecutor's office, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX> trainees are learning defensive tactics, ethics, criminal and courtroom procedures, communication skills, criminal law, crisis intervention, patrol procedures, traffic laws, use of force, firearms, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX> and first aid, emergency vehicle operations, criminal investigation and pepper spray, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX>.   The reserves test and will have to perform in mock scenes before the class is completed. The final test is the state exam, which is for state certification.   "When they graduate they will be a state certified officer for their department," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cunningham</ENAMEX>. "When they're on duty they're like any other officer. They have the power and authority to give tickets and put people in jail.   "A lot of these guys are taking the academy with the future hope of becoming an officer."   The class meets every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, but there have also been several <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> classes held to provide the reserves with additional practice.   The class will be completed by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of May</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

