


<P ID="1">Mystery rock leaves local folks with questions
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> a loud crash startled long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Della Vasquez</ENAMEX>, leading her to the discovery of a mysterious rock resting on the roof of her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Road</ENAMEX> home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasquez</ENAMEX>, who had never seen the rock on her roof before, thought it may have caused the large noise.
</P><P ID="5">   "At first she thought a car had crashed into her house, the noise was so loud," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasquez</ENAMEX>'s daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yollie Hernandez</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   But the rock was the only thing which seemed to be out of place when she investigated the cause of the crash.
</P><P ID="7">   "We don't know how it got up there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX>. "It is too heavy to have been thrown up there to cause the noise," she said.
</P><P ID="8">   "At first we thought it might be a piece of fallout from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount</ENAMEX>. St. Helen's, but that seemed improbable," she said.
</P><P ID="9">   The rock, which weighs about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 pounds</NUMEX>, isn't a part of a meteorite either, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Cone</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> science teacher.
</P><P ID="10">   It's a pretty interesting rock, but it's not from outer space, he said.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cone</ENAMEX>, who along with fellow science teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Beals</ENAMEX> examined the rock <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, said it also is not volcanic in nature.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cone</ENAMEX> said the rock is not basalt, as is normally found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. "It likely dates to the ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missoula</ENAMEX> flood, which formed much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>," he theorized.
</P><P ID="13">   The rock appears to be formed of grandiorite, which accounts for its crystallized specks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cone</ENAMEX> said. Now covered with slow growing lichens, the slightly elongated rock may have been a part of a rock wall at some point.
</P><P ID="14">   "There appears to be some type of sealant near the flat side of the rock," he noted.
</P><P ID="15">   But just how it came to be on Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vasquez</ENAMEX>'s roof is still a mystery.
</P><P ID="16">   "Someone may have placed it on the roof to hold something down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cone</ENAMEX> suggested.
</P><P ID="17">   But Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> said no work has been done on her mother's roof in over a year.
</P><P ID="18">   "Still, it is a pretty cool rock," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cone</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="19">   "But we still don't know what caused that loud noise my mother heard," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> said.
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




