
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> displeased with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> supplemental budget
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area lawmakers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> maintain that the Democratic-crafted supplemental budget adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Representatives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> puts taxpayers at risk.   The two Republican representatives said the Democrat budget plan puts taxpayers back into a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> budget hole. The Washington State House approved the supplemental budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on a straight party-line vote, 51-45.   During the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> session, the state legislature adopted a bipartisan two-year operating budget that closed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.7 billion</NUMEX> shortfall without general fund tax increases. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, lawmakers worked on a supplemental budget to make adjustments for emergencies and unforeseen costs, such as increased school enrollment and prison populations.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, though, say the supplemental budget that was brought to the floor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> spends reserves down to dangerous levels.   "We're seeing a slight recovery in our economy, but everyone knows we are facing a shortfall in the next budget cycle," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>). "Instead of using this supplemental budget as an opportunity to begin correcting the problem, they've developed a plan that makes the situation worse and puts taxpayers at risk."   The two legislators explained that the House Democrat spending plan leaves an ending balance of just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$199 million</NUMEX> in the state general fund, and would leave the state with a projected shortfall of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> in the next biennium. The two lawmakers say the spending plan includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$261 million</NUMEX> in new spending for expanded programs, offset by just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17 million</NUMEX> in proposed cuts.   That, say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, is a significant contrast to the more responsible budget plan passed by the Washington State Senate on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>'s supplemental budget, crafted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX>, increases state spending by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$69 million</NUMEX>, but leaves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$399 million</NUMEX> in the state's emergency reserve account. It also includes no new taxes and represents the slowest growing budget in state history, say Republican leaders.   "I feel we did the right thing for our jobs climate, for the elderly, for students, for low-income families and for taxpayers in general," said Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Zarelli</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ridgefield</ENAMEX>), chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zarelli</ENAMEX> points out that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> budget provides full funding for nursing homes and preserves community mental health funding. He also notes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> budget provides a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> salary increase for classified employees of school districts, and appropriates <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX> yearly in county backfill motor vehicle excise tax money.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>) said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Democratic plan is shortsighted and ignores the budget challenge facing lawmakers.   "We do not have the money to support this level of spending," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>. "It will force us to make drastic cuts to core services or raise taxes at a time when families and employers can least afford it.   "The looming tax burden is bad medicine for taxpayers and for our state's economy," he added.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> legislative session is scheduled to end <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>. Lawmakers from both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> will negotiate in the remaining days to work out differences in the competing budget proposals.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

