
<P ID="1">Public comments at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meetings to be limited
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> agreed this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to a change in procedures for its meetings.   The change involves the format for allowing public comment on non-agenda items. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> allows two public comment periods, one at the beginning and one at the end of each meeting. Under a new format, proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will allow for only one public comment period, which will be towards the end of each meeting.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is expected to formally adopt the change in the rules of procedure at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26</TIMEX> meeting.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he proposed the change because it would help make the meetings more efficient. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> mentioned that while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is limiting the amount of time each person can speak to five minutes, which is the current limit that is supposed to be enforced for public comment, there is no desire not to hear from community members.   The public comment period will be limited to five minutes for both agenda and non-agenda items.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> had originally wanted to limit the time for public comment to three minutes, but Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> felt the time should be extended to five minutes, especially for comment on agenda items. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said he felt three minutes provided too much of a limitation for people.   "I think three minutes is intimidating to people," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> eliminate asking people to give their address when making public comment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said there are concerns over privacy issues. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, though, said he liked the idea of asking people to give their address because it allowed the city to get in contact with each individual person. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed to give citizens, as it currently does, the option to not include their address when providing public comment. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will ask residents to say if they live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> or not.   At the suggestion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed to move the public comment portion for non-agenda items to the end of the meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> said that many times <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has staff from other agencies on hand to make reports. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> said it is costing taxpayers money to have these people sit through the public comment portion of the meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> also hoped that people would bring more of their concerns to city staff, which in turn would bring the issues before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also agreed to a recommendation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> to include more items under the consent agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> pointed out on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s agenda a couple of items that had already been discussed at previous meetings, which could have easily been placed under the consent agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said any items under the consent agenda can be pulled from approval for further discussion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said this method will make for a more efficient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

