
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> defeats Bulldogs
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/14/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - While the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> lay covered in clouds and cold weather <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> baseball team made the trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, where the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sun</TIMEX> shined bright on the Grizzlies.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> defeated the Bulldogs 6-4 to move to 5-1 in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> play (8-3 overall). The Grizzlies will host <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> in a twin bill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX>.   About the only gray spot for the Grizzlies in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s game was the two errors that led to three unearned runs by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   "I am happy with the way our kids played," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Coach Dave Martinez. "There were some things that happened in that game, but the kids kept their chins up."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> scored two runs in the first and lone tallies in the second and fourth innings.   The Bulldogs had a pretty good day at the plate, recording nine hits. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> also had two errors in the game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> scored three runs in the first inning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah Zakahi</ENAMEX> had a sacrifice fly to score <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX> and teammate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Anderson</ENAMEX> ripped a two-run single.   The Grizzlies picked up a lone run in the third inning and then two more runs in the top of the fourth.   With one out in the fourth inning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> moved to third off an error in the outfield. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammate Tyler Esqueda</ENAMEX> made it to first base on the same play and later stole second. Two passed balls then scored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esqueda</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zakahi</ENAMEX> gained his third win of the season (3-2) with his three innings of work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zakahi</ENAMEX> gave up one earned run, five hits, two walks and had five strikeouts. R.J. Elizondo worked the middle of the game on the mound, going 2-1/3 innings. Elizondo allowed four hits and three walks. He had one strikeout. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Uberuaga</ENAMEX>, though, came up big in his first save of the season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> pitched in relief in the sixth inning with one out and the bases loaded. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> got the first batter he faced to pop up and then the next one to strike out to end the inning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> had three strikeouts and one walk.   "That was a good test for him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> got it done."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had a decent day at the plate with six hits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esqueda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson</ENAMEX>, Elizondo and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Newberry</ENAMEX> each had a hit in the game. Grizzly catcher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Johnson</ENAMEX> had three walks in the game and scored two runs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newberry</ENAMEX> was also walked twice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> has a team-high 13 walks while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newberry</ENAMEX> is second with 12.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he is excited about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>'s doubleheader against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>. He said the Falcons have been scoring a lot of runs lately, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> has also been giving up a lot of runs.   "I hope we have a big crowd," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "We will go out there and see what happens."      
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

