31 25 33 7 21 5
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Think about a woman. Doesn't know you're thinking about her. Doesn't care you're thinking about her. Makes you think about her even more.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Sage</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sybil Adelman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Exposure</ENAMEX>, The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bumpy Road</ENAMEX> to Love, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>