


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX> promotes partnerships 
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX> is pumped.
</P><P ID="5">   The five-year veteran of county government is excited about the recent completion of the Wal-Mart distribution center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and the many multi-jurisdiction partnerships the project created.
</P><P ID="6">   "I'm excited about the many partnerships that have developed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>, helping to increase and improve development in the county and its cities," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Posse sees those partnerships as the start of many more such linking of mutual interests, such as his latest effort to partner with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> on an improvement project northeast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Posse said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Commission</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> are worked to create a partnership for improving infrastructures in the area north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rouse Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beckner Alley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   The area, which borders the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city limits, is the target of a major infusion of state and federal funds to extend sewer lines, as well as sidewalks and paved streets to the area, if the partnership proves successful, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX> told the Rotarians.
</P><P ID="10">   He said the partnership includes the changing of the designation of streets and roads in the area near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baggley Drive</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beckner Road</ENAMEX>, and could result in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> project.
</P><P ID="11">   Posse said the city and the county are in the process of seeking funds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX>, as well as community block grants to finance the project. Added to the partnership is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, which will be building a new school in the area just to the east of the targeted area, he said.
</P><P ID="12">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s recent decision with the voters' approval to build a new school on the east side of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX>, just beyond the city limits, is an opportunity for yet more growth in that area, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   Another partnership being developed is with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Irrigation District</ENAMEX>, for the purpose of piping the canal area along the east side of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX>, he said.
</P><P ID="14">   "These are very exciting times," he said. "We now have to work out the details. But the groundwork has been laid," he said.
</P><P ID="15">   "I think when it is completed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north Alderwood</ENAMEX> project will be one we can all be proud of," he added.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




