50 3 44 39 28 28
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  When a man says he approves of something in principle, it means he hasn't the slightest intention of putting it into practice.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Otto von Bismarck</ENAMEX> (1815 - 1898)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>