
<P ID="1">Outlook troop doing its part to save <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scout Council</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Daisy Girl Scout</ENAMEX> leader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Gatica</ENAMEX> learned that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid Columbia Council</ENAMEX> had to come up with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> or face closure, she nearly fell over.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX> said that every council is required to have a "Give from the Heart" fund, which allows girls who can't afford Girl Scouts to still participate in the program. The money is used for dues, uniforms and other expenses the girls have, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX>. There are 90 troops in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid Columbia Council</ENAMEX>. Six of those troops are in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, five in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and one in Outlook.   Since she learned the news, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX> and other parents of Girl Scouts have been working to raise the money needed, finding individual donors and businesses interested in supporting Girl Scouts.   "A lot of parents just don't have the funding," she said.   The troop also made a donation to the fund.   Outlook Daisy Girl Scout troop #397 donated half of its winnings for their booth at the Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo to the "Give from the Heart" fund. The other half of the money, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX>, will be used to purchase ceremonial flags, which will be needed as the girls transfer from Daisies to Brownies.   The vibrant red display at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> fair featured pictures of the girl's activities, as well as the goals the Daisy Scouts learn to live by.   "We were not expecting to win," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX>.   As part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>'s activities they Outlook group made "Girls are Great" suncatchers, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX>.   Their scrapbook highlighted events such as the Daddy-Daughter Dinner.   "They made invitations for their dads and for half an hour they got to sit down with their dad or grandfather, an adult male who cares about them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX>.   At the dinner, the girls made each of their dad's favorite dish for the meal.   The girls also had a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mommy</ENAMEX> and Me Tea, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX>.   "We taught them how to serve, and etiquette," she added.   The girls had a Got Sweats drive at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> and were able to collect three huge boxes of clothing, which will be used for students at the school <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this next year</TIMEX>.   After the clothing drive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX> said, the girls had to find five additional acts of service that they wouldn't normally do.   "It's about going out and making yourself a better person," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX> added.   "I've already seen a change even in my own child, in her behavior and how she treats people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gatica</ENAMEX>.   Those interested in donating to the Give from the Heart fund can call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Girl Scout Council</ENAMEX>, (800) 967-8113. Contributions are tax deductible.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

