


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> cancels investigation
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton Laboratories</ENAMEX> spokesperson <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurel Sulfate</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> has discontinued its investigation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> institution.  "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> informed us it was not pursuing its investigation of the laboratory, and that no operational modifications or impacts are imposed.  We see this as a complete vote of confidence in the critical work <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX> is doing for the nation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sulfate</ENAMEX>. 
</P>
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phone</ENAMEX> calls to Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX>, lab director, or Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VonRyker</ENAMEX>, chief scientist, were not returned. It is believed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">VonRyker</ENAMEX> is currenly in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paraguay</ENAMEX> performing experimental field tests on infected cattle in that country.
</P>



 










<P ID="6">Webmaster
</P><P ID="7">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




