
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> shortens spring break
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> will make up two school days lost to icy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> weather during its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> spring break.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX>, meeting this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, approved removing two days from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX> break schedule to give students more class time before they face their annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> examinations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> closures in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> due to inclement weather will be made up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> and 2.
Originally, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> was to have been on spring break <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 1</TIMEX>, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 9</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> students will celebrate spring break beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, April 5</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of school will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX> with seniors graduating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> boosts lunch prices
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> during its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> meeting approved increases in lunch prices.
The student lunch prices, which haven't been raised in two years, will increase by 10¢ at the elementary school and by 5¢ at the high school, following the board action.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> lunch prices will jump from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.50</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.60</NUMEX></NUMEX> with lunch prices going from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.75</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.80</NUMEX></NUMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Junior-Senior High School</ENAMEX>.
The increased prices will go into effect during the 2004-05 school year.
</P> 
 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> hosts national literacy expert
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Nationally known reading expert <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelley Harwayne</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York City</ENAMEX> will hold a literacy workshop in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 1</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harwayne</ENAMEX> will work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> teaching staff from 8 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>, as part of the district's emphasis on reading and writing improvements and teacher coaching. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harwayne</ENAMEX> is also expected to work with teaching coaches from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> school districts during her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> visit, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> superintendent.
A retired <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York City Community School District</ENAMEX> 2 Superintendent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harwayne</ENAMEX> is the author of several books, including  Lasting Impressions: Weaving Literature into Writing Workshops and Going Public: Priorities and Practices at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Manhattan New School</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Roettger</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High</ENAMEX> head track coach
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Roettger</ENAMEX> has been appointed head track coach at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Junior-Senior High School</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>, who is serving as a literacy coach through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>'s Reading First Grant, will begin spring track practices the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first of March</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> will be assisted by D.J. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>, who coaches the Viking football team.
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

