
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local Perry Tech</ENAMEX> grads secure jobs while still in school
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Before graduation at least three of six <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area graduates from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Technical Institute</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> had secured jobs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Kelley</ENAMEX>, a recent graduate of the telecommunication technology program, is now working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX> in the Tri-Cities; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Sabedra Jr.</ENAMEX>, a recent graduate of the electrical technology program, is now working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berg Electric</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Rasmusson</ENAMEX>, a recent graduate of the electrical technology program, is now working at Shields Bags and Printing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   All three of the former students, who graduated on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 26</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Tech</ENAMEX> helped get them ready for the jobs they are currently doing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> said through the telecommunication technology program he learned about everything from the phone industry to the internet and low voltage wiring.   "It gives you a good basis for the whole field," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Tech</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> is currently using his education at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lockheed Martin</ENAMEX> in the Tri-Cities, working on everything from running computer networks to setting up and running different simulator programs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabedra</ENAMEX> said his education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Tech</ENAMEX> helped introduce him to a variety of different things in the field of electrical technology. He said he learned about everything from the National Electric Code to using a computer to controling a plant's electrical system.   Now that he is working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Berg Electric</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabedra</ENAMEX> said he is using what he learned at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Tech</ENAMEX>.   "So far it's been great," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabedra</ENAMEX> said of his new job, which he secured while he was still a student at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Tech</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rasmusson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Tech</ENAMEX> showed him how to do a little bit of everything.   "They just give you a foot in the door," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rasmusson</ENAMEX> currently works as a maintenance electrician at Shields Bags and Printing, a job he secured three weeks before graduation. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rasmusson</ENAMEX> isn't the first electrician in his family, he said his grandfather was an electrician, as well as several other family members.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rasmusson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabedra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX> weren't the only recent graduates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perry Tech</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delfino R. Campos</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Cervantes Jr.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> both graduated from the electrical technology program, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> graduated from the telecommunication technology program.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

