
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
S’side Wal-Mart fashion showon for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Wal-Mart store will host a patriotic fashion show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, May 29</TIMEX>.
The 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> affair will serve as a fund-raiser for Children's Miracle Network. Those attending the fashion show may make donations, with all proceeds benefiting Children's Miracle Network.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Train showchugs intoSeattle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9-11</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - The 15th annual National Train Show, the world's largest model train show, will be staged at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle's Seahawks Exhibition Center</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9-11</TIMEX>.
The illustrious event is held in a different city and state each year.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> extravaganza will showcase all aspects of model railroading, including the industry's newest and most unique products and services from national manufacturers and retailers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> and around the world. The event will cover more than 165,000 square feet of space, including 35,000 square feet featuring extraordinary operating model train displays.
Special highlights at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s show will include a free hands-on program for youths 6 to 15 years of age, an on-site collectibles appraiser, a children's play area, hands-on demonstrations and a display of an operating model railroad and metro cityscape made from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LEGOs</ENAMEX>.
Show hours will be from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 9</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10</TIMEX> and from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX>. Admission prices are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX> for senior citizens and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for children 6 to 12 years of age. Children 5 and younger will be admitted free of charge.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Sign-ups setfor kids <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> drama camp
The annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Drama Camp</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14-18</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.
The camp, directed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS Drama Club</ENAMEX> students and advisors, will be held daily from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>
Cost of the camp, which will include workshops in drama, singing, dancing and sword play, is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per child or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> per child for families with more than one child attending. Fees may be paid the first day of camp.
Tuition includes a camp t-shirt. Campers are asked to bring a sack lunch. The camp will conclude with a show on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 18</TIMEX>.
To register pick up forms at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> or call Maisy Sylling at 837-2601 for more information.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Follow your nose to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Garlic Festival
OCEAN PARK</ENAMEX> -  The 23rd annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Garlic Festival</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX> and 20 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean Park</ENAMEX>.
The two-day event features more than 80 food and craft vendors gathered at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheldon Field</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Long Beach Peninsula</ENAMEX>, three blocks from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Ocean</ENAMEX>.
In addition to a plethora of garlic-laced foods, live music from the Lipstick Dolls and Thunder Rose Band and the Blue Light Band will be heard throughout both days.
To learn more about the festival and the annual garlic dessert cook-off, visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Park Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> web site at www.opwa.com.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> poker run planned
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The annual Wine Country Rod Poker Run will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 29</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Country Park</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Way</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
Sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classic Knights Car Club</ENAMEX>, hot rods of all types will register from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at the park.
For more information call 882-2610 0r (509) 698-5650.
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

