


<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">DON <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. BRUNELL</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   Growing up outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Butte</ENAMEX>, there were three things I grew to dislike: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>'s convoluted state income tax, prolonged miners strikes and the state's primary election system.
</P><P ID="5">   Thank goodness <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> doesn't have its income tax and my family hasn't had to weather a prolonged work stoppage. But now, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> has <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>'s primary election system.
</P><P ID="6">   Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> voters took part in an "open primary," where they could vote across party lines for the candidates of their choice. But the courts threw out that system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   So, with no chance to reinstate the open primary, the Legislature passed a "Cajun primary" like the one used in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>, where the top two vote getters advance to the general election. As a back-up, they passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> prototype, to make sure <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> had a primary system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> vetoed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> system and left us with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> primary.
</P><P ID="9">   The political parties fought for the change on the grounds that the primary is for members of a party to select the party's candidate. They love our new system because it forces voters to select a Democrat, Libertarian or Republican ballot - and that makes it easier to develop target voter lists for fund-raising and campaign literature.
</P><P ID="10">   While they claim it won't label voters as being of one party or another, that's exactly what happened in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>. Here's how it worked: even though <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Butte</ENAMEX> was controlled by the Democrats, there was a shell of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>. In rural <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern Montana</ENAMEX>, it was just the opposite.
</P><P ID="11">   My dad was treasurer of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democrat Party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silver Bow County</ENAMEX>, in charge of lining up poll watchers. Each party had their people at the polls to make sure there was no political skullduggery and to find out whether the people they knew were voting Democrat or Republican.
</P><P ID="12">   How did they know? Because they could see which party's ballot voters took into the polling booth. So, word spread around <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Butte</ENAMEX> who the Republicans were and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern Montana</ENAMEX> who the Democrats were-and it could be most uncomfortable for those who were in the minority.
</P><P ID="13">   In fact, later in life when I worked for a Republican congressman from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">western Montana</ENAMEX>, I spoke to the Republican Women's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Butte-a</ENAMEX> handful of brave souls-including my high school civics teacher. She stayed after and said, "I hope your dad won't hold it against me that I came to hear you speak."
</P><P ID="14">   I told her that Dad didn't hold it against the priest at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary's Church</ENAMEX> because he would always request the lone Republican ballot in the precinct. I'm not sure he was a true Republican or just liked to tweak my father.
</P><P ID="15">   Fortunately, my father was a very understanding and tolerant man, and if the truth were known, he didn't like the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> primary system either. He called the teacher and told her he admired her courage for standing up for her convictions and that at least a few people turned out to hear his son explain why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>'s boys broke into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Watergate Hotel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> voters will have a chance to change the current primary. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Grange</ENAMEX> has qualified Initiative 872, which would allow voters to cross party lines and select the top two candidates for the general election. It will be different than the old open primary because the top two can be from the same political party.
</P><P ID="17">   So rather than taking out your frustration on Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX>, make your preference known in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don C. Brunell</ENAMEX> is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




