
<P ID="1">School board reverses itself, awards bid to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel Ford</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">It is not the cars the office of Migrant Student Data and Recruitment (MSDR) were originally looking for, but nonetheless, MSDR staff does have something now to drive.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> cleaned up some confusion at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting concerning the purchase of a pair of vehicles for MSDR.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> serves as the fiscal manager for the MSDR program.   At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting, the school board approved the bid from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel Ford</ENAMEX> to purchase two <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford Taurus</ENAMEX> vehicles.   MSDR will be leasing the vehicles from the school district. MSDR will pay the school district for all lease associated costs, such as maintenance.   The issue goes back to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> school board meeting. At that meeting, school board members approved a request from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MSDR Director Lee Campos</ENAMEX> to purchase a pair of Camrys from Toyota of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. The bids from the Yakima dealership were <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,195</NUMEX> for each vehicle, significantly higher than two other bids received. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel Ford</ENAMEX> submitted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> a bid of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,212</NUMEX> per car for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford Taurus</ENAMEX>. At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> meeting, the board also received a bid of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,429</NUMEX> per car from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Ford Inc.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX> for a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford Taurus</ENAMEX>. The board went with the more expensive bid under the understanding it was because the MSDR needed the vehicles immediately.   MSDR had received direction from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of Superintendent of Public Instruction to purchase vehicles for its staff. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campos</ENAMEX> explained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> that his staff members were turning in high requests for mileage checks. MSDR staff members have been using their personal vehicles to travel across the state to track the educational progress of migrant students.   The day following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> halted the awarding of the bid until he could clarify some issues surrounding the board's decision. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> was unable to be in attendance at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> meeting because of personal reasons.   Under state law, a governing body using taxpayer dollars has to go with the most conservative bid presented to them unless they can properly justify the reason for going with a higher bid.   At a special board meeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> suggested the board reject all bids submitted at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> meeting and readvertise the process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said he felt the bid specifications weren't as specific as they could have been. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> told the board he wanted the specifications to outline more what the district was looking for.   This time around, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Dave Plesha</ENAMEX> suggested the board go with the bid from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel Ford</ENAMEX>. Plesha said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> officials told him they could have the vehicles available in the next few days. Plesha said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> originally told him it would be up to 45 days before the vehicles could be delivered.   The school board actually went with the state bid amount submitted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harris Ford Inc</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,773</NUMEX> per <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford Taurus</ENAMEX>. The catch is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> agreed to match the state bid, which board members approved.   The original state bid amount was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,753</NUMEX> per vehicle before taxes. The amount rose with the addition of fees for daytime running lights and a 60/40 split fold rear seat. Following license and title fees the final bid amount increased to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,773</NUMEX> per vehicle.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> agreed to provide all the items that were included in the state bid.   Some of the items that will be featured in the two <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taurus</ENAMEX> cars include side-impact door beams, power front disc and rear drum brakes, air bags, fabric cloth seats, sunglass holder, outside temperature gauge and digital clock, power windows, air conditioning, remote keyless entry with trunk release, cruise control and deluxe AM/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">FM</ENAMEX>/Cassette/CD audio with six speakers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Kilian</ENAMEX> said he was glad to see the district accept the best offer for the vehicles. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said the savings will prove out in the long run for the school district.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

