
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">   Board votes to call for road improvement bids   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved a call for bids to make improvements to the district's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX> property.   The improvements include the installation of a six-foot pipe in the ditch that is located along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX>. According to the school district, approximately 1,000 feet of pipe will be needed to cover the ditch. The cost of pipe is estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX> a foot.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves six MSDR contracts   Members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> approved six contracts for the Migrant Student Data and Recruitment (MSDR) office.   The contracts are with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Reddinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald D. Vanderholm</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Yazmin Gil-Preciado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Alcantar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Johnson</ENAMEX> and Candelario Gonzalez. The contracts with each run <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from May 12 through Aug. 30</TIMEX>, except the contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil-Preciado</ENAMEX>, which runs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from June 8 through Aug. 30</TIMEX>.   The contracts are for reviewing districts and classrooms as assigned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction (OSPI). Those contracted will attend a special training through OSPI, and will then receive each of the assigned classrooms for approximately 20 minutes per room.   The contract states that MSDR will pay each of the consultants <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> per classroom they review with approximately 50 classrooms per week set to be reviewed.      SEMY contract approved   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved a contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Weron</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office of Secondary Education</ENAMEX> for Migrant Youth (SEMY).   The contract is effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6 through Aug. 31</TIMEX>, and calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weron</ENAMEX> to rewrite tests from the national PASS geometry course to fit the Scantron format.   The contract is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23</NUMEX> per hour, not to exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,200</NUMEX> for writing the course.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves contract for personal services   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved a contract for personal services with Positive Outlook, an organization out of Outlook.   The contract states that Positive Outlook will serve as a liaison between the school district and home school families, ensuring that they have access to certain programs.   The contract is for up to 100 hours of service throughout the school year, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX> an hour.      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> to receive equipment   from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> approved an equipment gift agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Energy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>.   According to the agreement the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX>, through an executive order, must give highest preference to elementary and secondary schools when it comes to gifting education-related federal equipment.   The equipment the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> is set to receive includes 10 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dell</ENAMEX> computers.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves mentor program agreement   An agreement approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> will mean the implementation of a mentoring program through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Community Action Center</ENAMEX>.   The agreement states that the district agrees to work with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Community Action Center</ENAMEX> to operate the school-based program. According to the agreement, the district will refer both students and potential mentors to the program, as well as promote the services through various school district communication channels.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves agreement with Lourdes Health Network   An agreement between Our Lady of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lourdes Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> will help provide education and therapy programs for students in the day treatment program.   The agreement, which was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>, is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36</NUMEX> an hour per student for each student enrolled in the day treatment program. The services will be offered through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lourdes Counseling Center</ENAMEX>.      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> enters into agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> schools   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> approved an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima School District</ENAMEX> to provide services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Valley</ENAMEX> district.   The agreement states that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> will provide the services of a certified occupational therapist assistant to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> district at a fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> a day, based on a seven-hour school day.   The agreement runs from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 24</TIMEX> to the end of the 2004-05 school year.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> enters into agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> district   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> to provide services to a severely disabled student.   The agreement states that the student will be allowed to take part in the program services offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>. The estimated cost of providing services to the student is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,000</NUMEX>, which will be paid by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves grant writer agreement   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> approved an agreement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> between the local school district, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital Association</ENAMEX> for grant writing services.   The 12-month agreement runs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from January to December 2004</TIMEX>.      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> enters agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Comprehensive Mental Health</ENAMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members approved an agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Comprehensive Mental Health</ENAMEX>. According to the agreement, it is to establish a "school-based collaborative behavior disorder counseling service delivery program" between the two groups.   The agreement is effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from September 2004 to June 2005</TIMEX>, and calls for the school district to pay the equivalent of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> or 20 hours of a case manager's salary, benefits and overhead not to exceed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22,000</NUMEX> during the agreed term.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

