


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrada</ENAMEX> recognized as Youth of the Month
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Estrada</ENAMEX> as the recipient of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> Mayor's Youth of the Month award.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrada</ENAMEX> is a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Compass High School</ENAMEX>. He was nominated for the award by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Felman</ENAMEX>, a counselor at the school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felman</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estrada</ENAMEX> maintains a positive attitude and is honest, noting that he found a money order written for a large sum of money in the Westside Market parking lot and turned the money order into the staff at the school.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves property tax levy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members approved the property tax levy for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, identifying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 million</NUMEX> of expected revenue for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Treasurer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Myers</ENAMEX> explained that every year the city has to levy property taxes so the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> treasurer can assess them. He noted that the property taxes levied by the city in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> will see a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> levied <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$987,029</NUMEX> in property taxes. The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> increase will mean an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9,870</NUMEX> of revenue for the city. The remaining $104,000, which makes up the difference between the amount levied in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> and the amount to be levied in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, comes from new construction in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G'view Council</ENAMEX> approves specifications for well project
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> voted to approve specifications for the bid process involved with the creation of new well #4.
</P>  


<P ID="12">The project includes the decommissioning of the original well, as well as the drilling, casing and testing of the new well. It also includes the construction of a new pump house for well #4.
</P>

 


<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> pushes forward with charitable solicitations ordinance
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> gave its nod to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Maxwell</ENAMEX> on the subject of charitable solicitations.
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that several months ago members of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s banking community brought a concern to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> regarding charitable solicitors standing outside of their facilities. He noted that they were standing on public right-of-way, blocking the sidewalk as they asked for donations.
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the city took a look at a solicitations ordinance in place in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and were working to adapt it to fit the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17">The ordinance would require charitable groups to register with the city in order to be able to solicit donations on public right-of-ways.
</P>

<P ID="18">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> noted that when the groups register the ordinance should be written so the charitable organizations have to provide proof of their 501(c)3 status.
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> suggested that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> take another look at the proposed ordinance after the first of the year.
</P>

 


<P ID="20"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves amendment to correct sewer rates
</P>

<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted to approve an amendment to the resolution originally passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2004</TIMEX>, which set sewer rates for residential and public users within the city during the irrigation season.
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Clerk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Posse</ENAMEX> noted that after the resolution was originally approved she inadvertently inputted the wrong rate schedule into the computer. The amendment corrects the rate change.
</P>

 


<P ID="23"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G'view</ENAMEX> city officials discuss fate of motorized scooters
</P>

<P ID="24"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members that he has been discussing the proposed motorized scooter ordinance with his staff, noting that he knows the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wants <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to be a scooter friendly community.
</P>

<P ID="25">However, he explained that looking at what other communities are doing, including total scooter bans and banning the vehicles in the downtown corridor, he doesn't know if being scooter friendly is something that is going to be possible.
</P>

<P ID="26"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> hold off on implementing a motorized scooter ordinance, until it sees what the results are of the newly adopted ordinances in other surrounding communities.
</P>

<P ID="27">"Let's see what the impact is," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

<P ID="28"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed to put off making any decision on motorized scooters until more information is known.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="29">Webmaster
</P><P ID="30">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




