
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s wife stumps for votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">On the campaign trail for her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Beth Nethercutt</ENAMEX> stopped in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> to speak to a group of women about farming, finance and women's issues.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s husband, Congressmen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, is seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>'s position in the U.S. Senate.   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, said her husband is standing on his voting record that has been positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state, which includes supporting farmers and supporting the dams when the push was to remove them.   "He's also in favor of an energy policy," said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>. "Our current senator has voted against a common sense energy policy."   She said that her husband has been able to reach across party lines and work with both Republicans and Democrats alike to accomplish things that are good for the country.   "You can't get everything you want, but if you can get 75 or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX>, then that's good," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.   She said her husband's opponent has repeatedly voted to filibuster, which keeps debate on a topic from ending so that even a preliminary vote can't get to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> floor. The judges nominated by President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is one of the issues that hasn't been voted on.   "Approve or disapprove, but at least vote on it," she said.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> has a great voting record. He's got a great record on the issues," she said.   Unfortunately, she added, a lot of bills come out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and are "...buried in the graveyard of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>."   Besides stem cell research, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said her husband is in favor of drilling in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arctic</ENAMEX>. She said that when super-imposed over the continental <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> covers about 1/3rd of the country. She explained that when they talk about drilling they are only talking about touching 2,000 acres of 19 million acres of pristine wilderness.   "Until we have energy independence we are going to be held hostage at the fuel pumps," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX> native added that her husband supported the dams in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state when there was a push to remove them.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> has also been instrumental in working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> administration</ENAMEX> to develop a research facility at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> that would be able to test for Mad Cow Disease, she said.   "The next closest facility is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>," said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.   She added that her husband is also in favor of capping the amount that can be paid out for pain and suffering in lawsuits against doctors in the state. She said that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is losing talented physicians and it is not only the rural communities that are feeling the brunt of the shortage. At a rally in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, she said a woman who is due to have a baby in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> spoke about her needs of a obstetrician. She shared that this is her third child and third obstetrician, the others have left the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said that she is hoping her doctor will still be practicing when her baby is due.   "Doctors are worried about being sued," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>. "They will run more tests than their heart or mind tells them they should, and that drives up costs."   One of the most frustrating aspects of the election is the incumbent senator's reluctance to debate the issues. She said her husband invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> to debate in each of the counties in the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> agreed to two debates, said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.   Both were also invited to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Downtown Seattle Rotary Club</ENAMEX> for a debate, but only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> attended, because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> said her schedule was too busy, said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.   She added that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> went up against Speaker of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Folley</ENAMEX>, there were nine debates. Minority Leader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Daschle</ENAMEX> participated in seven debates.   "There must be a reason she doesn't want to talk about her voting record," said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.      .
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

