


<P ID="1">Interlocal agreement yet to be formalized
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> suggested that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> sit down and talk about the interlocal agreement the two sides have with one another.
</P><P ID="5">   The dialogue took place during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s joint meeting between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Bones told members of both sides that the district has not signed the interlocal agreement, which is renewed annually, but will continue to honor in good faith until the matter is resolved.
</P><P ID="7">   The interlocal agreement between the city and the school district states that both sides can use one another's facilities.
</P><P ID="8">   Bones said that he wanted to discuss including the district being able to use the community center and the city pool in the interlocal agreement, both of which are not included in the current contract.
</P><P ID="9">   School board member Arthur Wells expressed his concern over an issue that arose a couple of years ago where the district paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX> to the city to use the pool for the girls swim team. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> said he felt that was an unfair amount the district had to pay, considering the city has open access to all district facilities.
</P><P ID="10">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> couldn't agree more with the suggestions of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> wanted to even include the district being able to utilize <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   "I think we should have everything in there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   The two sides are scheduled to sit down and iron out the details of the interlocal agreement.
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




