


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">PAID OBITUARY
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ESTHER F. VICE</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther F. Vice</ENAMEX>, 94, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX> passed away peacefully <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Dec. 30, 2003</TIMEX>, at Warm Beach Community, where she resided for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1909</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garrett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ind.</ENAMEX> to Coney and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maude Clark</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX> was next to the oldest of seven children. She attended school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garrett</ENAMEX> and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Terre Haute Normal School</ENAMEX> with her teaching credential. She taught for several years in a one-room country school north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garrett</ENAMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Thomas Vice</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Martin County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ind.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>. They were itinerant ministers, traveling across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> to hold revival meetings in small communities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX> played the piano and the ukulele and led song services. They settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>. Her husband died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX> was a devoted wife and mother, teaching her three children how to live and be strong in difficult times. 
</P>

<P ID="9">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> she attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, updating her teaching certificate. She taught in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, when she moved to Edmonds to teach and be near her family. Upon her retirement from teaching, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX> kept active. She hiked, took German classes, learned to swim and became a proficient ballroom dancer with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Astaire Studio</ENAMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="10">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX> moved to the Warm Beach Senior Community in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX>, where she made many friends. The staff and volunteers at Warm <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beach</ENAMEX> made her last years happy ones. She appreciated the loving, competent care they gave to her daily. 
</P>

<P ID="11">She was a long-time member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Church</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lynnwood Assembly of God</ENAMEX>, and was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sno-King Retired Teachers Association</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX> is survived by her two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilma Jones</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia</ENAMEX> (Cyd) and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chi-Dooh</ENAMEX> (Skip) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Li</ENAMEX>; eight grandchildren, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacDonald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Vice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy and Antony Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Huotari</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph and Kara Li</ENAMEX>; 12 great-grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua</ENAMEX>, Tawnie and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allie Sailsbery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon MacDonald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tavia Vice</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte and Christopher Jones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler Huotari</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ella and Cleo Li</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floride Jean Sonnenberg</ENAMEX>; and numerous nieces and nephews in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">She was preceded in death by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Thomas Vice</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>; and five siblings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="14">A memorial service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 31, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beachwood Chapel</ENAMEX> at Warm Beach Senior Community in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor Esther’s memory may contribute to the Warm Beach Senior Community, 20420 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Marine Drive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX>. 98292, or to a charity of the donor’s choice. Arrangements are under the direction of Gilbertson Funeral Home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JUAN HERRERA IBARRA</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Herrera Ibarra</ENAMEX>, 73, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> went to be with his Lord and Savior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Dec. 27, 2003</TIMEX>, at his home with his loved ones.
</P>

<P ID="17">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26, 1930</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tornillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Herrera</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Ibarra</ENAMEX>. He spent his childhood in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> helping his family pick cotton. At the age of 18, he migrated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> and worked as a farm worker and then a sheepherder for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Martinez</ENAMEX> farms. He met and then married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria San Juana Ibarra</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sabinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coahuila</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 25, 1964</TIMEX>. Later they were sealed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Provo Temple</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5, 1979</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX>. They lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> for a few months after they were married and then moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He worked for Hull Farms in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as a farm laborer for 13 years. He worked at Independent Foods Incorporated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for 5 years, and then worked as a custodian at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of Jesus Christ of Latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saints</ENAMEX> until he retired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="18">He enjoyed working as a custodian and helping many people in the church. He loved camping with his family. He was baptized as a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> at the age of 17 while living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. He was an active member in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LDS Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He held many different callings of service in the church. He was always willing to help his fellow men in any way he could.
</P>

<P ID="19">He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juana Ibarra</ENAMEX>; seven children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilia Ibarra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra and Noe Rubulcava</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar and Wendy Ibarra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">J. Nicolas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlene Ibarra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven and Samira Ibarra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maleesa Ibarra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ind.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Ibarra</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; 14 grandchildren; and three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmen Castillo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enriqueta Cruz</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Paso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, and Manuela Lopez of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Caseta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="20">He was preceded in death by his parents; his sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe Robles</ENAMEX>; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Ibarra</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Ibarra</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="21">Visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 2, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 3, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m.</TIMEX> until time of service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of Jesus Christ of Latter-day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saints</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lincoln Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at Valley Memorial Gardens. In lieu of flowers donations may be made to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juana Ibarra</ENAMEX> at any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banner Bank</ENAMEX>. 
</P>

 


<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MAXINE MURPHY</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="23"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine “Max” Murphy</ENAMEX>, 67, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> was called by her Lord and Savior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Dec. 28, 2003</TIMEX>. She passed peacefully in her home with her family.
</P>

<P ID="24"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 28, 1936</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Polson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> She grew up on the family farm near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Polson</ENAMEX> with her brother and six sisters. She attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pablo Elementary School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> and graduated from high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ronan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> It was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ronan</ENAMEX> that she met and married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald J. Murphy</ENAMEX>, her husband of 49 years. Together they raised five children as they traveled and worked throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>. They had made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayden</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last four years</TIMEX>. Though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine</ENAMEX> worked at many things in her life, she most enjoyed working with developmentally disabled children and adults both in the public schools and with T.E.S.H. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Idaho</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="25"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine</ENAMEX> had a kind spirit and was always willing to help those in need. Her primary devotion was to love and care for her family. She loved to spend time with her 10 grandchildren and one great-grandchild. She was a gentle person, quick with a laugh and a hug. 
</P>

<P ID="26">She delighted in attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Bible Church</ENAMEX> with the fellowship the church provided. She enjoyed gardening, sewing and traveling to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> to visit her mother and sisters. She will be forever remembered as a loving wife, mother, grandmother, daughter and sister. She leaves behind a loving family who will miss her always.
</P>

<P ID="27">She is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Murphy</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon</ENAMEX>; three daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie</ENAMEX>; her mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adella Butt</ENAMEX>; one brother; six sisters; 10 grandchildren and one great-grandchild.
</P>

<P ID="28">A memorial service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 3, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at Yates Funeral Home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayden Chapel</ENAMEX>. A reception will follow at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yates Hayden Chapel’s Gathering Center</ENAMEX>. Memorial donations may be made to Hospice of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Idaho</ENAMEX>, 9493 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">North Government Way</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayden</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, 83835. Please visit Maxine’s memorial and sign the online guest book at 
www.yatesfuneralhomes.com
.
</P>

 
  






 










<P ID="29">Webmaster
</P><P ID="30">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




