
<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/21/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">DON <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. BRUNELL   Too</ENAMEX> bad <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ditka</ENAMEX> withdrew his name from the U.S. Senate race in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Illinois</ENAMEX>, because that bunch on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Capitol Hill</ENAMEX> needs a tough guy to shape them up.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX>, known for his bluntness and hair-trigger temper, is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chicago Bears</ENAMEX> all-pro tight end and football coach - a no-nonsense guy who at times went nose-to-nose with his players if he thought they weren't giving their best.   Republicans courted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX> to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Ryan</ENAMEX>, who dropped out of the race after a court unsealed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX>'s divorce file, in which his wife had accused him of forcing her to go to sex clubs. After thinking about the race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX> declined, saying the offer came five or six years too late.   That is unfortunate, because if any group needs a good swift kick, it is the U.S. Senate.   For example, their favorite tactic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> is to threaten a filibuster to kill a bill before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> even have a chance to vote on it. The only way to head off a filibuster is a process called "cloture." Unique to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, cloture requires the votes of 60 of the 100 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> to end the debate and force a vote - a difficult task in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s evenly split <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Consequently, the minority party can kill bills supported by the majority party simply by never letting them come up for a vote.   Another favorite maneuver is for opponents to load up a piece of legislation with so many non-related amendments that supporters can no longer vote for their own bill.   A recent example, the debacle over Senate Bill 2062-legislation restoring fairness to class action lawsuits. Opponents were threatening to filibuster the bill, so supporters tried to get a cloture vote. But in exchange for supporting cloture, opponents tried to turn the bill into a "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> tree" by hanging a ton of unrelated amendments on it.   For example, Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Kennedy</ENAMEX> (D-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MA</ENAMEX>) wanted to attach an unrelated amendment raising the minimum wage, while Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McCain</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">AZ</ENAMEX>) wanted an unrelated amendment on global warming.   When it came time to consider the bill, Republican leaders said "no" to all the amendments and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Cantwell</ENAMEX> (D) - who had publicly said she supported class action fairness - voted against cloture and the bill died. So effectively, they voted against class action fairness without being required to vote on the bill itself.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantwell</ENAMEX> wasn't the only senator to go south on the cloture vote, 43 others did as well. The anti-cloture vote was cast mostly by Democrats, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McCain</ENAMEX> and Idaho Republican Larry Craig joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantwell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>, a staunch opponent of class action reform, asbestos fairness and medical malpractice legal reform.   Thirteen others helped kill the bill by skipping the cloture vote entirely, including Democrats John Kerry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Clinton</ENAMEX>, and Republicans Ben Nighthorse Campbell of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pennsylvania</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Santorum</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Ditka</ENAMEX> would have been enraged by all the political jockeying. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX>'s world, players are paid to play, and they'd better be on crutches if they want to sit on the sidelines. Likewise, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> are paid to vote on legislation, not engage in parliamentary maneuvers to avoid an official vote.   One could imagine that, had <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX> been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, politicians would have been flying around the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> chambers in something resembling a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> free-for-all at the local pub. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX>'s style doesn't lend itself to the culture and character of the esteemed U.S. Senate, but it would be worth the price of admission to watch him shake up that crowd.   Bring on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ditka</ENAMEX>!   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don C. Brunell</ENAMEX> is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

