
<P ID="1">Suitcase project benefits foster kids
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/4/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - An art project in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Desmarais</ENAMEX>' resource room at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> is making some <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> foster kids very happy.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmarais</ENAMEX>' class, seeking to do a community project, happened on the suitcase project, thanks to a suggestion from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy LeyenSacher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeyenSacher</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmarais</ENAMEX> of the need for suitcases for youngsters who are often forced to throw their clothing and other belongings into grocery bags for their moves from home to home.   "The project, known as Love Luggage" by the students, resulted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> students decorating more than 20 suitcases for the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Child Protective Services Foster Child Program</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorene Perez</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> office of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPS</ENAMEX>.   "The children now have a suitcase to call their own," she said.   "We thought the students would enjoy helping others while learning how to transform the luggage from unsightly cast-offs into useful items," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmarais</ENAMEX>.   "They enjoyed the creative process, as well as the idea that they were helping others," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmarais</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desmarais</ENAMEX> hopes to continue the luggage project <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   "We are seeking donations of old, hard-sided suitcases which area residents may have tucked away some place," she said.   She asked that donations of suitcases be dropped off at the high school or those interested in helping call her at 894-4951.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

