
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> sworn in as new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> superintendent
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - A new superintendent begins work in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> was sworn-in during a special meeting held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m. Thursday morning</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> was hired to replace former superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX>, who resigned to take the head position at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> was offered the position as the head administrator of the school district after the school board reviewed the final two candidates in executive session for more than an hour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 6</TIMEX>.   The school board decided to offer the position to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>, who is employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> #105 as the director of the migrant education regional office.   With the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> has worked directly with administrators, principals and teachers at 32 school districts in the state. She said her department makes sure school district employees at all levels comply with federal and state legislation for program implementation. She said her job with the service district was to ensure effective results for children.   As the director of the program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said she has worked with budgets, audits and other details that have to do with administration.   "One of the most important things we do (at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX>) is we make sure children are celebrated and recognized," she added.   As the new superintendent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said her primary goal is to continue the work that is ongoing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>.   She said in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 15 years</TIMEX> of working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> she has noticed a steady progress in student performance.   "People look for big jumps," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>. "The true measure is steady progress."   She hopes to continue to see steady growth in the future.   Finishing the hiring process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>) is a big day for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> marked the end of a lengthy hiring process that started with 26 candidates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said the lot was narrowed to nine, then to four and finally two candidates.   The two finalists for the position were very close, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX>.   They underwent a day-long visit to the district, as well as questioning by the school board and by parents in a community forum.   The school board members went to the field to see which finalist would most meet the district's needs and continue the school district on the path they have already begun, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX>.   "It was a very hard decision to make," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> signed the contract with the school district <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said there are two contract inclusions the school board is considering.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said that the school board will be looking into adding an indemnity clause to the contract, which he said would protect the superintendent in case someone wanted to personally sue her for something the school is responsible for.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX>, the school district fully indemnifies all of its employees, but they will be looking into formally adding it to the contract. The school board has until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2005</TIMEX> to make a decision on adding it to the contract.   The second inclusion the school board is considering, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX>, is an "...allowance of funds to help realize the goals of getting the superintendent in the district."   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> finance director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Plesha</ENAMEX> explained that the board will be looking at providing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, with moving expenses.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> was given the authority at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting to negotiate the terms of the contract and adding a moving expense was one of the items that came up in the discussion.   "She wants to get into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> as soon as possible," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> added.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> school board will be investigating the two items, and, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX>, will make a decision at a later time.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

