
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Symphonyto celebrate60th anniversary
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - The opening concert, celebrating the 60th anniversary season of the Mid-Columbia Symphony, will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX> program will feature national award winning violinist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paige Kossuth</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX>. She will perform the Sibelius "Violin Concerto." Included in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s program will be the von Suppe "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Poet & Peasant Overture</ENAMEX>" and the Tchaikovsky "Symphony No. 2."
The music director and conductor for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> concert will be Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bode</ENAMEX>.
Three additional concerts to commemorate the 2004-05 anniversary season are scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 5</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 7</TIMEX>.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> area symphony orchestra got its start when 15 volunteer musicians, made up of housewives, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> scientists, students and business people, accompanied a performance of the "Messiah" in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1945</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, the Mid-Columbia orchestra consists of 60 professional musicians.
Tickets to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s concert can be obtained by calling (509) 943-6602.
</P> 
<P ID="4">‘Diggin' Dixie’ event slatedfor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5-7</TIMEX>
OCEAN SHORES - Eight Dixieland jazz bands will be appearing at four venues the first full weekend in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean Shores</ENAMEX>.
The occasion for the Dixieland gathering is the 22nd annual Ocean Shores Dixieland Jazz Festival.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 5-7</TIMEX> festival will be headquartered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Shores Convention Center</ENAMEX>. Tickets to the event for all three days at all four venues are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55</NUMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Single day</TIMEX> tickets are also available by calling (360) 289-4094.
The festival sites will include the convention center, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Quinault Beach Resort & Casino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Shores Elk Lodge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ocean Shores Lions Club</ENAMEX>.
The eight Dixieland bands that will perform include The New Reformation Band with the Oppermann brothers from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saginaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>, the Uptown Lowdown Jazz Band of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX>, The Black Swan Jazz Band of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, the Prohibition Jazz Band of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silverdale</ENAMEX>, the CanUS Jazz Band of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Victoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Park Jazz Band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aberdeen</ENAMEX> and the Monarch's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jazz Band</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">‘Tales of the Trails’ billed as fun for kids
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - "Tales of the Trails" is the theme of the 10th annual Rotary Storyfest, slated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16-19</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX>.
For the fifth consecutive year, performers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Stewart</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MaryLee Sunseri</ENAMEX> will bring the songs and stories of the Old West to life during "Tales of the Trails" at the local museum. The two women's repertoire for the program will include traditional songs, as well as many written specifically for this venue.
The event is billed as a program of storytelling and music designed for young people, which helps fulfill the museum's education mission.
Thanks to the sponsorship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Sunrise Rotary Club</ENAMEX>, all performances are free to the public. Seating, however, is limited and fills up quickly.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> teachers can reserve a spot for their classes by calling (509) 248-0747.
Children and their families are being invited to a special public performance <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 19</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Reservations are not needed for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> performance.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

