
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Preliminary plat approved for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>'s Wine Country Estates
GRANGER - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County commissioner approved a preliminary plat, which will add four lots to Wine Country Estates, a small subdivision located just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>.
The four-lot long plat will double the size of the subdivision, which was started with a four-lot short plat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>. The preliminary plat divides a 20.5 acre plot of land into four lots.
Although the preliminary plat was approved, it was approved with conditions that must be met before a final plat will be approved. The conditions state that there must be individual wells to serve each lot, that the existing approach onto Yakima Valley Highway must be upgraded to commercial road approach standards and a storm water management plan will have to be submitted to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>. Other conditions include such things as road width and the size of easements.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

