
<P ID="1">Sky high birthday wishes extended to 21-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> woman
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When planning her daughter's 21st birthday celebration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Kay Yarber</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> knew she needed to do something special.   Her daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Yarber</ENAMEX>, has spent the majority of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> recovering from an accident involving a horse that rolled on top of her, breaking her pelvis and hip and crushing her foot, she said.   "She spent 12 days in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harborview</ENAMEX> and was on crutches for six months," said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarber</ENAMEX>. "I thought, I've got to do something special for her."   The idea for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea</ENAMEX>'s birthday gift <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> came to Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarber</ENAMEX> in a dream.   For her youngest's 21st birthday, she hired an airplane pilot to pull a sign, reading "Happy 21st <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Yarber</ENAMEX>," through the skies over their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> home.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarber</ENAMEX> family was able to keep the birthday wishes from the sky a secret from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea</ENAMEX> until it was time to reveal the present <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> student was in her parents' home with her sister when the sister suggested they go outside because she was warm, said the birthday girl.   "I thought, OK," she said. Going outside she saw the sign circling above the house.   "I was shocked," said the 21-year-old. "I usually find out secrets kept from me before they happen, but this one they kept pretty well."   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarber</ENAMEX> was concerned that the pilot would not be able to make the flight because a storm was predicted to hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.   "I've been worrying and stewing all day," she said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.   "This is neat," said the birthday girl, who is the youngest of five children. "It's the nicest thing anyone has ever done for me."   Unfortunately, most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarber</ENAMEX>'s friends were working at the time and didn't get to see the birthday sign circling high above.   "I'll call them and let them know," she laughed.   Other plans <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea</ENAMEX> has for her birthday include a trip with her sister.   "I hope it's somewhere near water, but she tells me we're going to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarber</ENAMEX> added.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yarber</ENAMEX>'s always try to do something special for their five children on their birthdays. One year she and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>, sent one of their children on a trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and another to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

