
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/3/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Surplus property approved for sale
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members approved a list of items to be surplused. The list includes items from both the Public Works and the Grandview Police departments. Among those items approved for sale at auction are six used vehicle batteries, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chevy</ENAMEX> panel van, three truck tool boxes, a wide array of car stereos, two patrol cars and an animal control vehicle.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX> said the two patrol cars being surplused have already been replaced and the new animal control vehicle should arrive in the next couple of weeks.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> said the vehicles were scheduled for replacement <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">New stop signto be erected
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - A new stop sign will be erected at the intersection of Concord Avenue with East and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Concord Avenues</ENAMEX> following a decision made by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX> told council members he has received quite a few complaints from that neighborhood of cars speeding through the area. He said it was neighborhood residents who suggested a stop sign be placed at the intersection to help slow down traffic.
The intersection is currently unsigned.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> joins county efforts to update Growth Management Act requirements
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to join efforts with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> to update the city's Critical Area Ordinance and Shoreline Master Program, both of which are Growth Management Act requirements.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Clerk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Palacios</ENAMEX> explained that the county has received state grant funding and is offering to take a regional approach to the two requirements.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves comprehensive plan amendment and rezone
GRANDVIEW - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members approved a request made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Alexander</ENAMEX> to amend the city's Comprehensive Plan to change the future land use designation of approximately 13 acres located off of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> near the east entrance into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
The 13 acres is located in two parcels, both of which are currently zoned agriculture with a future land use designation of residential. The rezone request was to change the future land use designation of the north parcel to commercial and the other parcel to single family residential.
After approval by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> the request will be forwarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Growth Management Division</ENAMEX> for a 60-day review.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poteet</ENAMEX> honored for years of serviceto community
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members recognized police <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">dispatcher Sue Poteet</ENAMEX>, who recently retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poteet</ENAMEX> has worked full-time at the department since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1980</TIMEX> and just recently retired.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poteet</ENAMEX> told Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> that upon retiring she plans on traveling and visiting relatives.
</P>

 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

