
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> looking at ways to spruce up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> events
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> is in the middle of what some people might call a regrouping period. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourism</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Promotions</ENAMEX> Director for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX> explained to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary Club</ENAMEX> members that the chamber is currently working to redefine its goals, looking specifically at what the group hopes to accomplish in the next five to 10 years.   One example of the chamber's efforts was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s Sunshine Days festival. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said the chamber decided to try something different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, whittling the usual three-day event into a one-day affair, because Sunshine Days had been changing and morphing over the years into something that was almost unrecognizable.   "We want to get our hands around it and fix it or create something completely different," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> noted that one of the most exciting events she was able to be a part of over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> was Spring Fling Fest. She explained that the festival is a collaborative effort involving chambers from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, that is meant to capitalize on spring barrel tasting. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said over the past few years wineries have begun making spring barrel tasting a two weekend event, with special invitations being sent out to people to come to the wineries the weekend before barrel tasting for more one-on-one attention.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> explained that the local chambers have come together to try and fill the week between the two weekends with events that make people want to stay in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> for a few extra days.   "That is going to be a great thing," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said of the Spring Fling Fest.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said the next event <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has to look forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is the Lighted Farm Implement Parade. She told Rotarians that although this is already a great event, the chamber is looking at ways it can be improved. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> noted that the chamber is hoping to get more downtown businesses involved in lighting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and that the parade will return to ending at the Mid-Valley Mall parking lot as opposed to the parking lot at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, where the parade finished <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. Another change will move the award ceremony for the parade before the event, meaning that award winners can be announced while the entries head down the parade route.   Following the parade, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said the next big chamber event is the community awards banquet.   "This is a fantastic time for the community to come together," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said. She noted that there are now 10 award categories, including new business.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> then encouraged Rotary members to attend the annual Cinco de Mayo festival, which takes place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>. She said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the event brought in nearly 25,000 people over the course of the weekend.   The final chamber event <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> talked about was the three-on-three basketball tournament, which is held during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fourth weekend of July</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corliss</ENAMEX> said the chamber is hoping to move the event from the Mid-Valley Mall parking lot to the downtown area. She said the chamber hopes the move will mean vendors can be brought in for the event and that it will encourage more local businesses to get involved.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

