


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> sworn in as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> judge
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/27/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - For the second time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Engel</ENAMEX> has followed in the footsteps of now <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> Judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Reukauf</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, he replaced her as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court Commissioner</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> and now, he is taking her place on the bench as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> judge as she fills the vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> judge position.
</P><P ID="6">   "I want to assure her if she seeks higher office, I will be the first to sign up for her job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> joked at the investiture ceremony held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Courthouse <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The ceremony held amongst his family, friends and peers was the formal robing ceremony and swearing into office.
</P><P ID="8">   Judges sitting on the bench in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Municipal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> and Superior courtrooms around the county were on hand to witness as Judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Fitch</ENAMEX> conducted the ceremony and swearing in.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Kimbrough</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> has shared a Grandview office with for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>, introduced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> and spoke on his behalf.
</P><P ID="10">   He said that after spending a couple of years as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">court commissioner</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> and a judge pro-tem for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> before returning to private practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> learned his calling was really to the judge's bench.
</P><P ID="11">   Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> as a teen. After graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland High School</ENAMEX>, he attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>, where he earned a Bachelor of Arts degree in political science. He earned his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juris</ENAMEX> Doctor degree from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon School of Law</ENAMEX> before joining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Garrison</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> law office in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> he gave up his private practice to take on the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">court commissioner</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>, a position that was cut <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> due to budget and case load issues, according to Judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitch</ENAMEX>. He also spent a year as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">court commissioner</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> before returning to private practice about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fitch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimbrough</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> was a good choice for the district court position because he has a "...profound respect for land and compassion. I can't imagine a better person to serve in this position.
</P><P ID="14">   "We're going to miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> in my office. He was a very able lawyer," he said.
</P><P ID="15">   "Mostly we're going to miss him when we need to get things off high shelves. He's the only one in the office over six feet tall," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimbrough</ENAMEX> joked.
</P><P ID="16">   In the ceremony, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> was also referred to as a person who is fair and impartial and a person of common sense and integrity, by former employers and employees.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roasting Engel</ENAMEX> a little, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX>'s former employer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Garrison</ENAMEX>, said that in all the years they have known each other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> never made the same mistake twice.
</P><P ID="18">   "He made a lot of them, but he never repeated them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> credited his success as an attorney to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrison</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   "Much of what I am as an attorney and what I want to be as a judge is because of his tutelage," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX> was appointed to the position by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. He was named to the bench partially due to a poll of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Bar Association</ENAMEX>. His fellow attorneys overwhelming supported <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Engel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   His position on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> bench will be up for election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




