
<P ID="1">Steer clear of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> heat dangers
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/27/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">With <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> temperatures soaring into the 90s and even higher during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past week</TIMEX>, the temperatures inside a car can exceed 125 degrees in as little as 20 minutes.   The car's interior temperatures are already hotter than outside temperatures, and climb rapidly, causing grave danger for both children and pets. Parents and caregivers are reminded that children and infants' bodies warm three to five times faster than adults and are at extreme risk of heat stroke in such conditions.   Already <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, there have been at least 14 infants and children across the nation who have died after being left in hot cars, trucks, vans and SUVs, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Council</ENAMEX> for the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect.   Some of those deaths occurred on days with relatively mild temperatures, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> officials.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, there was a record 42 such preventable tragedies.   "We want people to remember one thing - never leave a child unattended in a car," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Sharp</ENAMEX>, executive director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.   "It is especially important that parents and caregivers and pet owners understand that the risks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> heat can bring," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharp</ENAMEX> said.   With heat stroke, a child's skin becomes red and dry. The child is unable to produce sweat needed to reduce his core body temperature. The heart rates quicken and the child becomes confused and may lose consciousness before his organ systems begin to fail.   Cracking the windows enough to let in air is not an effective way to avoid the heat risks involved with leaving a child alone in a car on a hot day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharp</ENAMEX> said.   She recommends seeking immediate emergency medical attention if you think that your child has been exposed to high temperatures by having been left in or accidentally trapped in a car. If a child gets locked inside the car, dial 9-1-1 immediately.   "If you observe a child left unattended in a car, it is appropriate to dial 9-1-1 or contact your local law enforcement agency. It's always better to be safe than sorry," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharp</ENAMEX>.   Don't forget to protect your pets too, advise animal experts. Just as children should never be left unattended in a car, the family pet should never be left in vehicles during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> heat, even with the window cracked. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Humane Society</ENAMEX> said dogs just can't cool off as fast as the temperatures are rising inside the vehicle.   Animals can suffer heat exhaustion and heat stoke rapidly in enclosed cars, even in a short periods of time.   When outside in the hot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> heat, to protect yourselves from the risks, health experts remind people to wear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sun</TIMEX> screen with a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sun</TIMEX> protection factor (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPF</ENAMEX>) of 15 or higher. Apply the sunscreen at least 15 minutes before going outdoors and reapply after swimming.   Don't forget to apply a lip balm with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPF</ENAMEX> to protect lips and wear sunglasses with ultraviolet protection to provide a defense from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sun</TIMEX> for your eyes, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Bruya</ENAMEX>, assistant dean for academic health services at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Intercollegiate College of Nursing</ENAMEX>.   Wear wide-brimmed hats to cover the neck area. This is important because the neck is the area of the body directly connected to the brain's temperature regulation system, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruya</ENAMEX> added.   She said wearing sunscreen and a hat will reduce UV radiation to the factor of almost zero.   "You can also reduce the risk of heat stroke by spending more time indoors during the hottest parts of the day (<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>) and on humid days," she advises.   Remember to avoid dehydration by drinking lots of water, she added.   "Drink at least eight glasses of water a day, more if really hot, " she added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

