


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> cows testing negative for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> has euthanized 119 of the 129 cows from the Mabton and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> dairies where the first cases of a cow with bovine spongiform encephalopathy were found. Of the 119 animals, 28 of the tests for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, or mad cow disease, have been completed and all of the tests have come back negative.
</P><P ID="4">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, an additional cattle facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> was quarantined after it was found that five of the 80 cows imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow were located at the facility.
</P><P ID="5">   A state hold order is also on a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quincy</ENAMEX> dairy. An additional three of 17 heifers dispersed from the Canadian farm where the Mabton and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> cows originated were found at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quincy</ENAMEX> dairy, according to officials. The 17 cows were not part of the 81 cows that were imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2001</TIMEX> along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cows.
</P><P ID="6">   Also put under a state hold order is a Mattawa dairy finishing facility, where three cows imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> are located. The three cows at the Mattawa facility will be killed in the near future, according to USDA officials.
</P>   
   






 










<P ID="7">Webmaster
</P><P ID="8">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




