
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> administrator 'Principal of the Year'
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School Principal Julie Schmick</ENAMEX> can be hard to find. Her office space is no longer in a spacious, windowed room in the bustling school's main office. Rather, her office is a small room off a main hallway with a sign on the door reading, "Welcome to the Closet."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX> is taking a different direction in the instructional leadership of the school and for her, the move is one way that helps her show where she is going.   She spends little time in the office, and instead is in the classrooms providing leadership for teachers as the school continuously strives to better educate its students.   "We're improving instructional practices in the classroom and we're all becoming stronger learners and leaders," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX>'s efforts at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> have earned her the recognition as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Central Washington Regional Principal</ENAMEX> of the Year for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105.   "It's really a team effort," she said. "I feel like I'm representing the hard work that's happening here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX> said she feels she is also representing all of the principals from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cle Elum</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "We have a dynamic group of principals from this region," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX> added.   A former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> teacher, who taught third, fourth and sixth grades, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX> made the switch to administration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven and a half years ago</TIMEX>. She mentored under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School Principal Stan Davis</ENAMEX> before being hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six years ago</TIMEX>.   Taking an active leadership role at her school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX> is working with kindergarten and first graders in a program called the "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breakfast Club</ENAMEX>" before school. And fourth through sixth graders are able to develop academics and self-concept while playing games during the "Lunch Bunch".   "It gets me back with the kids, which is what I love," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX>.   The principal of the year award will put her in the running for state principal of the year, which will be determined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

