
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">PAID <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OBITUARY
LEORA L. FORD
Leora L. Ford</ENAMEX>, 88, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 16, 2004</TIMEX>, at Prosser Memorial Nursing Home.
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 28, 1915</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elgin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neb.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sadie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bowen</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>. She received her early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1936</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Ford</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> Following their marriage they made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salem</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> the Fords moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, where they farmed. Following the death of her husband in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leora</ENAMEX> continued to make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> her home until the time of her death. 
She is survived by one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerald Ford</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Forrest Grove</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Leighty</ENAMEX> and husband <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; three grandchildren; five great- grandchildren; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ada Ford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Wells</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
She was preceded in death by her parents; her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rozella Ford</ENAMEX>; two brothers; and two sisters.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 19, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 20, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at Grandview Cemetery, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.  
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EVERETT ODEEN FOSTER
Everett Odeen Foster</ENAMEX>, 87, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 18, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 19, 1916</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.M</ENAMEX>. to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tex</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eula</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> (Alls) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Foster</ENAMEX>. He received his early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> and later served in the Merchant Marines during World War II. Following his military service he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Marie Clifton</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20, 1942</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>. Together they made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX> worked in the shipyard. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June of 1943</TIMEX> they moved to Seattle, and made their home there for a short time before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>, where they owned and operated a dairy farm for 30 years. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, later settling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>, where he had made his home until the time of his death. 
He is survived by his wife of 62 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Foster</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Odeen Foster</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; and one granddaughter. 
He was preceded in death by his parents; and two brothers.
Graveside services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July 21, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at Grandview Cemetery, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. 
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DONALD E. PALMER
Donald E. “Doc” Palmer</ENAMEX>, 81, a life-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 15, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 13, 1923</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva J.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred Palmer</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and graduated with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>. Following his education he served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> for three years and was honorably discharged as a sergeant, receiving many expert marksmanship medals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> returned home to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where he began working at the Hanford area, retiring after 40 years in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February of 1994</TIMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity Baptist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, past president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rifleman Association</ENAMEX>, a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I.B.E.W</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">H.A.M.T.A.C</ENAMEX>. local union. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> enjoyed fishing and hunting. 
He is survived by his wife of 54 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Palmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Cohu</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torchey</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Thomas</ENAMEX> of Outlook; two grandsons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Gannon</ENAMEX> of Seattle and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Desmarais</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.  He is also survived by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva J. Palmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> was preceded in death by his father.  
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July 21, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> until time of service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor Don’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trinity Baptist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PAUL KRUGER SAILOR
Paul Kruger Sailor</ENAMEX>, 97, a long-time businessman and resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 17, 2004</TIMEX>, at his home at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> Terrace. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 24, 1907</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Falls</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX> (Johanson) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sailor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clement Sailor</ENAMEX>.  The family moved from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> received his education, graduating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX>. While in high school he worked at a grocery store, a creamery making butter and running the projector at the silent movie theater. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> began working for Shell Oil and retired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> as the Shell oil jobber
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15, 1932</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary E. Christen</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Together they worked running the Shell Oil business for 41 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 29, 1969</TIMEX>. 
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> took his first airplane ride.  It didn’t take <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> long to get his private, instrument and commercial pilot’s license. He loved to fly and enjoyed sharing his love of flying with others. He worked toward getting good airports in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> was very giving of his time and energy to others, a true gentleman. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> was a very kind and loving person who made friends easily and was also well loved by those who knew him. 
He still enjoyed riding his tractor on his small farm when he was 94, keeping his farm neat and tidy on Riverside Avenue. He raised fruit and gave it to everyone. He always had a vegetable garden and beautiful flowers.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12, 1970</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dortha Partain</ENAMEX>, who passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 5, 1992</TIMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> was a 50-year member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Methodist</ENAMEX> church. After his marriage to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dortha</ENAMEX> he became a member of The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Side Baptist Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, where he was a member for 30 years.
Survivors include a daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Johnson</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and two grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Johnson</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fall City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamera Posey</ENAMEX> and  husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis</ENAMEX>, of Seattle; four great-grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah and Tyler Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fall City</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelby and Margot Posey</ENAMEX> of Seattle; and two nephews. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> enjoyed his special get togethers with his grandchildren and the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 10 years</TIMEX> with the great-grandchildren.  
He was preceded in death by his parents; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ada Meyerhoeffer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prudence Hegestrom</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Sailor</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 23, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 23, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of Wells Funeral Home. In lieu of flowers, donations can be made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gospel Mission</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McAllister Museum of Aviation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Home Care Services</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospice</ENAMEX>) or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements. 
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KIRK REED WATTENBARGER
Kirk Reed Wattenbarger</ENAMEX>, 53, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 17, 2004</TIMEX>, at home after a brave battle with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALS</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Gehrig’s</ENAMEX> disease).
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 29, 1950</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie</ENAMEX> (Kinkade) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wattenbarger</ENAMEX>. He received his early education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dorothy School</ENAMEX> and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. He attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18, 1977</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Turconi</ENAMEX>) were married. Together they had two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chad</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> was employed at Washington State Employment Security, both in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
He was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>, where he served on many committees, sang in the choir, and enjoyed singing solos. Music was a large part of Kirk’s life. He was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">“Sound Expressions”</ENAMEX>.
Kirk’s family always came first and he was very involved in the boys’ lives whether he was coaching baseball, soccer, football or being the number one fan from the sidelines in all their activities. He loved all sports, especially hunting, fishing and playing golf (most always with his family). 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri Cities Sports Officials Association</ENAMEX>, where he refereed football and basketball for more than 20 years.
After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> was diagnosed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALS</ENAMEX>, he was determined to fight for a cure by raising hundreds of dollars each year. He was an inspiration to those around him.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Wattenbarger</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chad</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, his brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dena</ENAMEX>; and their families, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alissa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kacie and Kyle Pugh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Watterbarger</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>. Also surviving him are his mother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Turconi</ENAMEX>; his sister-in-law, Kathy Van de Graaf and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>, and their children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his father-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Turconi</ENAMEX>; and his niece, Heather Van de Graaf.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 23, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. A private burial service will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>. A celebration of Kirk’s life will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>. Memorials may be made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ALS Evergreen Chapter</ENAMEX>, 6627 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. 191st Place</ENAMEX>, Suite F, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX>. 98032 or may be left at Wells Funeral Home. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.   
</P> 
 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

