


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to adopt ordinance banning car repairs on streets
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/4/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> currently has no ordinance on its books prohibiting people from performing vehicle repairs on public right-of-ways. That is about to change.
</P><P ID="5">   At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> voted unanimously to move forward with adopting an ordinance prohibiting people from repairing any vehicle on a public street. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is set to adopt the ordinance at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 10</TIMEX>, meeting.
</P><P ID="6">   The issue came to light during an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> asked staff to look into the matter of what the city can do to stop people from repairing their vehicles on the streets.
</P><P ID="7">   The new ordinance basically will prohibit local residents from performing any vehicle repairs, including changing oil, on any street, sidewalk or public right-of-way. The new ordinance does allow for such repairs to take place in case of an emergency.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> had a few concerns about the new ordinance. First, she wanted to know how this ordinance would be enforced in areas that don't have sidewalks. She also shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that numerous people have called her, voicing their concerns that the city is trying to nit-pick at residents, telling them how to live their lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she didn't feel the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was trying to pester residents, but felt the issue before members could be enforced from a safety standpoint.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said people simply need to do any kind of vehicle repairs on their own property or take their cars to a garage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said most cities have an ordinance like the one before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, banning residents from doing vehicle repairs on public streets.
</P><P ID="10">   "This is not just a public safety issue," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. It is a public nuisance issue. I think it is just common sense."
</P>





 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




