16 5 45 22 44 44
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Words calculated to catch everyone may catch no one.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adlai E. Stevenson Jr.</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1900</TIMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>), speech to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Democratic National Convention</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Illinois</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 21, 1952</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>