27 16 23 3 2 33
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Sometimes you feel other people's pain worse than your own. We're armored against our own troubles. We can't afford to give in to despair. Then you see someone else struggling, and it breaks your... heart.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Stewart</ENAMEX>, Perfect Circle, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>