
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> cuts meetings to two a month
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members have agreed to try a new format for their monthly meetings. The lone exception this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX>, who wasn't too keen on what was being suggested.   At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 26</TIMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is expected to formally adopt a new schedule that will have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> gathering only twice per month. The mayor pro-tem was the only one this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against the idea of changing the current format for meetings.   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meets four times per month on every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>. The new schedule will have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting only on the second and fourth Mondays of the month, starting at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will have at its disposal the opportunity to call special meetings, as needed. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is also expected to adopt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> a schedule that will limit meetings to three hours.   The new meeting schedule will take effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 1</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> provided those in attendance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> with some background on the changes. The change in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting format was discussed during a retreat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>.   "The suggestion came from staff," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said staff members felt the change in meetings would allow them to be more productive and efficient if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> met only twice per month. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also explained that by going to the two meetings per month format, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> would have more opportunities to hold workshop sessions to discuss items. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said by allowing for workshop sessions, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> would be able to discuss the preliminaries for items and then be able to make quicker, more productive decisions during the actual meetings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also added it is a goal of his to have staff continue to provide more precise reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that will make their decisions easier.   "I think we need to do it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX>. "I am not sure if we need to do it now."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said in the coming months <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will have a full slate of items before it, where it might be more beneficial to have the four meetings per month schedule format. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> was also the one who suggested the idea of moving the meetings to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> commented that he isn't one to give up every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for meetings. But, the mayor pro-tem added he didn't want <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to look as if it was conducting business out of the public spotlight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">seven years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> used to hold its workshop sessions at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX>, which was done at that time, he said, to make it inconvenient for community members to attend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said he was concerned about the public perception that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> would be making decisions behind closed doors.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> liked the idea of meeting twice per month. She said it would allow city staff to be more productive. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> also said she would like to meet the second and fourth Mondays of each month in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sing</ENAMEX> she wanted to attend a nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, which meets every first and third <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> was also in favor of the proposed change, feeling it would give him more time to 'digest' what is in the agenda.   "I think two meetings are enough," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX>. "Let's go ahead and try it and see what happens."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> was willing to give the new format a try, but disagreed with the suggestion there would be more time to study agenda items. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said items are always being added to the agenda at the last minute and doesn't expect that to change.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> was also in favor of trying the new format. He said he felt it would show citizens <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is trying to be more efficient. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said the city spends quite a bit of taxpayers' dollars to hold meetings every week.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

