
<P ID="1">Elerding advances to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> swim meet
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - Much like a pioneer farmer's wife was easily able to transform cream into butter, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Elerding</ENAMEX> churned through the competition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> swim meet.   Elerding earned <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> meet berths in both events in which he competed at District-the 100-yard butterfly and 100-yard breaststroke. To qualify for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>, swimmers had to finish either first or second in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> races.   Despite attending a class B school, Elerding had to compete in the 2A/3A ranks at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> because the WIAA does not offer postseason swimming competition at the B level.   Elerding made short work of the competition in both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> events he swam.   In the 100-'fly, he bested the next closest finisher by an unheard of near four-second margin. Elerding clocked a time of 53.39 seconds, compared to the runner-up time of 57.37 seconds set by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max McGuire</ENAMEX>.   Elerding blew away the field by an even larger margin in the 100-breast. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian standout bested <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Bernfeld</ENAMEX> by 4.93 seconds, clocking a 1:01.34 compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernfeld</ENAMEX>'s time of 1:06.27. Elerding's 1:01.34 clocking was a slight improvement on his season best time.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian junior will compete at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> meet on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Federal Way</ENAMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

