


<P ID="1">Dead animals dumped on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Port property
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The corpses of more than 50 animals dumped near the gate to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> rendering plant on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midvale Road</ENAMEX> greeted <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port District</ENAMEX> Operations Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Berk</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late yesterday afternoon</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berk</ENAMEX> happened upon the grisly sight of the bloated bodies of 45 calves, three cows and a dead brown pony, while making his routine inspection of Port property. He said the animals appear to have been dumped outside the gates of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Darling International</ENAMEX> sometime earlier in the week.
</P><P ID="6">   The local rendering plant is no long accepting the corpses of abandoned animals, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berk</ENAMEX>, who added <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s discovery is the biggest mess he has seen along the road.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berk</ENAMEX> said since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX> discovery of a case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, the plant has refused to accept any animals without first knowing the animals' origins. Attempts to contact the plant <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> were unsuccessful, but a person in the company's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX> office confirmed that the new policy is in effect as a safety measure.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berk</ENAMEX> said in the past he has found an occasional dead animal dumped outside the gates to the rendering plant. He said until recently the plant workers simply removed the animals, but that is no longer the case.
</P><P ID="9">   "There are even a couple fighting roosters and a dead dog in this pile," he said.
</P><P ID="10">   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> Port officials were attempting to determine how to dispose of the animals.
</P><P ID="11">   "We have been in contact with the USDA and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, but they have no interest in the case at this point," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M'Liss Bierlink</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX> spokesman.
</P><P ID="12">   "At this point we still don't know how we will remove the animals," she said.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX> said her office was contacted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art McKuen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Health Department</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> about the time "...Brad discovered the bodies."
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKuen</ENAMEX> told her he had received a call from the company's general manager, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Anderson</ENAMEX>, regarding the animals.
</P><P ID="15">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKuen</ENAMEX> said he would be getting back to me after talking with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Solid Waste Management Department</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   "We want people to know we plan to take steps to prevent the future dumping of animals along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midvale Road</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="17">   Exactly what those steps might be haven't been firmly established, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX> said. She suggested the steps may include the installation of video cameras, remote control gates and street lights.
</P><P ID="18">   "People usually dump off the animals under the cover of night," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berk</ENAMEX>. "Street light out there should help deter such activity," he added.
</P><P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="20">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




