
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> renews agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> renewed an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise organization at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s meeting.   Several entities are involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise and its efforts in improving the quality of life in the community. Such agencies include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Comprehensive Mental Health</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Horizon</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministerial Association</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> agrees to have administrative staff participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise meetings. Also under the agreement, the district agrees to provide for programs when funding is available. The district also agrees to act as a pass-through agency for any dollars coming into the program from outside agencies. Also per the agreement, the district will coordinate efforts with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise to constantly evaluate the safety and security of district buildings for students. The district also agrees to work on curriculum to assist <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise that will put in place a program teaching marketable skills to students.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

