
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spady</ENAMEX> family epitomizes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s citizen activists
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/24/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">It's always great to see the underdog win one! That's what happened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> when Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> signed a new law allowing 45 charter schools to be established in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.   In this case, the underdogs are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim and Fawn Spady</ENAMEX>, who almost single-handedly held the charter schools movement together for a decade. They poured their own money, countless days and hearts into a movement that would not even benefit their own two children.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spady</ENAMEX> family has a long tradition of philanthropy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>'s father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>, started <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>'s Drive-In, a chain of five hamburger stands in central and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north Seattle</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago</TIMEX>. It has been a very successful family-owned business that pays good wages, provides excellent benefits and gives scholarships for its workers to continue their education. In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>'s Drive-In supports a wide variety of charitable causes in their community and encourages customers to contribute as well through their "Change for Charities" program.   Despite two unsuccessful charter school initiatives and years of legislative roadblocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim and Fawn Spady</ENAMEX>'s tenacity paid off. Now, underserved children whose parents cannot afford to send them to a private school have an alternative. Charter schools have succeeded in 40 other states, and if they succeed here, the real winners will be our children.   If successful in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> (and with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spady</ENAMEX>'s persistence they will be) charter schools should be allowed to expand into every community in the state. After all, charter schools help realize our societal goal of graduating students who can compete head-to-head with their counterparts around the world.   As Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> has so often said, education is the great equalizer, and charter schools are one way to level the playing field for those who are not being served in the public school system.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim and Fawn Spady</ENAMEX> could have easily <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> back, bought a beach home and spent their weekends watching the tides roll in and out. Instead, they dedicated a major portion of their lives to something that will benefit countless children throughout the state. Regardless of your politics, you must agree that it is people like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim and Fawn Spady</ENAMEX> who have made the American dream come true.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>. C. Brunell is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

