


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Council</ENAMEX> OK's annexation
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton City</ENAMEX> boundaries will soon be a little larger and its treasury will be a little fuller following action taken by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voted to accept two annexation requests during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s public hearing.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX>'s vote clears the way for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> officials to forward annexation petitions from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Horticulture</ENAMEX> and the owners of the old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> property to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Boundary Review Board</ENAMEX> for final review, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ildia Jackson</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s night's vote ends nearly three years of waiting to annex the industrial nursery into the city boundaries and to the city's property tax base.
</P><P ID="7">   If approval comes back during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 45 days</TIMEX> from the county boundary review board, the annexation process could be completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, allowing more than 60 acres to become a part of the city's tax rolls in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   The council's approval given during the continuation of a public hearing opened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX>, attracted no public participation <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, but that didn't keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> from celebrating.
</P><P ID="9">   "We've waited a long time for this," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Velva Herrera</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   "I'm very excited about the annexation process moving forward," she said.
</P><P ID="11">   The annexation includes the old high school property at the east end of B Street, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Horticulture</ENAMEX> greenhouse property on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Allison Road</ENAMEX> and the plat of land known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark Addition</ENAMEX>, located along side State Route 22. The combined annexation proposals will more than double the city's property tax revenues once completed, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   The annexation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Allison Road</ENAMEX> area includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Horticulture</ENAMEX> greenhouse and about 20 houses, which are currently on city water lines.
</P><P ID="13">   While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said the residents in the proposed annexation can expect to see lower water rates once the area becomes part of the city limits, the city will see an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> flow into the city treasury.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said a public hearing will be scheduled in the near future to approve a zone change in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Allison Road</ENAMEX> area.
</P><P ID="15">   "We will be looking at changing the zoning to meet with our urban growth plan," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="16">   She said the city plans to allow residents in the newly annexed area to continue to raise animals on their property under a rural residential zone designation.
</P><P ID="17">   "There are a number of people in the are who raise a few cows or goats and in a rural residential zone, they will be able to maintain that lifestyle," she explained.
</P><P ID="18">   A date for the zoning change public hearing was not set during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P>





 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




