


<P ID="1">Firefighter takes exception to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman</ENAMEX>'s comments
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/20/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firefighter Bob Johnson</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, voiced his displeasure with a couple of comments made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="4">   During a discussion at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5</TIMEX> meeting regarding the hiring of a city manager, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> made a comment about how the city didn't have a problem with finding firemen like there was with hiring new police officers and a city manager. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> took exception to those comments and read some statistics from past hirings. Out of 28 applicants in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX> only 10 went on to take part in the oral examination, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. There were six applicants for another open position in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2000</TIMEX>, of those only three ended up certified to continue beyond the initial testing for the job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2001</TIMEX>, there were seven applicants for a position and only three qualified to move beyond the initial testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> a lot has changed in the job market since he applied in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>, when he was the 82nd person to test for his current position.
</P><P ID="5">   "There were enough people we had the written test at Chief Kamiakin's cafeteria," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said now there are firefighter applicants who test simply for the sake of testing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> a number of those applicants are just searching for the right paying position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said most applicants move on to better paying positions.
</P><P ID="7">   "They aren't going to work for a city that pays peanuts," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. "They are going to go to work for a city that pays almonds."
</P><P ID="8">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX> agenda items discussed
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> Finance Director Chad Stotz is scheduled to present some information at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting about water and sewer rates.
</P><P ID="10">   Also at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX> meeting, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will look to approve an agreement with the Yakima engineering firm of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gray & Osborne</ENAMEX> for work to be done on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> project. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will also be asked to approve a broad contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Conference of Governments, which will lay the work for future partnerships. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will also look at authorizing Fire Chief Jim Stanton and Stotz to write off some uncollectable debts from the ambulance service within the fire department.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> asked that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX> meeting agenda also includes a report on the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> board of director's allocation of dollars for projects. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> requested money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> to help fund the maintenance of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>. At the request of Councilman Alex de la Cruz, there will be a presentation on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX> on the one-stop permit center the city's planning department is looking at implementing, and another report on the remodeling project at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail that is set to begin. Adding on to de la Cruz's request from the planning department was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, who asked for a report on a proposed landscaping ordinance, which has been in the works for sometime.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> also asked about ways to honor past council members at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centennial Square</ENAMEX>. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> requested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> bring back cost estimates for her proposal. It wasn't clear if the item would be on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX> meeting for discussion.
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




