
<P ID="1">Food Fore Thought
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzie Loffer</ENAMEX>   As more of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s intellectually elite embrace the benefits of plant biotechnology, it is rumored that we are again on the cusp of a new agricultural movement, reminiscent of the green revolution <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">40 years ago</TIMEX>.   In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1960's</TIMEX> a group of scientists and students deemed "scientific rebels" caused a world-wide revolution in farming by teaching peasants how to farm more efficiently using new varieties of wheat that were pest resistant, climate hardy and high yielding. The scientist credited for launching the "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green Revolution</ENAMEX>" and receiving the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX> Nobel Peace Prize for this effort was Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Borlaug</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> it is a new generation of "scientific rebels" that explore the cutting edge of plant biotechnology. Like their earlier counterparts, they are facing the usual hostile opposition to a paradigm shift in technology. This time, however, it is from an unanticipated foe... the European continent.   Quite simply, Europeans seem unable to taste the future.   So, why does technology that many see as a miracle, frighten Europeans so?   Europeans who oppose <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> crops do so for a myriad of reasons. Many strongly favor traditional farming practices, having not been exposed to large production agriculture like most Americans. There is the concern that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMO</ENAMEX> crops cannot be contained, coupled with the unwarranted fear that they will spawn super pests, "Franken bugs". Topping it off is a strong dose of cynicism from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">France</ENAMEX> who view anything from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> with skepticism. Thus, the nasty mix of dialog does not leave much room for reason.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> position continues to rub salt in the American farmer's wound. Now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> is preparing to implement new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GM</ENAMEX> labeling laws. Fearing that other countries throughout the world could follow suit, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is lobbying hard against such strict labeling. American farmers have estimated that the restrictions on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GMO</ENAMEX> foods in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> have cost them <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> a year in just corn exports alone.   In the words of writer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Sterling</ENAMEX>, "the potentials of GM Food should be dead obvious to us all. It is a miracle technology that if properly handled by a mature, honest insightful society could make it possible to grow bountiful crops on marginal lands."   The European mindset is all the more ironic when balanced with the legacy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Borlaug</ENAMEX>. Now in his nineties the father of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Green Revolution</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borlaug</ENAMEX> is still actively urging his followers to be "scientific rebels". Hopefully, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Borlaug</ENAMEX>'s philosophy will help convert the current brood of European skeptics, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> will finally be able to "taste the future".   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzie Loffer</ENAMEX> writes for Loffer Media, the public relations firm responsible for distributing the Food Fore Thought monthly column.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

