


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds win against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NACHES</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> roared into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, winning against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX> and leaving them looking forward to their next match, which will determine the league champion.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team won against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> by scores of 25-15, 25-12, 25-7.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team looked pretty good against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls did a good job of getting the ball to the team's big hitters, adding that overall his team played a pretty good game.
</P><P ID="8">   Helping the Lady 'Hounds defeat <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX> were sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chante Bottineau</ENAMEX>, who had 25 assists, 11 service points, 1 kill and 4 digs on the night.
</P><P ID="9">   "She played pretty well," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottineau</ENAMEX>. "She's running the team real well, and doing a good job serving."
</P><P ID="10">   Also working hard for the Greyhounds were freshman Kealey Johnston with 10 service points, 2 kills and 17 digs; senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> with 7 service points, 3 kills, 7 digs and 8 blocks; senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> with 11 kills, 2 digs and 2 blocks; junior Tonhya Wysong with 26 digs; senior Danelle Cowan with 6 service points, 13 kills, 8 digs and 10 blocks; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> with 3 aces, 15 service points, 2 kills and 9 digs.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> added that although the team was playing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, they were already looking ahead to their next match.
</P><P ID="12">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> the Lady 'Hounds will come up against Ki-Be in a match that will determine the league champion.
</P><P ID="13">   "Ki-Be will be for the outright league championship," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said, adding that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s match should be a fun one to watch.
</P><P ID="14">   The Lady 'Hounds (8-0) will take on Ki-Be at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




