10 4 48 40 7 28
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  We are drawn to our television sets each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> the way we are drawn to the scene of an accident.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Canby</ENAMEX>, on the Academy Awards
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>