
<P ID="1">Across Our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/6/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">We've become quite familiar with initiatives lately. When did they become law, how effective have they been in our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State's</ENAMEX> history, and what does it take to sponsor one? These are the questions that sent me on an investigative tour of some offices in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia-the</ENAMEX> office of Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> who supervises elections; the State Archives where all kinds of documents are stored and made available; and BIAW whose director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom McCabe</ENAMEX> led the successful I-841 campaign.   First to the archives. Chief archivist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Handfield</ENAMEX>, directed me to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1944</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> Quarterly and an article by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudius O. Johnson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> was among the first states to approve both the initiative and the referendum as a method of direct legislation because of the work of a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Populist Party</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Simon U'Ren</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">U'Ren</ENAMEX> wrote the legislation but couldn't find interest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> legislature, so he ran for the Oregon House. After he was elected, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> did not organize in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1897</TIMEX> because of his plans. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1899</TIMEX> both houses passed his bill. It was approved by the people in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1902</TIMEX>. Between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX> the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> had to decide on 64 measures that were submitted directly to them.   After the death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1901</TIMEX> of populist governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John R. Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> groups looked at the events to the south with much interest. They felt "back-room" politics between legislators and lobbyists happened with regularity. Farm groups, especially the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX>, began to plan for an initiative and referendum system in our state.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1905</TIMEX> C.B. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kegley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pullman</ENAMEX> was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">State Grange Master</ENAMEX> and he kept this as his number one issue until it was adopted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>. By that time many others had joined with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX>.   It is interesting to read how the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX> organized the campaign to get their legislation. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1902</TIMEX> convention the members were instructed to appoint a committee in each county to interview prospective legislative candidates and persuade them to secure passage of the direct legislation proposal. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1903</TIMEX> convention the members were told to begin a "campaign of education now, and cooperate with all other organizations who are working in favor of this measure."   One story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Chamberlin</ENAMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grange News</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 30, 1919</TIMEX> tells that as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> was debating the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX>-sponsored legislation, grim-faced farmers filled the galleries. This made one Senator so uneasy that he turned to them shouting they should "be home raising crops instead of in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> raising hell."   The Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>'s office produces a website where we can find every initiative that has been filed, its subject, and what happened to it. The first initiative was filed on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2, 1914</TIMEX>. Its subject was prohibition. It was later refiled as number 3 and approved on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 3, 1914</TIMEX>, by a vote of 189,840 for and 171,208 against. A total of 799 initiatives have been filed between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1914</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. Only 118 were certified; of those exactly half have passed and half rejected by the people. That website is www.secstate.wa.gov/elections/initiatives.   It is interesting to note that in the month of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January this year</TIMEX>, 26 have already been filed. We won't know until much closer to election time whether or not they will be certified with the proper number of signatures by registered voters who voted in the last gubernatorial election.   Then I talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom McCabe</ENAMEX> about the process of getting an initiative passed. There are three hurdles to surmount according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>. The first one is that high threshold for signatures. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> that number was 198,000, but at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> more are needed to be sure the signers are registered voters in our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>. The second hurdle is to educate the voters. Voters are more likely to vote NO if the issue is not taxation-related and if it is more difficult to understand. The last hurdle is the resistance to making legislation this way. Government and governmental agencies feel power being taken from them.   What about the money it takes to run a successful campaign? BIAW members raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.1 million</NUMEX> in supporting an anti-ergonomic regulations initiative. An additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX> came from others. It's expensive, but the impacts of ergonomics would have been so much more costly to their members and to the job market in general in our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.   The initiative process was little used in the 40's and 50's. There seems to be an increased interest in it now. I just hope it is used well and wisely so that it can be one of the tools for better government.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerri Honeyford</ENAMEX>, wife of Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>), provides her Across our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> column as her take on the legislative happenings currently underway in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

