
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">MARIO <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G
MARIO G. CHAVEZ
Mario G. Chavez</ENAMEX>, 45, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 23, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 2, 1958</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramiro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria (Gutierrez) Chavez</ENAMEX>. At the age of 17 he moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, where he worked for various farmers.
He cherished time spent with his children. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> enjoyed racing, working on cars, watching soccer and gambling. He loved the outdoors, camping, fishing, swimming, bike riding and walking on the beach.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Alaniz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; four children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Chavez Jr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariaisabel Chavez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Anthony Chavez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; and three step-children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam J. Venecia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesselle Venecia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Venecia</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gutierrez Barajas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>; eight brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Israel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santa Maria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>, Octavio, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX>, Eliodoro and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>; and five sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Del Jesus</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Santa Maria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lidia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Elena</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramiro Chavez</ENAMEX>; and four siblings.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, March 25, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 26, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at Mabton Cemetery, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JEANNETTE HUETSON
Jeannette</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marian Huetson</ENAMEX>, 86, of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pioneer family passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 23, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4, 1918</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gladys Irena</ENAMEX> (Woolliscroft) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Leighton Johnson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> received her early education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendell Phillips School</ENAMEX> and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>. Following her graduation <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellensburg Beauty School</ENAMEX> and worked as a beautician for several years. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20, 1939</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl Huetson</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. They made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, where their two children were born. A dream of farming brought the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huetson</ENAMEX> family back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where they purchased a farm on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Emerald Road</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>. They started a dairy, grew grapes, corn, asparagus and alfalfa.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> was a long-time member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Valley Women’s Club</ENAMEX>. She enjoyed crafts, gardening, cooking, crocheting and rock hounding. After retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> enjoyed traveling in their R.V. and spending their winters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>.
Her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Earl</ENAMEX> of 61 years passed away in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> had continued to make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> her home until the time of her death.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> is survived by one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Maas</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Huetson</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattie</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; five grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Huetson</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl Newhouse</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Will</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Maas</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Maas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Maas</ENAMEX>; four great grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiefer Huetson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Nieswonger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Maas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Maas</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold L. Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She is also survived by several nieces and nephews.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> was preceded in death by her parents; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia N. Verhulp</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 28, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 29, 2004</TIMEX>, from 8 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Cemetery. Those wishing to honor her memory may contribute to the donor’s choice.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HAROLD R. KELLY
Harold R. Kelly</ENAMEX>, 74, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 23, 2004</TIMEX>, at his home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, surrounded by his family following a short illness.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17, 1930</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Decatur</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett Ray</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margarita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adair</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX> received his early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>, later moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, making his home on the Satus. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> he enlisted in the U.S. Navy, serving during the Korean War until his honorable discharge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1951</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30, 1953</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Gimlin</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. They together made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX> worked for Copeland Lumber in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> for several years, later working as a timber faller in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Glenwood</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Regis Paper Co.</ENAMEX> The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX> family returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, where he worked as a line truck operator for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benton Rural Electric</ENAMEX> until his retirement.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX> was a life member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans</ENAMEX> of Foreign War 3207 of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, and was also a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Eagles</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX> enjoyed fishing, hunting and reading. He cherished time spent with his children and grandchildren.
He is survived by his wife of 50 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Marie Kelly</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold Raymond Kelly Jr.</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Springfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Kelly</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danica</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Anacortes</ENAMEX>; three daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Cloud</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arvada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Marley</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelly</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Miller</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sky</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Marysville</ENAMEX>; 22 grandchildren; and one great-grandson. He is also survived by two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Kelley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kellerton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doyle Kelley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; and three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Mae Bunting</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leola Milburn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rayetta Browne</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his parents; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kelley</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 26, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 27, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of Wells Funeral Home. Those wishing to honor Harold’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Myeloma Foundation</ENAMEX>, c/o 12650 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside</ENAMEX> Dr., Suite 206, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Hollywood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CA</ENAMEX> 91607.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

