
<P ID="1">New motel slated for construction in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Tourists, business travelers or people who just want to get away from it all will have somewhere new to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> by the end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denlea</ENAMEX> purchased land owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Christensen</ENAMEX>, near the historic barn along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waneta Road</ENAMEX> overlooking Interstate 82. Denlea plans to build a new Best Western motel.   Denlea plans to build a 70,000 square foot, two-story Best Western motel near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> landmark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> said he will begin construction on the new motel as soon as possible, with expectations of having the latest in the popular chain of motels completed by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of July</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> will be a managing partner in the newest <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> motel, as he is with the Prosser Best Western and the Best Western Ahtanum in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> has been eyeing the piece of property for about 10 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> made final the purchase of the property from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christensen</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX>.   "It is an outstanding freeway location," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX>. "It has outstanding visibility."   The actual motel will take up about 38,000 square feet, covering two stories. The rest of the area will go towards parking and landscaping. The motel will consist of 55 rooms, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX>. The motel will be built up on the hill area just to the west of the barn. The motel will be located between the historic barn and a group of vineyards.   Right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> is working with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> officials on tying up some loose ends with permits and addressing other construction related issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> said as soon as those official matters are addressed and permits are issued he will begin construction. The motel will be built by A&A Development and Construction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.   One of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> decided to build a new motel is that he sees potential for financial success in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He cited a number of reasons for the decision to move forward with the motel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> said economic development is on the upswing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area. He referred to the new Wal-Mart distribution center, but also added that he expects a lot more additional economic growth to take place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> in the form of restaurants and other businesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> also said the extensive tourism that hits the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, especially during the wine touring season, was another factor in the decision to move forward with constructing the new motel.   "This area is growing," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX>. "There is a lot of potential here. There is quite a bit of upside for tourism in the area."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> said he is looking forward to building a new motel in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He said the actual opening date for the business <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will depend on when he is able to break ground for the facility.   "It will be a nice facility," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX>. "I think it is a good project for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>."      
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

