
<P ID="1">Familiar face taking over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls program
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/18/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> native <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Roettger</ENAMEX> is coming home.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>, 27, was hired as the new coach of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> girls basketball team, replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Simpson</ENAMEX>, who is leaving after five seasons.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett</ENAMEX> did a heck of a job," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> is no stranger to the hardwood at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> comes from an athletic family. His brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob</ENAMEX>, who is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> track and field coach IS well-known for his basketball skills in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, having scored his 1,000th point his junior season. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>, is no slouch himself. He is considered one of the best players to ever touch a ball in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, getting a berth to the all-state game his senior year.   Prior to accepting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls coaching job, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> oversaw the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School</ENAMEX> junior varsity boys basketball program. The Spartans' junior squad went 33-7 under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> and 47-13 during his three-year tenure.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> learned the art of coaching from one of the best coaches the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> has ever seen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Affholter</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> played what he terms as four memorable years for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> coaching legend.   "I still call him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>. "I am not afraid to admit I don't know everything."   The part that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> remembers about playing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affholter</ENAMEX> was that the game was simple.   "Things were basic," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>. "He never really got on us. He was positive."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affholter</ENAMEX>'s emphasis was executing the fundamentals of the sport. One part of playing under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Affholter</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> fondly remembers is the coach's desire to do his best and have his players leave all they could on the floor.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> had the will to win," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>. "And he was going to instill that in everyone."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> said he is hoping to implement that same philosophy with his Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> this season.   Even though he is the new coach of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> girls basketball team, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> won't be completely in the dark. His older brother is the middle school boys and girls coach, so <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> is hoping to gain a lot of insight into players coming through the system.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> will also have his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, to fall back on. His wife is a teacher at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. The couple has two children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naya</ENAMEX>, 3, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaitlyn</ENAMEX>, 1.   Making the transition from coaching boys basketball to girls hoops won't be that difficult, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>.   "I think it is going to be fun," he said. "Basketball is basketball. It is going to be a fairly smooth transition."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> is very excited about coming back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and leading the girls basketball program.   "This is home," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>. "The opportunity to come home is just unbelievable."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> hit the road running with the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>. The team is busy with its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> season.   "I have got to learn the kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>. "I want to get a feel for the kids and I want them to get a feel for me."   So far, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> has been impressed with the work ethic of his players.   "There is some talent there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>. "I am walking into a system that is on the rise."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> has some simple goals for this season. He wants to get enough players out to field three teams. And he also feels the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> can make the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> tournament this season, it is just a matter of upsetting one of the top three teams in the Greater Columbia 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">northern division-Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian, Riverside Christian or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LaSalle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> is also planning to put a lot more emphasis on offense this season. He wants his players to be able to play at a quickened pace to throw others teams off guard.   As far as his coaching philosophy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> said the most important aspect is for students to maintain high academic standards.   "If a kid can't pass a class, they are not going to be out there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> also wants to imprint on his players the need to play as a unit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> encourages any players who are interested in turning out or want to talk to him more about the team to call him at 830-4647.   Coming back home is something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX> is happy to be doing.   "No matter what a coach tells you, they always want to come back home," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roettger</ENAMEX>. ""I want to give back what I got out of the school and the community."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

