
<P ID="1">Karate students earn regional tournament honors
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> has been a good month for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocky Gonzales</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> karate school. His students recently earned karate honors and trophies for martial arts style and form at regional tournaments held on opposite sides of the state.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students collected seven trophies at the Seattle Battle at the Beach Tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX>. They then traveled to the Spokane Inland Empire Martial Arts Tournament held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX>, where they picked up eight more trophies.   Green belt student <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haydee Navarro</ENAMEX>, 13, came home the grand champion in form at the Seattle tourney, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX>.   She also claimed first place honors in the form and sparring events at the Seattle event. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX> was also the first place winner in her division's sparring contest at the Inland Empire event.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yzuda Montes</ENAMEX>, 11, also a green belt student, brought home first place honors in the form and sparring events from the Seattle tourney. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montes</ENAMEX> then earned a first place trophy in the form event at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>. She also had a third place finish in sparring at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.   Also earning honors was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio Montes</ENAMEX>, 15, a brown belt student. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montes</ENAMEX> earned a sparring medal in his division in Seattle. Green belt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordan Salazar</ENAMEX>, 14, claimed a first place medal in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo</ENAMEX> contest and a second place finish in sparring in Seattle. He also claimed a third place form trophy at the Seattle tourney. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salazar</ENAMEX> then went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, where he finished first in form and second in sparring.   Also competing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> school was white belt student A.J. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterman</ENAMEX>. The 7-year-old traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> with his fellow competitors to bring home twin first place honors in the form and sparring events.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX>, who operates the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Tae Kwon</ENAMEX> Do <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association</ENAMEX>, holds weekly classes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navarro Family Community Center</ENAMEX> in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX>, who has been practicing martial arts for most of his life, said the majority of his students have been studying with him for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX>.   A grand master in the martial arts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX> said his students will be competing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tillamook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> at the regional grand championships.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

