
<P ID="1">Support sought for highway name change
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">After more than 20 years of having a twin identity, old State Highway 12 may yet again be renamed - at least on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area stretch of road now known as Yakima Valley Highway.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc. Economic Development Board</ENAMEX> of Directors recently discussed the possibility of renaming Yakima Valley Highway as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>, as it is known throughout the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   The board is now in the process of seeing what level of support there may be in the community for the name change proposal, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Doak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> executive director.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port District</ENAMEX> commissioners recently heard a report about the economic development board's discussion regarding the name change, but has chosen to take a "wait and see" stance until more public input on the name change is gathered, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Hansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port</ENAMEX> manager.   The old State Highway 12, which was once the primary highway, which lies to the north of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima River</ENAMEX>, was renamed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1980s</TIMEX>, upon the completion of Interstate 82.   The public opinion at the time was equally divided as to whether or not to call the highway "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>" in recognition of the area's rapidly growing wine industry, or to name the highway "Yakima Valley Highway," with the result being the double moniker.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> representatives will be discussing the possible name change with various groups in coming weeks, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

