26 11 20 47 19 13
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Don't bother just to be better than your contemporaries or predecessors. Try to be better than yourself.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Faulkner</ENAMEX> (1897 - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX>)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>