




 


<P ID="1">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="2">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="3">Vocalist to appear at Jazz Alley
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - Dimitriou's Jazz Alley in Seattle will present up and coming vocalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Gazarek</ENAMEX> for a one-night only performance on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Jan. 5</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Ratliff</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York Times</ENAMEX> describes a recent performance by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gazarek</ENAMEX> as, "Professional isn't the word; her performance was sublime."
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gazarek</ENAMEX> is one of the most talked about young vocalists emerging from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s jazz scene. Currently a senior at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Southern Cal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gazarek</ENAMEX> has already found her own unique style, with an inviting stage presence and a powerful sense of swing. She has won numerous awards, including the Ella Fitzgerald Outstanding Vocalist Award.
</P>

<P ID="7">The band members who will be accompanying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gazarek</ENAMEX> at Dimitriou's Jazz Alley include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Pierson</ENAMEX> of keyboard, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erik Kertes</ENAMEX> on bass and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil Parisot</ENAMEX> on drums.
</P>

<P ID="8">Tickets for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5</TIMEX> performance are available by calling (206) 441-9729.
</P>

 


<P ID="9">‘Wild West’ show in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The Yakima Folklife Concert Series will feature "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wylie</ENAMEX> and the Wild West" in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 9</TIMEX>, in the Great Hall of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Museum</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="11">Featuring cowboy yodeling, honky tonk and fine western music, the band is said to have the best singing cowboy alive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 9</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> performance is open to the public. Tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> for children, will be available at the door that evening.
</P>

 


<P ID="13">Dixie Melody Boys in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 10</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="14">YAKIMA - One of Gospel music's most popular artists, The Dixie Melody Boys, will be featured in concert on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 10</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima's Stone Church</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15">The band has enjoyed much success, including a Grammy nomination. Hit releases have flowed their way in bunches, including recent releases "I'll be Living that Way" and "I Won't Compromise."
</P>

<P ID="16">The group's energy and excitement, coupled with their exceptional vocal blend, is appealing to audiences of all ages.
</P>

<P ID="17">The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 10</TIMEX>, concert will begin at p.m.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="18">Webmaster
</P><P ID="19">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




