
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> recieves recognition for mentoring work
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/17/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Working to promote the medical field amongst high school students is something Mid-Valley Community Clinic's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Clark</ENAMEX> has been doing since moving to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2003</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>, a physician's assistant, said upon her arrival at the local clinic she was approached to take part in Project HOPE, which helps introduce young people to the field of medicine.   "I had wonderful people who mentored and trained me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said. "I hope to do the same."   So far <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> has worked with one student through Project HOPE, but that is just the tip of the iceberg as far as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> is concerned. She said she is expecting to have more students to mentor over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and said she will begin mentoring three students from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> in the next couple of weeks.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said when working with a student she tries to give them a dose of what it's like to work at the clinic. She said with patient permission the students she is mentoring get a chance to come in with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> during examinations and check-ups, observing how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> interacts with her patients. She said the students also have a chance to ask questions during the experience.   "I'm assisting them in learning what we do at the clinic," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said.   Through Project HOPE <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> works with any given student for at least 15 hours, teaching them what she does every day, as well as providing them a basic understanding of how the medical world works.   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> is new in her experience with Project HOPE, she is no stranger to serving as a teacher. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said she has experience through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington and Olympia College</ENAMEX> helping nurses make the transition from nurse to nurse practioner to physician's assistant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> was recently recognized for her work with Project HOPE. The Mid-Valley Community Clinic was presented a plaque for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s participation in the project.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

