
<P ID="1">Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> play well in weekend losses
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For some teams it takes a while to get going. And the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> girls basketball team seems to be getting going at the right time.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> didn't win either of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>'s games against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> looked a lot better than the first time each of the teams met.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> nearly avenged an earlier season blowout by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, but came up short in the fourth quarter, losing 57-43. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> proved to be nearly a mirror image of the first time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> met, as the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> jumped on the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> early on their way to a 52-37 victory.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, which has traditionally struggled at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, played well off the bat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> were down 41-35 going into the fourth quarter. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> put the game away with a 16-8 fourth period.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Leo Gomez</ENAMEX> said the difference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> boiled down to a few officiating calls not going in favor of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> down the stretch.   "It was a good game for us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "But a couple of calls didn't happen. No calls for us (ended up as) points for them."   While <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> had a notable game with 13 points and nine rebounds, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanna Pangle</ENAMEX> who showed up to play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pangle</ENAMEX> had 13 points and eight rebounds.   "She came through for us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>.   The biggest difference for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>, was the amount of patience the team showed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said his team also did a good job of finding the open player, a lot more than in previous games.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> opened with a 14-2 first quarter and never looked back. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> led 27-9 at the break on its way to a 52-37 win.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> came out and played some tough man-to-man defense," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> put together a solid second half, outscoring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> 28-25. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was much more effective at pushing the ball up the court in the second half.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said he was displeased with the play of his team. He said the only thing he knew going into the game was that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> would have to stop <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> in the first quarter or it would be tough to win the game.   Bobi Haringa played big for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> with 9 points and eight rebounds.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> (3-9, 6-12) will be looking to take a huge step towards securing the No. 6 seed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> and a playoff berth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> is currently a game behind in the standings. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will then travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to finish up the regular season. Depending on the outcome of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>'s games, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> could face off on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in a playoff for the final postseason berth.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   1 2 3 4 T   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 11 12 12 8 43   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> 13 14 14 16 57   Scoring: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 13, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanna Pangle</ENAMEX> 13, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 5, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 5, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniella Rivera</ENAMEX> 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monique Montelongo</ENAMEX> 3.   Ellensburg-Melissa Kuhm 17.   Rebounds: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 9.   Assists: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 3, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 3.      1 2 3 4 T   West Valley 14 13 13 12 52   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 2 7 12 16 37   Scoring: Bobi Haringa 9, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 5, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Caballero</ENAMEX> 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Alvarez</ENAMEX> 3, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monique Montelongo</ENAMEX> 2. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniella Rivera</ENAMEX> 1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley-Cassie Murrillo</ENAMEX> 14.   Rebounds: Bobi Haringa 8, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 7, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 4.   Assists: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 3, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 2.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

