
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> teen gains better understanding about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> policy, politics at conference
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/30/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WASHINGTON D.C</ENAMEX>. - For 10 days of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> vacation <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Meininger</ENAMEX> learned about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> policy and politics at the National Student Leadership Conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>.   For two years in a row, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX> was invited to attend the conference, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> was the first time he took part in it.   Of several areas of interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX> could pursue at the conference, he chose policy and politics because it was something he had an interest in learning more about, he said.   "I have an interest in law and the political field," said the 17-year-old. "I wanted to learn about the entire process."   As a part of the conference he had the opportunity to listen to numerous speakers, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry McAuliffe</ENAMEX>, the chairperson of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democratic National Committee</ENAMEX>.   "Most of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McAuliffe</ENAMEX>'s speech was anti-president," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX>. Also addressing the youths was Republican Senator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Hagel</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX>.   "He talked about the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> situation and his views on it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McAuliffe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hagel</ENAMEX> were just two of the daily speakers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX> and his fellow policy and politics classmates heard during the conference. The 200 students attending the conference also heard speakers talk on politics and money, media and politics, the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> executive offices, and influential analysts and advisors on the hill.   During the conference <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX> was able to participate in senate and campaign simulations.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX> explained that the conference attendees debated on hot topics, such as capital punishment and affirmative action as part of the reenactments.   As a part of the senate simulations <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX> played the assigned role of a Democratic representative from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Massachusetts</ENAMEX>. His roles included writing a bill in the judicial committee, which he <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> on in the simulation, and co-writing a bill on minority rights.   In the presidential campaign simulations, he played a member of the media.   "I now have a greater understanding of the political system," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX>.   Besides attending sessions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX>, who is the son of Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rochelle Meininger</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, also had the opportunity to see the nation's capital. He visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Old Town Alexandra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baltimore Harbor</ENAMEX>, the National Mall and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holocaust Museum</ENAMEX>. He was able to take a night tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>., which included stops at the different national memorials and the newly constructed World War II monument. Also a highlight, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meininger</ENAMEX>, was the political satire "Capitol Steps," which he was able to see performed.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

