


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> says no (again) to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>' bid
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> started the night off defending his position for voting to reject the lone bid submitted to the city <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> for publishing the city's legal notices. But by the time everything was said and done, there was some doubt left about what the one-term councilman was truly saying.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daily News Publisher Tim Graff</ENAMEX> came before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> asking the governing body to reconsider the newspapers' legal publication bid the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> rejected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> initiated the process at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Monday</TIMEX>'s meeting for rejecting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>' bid for legal publications. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> reasoning, he said, was that he didn't feel the city had done a good job of seeking bids from different newspapers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> sent out a negative message to other publications by rejecting the then lower bid of the Yakima Herald-Republic to publish legal notices in its weekly Voices section. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said by rejecting the Yakima Herald-Republic bid, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> sent a message that it was showing favoritism to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and for other newspapers to not even bother to go through the process. At that time, however, then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX> explained in a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that it would be more cost effective to go with the legal bid from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> because the city would have to pay a more significant legal publication rate for notices that weren't able to be published in Voices and had to be inserted in the regular legal section of the Yakima Herald-Republic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> said there was also more flexibility in scheduling by going with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>' bid.
</P><P ID="7">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> was the lone publication to submit a bid to be the official newspaper of the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The rate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> submitted was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.70</NUMEX> per column inch, a 30¢ increase over past rates.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that he believes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> met all of the requirements set forth by the city in submitting its bid in a timely manner. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> said by rejecting the newspapers' bid <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> it puts the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> at a competitive disadvantage because the bid rate it already submitted was made public, giving other publications an advantage in the forthcoming bid resubmission process.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> said under the terms set forth by the city only two publications qualify to be the official newspaper of the city, those being the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and the Yakima Herald-Republic.
</P><P ID="10">   The specifications set forth in the process require any publication submitting a bid to be of "general circulation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> and must be compiled in whole or in part in an office maintained at the place of publication." The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and the Yakima Herald-Republic, both with offices on Sixth Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, apear to be the only publications meeting those requirements.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> the city spent about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,300</NUMEX> for legal advertising. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> said the newspaper at many times met needed deadlines for the city at a moment's notice.
</P><P ID="12">   "We have always worked well with city staff," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> said he felt justified in asking for the minimal <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> increase in rates because he believes the newspaper has done a superb job for the city. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> said the rejection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>' bid makes him wonder if it was personally motivated.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> said the legal newspaper bid rejection was nothing personal with him. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he wanted to make sure the city was getting the best and most conservative bids needed to make sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is spending taxpayers' dollars appropriately. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has rejected bids in the past and he felt having just one bid wasn't sufficient.
</P><P ID="15">   "It is not something new or abnormal (to reject a lone bid)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. "I am going to go with the low bidder. I don't know who is going to be the low bidder."
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> responded to the comments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "I think there are other newspapers who serve this community as well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> praised the work completed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> in the cost comparison done in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, but rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX>'s comments that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> went with the most conservative bid in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he wants to look for the best way the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> can spend the citizens' money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> added another comment regarding personal issues in the rejection of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>' bid. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said it is interesting the newspaper can write editorials voicing their opinion on topics, but said he found it equally as interesting that the newspaper is the only one who can have a "vendetta."
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graff</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to reconsider the action taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to reject the bid. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opted to stand by its decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   But the evening wasn't done yet concerning issues surrounding the conduct of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> fireman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Johnson</ENAMEX> read a letter, sent via e-mail, into public record that had come from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>. No date was given on the letter, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> did acknowledge at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s meeting he had written the letter. The e-mail includes comments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> made following a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> meeting. The letter also makes reference to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>. The letter also talks about how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> will use his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> vote in ways he sees fit.
</P><P ID="22">   "I find this really, really disturbing," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> after he read the letter.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said he felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> was acting inappropriately and that he did use his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> vote to get into the pockets of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   The following is a copy of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>' e-mail letter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> read into public record at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="25">   "I am finer than frogs hair---all is well and every day is sunshine--this was just an initial volley at the mother of all lies in our city (DSN) and if it has $ome (any) impact I will feel a lot better--
</P><P ID="26">   to me the def: of a lie is if a lie is spoke OR if a lie is known and not spoken--same thing (sin of omission or sin of commission)
</P><P ID="27">   I attended the 1st half of the chamber mtg. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fri.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. However, after I was gone the attendees spoke about how awful it was that members of the city council were beating up on B.A. And the fact the whole chamber board knows the truth and did and said NOTHING to defend its self and in particular council, after we have spent so much political capital defending the chamber and its programs and bringing to light the attempt to divide the chamber and the efforts to shed a bad light on it, I am personally ashamed to be associated with such a spineless group that I will <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEVER</ENAMEX> go to bat for them again and I will <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NEVER</ENAMEX> AGAIN work behind the scenes in their behalf--
</P><P ID="28">   Then the paper who knows the truth and refuses to print all sides of it---I will try to get into their pockets at any opportunity--I DO NOW HAVE AN AGENDA--TRUTH, OR DARE (ME)
</P><P ID="29">   STRENGTH <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THROUGH SUPERIOR FIRE POWER--I HAVE MY COUNCIL VOTE--I INTEND</ENAMEX> TO <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USE</ENAMEX> IT
</P><P ID="30">   LEAD FOLLOW OR GET THE HECK OUT OF MY WAY---but you know that I will do it with a smile and keep my old theme-------
</P><P ID="31">   TACT: THE ABILITY TO TELL SOMEONE WHERE TO GO AND HAVE THEM ANXIOUS TO GET THERE
</P><P ID="32">   Share this with whomever you wish
</P><P ID="33">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX>
</P>   






 










<P ID="34">Webmaster
</P><P ID="35">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




