


<P ID="1">New fire truck showcased for G'view community
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/1/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>) has helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> maintain its fire rating, as well as city residents' insurance premiums.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Fire Chief Charles Damron</ENAMEX> gave rides to local residents <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> on the city's new Class A pumper truck that was purchased by the city with the USDA grant.
</P><P ID="6">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX>, without the new truck insurance premiums were expected to increase by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> residents voted down a levy that would have paid for the new pumper. So instead, city officials looked to grant funding to update their fire department fleet.
</P><P ID="8">   The truck, which replaces a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> Commercial pumper, is one of three Class A engines in service.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> also has a 75-foot ladder truck. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> explained that the ladder truck isn't for tall buildings, but rather for the numerous warehouses in the community.
</P><P ID="10">   The new pumper features a five-man cab, compared to the three people the old cab held. The new truck also has self-contained breathing apparatus built into four of the seats.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> said with the new truck his department can have the five people needed on-scene to initiate firefighting efforts to immediately enter a building.
</P><P ID="12">   He added that the truck will help with the 450 city calls and 200 county calls the small department responds to annually.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> said that besides applying for the grant, the city contacted Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> to encourage funding for the truck.
</P><P ID="14">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX> was probably getting tired of us sending e-mails and calling," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   "If we hadn't been able to this now, our fire rating would have gone up and it would have cost people more money," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> and the USDA for more than a year on arranging the funding for the truck.
</P><P ID="17">   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Fire Department</ENAMEX> works very hard to protect the local community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> told those who attended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s unveiling of the new pumper. "These funds will help the department upgrade its fire equipment and enhance its capabilities," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   Also on hand for the introduction of the truck into the community was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie J. Gleason</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> Director for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA Rural Development</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleason</ENAMEX> said that after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2000</TIMEX>, President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> said there was a need for more first responders.
</P><P ID="20">   "He said, 'We need to do more'," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleason</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> administration</ENAMEX> added <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500 million</NUMEX> to the budget to help provide funding to fire departments across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   "This is what government is supposed to do. We're supposed to be partners," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gleason</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




