
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Choose correctly
Whether you vote for President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> or not, be sure to do one thing—get the facts straight.
In this time of over exaggerated, slandering, political commercials, it's vital you understand where each candidate stands on the issues.
Just because "The Right" overwhelmingly dominates <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> doesn't mean people shouldn't take the time to do some research. Expand your mind and think.
Someone once said, "Conservatism is sometimes a symptom of sterility. Those who have nothing in them that can grow and develop must cling to what they have in beliefs, ideas and possessions. The sterile radical, too, is basically conservative. He is afraid to let go of the ideas and beliefs he picked up in his youth lest his life be seen as empty and wasted."
Be your own person and choose wisely.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Amador</ENAMEX>, Seattle, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Re-elect <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush
When</ENAMEX> people look back at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> Administration</ENAMEX> in years to come, they will see that the No Child Left Behind Act was one of the most significant pieces of legislation signed into law in decades. Why?
Because it puts educational standards into place for all students. This is especially important for low income and minority students, too many of whom have fallen through the cracks in our public education system over the years. Results are already showing up in our local school districts, as well as in other districts that have struggled across the country.
As with so many other issues, President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is a noteworthy exception to the average politician. When he encounters a problem, his response is not to complain or blame someone else for the problem. His response is to try to solve the problem.
We don't often have a president with the vision to lead in this fashion. But we can certainly keep this one for four more years. Please join me in voting to re-elect George W. Bush.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Linde</ENAMEX>, Outlook
</P> 
<P ID="5">Privatization—at what cost?
The proposal to privatize <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s public works department raises some important issues.
Having lived in an urban center on the west side of the state for several years, I had the opportunity to observe the performances of a number of agencies that chose to employ privatized service providers. Privatization was generally initiated by new management, often not long term residents of the locale, interested in trimming the budget. The tactic was to persuade the general public that eliminating such expensive items as decent living wages, cost of living allowances and health benefit packages would lower the cost of city and county services and provide a financial boost for the local economy.
However, a major consideration was ignored: when a public works crew, like the one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, dedicates a consistent work effort, shows concern for the needs of the public, and invests time and money in the community voluntarily, as residents, outside of the work schedule.
The result is that not only do the new "privatized" employees fail to respond in a timely fashion to citizens' needs, but they are not invested in the community. So the quality of performance is heavily diminished.
I would hope that the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> are willing to carefully scrutinize the proposal to privatize the public works department. It would be, in my opinion, a major error in judgment.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonja McDaniel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‘Little’ Council of S’side</ENAMEX> (Related to The Little Red Hen)
One day as the little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was struggling, having issues with clean air, clean water and quality of life;
"This should be resolved," they said. "Who will help us with this problem?" "Not I," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>. "Not I," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Clean Air Authority</ENAMEX>. "Not I," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">New Vision</ENAMEX>.
"Then we will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. And they did.
Soon, the need to measure and define the problem came. "The problem is ripe," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. "Who will help us measure and define?" "Not I," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Dept.</ENAMEX> of Ecology. "Not I," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Dept. of Agriculture</ENAMEX>. "Not I," said the Washington Dairy Federation.
"Then we will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. And they did.
When the issues were defined and partners were needed to help resolve, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> said, "Who will partner with us in this endeavor?" "Not I," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port District</ENAMEX>. "Not I," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> board. "Not I," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>.
"Then we will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. And they did.
When the issue became political, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> said, "Who will help resolve these politics?" "Not I," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX>. "Not I," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX>. "Not I," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Palacios</ENAMEX>.
"Then we will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. And they tried.
They addressed the issue to the press and asked for fair and balanced reporting. Then asked, "Who will report the information fair and balanced?" "Not I," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dark Side News</ENAMEX>. "Not I," said the Yakima Herald. "Not I," said the Tri-Cities Herald.
"Then we will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. And they tried.
They negotiated the deal, paid the costs, became their own partners and made it a win-win.
"Who will take the credit and benefit from this?" "Oh! I will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX>. "Oh! I will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>. "Oh! I will," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.
"No, no," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. "We will do that."
AND <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">THEY DID</ENAMEX>.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">John Torch</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="7">Why buy a car?
Recently, I went into a local automobile dealership in an attempt to trade-in my car. I didn't get a new car, but did get confused and somewhat shocked with the whole "trading in your car" business. I understand that a dealership needs to make money in order to have a viable business, but how much is too much? And at whose expense?
Like many of your readers, I know the difference between the retail values and and the trade-in values. But it wasn't until my last negotiating attempts that I really grasped what it meant.
Let's assume that a trade-in value for a car is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> less than the retail value. Automobile dealerships will not typically pay more than the trade-in value of a car, which means they automatically make a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> profit.
Furthermore, the cars at dealerships are typically overpriced by an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> (from what I have been told by friends in the car business). This means that if you trade in your car at the trade-in value rate and buy a car at the retail value, the dealership would make <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,500</NUMEX> in one deal. Imagine that!
Now...imagine this happening to about 50 deals a month. That totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$325,000</NUMEX> in profits in one month.
Automobile dealerships are out to take advantage of consumers. It's not like if consumers can just say to heck with it. The reality is, consumers need transportation to survive. The price that dealerships blindly force consumers to pay, however, is an outrage.
Consumers, including myself, need to be thoroughly educated on the type of deals they are getting into. After all, it's not a well kept secret that cars are a bad investment. If you don't really need a new car, why reinvest into yet another money shortfall.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Gonzales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

