
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX> couple reopens <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Shell</ENAMEX> station
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Toshi and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pilrang Owa</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everett</ENAMEX> have reopened the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Country Shell</ENAMEX> station on Yakima Valley Highway, re-naming the convenience store <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Country Foods USA</ENAMEX>.   "We opened about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX>" said the first-time gas station store owner.   While no stranger to business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owa</ENAMEX> and his wife haven't worked in gas stations or quick markets before. He is a retired exporter, having spent most of his career supplying meat to restaurants all over the world.   The couple became familiar with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> area recently when they purchased the former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalke RV</ENAMEX> park, located next to the former Moose Lodge on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scoon Road</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "We like this area, and expect to move here in the future," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owa</ENAMEX> said.   "As we get to know the area we are finding the people friendly and living very relaxed," he said.   The store will offer a variety of fast foods, snacks and picnicking items. "We plan to cater to the families who use the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunny View Park</ENAMEX> and will have sporting programs broadcast over our television system," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owa</ENAMEX> is now seeking a license to sell beer and wine at the store, located midway between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> on Yakima Valley Highway.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Country Store USA</ENAMEX> will be open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>, seven days a week.   "We're planning a grand opening about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owa</ENAMEX> added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

