
<P ID="1">Southern posts personal best at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pendleton</ENAMEX> invite
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PENDLETON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Southern</ENAMEX>, a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, toured the back nine of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pendleton Country Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> with a personal best four-over 41.   Coupled with the 50 she shot on the front side, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> posted a team low round of 91.   "It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX>'s best nine-hole score ever," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Gary Rohde</ENAMEX>. "I believe the 91 was also her best 18-hole score."   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzly</ENAMEX> golf team was one of 17 prep squads competing at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s Pendleton Invitational. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't figure into the team scoring, though, as only three of the four girls on the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzly</ENAMEX> team were able to make the trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pendleton</ENAMEX>.   "If we had had Jensie (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hernandez</ENAMEX>) there, I think we would have beaten half a dozen of the teams," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rohde</ENAMEX>.   As it turned out, Class 4A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> won the invite team title, posting a tournament low aggregate score of 349. Class 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hanford</ENAMEX> claimed runner-up honors with a 364.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>'s medalist was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Black</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>, who hit the clubhouse with a three-over 77.   In carding her lowest nine-hole score ever, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX> knocked down five pars on the back side. Her steady back nine play included a string of three consecutive pars, on the par-5 11th and 12th holes and the par-3 13th.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi</ENAMEX> was very consistent on the back side," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rohde</ENAMEX>.   Second in for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> was sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Downing</ENAMEX>. She posted a 121 on front and back scores of 64-57. Playing on her 16th birthday, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX>'s present came on No. 8, when she parred the par-3, 150-yard hole.   Rounding out the team scoring for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Kim</ENAMEX>, who took a 155 (80-75).   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> nine-hole competition against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girls prevailed by a 246-296 count. The victory boosted the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>' conference record to 2-1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern</ENAMEX>, again, had the low round for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, claiming a 50 on the front nine at Black Rock Creek Golf Course. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> also got a 61 from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hernandez</ENAMEX>, a 64 from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> and a 71 from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s low scorer was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Lochrie</ENAMEX> with a 62.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girls squad will play next at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley Rams</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, April 27</TIMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

