


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/14/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> takes no action following executive session
</P>

<P ID="5">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> met for about 10 minutes in executive session to discuss land acquisition this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> took no formal action following the executive session.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves mayor's appointments
</P>

<P ID="8">At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members formally approved three appointments of Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">Two of the mayor's appointments were for positions on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>. The other appointment was for a spot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority Board</ENAMEX> of Commissioners.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approved the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Raab</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority Board</ENAMEX> of Commissioners. She is scheduled to serve a five-year term, which will expire on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7, 2009</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raab</ENAMEX> was first appointed to the board in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2000</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also approved the appointments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bierlink</ENAMEX> to the planning commission. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX>'s term will expire on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17, 2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX>'s term is set to expire on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 15, 2008</TIMEX>.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="12">Beautification awards to be presented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="13">One of the items on a so far short agenda for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Sept. 27</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting is the presentation of the community beautification awards.
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will also consider surplusing 96 bicycles. Also coming before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will be several liquor license renewals. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> may also be holding an executive session.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="15">Housing fair to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> reminded her fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that there will be a housing fair going on at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph's Catholic Church</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 24</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said there will be information at the housing fair that helps people learn more about owning their own home.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman</ENAMEX> wants problems looked into at community center
</P>

<P ID="19">This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> enlightened the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on some problems at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="20"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the baseboard in the entryway of the community center is coming off. She said she also understands there are problems with water leaks that are affecting the foundation of the building.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




