
<P ID="1">County commissioner stumps for votes
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay</ENAMEX> addressed members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> about the upcoming commissioner election.   Since the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> man took office nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> he has been focusing on economic development in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. A member of three different economic development boards, New Vision, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley SEID Board</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource Conservation Development Commission</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> has been on the front lines of economic development. He said as a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEID</ENAMEX> board he has had a hand in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> projects, including the nursery in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and the Wal-Mart distribution center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource Conservation Development Commission</ENAMEX> has assisted in developing the Toppenish Highway tourist radio station.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> has also favored the restructuring of the county's permitting and planning departments to develop a one-stop-shop for those looking to develop or build in the county. He said the county is offering a money-back guarantee to ensure that permits and plans are processed in a timely manner.   A touchy subject, the new county jail, which is currently under construction in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> addressed club members' concerns saying that he did not make the decision in a vacuum. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> sites in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> were considered by a citizen siting committee, but ultimately, after the county purchased land in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> that didn't have water rights. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> was chosen as the site for the new jail. County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Palacios</ENAMEX>, who was also at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> meeting, said that they were told by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish City</ENAMEX> officials through the process that the land had water rights. But there are two different kinds of water rights. The land had rights for how much water flow was allowed in a year, but now for how much water could be pumped in a day, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>.   The Yakama Nation brought the water issue to the county commissioners' attention during the SEPA process.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> added that he believes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> fairgrounds location was the best for the county. Although one of his opponents vows to stop construction on the jail if elected, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said stopping the jail project would cost the county <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5 million</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> explained that bonds were sold to build the facility. If the county were to stop the project the bonds would still have to be repaid.   "The revenue from the jail is supposed to pay for the bonds," he added.   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, the county has been able to gain <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$53 million</NUMEX> from jail bed sales, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>. Looking to the future he said it will cost the county <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27 million</NUMEX> just to house its own population.   "The bottom line is we had to build anyway. This way we don't have to pay for it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>, who agreed that although the jail numbers and costs are just projections, he felt it best to be prepared.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said that the commissioners would have been criticized either way. He said if they didn't build the jail when they had the opportunity they would have been criticized in the future when the need was great.   "In the long run I believe it will save us money," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said that the siting committee was down to one site in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> that looked feasible, but the cost to purchase the property and help <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with a sewer system upgrade was not cost effective.   "I think that's (the sewer system) part of the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> wanted us to come-as a solution to their problem," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>.   Former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman Chad Werkhoven</ENAMEX> further questioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> on the jail project, asking why the county commissioners were not at a meeting billed as a public hearing, which was held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX> said that the citizen siting committee was on-hand, but made it very clear that they had no intention of siting the jail in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "It turns out it wasn't a public hearing, it was a dog and pony show," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> countered that the siting committee was part of the process of selecting a site for the facility.   "You don't have them do your thinking for you," answered back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX>, who added that statistics are like eggs, you can cook them any way you want to.   "It was our understanding here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, that it would have been very cost effective," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Schuler</ENAMEX>, who also attended the meeting.   At the meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> was also asked if he supports the Black Rock Creek Reservoir project.   "We've been there all the way," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>.   Although there aren't any county funds to spare to support the project at this point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110,000</NUMEX> has already been given to the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton</ENAMEX> counties contributed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to the feasibility study of the project and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> was given by the county to start a website to inform residents on the project.   "Personally, I've given funds to the Black Rock Creek project," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

