
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">June & Clark ‘Heritage Day’set</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PASCO</ENAMEX> - A re-enactment of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">June & Clark</ENAMEX> arriving by traditional dugout canoe will be one of the highlights of the second annual "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">June & Clark Heritage Day</ENAMEX>," to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sacajawea State Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>.
The arrival of the canoe, to be manned by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX> re-enactors, is slated for approximately <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX> event will commemorate the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1805</TIMEX> experience at the confluence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> rivers.
Other activities planned for that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> include living history presentations, first-person interpretations, entertainment, artistic displays, a hands-on children's camp, Columbia Plateau tribal dancing and skills demonstrations, guest speakers, nature walks, jet boat rides and more.
Living history presentations will include first-person re-enactors portraying Captain Meriwether <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Drouillard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Gass</ENAMEX>, John Collins and Toissant Charbonneau—all of whom were members ofthe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Volunteers</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Discovery</ENAMEX>.
Admission and parking for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16</TIMEX> eventis free, thanks in part to corporate sponsor <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Battelle</ENAMEX>.
"This is a great opportunity for visitors and locals alike to learn about the two cultures that met at this place almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">200 years ago</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Watkins</ENAMEX>, president and CEO of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Visitor and Convention Bureau</ENAMEX>.
An estimated 200 Native Americans greeted the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX> at the confluence of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snake</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia</ENAMEX> rivers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1805</TIMEX>. While in the midst of these Sahaptian-speaking people the explorers traded goods, purchased food, catalogued the local dialects, repaired their equipment and explored the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX> to the mouth of the Tapteal, which is known <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima River</ENAMEX>. It was also at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> site that the expedition members knew for the first time since entering unchartered territory exactly where they were, as they had found the object of their journey, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, about 4,000 people attended in the inaugural <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Heritage Day</TIMEX> event. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> organizers are expecting more than 5,000 people to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sacajawea State Park</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Gospel music jamboree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 17</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX> will be the site for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 17</TIMEX>, Gospel music jamboree. The 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> event, which will feature an open microphone for anyone wanting to perform, is open to the public.
Local musicians that have performed regularly at the monthly jamborees in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Strings & Bill Lawson</ENAMEX>, The Gospeliers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Diamond</ENAMEX> and Joyfull Noise.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> church is located at 428 'B' St.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrel</ENAMEX> racing to benefit sexual assault program
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> and cowgirls are saddling up for a great cause. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Sunday, Oct. 10</TIMEX>, riders from around the region will compete for cash prizes and bragging rights at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Barrel Racing Association</ENAMEX>'s regional benefit race in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
Proceeds generated from the one-day event will benefit the Yakima Sexual Assault Advocacy Program.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This Sunday</TIMEX>'s event boasts a competition for all riders—a pee wee division for kids 10 years of age and younger, a youth division for those 18 and under, a senior division for riders over 45 and the open 4-D division. Each rider will get one shot to make his or her best ride.
"We find that this format allows all riders from novice to professional to be competitive," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Randall</ENAMEX>, past district director.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 10</TIMEX> event is an annual regional event. Funds are raised through entry fees, which are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> for the open category, plus a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> stable fee. The youth and senior division fees are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>, plus the stable fee. The pee wee division competitors will only be charged <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>. For an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> contribution riders will be able totake a practice run before the competition begins.
For funding recipients like the Sexual Assault Program, these forms of community initiatives are an important way to both raise money and build awareness.
"We are extremely grateful to be selected as the recipient for these funds," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Foley</ENAMEX>, volunteer programs coordinator. "We are always looking for creative ways to get out into the community."
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s event will take place at Van de Graaf Ranches arena on Bishop <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Road</ENAMEX>, just outside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Registration for the event opens at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> that morning. The initial exhibition run will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Cash</ENAMEX> tribute plannedfor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KENNEWICK</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy Cash</ENAMEX> will pay a tribute to his brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Cash</ENAMEX>, tomorrw, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 9</TIMEX>, at Art Fuller Auditorium at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennewick High School</ENAMEX>.
The musical performance will also include a tribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Williams</ENAMEX>, by his daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jett Williams</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s show will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>, and is being sponsored by Waymaker Ministries and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton Franklin Mounted Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s Posse.
Tickets, if purchased in advance at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chuck</ENAMEX>'s Meats at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">First</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>, are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX>. Tickets will also be available at the door <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger Berry Patch’s</ENAMEX> pumpkin festival underway now through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - The Granger Berry Patch is sponsoring its 18th annual pumpkin festival. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s theme is "On the Farm."
The festival opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday, Oct. 1</TIMEX>, and runs through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
Organizers say the straw maze, seemingly never ending, will continue to be popular with kids of all ages. Admission also includes an opportunity for festival goers to find their way through acres of corn in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>'s original cornfield maze.
Also featured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s festival is a hay fort, hay rides, a petting zoo, numerous displays of pumpkins and squash, games, contests and thousands of pumpkins for the taking. Also, as tradition dictates, pumpkin carving contests will be held each weekend throughout the month of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.
The concessions that are available each day include pumpkin cookies, bread, pies, apple cider, nachos, hotdog and burgers.
The festival will be open on the weekends from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, and weekdays from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> The price of admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.50</NUMEX> per person.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> group tours are also available weekdays by reservation.
The Granger Berry Patch is located at 1731 Beam Rd., just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

