


<P ID="1">State Senate wants mad cow disease tests for live animals
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - The Washington State Senate this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Tuesday</TIMEX> adopted Joint Memorial 8050, asking the federal government to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> money to develop a mad cow disease test that can be used on live animals.
</P><P ID="4">   Mad cow disease is the common name for bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>).
</P><P ID="5">   "Sheep can contract a similar disease called scrapie, and a live test for sheep was first developed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX>," said Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Sheahan</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>). "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX> has the knowledge, the technology and the ability to develop a test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "With a live test, we can save disease-free animals from being slaughtered.
</P><P ID="7">   "The federal government is looking at providing additional money for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> research, and this memorial asks the government to consider <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheahan</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="8">   The memorial adopted by the state senate requests federal funding to build a WSU-certified facility to create a live <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> test. In addition, it would create a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX> testing facility for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>. Currently, the nearest facility to test animals for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ames</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>. The memorial passed on a vote of 48-0.
</P><P ID="9">   "We have a great opportunity before us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheahan</ENAMEX> said. "We can develop a test that will save thousands of animals and protect ranchers, and we can build a mad cow testing facility here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX> is on the cutting edge of research. We need to take advantage of it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheahan</ENAMEX> added.
</P>   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




