
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Mabton</ENAMEX> superintendent looks forward to interpersonal contact with students, parents
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Making a full circle in her career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> is returning to make close contact with students and parents.   "I wanted to end my career where I began it, with the families and the kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>.   A native of the Republic of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Panama</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> was hired <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> to take over the leadership of the school district.   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> does not consider her role as superintendent as one of leadership, rather one of stewardship.   "I see this as a combination of leadership and service," she said, adding that she will service the families, the community and the school district staff in her new position.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> at age 17, as a young college student with aspirations of becoming a pediatrician.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Attending Barry University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miami Shores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fla.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> studied science and chemistry as a pre-med student for one year before she looked into a different field.   "I still have a great passion and love for science and math," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>. "We're all born little, natural scientists. We want to know how the world works so, we ask, 'why'."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said her aspirations of becoming a doctor ended when she fell in love.   "Pre-med and love don't mix," she said with a smile, adding that medical programs are very difficult to manage around a relationship.   She then switched her course of study to an English major with minors in history, philosophy and science.   "It was so much fun," she said.   When she graduated and it came time for her to find a job, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> was offered two jobs, one as a librarian and one as a classroom teacher, although at the time she didn't have her teaching certificate.   "I love kids," she said. "They're dynamic, they're really energizing to be around."   After a year of teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> took a year off to go back to school for her teaching certificate. It was then she had her first child.   With a strong belief that parents should be home with their children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> took time off for her second child as well, before going back to teaching.   It was while she was teaching in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Compton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> that she went back to school again to work on her Master's degree and earn her secondary accreditation.   Working in a school that was a mix of white students, black students and Hispanic students, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said she found the students didn't understand each other.   "We helped them understand that they aren't all that different," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>, adding that it was through parental involvement that they were able to break through to the students.   "That's where I fell in love with parental involvement," she explained, saying she made numerous home visits while teaching in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Compton</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Compton</ENAMEX> that she learned the importance of respect and has built it in as a non-negotiable value.   "We start with respect, end with respect and work with respect," she said.   In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX>, moving from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Compton</ENAMEX>, where literacy was the largest issue, she relocated to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, where there were huge gang problems.   She received her bilingual certification and worked with language issues in the schools.   She was a UCLA doctoral candidate and completed the entire course, but moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> to take a job with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> #105 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> before she could write her thesis.   "It was a hard decision, but all of life's good decisions are hard decisions," said the mother of three. "It was also richly rewarding."   She resigned her position as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105 director of the migrant educational regional office to take the position in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>.   With <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> worked directly with administrators, principals and teachers. Taking the position as the superintendent will put her in closer contact with students and parents.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> marks <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>' first full week in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. One of her first duties is to work with a team to hire a new elementary school principal.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

