


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsdorf</ENAMEX> one of six candidates running for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Supreme Court</ENAMEX> position
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert H. Alsdorf</ENAMEX> is one of six candidates who have filed for position one in the race for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Supreme Court</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsdorf</ENAMEX>, who has served 14 years as a King <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX> judge, is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Law School</ENAMEX> and practiced law in Seattle until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, when he became a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> justice. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsdorf</ENAMEX> was first appointed to his position as a judge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1990</TIMEX>, but was then elected to the position in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1990</TIMEX> and re-elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   During his professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">career Alsdorf</ENAMEX> has received a laundry list of awards. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, he was honored as Judge of the Year by the King <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Bar Association</ENAMEX> and was the recipient of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> Vanguard Award, an honor presented by Washington Women Voters.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsdorf</ENAMEX> is also involved in a number of professional activities, ranging from serving as an elected member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Law Institute</ENAMEX> to serving as a member of the honorary advisory committee to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps Master</ENAMEX>'s Degree Program at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daniel J. Evans School of Public Affairs</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   At this point in the race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsdorf</ENAMEX> has been endorsed by a wide variety of organizations and individuals, including the Mainstream Republicans of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, King County Young Democrats, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Council of Fire Fighters</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Labor Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsdorf</ENAMEX> was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX>, the son of missionary parents, and later worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sierra Leone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Africa</ENAMEX> as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX> volunteer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alsdorf</ENAMEX> is married to his wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah</ENAMEX>, a third grade teacher at a Seattle public school, and has two grown sons.
</P>





 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




