
<P ID="1">'Quit dieting and get moving,' advises <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> fitness expert
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Americans' passion for fad diets and an enthusiastic aversion to exercise is making them fatter, claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ogie Shaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s answer to national fitness guru <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack LaLayne</ENAMEX>.   After more than 25 years as a fitness trainer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX>, a fitness guru in his own right, has sworn off trying to get people to run, jump and do hundreds of sit-ups.   "You still aren't exercising," he told a room of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary Club</ENAMEX> members during their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> meeting.   "I can see you are not," he said. "There are a lot of you in this room who have 'furniture disease'. Your chest has slipped into your drawers," he said.   "For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 30 years</TIMEX>, we've known that we are failing basic fitness tests and yet for 30 years Americans have had the strength to resist exercise," he added.   Americans list being lazy and not having enough time as excuses as their main reasons for failing to stick to a regime of physical fitness. Others say they can't stay motivated and exercise routines are not fun.   "If it's fun you're not doing it right," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> said. "Exercise doesn't do you any good if it doesn't tire you out, if it doesn't raise your heart rate," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX>, who is the CEO of his own company, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ogie Shaw Fitness</ENAMEX>, has a prestigious list of clients, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> troops, the Portland Trail Blazers basketball team and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Seahawks</ENAMEX> football team. He has worked with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX>'s astronaut physical fitness training program and is an athlete in his own right.   "You all know what you should be doing to stay fit," he said. "But how many of you exercise a minimum of 45 minutes a day, three times a week?" he asked, nodding his head when only a few hands were raised in response.   "But all of you have gone on diets at one time or another," he noted. "Quit that," he advised. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> said since Americans decided that dieting would cure their fitness problems, the obesity rate has gone out of control.   "Dieting doesn't work," he said, saying that cutting back on food just makes a person's brain think the body is being starved.   "Dieting slows your metabolism rate, causing your body to store fat," he explained.   While blasting Americans' obsession with dieting and avoidance of exercise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> did have some suggestions for getting on the right track.   "There is an exercise program which will help you get back into shape," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> said.   Developed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> program to help astronauts keep in shape while in a zero gravity state, the gadget is a silver tube with two pulley ropes. Called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Isorobic</ENAMEX> exerciser, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> demonstrated how the exerciser uses tension and resistance to build muscle strength and improve cardiovascular tone in a simple five-minute workout.   He also encouraged the club members to make exercise, any kind of movement, a part of their daily habits, "just like brushing your teeth. Just stick to it."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> recommended the Rotarians read Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Vartabedian</ENAMEX>'s book, "Nutripoints," a book <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaw</ENAMEX> believes offers the "best information about getting proper nutrition."   "Don't diet, just eat right," he advised.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

