
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
3-5 briefly
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> noxious weed board plans review of policies
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The annual meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Noxious Weed Board</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 9</TIMEX>, in the Commissioner's Hearing Room in the basement of the Yakima County Courthouse, 128 North 2nd <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
On the board's <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> agenda will be the adoption of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> county weed policy and the announcement of the current noxious weed list.
A public hearing is also scheduled to preview the board's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> plan of operation.
The public is encouraged to attend and address their concerns about weed problems.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>      to act on bond  sale resolution
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> will hold a special meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 10</TIMEX>, in order to act on a resolution regarding the sale of bonds to be used for the construction of the district's new middle school.
The school board will meet at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at the office of instruction and learning, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Blaine</ENAMEX> building, 810 E. Custer Ave. The board is also expected to sign a purchase agreement with Seattle Northwest Securities to handle the bond sale.
Prior to its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> board meeting, the board will meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> staff on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 9</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, for dinner and a tour of the middle school.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Jr. Indelook women to meet
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Indelook Club</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 10</TIMEX>, at the home of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie Cullen</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> The program for the evening will be a presentation by an exchange student, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ella Peebles</ENAMEX>, a club spokesperson.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille Cullen</ENAMEX> will be co-hostess for the gathering.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s R.E. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell  Museum</ENAMEX> opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 16</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The R.E. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Powell Museum</ENAMEX> will open for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> season <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 16</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
The museum, located next the Bleyhl Community Library, 313 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division St.</ENAMEX>, features exhibits of Native American artifacts, war memorabilia, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> schools alumni photographs and a vast array of other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> historical items.
To arrange for a group tour call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> at 882-9219.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Weather spotter training offered
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Severe weather conditions,  such as recent hail storms and tornadoes, are likely to hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. To help it detect unusual weather patterns, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX> is hosting training for rural area Skywarn Storm Spotters.
Amateur weather watchers are being encouraged to attend a special meteorologist training  meeting to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 15</TIMEX>.
The training will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North First Street Conference Room</ENAMEX>, located in the former Pizza Hut building, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> No pre-registration is required.
Trained storm spotters will report directly to the Pendleton weather office, in order for it to issue timely warnings to protect lives and property.
For more information go to www.wrh.noaa.gov/pendleton.
</P> 
 
 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

