


<P ID="1">Starlings dropping like flies
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The colder the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> the higher the number of starlings that visit the feedlots and dairy operations to fill their bellies on the best picks of grain for the cows, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roger Woodruff</ENAMEX>, state director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   In one <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> feedlot operation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX> said there have been up to 100,000 starlings. The birds not only eat the feed, they also compete for food and nesting sights with other cavity nesting birds, including blue birds and woodpeckers, and they also cause millions of dollars in damages to the fruit industry, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "Starlings have a tremendous capability for reproduction," he said. "They can produce three broods per year and have three to five young per brood."
</P><P ID="7">   To help control the birds, which are European Starlings and not native to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> contracts with feed operations to bait the birds with an avicide called <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">DRC</ENAMEX> 1339. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX> said that he could not legally identify the feedlot where the birds have been baited.
</P><P ID="8">   The chemical, which was described by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX> as "very selective," was developed several years ago and has virtually no secondary hazards to other animals when used properly.
</P><P ID="9">   "It's primarily used in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> time when birds come to the feedlots to feed," he said.
</P><P ID="10">   The starlings migrate out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> and feed across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state. In the baiting process, the birds are poisoned at the feedlots and die within 24 hours.
</P><P ID="11">   "This toxicant is called fast-acting. Typically most birds, once they've ingested this, they'll die on the roost," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX>. "They pretty much go to sleep and don't wake up."
</P><P ID="12">   The problem is many of the birds root in trees along Mabton-Alderwood Highway at about milepost #5.
</P><P ID="13">   Neighbors living along that stretch of road know exactly which years the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> contracts with local feedlots because they end up with hundreds of dead birds and questions on who to contact to clean them up.
</P><P ID="14">   Four days after the birds died at his mother's house, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Stearns</ENAMEX> found the proper people to contact to clean up the dead bird carcasses at his mother's house.
</P><P ID="15">   His nephew, who lives across the road from his mother, has children and decided to clean up the birds himself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stearns</ENAMEX> said. His nephew picked up 475 birds in his yard.
</P><P ID="16">   As a part of the contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX>, feeding operations are required to send workers out to clean up the dead animals, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX>, but often those living along Mabton-Alderwood Highway don't know who to call.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX> said the health department is contacted when the birds are baited and he said in the future there is a possibility that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> will also contact home owners in the area where the birds roost and die.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve ETorchon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van de Graaf Ranches</ENAMEX> said that his feedlot operation contracted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> to bait the birds.
</P><P ID="19">   "When they come in they're in a swarm," he said. "They're like a small black cloud. It's unbelievable."
</P><P ID="20">   He said the birds eat an incredible amount of feed and leave a mess behind.
</P><P ID="21">   "We're doing a public service," he said.
</P><P ID="22">   On dairies and feedlots, the birds can eat up to half their body weight in a day, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   "They can eat tons of feed per day," he said, adding that they peck out all of the protein pellets in the feed, which causes beef weight to taper off.
</P><P ID="24">   For those with dead birds on their property, they can call the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> district office in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> to have clean-up crews come and dispose of the dead birds. The district office can be reached at (509) 765-7962.
</P><P ID="25">   For those who pick up the dead birds themselves, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Woodruff</ENAMEX> suggests they wear gloves and dispose of the animals in trash bags. He said washing up after disposing of the animals is essential.
</P><P ID="26">   "I don't encourage people to clean them up, themselves," he added.
</P>   
<P ID="27">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="28">Webmaster
</P><P ID="29">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




