
<P ID="1">Mabton grid team tethers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Goats</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PATEROS</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros Billy Goats</ENAMEX> were undefeated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> play heading into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s football game against visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>. They no longer are.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> bullied the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Goats</ENAMEX> enroute to scoring a 35-17 conference victory.   "It was big," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Coach D.J</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "We out-physicaled them.   "The coaches and kids did a good of watching film <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. We were all confident we were going to be more physical than them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> credits his offensive and defensive lines for taking control of the game. "Both lines played outstanding," he said.   Defensively, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> limited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros</ENAMEX> to just 86 rushing yards. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Goats</ENAMEX> did gain about 150 yards through the air, although the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros QB</ENAMEX>, Zahn, was picked once. The interception was claimed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> free safety <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Harris</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros</ENAMEX> employed a spread offense against his club, often times using pro sets in the backfield.   "We just played assignment defense against them," he said. "We stayed in our 5-3 defense, except on 3rd and long plays when we jumped into something else.   "We were very physical against them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> added. "Our whole defense did their job. They came to play. Tackling was very good."   Offensively, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>' line was just as physical, which resulted in some large holes being opened for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s running backs. The Vikes' leading ground gainers were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pablo Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Zavala</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Elizondo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> tallied 108 yards on the ground on 13 carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> scooted for 93 yards on 10 totes, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizondo</ENAMEX> ran the ball 11 times for 61 yards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton QB Ryan Harris</ENAMEX> didn't have to air it out much <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. He only attempted nine passes, completing three of them for 80 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> had two of the receptions, accouting for 72 of the 80 passing yards.   The Vikes opened a 14-0 lead on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros</ENAMEX> with two first quarter scores. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> had the first TD, that coming on a 61-yard breakaway run. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> had a 2-yard dive for the second touchdown.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros</ENAMEX> countered with a 39-yard TD pass late in the opening quarter to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s lead to 14-6.   The Vikes responded in the second quarter, though, punching in two more touchdowns to build their lead to 28-6. Jovanni Ochoa, on his only carry of the game because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>'s helmet was broken, scored the first of the two TD's on a 3-yard plunge. The other touchdown came on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>'s second score of the night, a 9-yard scamper.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros</ENAMEX> closed the gap to 28-10 just before the half on a 28-yard field goal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> added an insurance score in the third quarter when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> broke loose and raced 16 yards for a TD. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Zepeda</ENAMEX> followed up the touchdown with his fifth consecutive successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAT</ENAMEX> kick of the night.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Goats</ENAMEX> got a second TD pass from Zahn in the final quarter to account for the final 35-17 score.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>'s win improved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Central</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> record to 4-2, 5-2 overall. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> are scheduled to play a non-league game at Highland (3-4) this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pateros</ENAMEX> slipped to 4-1 in conference play with the loss, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Goats</ENAMEX> still have to play league leading <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX> (5-0).      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

