


<P ID="1">Former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> history teacher visits <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX> 
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Galbraith</ENAMEX> spent 32 years teaching Russian history, and this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past spring</TIMEX> he was able to experience the country first-hand as he and his wife traveled on a boat tour from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> shared his experiences and thoughts on the trip with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Having traveled extensively through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Europe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said he has seen the picture perfect sites of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX> you can buy lots of postcards and none of them are picture perfect," he said.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> and his wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX> first became interested in the adventure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this year</TIMEX> when family members said they would be taking a cruise along the rivers from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>. When the relatives had to back out at the last minute, the Galbraiths still made the journey.
</P><P ID="9">   Arriving at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> airport, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said he was not very impressed with the facility. The city, he added, which was built in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1703</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> the Great, was drab looking.
</P><P ID="10">   "All I saw was high rise apartment building after high rise apartment building and lots of traffic," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   A city of 5 million people, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> has no freeways. The largest road was three lanes. He added that all of the streets are in bad shape.
</P><P ID="12">   While in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> visited the Peterhof, a palace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> the Great commissioned the building of, beginning in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1703</TIMEX>. The palace is currently being restored following it destruction during World War II.
</P><P ID="13">   The gardens are filled with fountains, all of which operate on a gravity flow system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said there was gold leave and gilt throughout the grounds.
</P><P ID="14">   Leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX> by boat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said the river cruise included guides and experts who provided the tourists with the history and culture of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   They were also entertained with folkloric performances.
</P><P ID="16">   One of the speakers on the boat was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PhD</ENAMEX> professor, who shared some of his independent findings when polling the Russian people for his government.
</P><P ID="17">   Interestingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said, the Russian people like their current leader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vladimir Putin</ENAMEX> the best. Second best was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Stalin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   "That should probably tell you that Russians are probably not going to embrace democracy for another generation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   Navigating the Russian rivers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said the rivers were lined with endless timber.
</P><P ID="20">   "Lumbering is evident," he said, "but all of the logs are very small."
</P><P ID="21">   He said that along the river he would see small villages, often only eight to 12 houses large with little or no access to the outside world. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said they are self-sufficient, living off the land without running water or electricity.
</P><P ID="22">   One common thing among Russians living in the country-side, he said, was the presence of "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Victory Gardens</ENAMEX>." He said the gardens were up to half an acre in size, and make up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">54 percent</NUMEX> of all Russian agriculture.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> also visited the Russian national museum, which he said was filled with the works of great painters, but not the ones you see in the history books.
</P><P ID="24">   There were Picassos and Rembrandts, he said. There were also numerous works of modern art.
</P><P ID="25">   He also visited the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter and Paul Fortress</ENAMEX> and attended church there.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said that before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> of communism there were about five churches in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Petersburg</ENAMEX>. There are now 150. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>, a city of more than 10 million people, there were 15 churches before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> of communism, now there are about 500.
</P><P ID="27">   "There are no seats in Russian churches," he said. "The churches are for individual worship. You go in and stand next to whichever icon you prefer and worship."
</P><P ID="28">   He said that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX> is known for its icons.
</P><P ID="29">   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> visited Red Square and Gum, a "glorified shopping mall."
</P><P ID="30">   Preparing for their independence celebration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said that portions of Red Square were sectioned off.
</P><P ID="31">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galbraith</ENAMEX> said that the most repairs he saw to the buildings was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="32">   "They pay close attention to anything with historical significance because that's what the tourists want to see," he said.
</P><P ID="33">   He said there were actually very few Russians shopping at Gum. "They can't afford to," he said, explaining that earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX></NUMEX> in American dollars each year makes for a pretty good living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="34">Webmaster
</P><P ID="35">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




