
<P ID="1">Local girl's art published in Sesame Street magazine
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has a new, nationally recognized artist.   The latest of nationally recognized artists just happens to be 6-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anikka Campbell</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s artwork is featured in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> edition of the "Sesame Street" magazine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s drawing can be seen on the first page of a section called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bird</ENAMEX>'s Fridge. This monthly section showcases drawings sent in by children.   "They say they get quite a large volume (of drawings)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s mom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>.   The drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> submitted to "Sesame Street" was of her walking her dog, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly</ENAMEX>, a golden lab, on a sunny day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> submitted the drawing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> to the magazine. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> said she drew the piece when she was interested in dogs. Now her love for drawing has turned to horses.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> said her daughter has been drawing and coloring pictures since she was 4 years of age and considers herself pretty good at the skill. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> can be found drawing just about everywhere she goes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX>'s mom said she always takes her drawing kits with her when traveling in the car.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> said that her daughter likes to say she is good at a couple of things, those being drawing and running fast.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> said her daughter was very surprised when she learned a few weeks ago that "Sesame Street" magazine was going to publish her drawing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> said her daughter was also a bit embarrassed when she found out that her drawing was going to be in the magazine.   "She said she didn't want everyone to make a fuss about it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> said she is proud of her daughter's accomplishments by getting her drawing published in a national magazine.   "I think it is a good reinforcement for her," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>. "She doesn't like a lot of attention."   The 6-year-old said she plans to continue drawing and might even submit some more pieces of her work to various magazines.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daily News   Anikka Campbell</ENAMEX> is now a nationally recognized artist. Her work can be found on the opening page of a section called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bird</ENAMEX>'s Fridge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>'s edition of the "Sesame Street" magazine.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

