
<P ID="1">Asst. principal cites need for pre-school classes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School Assistant Principal Diann Zavala</ENAMEX> presented the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> with a report <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> about implementing a pre-school program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> told the school board pre-school can serve as an important tool for preventing literacy problems in students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> cited many risk factors in the area concerning delaying early literacy development. One of the major issues is poverty. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s elementary students qualify for free or reduced lunches. She also said that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of the district's kindergarten students need classes to learn English. A total of 196 out of 490 kindergarten students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> come from a home where Spanish is the dominant language.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> also pointed out several risk factors for children involving parents. Based on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> census, for participants 25 years of age and older, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52 percent</NUMEX> of Hispanic females and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> of Hispanic males have less than a ninth grade education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> also pointed out that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> females and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">46 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> males in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> have less than a ninth grade education. Only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> of Hispanic males and females in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> have a four-year degree based on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> census. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> females and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anglo</ENAMEX> males have a four-year degree.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> said the more education parents have the better off their child will do in school, and especially in literacy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> cited research that showed a 4-year-old child from a family whose mother has a college degree has more vocabulary than an adult who is on federal assistance. A 4-year-old child whose mother has a college education has been exposed to 45 million words. A 4-year-old child who comes from a household in poverty has only been exposed to 13 million words.   "We are at a very high risk for early literacy delays," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX>.   It is important for children to develop their language skills early on, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> read a rather dismal figure to the school board about how <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of first grade students who are considered poor readers will have no improved reading skills by the end of the fourth grade.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> said there is a need for additional pre-school programs in the community. There are numerous pre-school programs offered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, serving a total of 345 4-year-old children. EPIC has the largest preschool enrollment with 150 children. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> serves another 72 children with Calvary Lutheran serving another 58.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> cited a list of 114 pre-school migrant age children who are not receiving any kind of educational services.   "There definitely is a need in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> (for additional pre-school programs)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> said after the school board meeting that she is researching the possibility of providing pre-school for all 4-year-old children in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>. Currently, the district serves developmentally delayed pre-school children in a set of portables behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX>. The district will be moving those classrooms around to each of the elementary schools <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> said the 3-and-4-year-old children in those classes face a variety of learning problems, but more dominantly language development issues.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> said it is her hope the district continues to explore implementing a pre-school program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> said a pre-school transition class can help address some of the learning issues, such as language development, that teachers are having to deal with. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> said the main obstacle in implementing a pre-school program is funding.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

