


<P ID="1">Candidate withdraws from city council consideration
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The field of candidates for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> seat vacated earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> has narrowed by one. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 30</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> withdrew his name from the running.
</P><P ID="5">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> had no comment on why he decided to withdraw from consideration for the city council position.
</P><P ID="6">   In a letter addressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> and members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> wrote: "I saw the opportunity to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> here recently as a chance to fulfill my personal objectives. But, there are jobs where one can't cross their personal and professional life and I have one of those."
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX>, who works as a reporter for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, wrote that he has a lot of respect for city council and what each member goes through, adding that he also has a lot of respect for the "...integrity of the journalism industry."
</P><P ID="8">   "Personally, I would love to serve the community on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>, but I can't wear two hats," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> wrote. "And I happen to like the one I wear now as a journalist for our wonderful community."
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX>'s withdrawal that he appreciates his desire to serve his community.
</P><P ID="10">   "He had determined that elected office will not work for him at this time, but I am confident that he will find other ways to assist this community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   The remaining candidates for the position are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Drysdale</ENAMEX>, Ermenejildo Rodriguez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> will interview each of the remaining candidates during a special session set to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX> in the council chambers. Following the public meeting, council members will go into executive session to discuss their decision.
</P><P ID="13">   The candidate selected to fill the position will then have to seek election to the office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to finish out the remainder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>'s four-year term.
</P><P ID="14">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




