
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> decides on uses for I-728 monies
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/29/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> decided this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on how to spend the money it receives from the state as part of Initiative 728.   I-728 was overwhelmingly supported by state voters, passing with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">72 percent</NUMEX> approval rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2000</TIMEX>. The purpose of the money is to provide additional funding to help students reach new academic standards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> pointed out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that districts more often than not have to use I-728 money to supplement other areas that the state has reduced funding in.   Every school district in the state is required to annually hold a public meeting to receive comments on what to do with I-728 funds.   There are strict uses for I-728 dollars. The monies may be used to reduce class sizes in grades kindergarten through fourth. Money may also be used to make selected class size reductions in grades five through 12. The state funding may also be used to provide extended learning opportunities for students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Dave Plesha</ENAMEX> said I-728 monies may also be used to provide professional development for educators and make improvements or additions to school facilities that assist in reducing class size and extending learning opportunities.   The money for funding voter-approved I-728 comes from state property tax and any excess funds from the state's emergency reserve. Next school year will also be the final year funding comes from state lottery sales.   When the state started allocating I-728 funds to school districts during the 2001-02 school year, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$194</NUMEX> per student. Next school year, the district will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$254</NUMEX> per student. Plesha said that is far less than the projected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$450</NUMEX> per student districts were expected to receive from the state <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. He also said the district could receive even less money depending on state funding situations.   Plesha presented the board with an outline of how he wants to use the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX> the district is expected to receive in I-728 funding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. Plesha has set aside <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$672,783</NUMEX> to assist in the reduction of class sizes at all grades throughout the district. He has also increased the amount of funds each building principal receives for professional development from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$87,000</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX></NUMEX>. Plesha has also set aside <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$404,277</NUMEX> to assist in professional development for district staff during inservice days. Another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> has been allocated for extended learning opportunities, such as after-school programs. Plesha said there is another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$152,000</NUMEX> sitting in a pool that can be used for indirect costs, such as extended day opportunities and field trips. Plesha said additional monies could go to these programs if there is any unused funds left from other areas.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Linde</ENAMEX> provided the lone public comment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. She said she wanted to see the district use the I-728 funds to reduce class sizes even further. She also wanted more funds for teacher development.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> directors approved Plesha's plan of spending.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> board member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wells</ENAMEX> expressed some concern about the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$152,000</NUMEX> the district has reserved for indirect costs, such as field trips. The issue <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> had was he didn't like seeing that much money allocated for programs such as field trips. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said he sees the value in field trips and other learning enhancement programs outside the classroom. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said he feels students aren't spending enough time in the classroom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said he wants to discuss the issue even more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, but added the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$152,000</NUMEX> should go into other areas like reducing class size.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

