
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library to host storyteller
Storyteller and actress <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Dimitre</ENAMEX> will bring to life the stories of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pocahontas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sacajawea</ENAMEX> and Angeline—Chief Seattle's daughter—during a special dramatic presentation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July 21</TIMEX>.
Children and adults of all ages are invited to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> presentation.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dimitre</ENAMEX>, a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Storytellers Guild</ENAMEX>, brings to life women and young girls in history through dramatic storytelling, folklore, legends and poetry. Her hour-long program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library is free of charge, and is appropriate for all school-age children and adults.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> names honor roll students
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - Several Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> students have been named to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> spring quarter honor roll.
To earn that distinction, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> students had to earn at least a 3.50 grade point average while carrying at least 12 graded credit hours of study.
The academic achievers include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabitha Sanders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackie Morrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Kinsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramirez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiffanie Bodine</ENAMEX>; Outlook's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Bryant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David McCardle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenton Barry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelli Plooster</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Rivard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon Pierce</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fabian Partida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terri Marrs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Panton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo Martinez</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">REC boardto meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 27</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX> will be the site of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 27</TIMEX>, meeting of the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> board of directors.
The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 p.m.</TIMEX> meeting is open to the public.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

