
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca</ENAMEX> announcement leaves state's asparagus industry on life support
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">This is asparagus season in the Yakima and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Walla Walla</ENAMEX> river valleys. The region's rich soil and perfect growing conditions have produced another bumper crop of high-quality asparagus destined for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s dinner tables.   Despite that, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 million</NUMEX> a year asparagus industry is in jeopardy. It may even be on its death bed.   On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 3</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca Foods Corporation</ENAMEX> announced that, after 70 years in operation, it will close its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dayton</ENAMEX>, asparagus packing plant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. The news followed a decision by General Mills, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca</ENAMEX>'s largest customer, to begin importing its asparagus from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Peru</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca Foods</ENAMEX> is the third and final asparagus canner to shut its doors in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> in less than a year, following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Del Monte</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiquita</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Walla Walla</ENAMEX>.   In fact since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s asparagus farm lands have shrunk from 30,000 acres to 15,000. Another 1,700 acres are being plowed under since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Del Monte Foods</ENAMEX> moved its asparagus processing line to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Peru</ENAMEX>, along with 350 jobs.   But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca</ENAMEX> announcement is different. The company's plant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dayton</ENAMEX> is the world's largest asparagus processing facility, employing more than 1,000 seasonal workers, 50 full-time employees, and providing growers with more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> in annual revenues.   In other words, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seneca</ENAMEX> is to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dayton</ENAMEX> what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> is to Seattle.   This crisis has nothing to do with growing conditions, urban sprawl or plant diseases; it has to do with several well-intentioned federal and state policies that are combining to kill an entire industry.   One of those policies is the Andean Trade Preference Act. Part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s war on drugs, the Act was supposed to get Andean farmers to switch from growing coca leaves - the base for cocaine - to other crops, such as asparagus. As an incentive, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> agreed to a zero tariff on Peruvian asparagus imports.   Unfortunately, the agreement was doomed to fail because asparagus and coca are grown in two very different regions. Instead of switching from coca to asparagus, Peruvians are now growing both crops. And since the Andean agreement allows Peruvian asparagus to enter the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> without tariffs, it undercuts our crops at supermarkets.   According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">General Accounting Office</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this 1991</TIMEX> act has not stemmed coca production, but has put asparagus growers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Michigan</ENAMEX> at risk.   Along with federal trade policy, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s minimum wage law is also helping to kill this labor intensive industry. Our state's growers and processors must pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.16</NUMEX> per hour - the highest starting wage in the nation, which automatically escalates each year. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Peru</ENAMEX>, workers get <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> per day.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the Washington State Legislature must step in if our state's asparagus industry is to be saved.   First, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Commerce</ENAMEX> should impose a tariff on Peruvian asparagus. It could do so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> if it wanted to. It has done just that for powerful sugar and wheat interests, but has turned a deaf ear to the pleas of asparagus growers. Our Congressional delegation should put pressure on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commerce Department</ENAMEX> to ensure fair treatment for American asparagus growers.   Secondly, lawmakers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> must change our state's minimum wage law. Because our minimum wage automatically increases each year, it continually widens the gap between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and the rest of the world. Legislators should freeze the wage at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.16</NUMEX> until the rest of the country catches up, and tie future increases to economic conditions in agriculture and other industries where labor costs are especially sensitive.   Asparagus growers are not asking for special treatment, just fair treatment. But an entire industry in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is in danger of collapse unless elected officials in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. act quickly.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don C. Brunell</ENAMEX> is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

