


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EUGENE PATRICK CHARVET JR</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">EUGENE PATRICK CHARVET JR.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Patrick Charvet Jr.</ENAMEX>, 75, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> went to be with his Lord and Savior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, March 25, 2004</TIMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Regional Hospital</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5, 1929</TIMEX> at the family home, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Edna</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlson</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene Patrick Charvet</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> received his grade school education from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sacred Heart School</ENAMEX> in Seattle, middle school from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brisco School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kent</ENAMEX>, and secondary school from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">O’Day High School</ENAMEX> in Seattle, receiving a degree in theology and music from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Martin’s College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacey</ENAMEX>, in three years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> served for two years in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, receiving his basic training at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Ord</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, then was stationed and served at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Alamos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> spent seven years at the Trappist Monastery Guadalupe at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lafayette</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> He was sent home by the Abbot of the Trappist to care for his parents and brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX>. He took his assignment to heart and cared for his family very well and faithfully.
</P>

<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> became a strong part of the Fabric of the Blessed Sacrament Parish of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, a part of the establishment To Say! He attended daily <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX>, taught <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCD</ENAMEX>, baptish, confirmation and marriage preparation classes, along with helping with daily <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mass. Eugene</ENAMEX> was like a sacristan, performing many duties at different times, like typing the church bulletin, playing organ, and piano, directing and singing in the choir. He was on the Bishops <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Religious Education Council</ENAMEX> and was selected to be the representative from the Yakima Diocese to attend the religious convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knights</ENAMEX> of Columbus and went through all the chairs, serving as Grand Knight and also served as financial secretary for many years. He was a life member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth Degree Honor Guard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fourth Degree Knights</ENAMEX> of Columbus. He became a Eucharistic minister distributing communion, reading scriptures and giving faith and hope to the sick and shut-ins.
</P>

<P ID="9">He played the piano for the residents in most of the nursing homes in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> spent time ministering at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> jail. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> was recognized at the Yakima Diocese Fifty-Year Celebration for his self-selected duties at the parish, jail, nursing homes, shut-ins and much more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> was very helpful to all the priests that served at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, preparing for daily <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> and anything that was needed. Monsignor McDonnell was a very special friend to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> also headed up the Legion of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mary</ENAMEX>. He made many rosaries, said the rosary and meditated over each one before it was given with love. He was deeply devoted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> and prayed the Rosary and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Divine Office</ENAMEX> daily.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> was a bookkeeper for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Top Side Canning Company</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">R. H. Jones</ENAMEX>. He farmed hops for a period of time and kept books for the family farm.
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> loved sharing his time and talent of music with the sick and those in need. No one, but the Lord, will know how many lives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> touched in so many ways.
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eugene</ENAMEX> is survived by one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Waddle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest Charvet</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; one special aunt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Carlson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Healy</ENAMEX> of Seattle; one sister-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; 27 nieces and nephews; and numerous great nieces and nephews.
</P>

<P ID="13">He was preceded in death by his parents; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josie Healy</ENAMEX>; three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosella</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tommy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry</ENAMEX>; one sister-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Charvet</ENAMEX>; one brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Waddle</ENAMEX>; and five nephews.
</P>

<P ID="14">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 29, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Recitation of the Holy Rosary will be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 30, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at Mabton Cemetery, under the direction of Jones Funeral Home. Those wishing to honor his memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seminary Fund</ENAMEX> at the Diocese of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> at 5301-A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tieton</ENAMEX> Dr., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98908.
</P>

 


<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MYRTIE VIRGINIA SHAW</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtie Virginia Shaw</ENAMEX>, 70, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> went to be in the arms of her Savior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 26, 2004</TIMEX>, from her home.
</P>

<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtie</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2, 1933</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Celina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenn.</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattie McAppen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clurie Albert Strong</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtie</ENAMEX> received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Shaw</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX>. Following their marriage they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>, then back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX>. Her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard</ENAMEX>, died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. She later moved to Flordia in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> before settling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtie</ENAMEX> enjoyed yard sales, her canine companion, Little Bit, gardening, flowers and spending time with her grandchildren and great-grandchildren.
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtie</ENAMEX> is survived by two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JoAnn Pierce</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Shaw</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Lee Swails</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Swails</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; 14 grandchildren and numerous great-grandchildren; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Strong</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kentucky</ENAMEX>. She is also survived by her significant other, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Bueno</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="19">She was preceded in death by her parents; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Shaw</ENAMEX>; one grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Michael Swails</ENAMEX>; one great-grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Antonio Munoz Jr.</ENAMEX>; three brothers and two sisters.
</P>

<P ID="20">Viewing and visitation were held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 28, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 29, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> until time of funeral at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




