


<P ID="1">County voters lean toward Republican candidates
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Of the votes counted county-wide in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election, more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.9 percent</NUMEX> were cast for Republican candidates.
</P><P ID="5">   Incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> emerged victorious in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s primary election after beating out fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican Judy Boekholder</ENAMEX>, also of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>, who collected <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43.6 percent</NUMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s Republican ballots, narrowly pushed ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boekholder</ENAMEX>, who also sought the district #2 commissioner seat.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boekholder</ENAMEX> collected 816 votes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>'s 1,087 votes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election in early returns.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX> will now face <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul George</ENAMEX>, a Democrat, who beat out fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Wylie G. Mills</ENAMEX> with a vote of 1,439 to 501, winning the right to challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camay</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Commission District</ENAMEX> #1 candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leita</ENAMEX> beat out two fellow Republicans, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Dell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Frank Hendrix</ENAMEX>, while collecting <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45.5 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> votes cast for Republican candidates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> will face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Earl S. Lee</ENAMEX>, who ran unopposed in the primary election.
</P><P ID="10">   In the race to see which <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> attorney will replace Judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Van Nuys</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> bench, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine George Gibson</ENAMEX> will face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Tait</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> in the non-partisan race. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> collected 6,209 votes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX> received 5,417 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Bruns</ENAMEX>, who also sought the judgeship, received 3,478 votes.
</P><P ID="11">   In congressional races, incumbent Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> (R) will face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Matheson</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tri-Cities Democrat</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>'s election. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, voters gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> 9,401 votes while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheson</ENAMEX> received 3,380 votes for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56.3 percent</NUMEX> of the Democratic vote. She beat out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard K. Wright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Mason</ENAMEX> to advance to the general election.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> legislators <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, who ran unopposed, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> each advance to the general election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following yesterday</TIMEX>'s election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, who earned 2,371 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> votes, will face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Michael H. Kepcha</ENAMEX>, who collected 1,482 votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   In the state governor's race, state Attorney General <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Gregoire</ENAMEX> (D) will face <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> in the general election.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> beat out her nearest opponent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Sims</ENAMEX>, to advance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> faced two Republicans to earn the right to advance to the general election.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> voters gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> 7,673 votes while county Democrats gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX> 4,331 votes over the other Democratic candidates.
</P><P ID="16">   In the statewide race to see who will challenge <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> (D) in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George R. Nethercutt Jr.</ENAMEX> (R) received his party's approval to advance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> collected <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84.1 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Republican</ENAMEX> votes while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> garnered 6,048 of her party's votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




