
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> school superintendent puts vehicle bids on hold
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> approved a bid to purchase two vehicles for the Migrant Student Records System (MSRS) program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, though, put a hold on the bid. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> was unable to be at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s school board meeting because of a personal commitment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said until he can get some more clarification on what happened with the bid process for the vehicles, he is putting the issue on hold.   "(The) bid (is) on hold until we can review it with legal counsel and the state auditor," said Bones <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.   The issue concerns the district purchasing two vehicles for the MSRS program, which would in turn lease the cars from the school district. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> is the fiscal agent for the MSRS program. MSRS program workers travel all over the state to aid migrant students. MSRS Director Lee Campos wants to purchase the vehicles because it will be less expensive than paying his staff a mileage stipend.   The school district received three bids for the vehicles, one from Toyota of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, another from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel Ford</ENAMEX> and a third from the state vehicle bid process through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris Ford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX>.   The bid from Toyota of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> for each vehicle was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,195</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>'s had a significantly less bid of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,212</NUMEX> per car while the state bid from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris Ford</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,429</NUMEX>.   The school board went with the recommendation of Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Finance</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Plesha</ENAMEX> to purchase two, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Camrys from Toyota of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> he will be reviewing the entire bid process for the vehicles again before any final decision is made.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

