


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> says no to Dr. King holiday
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/7/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> has long been known for standing alone on several issues. Add another item to the list for the local governing body.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> refused to take action this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to have the city recognize Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Luther King Jr. Day</TIMEX> as a legal holiday.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> made the motion to have the federally recognized holiday in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> as a legal holiday in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Currently, all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> employees work on Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Luther King Jr. Day</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> also holds meetings on the same day.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> brought the issue before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in hopes the body would designate it as a legal holiday so employees could be with their families. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is one of very few municipalities in the state that doesn't recognize the holiday.
</P><P ID="9">   But about the only support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> found in her efforts came from Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   The motion to have Dr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Martin Luther Jr. Day</TIMEX> recognized as a legal holiday in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> failed convincingly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> due to the lack of a second motion from any councilman.
</P><P ID="11">   Prior to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> failing to take formal action on the holiday, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> acknowledged the city does recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Luther King Jr. Day</TIMEX> as a holiday with a proclamation and other events. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she simply felt city staff and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> should have the holiday off like everyone else. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> even wanted to see the day turned into an opportunity where citizens could come together and volunteer with different community projects.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, but differed on who should and shouldn't have the day off. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he felt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> shouldn't hold meetings on the holiday. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said there really isn't anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> can do to assist city employees. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said the matter of which days are recognized holidays is something that is negotiated with the different employee bargaining units.
</P><P ID="13">   None of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members offered a comment when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> asked for a second on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s motion.
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




