


<P ID="1">Local dentist honored for work with low-income children
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Walking into the under-sea themed office at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spavinaw Dental Center</ENAMEX> children are at ease as they prepare to have their teeth checked.
</P><P ID="5">   Immediately put at ease with the peaceful surroundings, it's the wall of pictures of smiling children that catch the eye of visitors. The wall displays patients who are cavity free. Every one of the pictures is of kids, who have learned good dental health from their friendly dentist, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregory Norell</ENAMEX>, who at 6'5" has been described as a "gentle giant" who uses humor and charisma to charm his young patients.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX>, the owner of the clinic, focuses on children's dental health, which is why he is being honored in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this month</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX>, 38, will receive the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Plate of Bounty Award at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Migrant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seasonal</ENAMEX> Head <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Start Conference</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. The award will be presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexican Embassy</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "The Plate of Bounty award is given each year to the persons in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> who have made outstanding contributions to their communities and specifically to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seasonal</ENAMEX> Head <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Start</ENAMEX> program," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manda Lopez</ENAMEX>, executive director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Migrant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seasonal</ENAMEX> Head <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Start Association</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX> has been working closely with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPIC</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Enterprise</ENAMEX> for Progress in the Community) Head <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Start</ENAMEX>, providing dental check-ups, fluoride and sealants at the Head <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Start</ENAMEX> centers from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> and many communities in the Columbia Basin. Most of the children he serves at the centers are low-income or disabled.
</P><P ID="10">   "I love going out to the day cares and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> centers," he said. "People are less pretensive."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX> said the idea to visit the different Head <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Start</ENAMEX> sites came after speaking to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barb Williams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> health coordinator.
</P><P ID="12">   "She wanted something simple, other than having the kids come to the office, which isn't very effective," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   He was nominated for the Plate of Bounty award by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Weiss Standley</ENAMEX>, health and nutrition program manager for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EPIC</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX>, who mostly treats children, estimates that about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of his patients are low-income children and their families.
</P><P ID="15">   He said he saw a high need for dental care for children in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> and especially those who are from low-income families.
</P><P ID="16">   "It makes me feel like I'm filling a role," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX>. "I'm proud to accept this on the behalf of my office."
</P><P ID="17">   A native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oklahoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX> graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southern Nazarene University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bethany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oklahoma</ENAMEX> with a degree in biology in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>. He worked for a biotechnology company, in a laboratory and in the sales field for several years before he was encouraged by friends to pursue a degree in dentistry. He attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oklahoma College of Dentistry</ENAMEX>, which he graduated from in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, the same year he opened a practice in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX> realized there was a need in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> to provide dental services to low income and migrant families in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and surrounding areas," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clydine Norell</ENAMEX>, wife of Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX>, in a biography she wrote on her husband.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norell</ENAMEX> helped develop the SmileSavers program, which is run by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Dental Foundation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, before opening his office in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   He is also the owner of Eastway Dental.
</P>   
<P ID="21">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




