
<P ID="1">Obtiuaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">GAYLORD <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MANNING FREEPONS
GAYLORD MANNING FREEPONS
 Gaylord Manning Freepons</ENAMEX>, 80, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 1, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1924</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Walla Walla</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest T. Freepons</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Johnson</ENAMEX>) Freepons. He attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Chapel Elementary School</ENAMEX>. After completing the eight grade he attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walla Walla High School</ENAMEX>. After graduating he worked on the family farm and briefly attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 4, 1949</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Murchland</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Baptist Church</ENAMEX>. Together they raised seven children, and developed many acres of productive farmland.
He is survived by his wife of 55 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Freepons</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>) Coombs of Fielding, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alys</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>) Means of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>; five sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jody</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phil</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX>) Freepons, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>; 15 grandchildren; two great-grandchildren; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Freepons Norman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>; one sister-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bette Freepons Fread</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Walla Walla</ENAMEX>; numerous nieces and nephews.
He was preceded in death by his parents; an infant sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Virginia</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marion</ENAMEX>; and three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX>.
An open house will be held for family and friends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 13, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> at 1114 Colena St., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>. In lieu of flowers, memorial contributions can be made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Muscular Dystrophy Association</ENAMEX>, 101 W. Indiana Ave., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 99205 or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser High School Future Farmers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX>), 1203 Prosser Ave., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 99350.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ESTHER  LOIS SHOCKLEY
Esther Lois Shockley</ENAMEX>, 91, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 2, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
She was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1913</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> and Elta (Sparks) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muir</ENAMEX>. She attended grade school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maple Grove School</ENAMEX> and completed her education in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1, 1931</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford I. Shockley</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. They farmed in the Outlook area. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> they moved to the Tri-Cities, where they continued farming. She worked in retail at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Haskins</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">J.C</ENAMEX>. Penney and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sears</ENAMEX>.
She is survived by two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beverly Newhouse</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole Plunkitt</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Warmenhoven</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornie</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>; one brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Shockley</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline</ENAMEX>) of Outlook; seven grandchildren; 12 great-grandchildren.
She was preceded in death by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Shockley</ENAMEX>; her parents; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leta Travaille</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verna Belcher</ENAMEX>; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buster</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Muir</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 5, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 6, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 6, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at Wells Funeral Home. Burial will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Memorials may be made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Brethren Church Missions Program</ENAMEX>. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">STEVE J. EVANS
Steve J. Evans</ENAMEX>, 50, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was called home to his Savior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 30, 2004</TIMEX>, due to an apparent heart attack while enjoying his favorite pastime, hunting.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11, 1954</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Paul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jayne LaClaire</ENAMEX> (Skold) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlyn Wayne Evans</ENAMEX>. He received his high school diploma from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colville High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1973 to 1976</TIMEX> with the 101 Airborne Divisions at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Campbell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ky.</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> started his employment with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>. He graduated from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Police Academy</ENAMEX> returning to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>., where he served as a patrolman, a detective and was active on the H.E.A.T Team. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was very instrumental in getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>. accredited. He was a DARE/GREAT teacher and one of his favorite projects was obtaining and restoring a car for the DARE program. He was the Explorer post advisor and advanced hunter educator instructor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was also active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> as a volunteer and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMT</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8, 2001</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawna Page</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where they made their home.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> enjoyed camping, the outdoors, hunting, fishing, fly tying, reloading shells, working in his yard, designing and building projects, and restoring old cars. He was a Civil War buff.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawna</ENAMEX>; daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MacKenzie Lynn</ENAMEX> (Tinky Butt) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Evans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Federal Way</ENAMEX>, and daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Evans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">James Town</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.D</ENAMEX>.; one grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coven Mikel Evans</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by his mother and stepfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim and Jayne Northrup</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colville</ENAMEX>;  his mother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Page</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Evans</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicki</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>; three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Bylsma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Austin</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Monroe</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Clark</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">James</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>; one stepbrother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Northrup</ENAMEX> of Seattle; two stepsisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Evans</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candy Acevedo</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil</ENAMEX>), of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>; his brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Page</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and numerous nieces and nephews.
He was preceded in death by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merlyn Wayne Evans</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 5, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 6, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Military graveside services will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  In lieu of flowers, those wishing to honor Steve’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MacKenzie Evans College Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX> at Yakima Federal Savings and Loan in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
“Daddy, even though I’m too little to express myself with words and my thoughts remain unspoken, I want you to know that I love when you look at me, talk to me, and most of all when you play with me. When I look back at you and smile, that’s my way of letting you know that you make me happy and I love you very much. Being your daughter is the best thing that ever happened to me! I love You Paw Paw, MacKenzie.”
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

