
<P ID="1">Teacher has no plans to retire anytime soon
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Getting up and going work is a pleasure for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Hall</ENAMEX>.   At an age when most people are thinking about retiring, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> eagerly heads off to school where she is greeted by a room of equally enthusiastic fourth graders. It's a daily routine the 63-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> has kept up for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 38 years</TIMEX>.   "I did stop a three times to have my children, she admits.   "But after a while I'd get itchy feet to be back in the classroom," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> has taught in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 12 years</TIMEX>, settling in the district after a career that has taken her to many parts of the nation and the world.   "My husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, who is now a retired teacher, and I traveled and moved around a lot in the early days of our careers," she said.   The couple taught in seven states and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> before moving to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   The petite woman even spent a short time serving as a teacher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Peace Corps</ENAMEX>, one of the few adventures in her life she didn't enjoy.   "The conditions were so bad and we never felt wanted," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said of the couple's time in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ethiopia</ENAMEX>.   "I taught in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> prior to coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," she said.   For the majority of her career, her educational attentions have been given to the children in the fourth grade, an age she loves the best.   "I never wanted to teach higher than the fifth grade. I've always believed it takes a special person to teach the upper grades," she explained.   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> is a pretty special person herself. She is known to arrive in her classroom at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX> each morning and often stays as late as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> preparing and perfecting her 24 students' lesson plans. It's to her credit that each children feels as though he or she is the "teacher's pet."   "They all try hard to do well," she beams.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> earned her teaching degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Mary College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yankton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S.D</ENAMEX>., and holds a Master's degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>. She has been a mentor to numerous Sunyside teachers over the years. She has even named the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s Educator of the Year. She recently was selected to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> writing scorer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>'s dedication to the teaching profession was rewarded <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> when she was named the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Outstanding Educator, an honor she shared with her building principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Davis</ENAMEX>.   "I feel very honored to be chosen," she said. "But I feel there are so many other teachers who also deserve this honor."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX> said she doesn't have plans of retiring anytime soon.   "It's still fun to come to work and I enjoy teaching," she said.   "The kids all work so hard and I still feel good knowing they are trying to learn everything," she said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

