
<P ID="1">Legislative honors afforded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX>, a Republican from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, recently received two individual honors for his legislative efforts.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Association of Vocational</ENAMEX> Administrators (WAVA) selected the 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> lawmaker as its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Legislator of the Year. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Farm Bureau</ENAMEX> also presented <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> with a certificate of commendation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> received the WAVA award at its fall conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 20</TIMEX>.   "We appreciate Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>'s support for the state's career and technical education system," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WAVA</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Wallace</ENAMEX>. "He has worked diligently for our concerns over the years and is an excellent spokesman for our programs. For people who are interested in career and technical education, Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> has always had an open door and has been willing to listen and discuss issues. He has always been a friend of career and technical education and he is very deserving of this award."   "Our vocational and technical colleges help produce skilled workers in many important areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s economy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, a former educator. "They play an important and valuable role in both our economy and education system."   In a letter sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> about the state farm bureau's certificate of commendation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Wood</ENAMEX>, the farm bureau's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">director of government relations</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> wrote: "This commendation is not based on voting record alone. It is awarded only to those few legislators who went above and beyond, demonstrating leadership on key bills and negotiations vital to our members."   "Agriculture has been and will always be a key part of my legislative district's economy and way of life," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said. "Agriculture also continues to be one of the key industries in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s economy. As a fruit grower, I understand the needs and concerns of farmers and growers both in my region and throughout our state."
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

