
<P ID="1">Local dance students offer jazzy version of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> classic
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">It's not your grandmother's version of the Nutcracker. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin School of Dance</ENAMEX>'s version featured some of the classical music from time-honored holiday musical, but with a decidedly jazzed-up twist.   The more than 50 student dancers presented The Nutcracker All Jazzed Up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Auditorium</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to a near sold-out crowd.   The story of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clara</ENAMEX> and her magical nutcracker included all the charm of the more famous version of The Nutcracker, with stunning costumes and delightful sets created by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolores Howe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristina Platsman</ENAMEX>, all under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Martin</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

