
<P ID="1">Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> treks to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> to allay mad cow disease concerns
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/15/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Stressing the need to support of the state's livestock industry during the current mad cow crisis, Governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>) urge the public to continue to "eat beef."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> read a proclamation declaring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 17-24</TIMEX> as "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Beef</ENAMEX> and Dairy Week" and asked everyone to continue to enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> beef, milk and dairy products.   "I urge everyone to continue to support our state farmers and ranchers now and throughout the year," he said.   He said there is a need to develop a national identification program for all cattle, as well as funding the development of faster <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> (bovine spongiform encephalopathy) testing methods.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> asked for the input from the group of more than 100 livestock producers and distributors who gathered for his town hall meeting held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanita Grange Hall</ENAMEX>, located several miles north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>.   Listening to the beef and dairy growers' concerns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> said he will work to aid the state livestock industry as it works to regroup following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>'s announcement that the nation's first case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> had been discovered in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dairy cow.   He asked for the help of industry leaders in developing strategies to retain the public confidence in the safety of beef.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>'s visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> was seen as a show of support for the area, which came under the national and international spotlight on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>.   "The governor's proclamation comes at a very important time for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s beef and dairy industry," said Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "We need to continue to support our ranchers and farmers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, who accompanied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> on his visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. He said since the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> was found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, government officials have taken the proper steps to ensure that the nation's beef supply is safe.   "People need to be aware of that. I join the governor in urging citizens in our state to continue enjoying beef, milk and dairy products," the senator said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger dairyman LaDon Linde</ENAMEX> said he appreciated the Governor's support of the livestock industry. "We thank you for the proclamation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX>, who is the vice president of the Washington State Dairy Federation.   "We have confidence in the painstaking steps the USDA is taking in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> investigation," he added. "And, we appreciate the steps being taken to assure we remain pro-active."   Noting that the USDA has been testing for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> for 14 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said that of the 100,000 animals tested only two cows have been found to be infected with the disease.   "We have to maintain a sense of perspective in this situation," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Erickson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cattlefeeders Association</ENAMEX>, asked the governor to do what he can to remove the bans on the export of cattle which were issued immediately following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> discoveries.   "We're selling cattle every day," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erickson</ENAMEX> told the Governor.   "But the price of beef is steadily falling and we need to get those markets reopened," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erickson</ENAMEX> said his association is in favor of the national identification system. "We also need to speed up the testing for the disease," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erickson</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> said meetings with the Japanese and Mexican trade unions have already been held, toward the reopening of the overseas markets. "But it will take some time," he noted.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> thanked the livestock industry groups and local communities affected by this incident for their "...patience, understanding and cooperation with this federal investigation."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> held his town hall meeting at the grange hall following a tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ray</ENAMEX>'s Meats in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, where he not only observed how beef is processed but purchased meat for his family's use.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>, accompanied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valoria Loveland</ENAMEX>, director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> legislators made the purchase to reinforce the message that beef is safe.   "It's important that we all do what we can to support and promote our beef industry and the safety of our beef," he said.   "We will continue to cooperate with the federal government and are directing all available resources to assist the USDA in completing its investigation," he added.   "Only two cows were found to be infected with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, and our food supplies were not threatened," he said.   "It's important to remember that beef remains safe to eat," he said.   He praised the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> cattlemen and dairymen, as well as the surrounding communities affected by the aftershock of the mad cow announcement and investigation.   Noting that the past several weeks have been a challenging time for the growers and distributors, he also thanked the staffs of the USDA and the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> for their continued support and efforts.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

