15 9 38 8 28 46
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  You can't deny laughter; when it comes, it plops down in your favorite chair and stays as long as it wants.  <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stephen</ENAMEX> King (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> - ), "Hearts in Atlantis"
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>