
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> remains a winner with Idaho State Bengals
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/16/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">POCATELLO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">IDAHO</ENAMEX> - It seems no matter where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Schutt</ENAMEX> goes, she's a winner.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> hoop standout in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990's</TIMEX> who went on to star for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oregon</ENAMEX> women's basketball team, is now coaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho State University</ENAMEX>. Not so surprising, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> are heading for an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIT</ENAMEX> first round showdown with powerful <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa State</ENAMEX>.   It is only the second time in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho State University</ENAMEX> history that its women's basketball team has qualified for a postseason tournament. The first time was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, when the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> won the Big Sky Conference and earned an automatic bid to the NCAA Championship Tournament.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> is in the first year of her contract as an assistant coach, serving under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho State University</ENAMEX> head coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Newlee</ENAMEX>. She accepted the varsity assistant coaching position after serving one year as the head coach of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tacoma Community College</ENAMEX> women's basketball team. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tacoma Titans</ENAMEX>, who were 12-9 the year before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> came on board, finished the regular season with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20-5 mark</NUMEX>. Her Titans won the league title, earning a berth into the NWACC Championship Tournament. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tacoma</ENAMEX> school hadn't qualified for the NWACC tourney 17 years prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> coming on board. Because of the Titans' success, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> was selected by her peers as the NWACC coach of the year last season.   A similar turnaround occurred this season at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho State University</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Bengals</ENAMEX> finished at 6-20 last season in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newlee</ENAMEX>'s first year as head coach. This season, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> at his side, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho State</ENAMEX> has amassed 20 victories compared with only eight losses.   The difference in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho State</ENAMEX>'s record from the 2002-03 season to this season is the second biggest turnaround among all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NCAA Division</ENAMEX> I schools <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Only the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of North Carolina</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asheville</ENAMEX> women's basketball team has improved at a better clip, upping its <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2002-03 mark</NUMEX> of 3-25 to 19-9 in 2003-04.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> credits the dramatic improvement by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho State</ENAMEX> team to the leadership of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newlee</ENAMEX>. She said the turnaround is probably a combination of the fine job <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newlee</ENAMEX> did in recruiting seven new players to the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> program, and the philosophy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newlee</ENAMEX> has established with the team. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> also notes that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newlee</ENAMEX>'s motion offense has added zip and excitement to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho State</ENAMEX> game plan, explaining that the new offense was designed with the players who were on board in mind.   Now 30 years old, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> was the first <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> female basketball player to score more than 1,000 points during her prep career. There have been only two Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> since then to have accomplished that feat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX>, who was named the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MVP</ENAMEX> of the Class 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournaments both her junior and senior years in high school, went on to star for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oregon</ENAMEX> women's hoop team. As a junior, she led the Pac-10 in free throw shooting accuracy by sinking more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">83 percent</NUMEX> of her shots from the charity stripe. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> also set the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oregon</ENAMEX> school record for 3-point field goals made during a single game, when she bombed in eight treys against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USC</ENAMEX>.   Following her collegiate playing days, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> went on to serve as an assistant coach at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Martin</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">A year later</TIMEX>, she accepted the head assistant's job at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana State</ENAMEX>/Northern, staying with the women's basketball program there for four years until deciding to get away from basketball. A couple of seasons away from the game was all it took to convince <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> to return to coaching. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tacoma Community College</ENAMEX> head coach's position became her's for the taking, she got back into basketball at the start of the 2002-03 season.   Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> and company at little noticed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho State University</ENAMEX> are heading off to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa State University</ENAMEX> as decided underdogs.   "It's definitely going to be a challenge," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> said of drawing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa State</ENAMEX> as a first round opponent in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Invitation Tournament</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIT</ENAMEX>).   "We just got through playing in the Big Sky Conference championship game in front of 5,200 people. There'll be 12,000 people at our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIT</ENAMEX> game this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa State</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> said.   "They will definitely provide us with a challenge," she said of the Big 12 Conference school.   An upset victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa State</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Wednesday</TIMEX> would propel the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho State</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> into an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIT</ENAMEX> second round match-up against the winner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Xavier</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miami</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX> game that is also being played <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.   Whatever the outcome of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">tomorrow</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NIT</ENAMEX> contest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> said her first year being involved with the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bengals</ENAMEX> hoop program has been a positive experience.   "I love it here," she said of the Pocatello area. "I thoroughly enjoy working with the coaching staff here at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho State</ENAMEX>, as well as the players on the team.   "It's a super place to be, a great place to work," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> added.   And, of course, there are the fringe benefits. Like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s all-expenses paid trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Iowa State University</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

