
<P ID="1">Energetic teen youth award winner
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Her calm exterior and slender build belies the bundle of energy which makes up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> was honored as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce Outstanding Youth</ENAMEX>, has had no time to let that honor settle on her shoulders.   Between her huge academic load at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX>, the honor student is busy completing her senior project, while filling out reams of college scholarship applications. As one of the top five students in her class, the 4.0 G.P.A. student is also preparing to present her regional and state award-winning science project at the annual International Science and Engineering Fair to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>.   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-March</TIMEX>, the petite teen has kept busy carting her science project from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX>, "wowing" science fair judges with her insightful inquiries into the side effects of new drugs being used for cancer victims in chemotherapy treatments.   The youthful researcher, who has been collecting science fair awards since her middle school years, has had one of her best science years to date. She collected both the Grand Championship at the Mid-Columbia Regional Science Fair held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> in late-March and the bronze medal at the Washington State Science and Engineering Fair held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX>.   When not attending to her research or classes, she is in the midst of preparing scholarship applications in order to fund her future career as a pharmacist.   "I've been accepted to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Sciences</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX> to study pharmacology," she explained.   "I plan to focus on oncology pharmaceuticals," she explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> said it was a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> job working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Star Lodge</ENAMEX> for cancer patients in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> that helped her to decide her post-high school education plans. "The experience helped me to focus on the side effects of drugs on chemotherapy patients.   "Some of the new drugs used to treat the side effects of the chemo present their own set of side effects," she explained.   "I want to be more involved with that type of research," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> said she has always been interested in the science of medicine beginning with her first science project. "It seems pretty simple now, but I was looking at how blockages in the arteries affect blood flow as a sixth grader," she smiled.   "I've always studied compounds as they relate to disease on plants and animals. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is the first time I really focused on humans," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> said her research at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Star Lodge</ENAMEX> gave her an opportunity to see first-hand the effects of cancer fighting drugs on patients. "I was able to see the impact science research has on people," she said.   Her work experience has cemented her desire to help people, she said.   In addition to her dedication to research, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> has also found time for fun. She is a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Rotary Swim team and played high school soccer. For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>, she has also competed on the Grizzly Apple Bowl and Knowledge Bowl teams. Her area of expertise - science, of course.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

