


<P ID="1">G'view aquatic center back on drawing board
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The times are changing and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> is taking a fresh look at building an aquatic center in the community.
</P><P ID="5">   The board met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> chamber room to discuss moving forward with a campaign to build a new multi-faceted pool facility.
</P><P ID="6">   With the outdated and deteriorating pool facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX> explained that the city began looking at building a new pool in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Park and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> revisited the original plan as they discussed the possibility of going to the voters with a vote in favor of a new pool.
</P><P ID="7">   Looking at pools in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Freewater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pendleton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said a plan was developed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX> for a new state of the art aquatic center that includes slides, a lap pool section for swim team and a zero depth portion of the pool.
</P><P ID="8">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>, studies have shown that the lap pools similar to the current city pool do not make money, but zero depth pools do. The pool at the proposed aquatic center would be both.
</P><P ID="9">   A zero depth pool, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said, is a shallower pool which is similar to walking in the ocean. He said it is a pool that draws young mothers, as well kids wanting to cool off in the water. The original pool design also had water features that spray and spit water for kids to play in, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>. It also had a multi-purpose room, a concessions stand and an indoor lap pool that could potentially be open year-round.
</P><P ID="10">   "Based on what we've seen, we like the aquatic center idea," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Copeland</ENAMEX>, chairman of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   But, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mariotti</ENAMEX> questioned whether the city should push for such a large facility.
</P><P ID="12">   "This is really a first class outfit. I can see this going up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, but not working here," he said.
</P><P ID="13">   He said the city could just as easily do as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> did and build a nice, but smaller pool that would serve the community. He said he feels an aquatic center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, a town of nearly 9,000 people, wouldn't attract the numbers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> is hoping for.
</P><P ID="14">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX>, there are 54,000 people living within 16 miles of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and 42,000 within eight miles of the community.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> needs to build a facility that keeps people there for the day and wanting to go back the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next day</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   The aquatic center plan that was developed for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Black</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX>, an architectural firm that has built numerous pools around the state, has been laid out to fit in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Park</ENAMEX>, located at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Second</ENAMEX> streets.
</P><P ID="17">   The original project has an estimated value of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.9 million</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   After an intensive campaign the aquatic center was turned down with a vote of 1,421 people voting against the facility and 1,377 voting in favor. A super-majority, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the voters, had to vote in favor of the pool for the project to pass. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX>, on 326 of the ballots voters didn't vote either way. Voters affected by the vote are those living within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>, with the exception of the few who live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   Conditions weren't favorable at the time, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Copeland</ENAMEX>, who listed processing plants closing and declining agricultural conditions as part of the reason the aquatic center was put on hold until now.
</P><P ID="20">   One major change that makes the climate more favorable is the addition of the Wal-Mart distribution center, which added about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30 million</NUMEX> in assessed value to the city.
</P><P ID="21">   "There has been a huge infusion into the tax base," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   There has been a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">40 cent</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value reduction from schools taxes with even more expected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. The utility tax is expected to drop <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> and with more construction on the horizon <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the addition of 100 new homes over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next five years</TIMEX> could easily increase assessed value in the city by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX>, who attended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s meeting, said that the pool could easily come in at the same time the taxes are reduced, making it so residents see no significant difference in their taxes.
</P><P ID="24">   He said pool proponents should encourage votes for the pool by asking voters to keep their taxes the same and in return would get an aquatic center.
</P><P ID="25">   "What's wrong with breaking even, but having a new pool in town?," asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX> said he feels like the city should push forward and ask voters to support the aquatic center.
</P><P ID="27">   "If you want to build a community, you have to go for it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX>. "I don't think we should stop with an aquatic center. There are other quality of life issues that need to be addressed. We can't just sit on our hands."
</P><P ID="28">   Another benefit to building a new pool is that currently the city is subsidizing the pool to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55,000</NUMEX> a year, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="29">   In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Milton Freewater</ENAMEX>, the city subsidizes the pool for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27,000</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> is making money, he said.
</P><P ID="30">   "That's a savings to taxpayers," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="31">   He added that stepping out, taking a chance and building facilities like an aquatic center increases the likelihood that new businesses will locate in a community.
</P><P ID="32">   The next step is to get an updated cost estimate for the aquatic center. Members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> said they were open to potentially down-sizing the project if needed, but the current plan gives them someplace to start.
</P><P ID="33">   "We don't see ourselves as a commercial hub," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>, "We see ourselves as a good place to live."
</P><P ID="34">   He added that building a pool for the next three generations would be a way to improve the quality of life for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> residents.
</P><P ID="35">   Also on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Christensen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Churchill</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="36">Webmaster
</P><P ID="37">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




