
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Gospel music jamboree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Several local musicians will perform at the Gospel music jamboree scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 18</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton's Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX> (428 B St.).
All Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> residents are invited to attend the 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> event, which will feature an open microphone for anyone wanting to perform.
Scheduled to perform that day are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Strings & Bill Lawson</ENAMEX>, Joyfull Noise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Diamond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce McBride</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> Lathrup, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Colson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Plumlee</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Mayfest celebration in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S’side</ENAMEX> to include carnival, talent show
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s St. Joseph's Parish annual Mayfest celebration will be staged the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 21-23</TIMEX>. In addition to the carnival, food booths and entertainment, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s festival will feature a talent competition.
The talent show, set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX>, is open to anyone who can sing or dance and would like to compete for a cash prize. Singers and dancers will compete in different categories. Entry forms are available at the parish office, located in the former St. Joseph's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School on Sixth Street</ENAMEX>. The deadline to submit entries is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, May 14</TIMEX>.
For additional information, contact Nelda Gastelum (837-7980).
</P> 
<P ID="5">Spaghetti dinner, auction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">plannedby G’view 4-H/FFA
GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview 4-H/FFA</ENAMEX> livestock support group will once again host its all you can eat spaghetti dinner and auction. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s event is slated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 24</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
Organizers say there will be door prizes, surprise prizes and fun for everyone. The grand prize is an overnight stay at Whistlin Jack Lodge for two, which includes dinner and breakfast.
Tickets to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24</TIMEX> event, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for students, are being sold in advance. Tickets will also be available at the door that evening.
Proceeds generated from the dinner and auction will be used to support local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4-H</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> members by purchasing their animals at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Jr. Livestock Show</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first week of May</TIMEX>, and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fair & Rodeo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Lecture, hikeset for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GOLDENDALE</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 24</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum of Art</ENAMEX> will present a lecture by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> historian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Ziak</ENAMEX>, to be followed by a hike. Attendance is free with admission to the museum.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ziak</ENAMEX> will discuss his book, In Full View, written about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps of Discovery</ENAMEX>'s month-long search for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> camp at the mouth of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia</ENAMEX>, and the flora and fauna they encountered along the way.
"As a nationally recognized authority on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>'s arrival at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex</ENAMEX> is an engaging storyteller," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Schafroth</ENAMEX>, executive director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX>. "Copies of the book will be available for purchase, and he will be pleased to sign them."
At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schafroth</ENAMEX> will lead a moderate 30-minute hike from the museum's overlook of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX> to view several sites the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps</ENAMEX> documented while in the area.
"On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22, 1806</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corps</ENAMEX> walked across the land where the museum now sits," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schafroth</ENAMEX>. "To honor that event, the museum presents a related program each year, and this lecture and hike continues that tradition."
</P> 
<P ID="7">Follies to showcase Yakima Valley’s talent
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Who will be kicking up their heels at the Memorial Follies on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX>?
About 200 of your friends and neighbors—maybe even you!
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX> is reminding <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents that now is their chance to participate in the Memorial Follies, a biennial fund-raiser supporting community health initiatives. The follies are a professionally directed, community performed "Broadway style show." Organizers say no particular talent is required for participation—just a great sense of humor.
A director's party for all interested singers, dancers and good sports will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, April 26</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s Capitol Theatre. In addition to performers, the show will need volunteers to assist with make-up, costumes, sets and other projects.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Starlab, Space Odyssey exhibitson display <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> will host a free family day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 10</TIMEX>. The one-day event will feature the Starlab planetarium and Space Odyssey exhibits from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Science Center</ENAMEX> in Seattle.
The Space Odyssey exhibits will be available from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, with Starlab shows beginning at 1, 2, 3 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> The 2 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> shows will be presented in Spanish.
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

