
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Renowned</ENAMEX> doctor to speak about healing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 26</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - A message of hope and healing from renowned author and physician Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie Siegel</ENAMEX> will be presented at the Yakima Capitol Theatre <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 26</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> presentation, "The Art of Healing," has been described as dynamic, positive and upbeat. His talk is designed to inspire listeners, as well as help them reflect on living life more fully, no matter what the challenges are.
Tickets are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> and are currently available at the Capitol Theatre box office. Proceeds from ticket sales will benefit cancer patients in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
As a physician who has cared for and counseled thousands of people with life-threatening illnesses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siegel</ENAMEX> embraces a philosophy of living, and dying, that stands at what some describe the forefront of medicine. He is a best selling author of six books.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Spilyay Indian Market returnsto Legends Casino
TOPPENISH - The 40th annual Spilyay Indian Market returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>'s Legends Casino <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 13-14</TIMEX>. The doors to the public will open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>
The public is encouraged to view a unique showcase of American Indian arts and crafts. Many of the items will be offered for sale.
The Native American fair will include an Indian baby and toddler fashion show on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 p.m.</TIMEX> The "Beloved Children" dancers of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Swan</ENAMEX> will perform that day at 3 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> Art awards will be presented at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m. Saturday evening</TIMEX>, with the fair closing at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s program will begin with a prayer song at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:15 a.m.</TIMEX> At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:30 p.m.</TIMEX> that day, Rocco Clark's Indian dancers will perform, to be followed by a hand drum contest. Doors to the fair will close at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">‘Heartstrings’back in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 14</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Gospel singing group "Heartstrings" is back in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 14</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Christian Church</ENAMEX>.
All <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents are invited to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> concert at the church, located at 310 Euclid Ave. A recently released CD, as well as cassettes, will be on sale that evening, as well.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Kids’ chess setsto be displayedat G’dale museum
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GOLDENDALE</ENAMEX> - A special opening reception will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 20</TIMEX>, for the young artists who created chess sets that will be displayed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX> through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first of July</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From March 15 through July 4</TIMEX>, the Goldendale area museum will exhibit chess sets created by children from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX> reception, scheduled for 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, will include opportunities to learn how to play chess, as well as a live performance by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldendale High School</ENAMEX> jazz band.
Teams of students joined forces to create some of the chess sets, while others show the unmistakable hand of an individual.
"World cultures and individuals from such diverse art movements as Dada, Surealism and Bauhaus Internationalism have interpreted chess pieces according to their aesthetic concepts," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Spousta</ENAMEX>, curator of educational exhibits at the museum. "These students are helping to keep the tradition going."
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX>, a castle-like mansion overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX>, is open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> daily. The Maryhill Cafe offers beverages, deli food and desserts to visitors. General admission prices to the museum are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> for adults, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> for senior citizens and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> for children.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Yakima Family Theatre Series presents ‘Matilda’ in sign language <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday</TIMEX> 
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Council of Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> will present the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleveland Signstage Theater</ENAMEX>'s production of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Matilda</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, March 11</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Center</ENAMEX>, 5000 W. Lincoln Ave., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
Tickets for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> performance are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> for children and senior citizens.
Season tickets are available at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21</NUMEX> for children and seniors.  
The play, presented in both English and American sign language, is the first of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Council</ENAMEX>'s 21st annual Family Theater Series.  
 Two additional productions in the Family Theater Series are the ArtsPowers National Touring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theater</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Gables</ENAMEX>  on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6</TIMEX>, and the Missoula Children's Theatre's The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Frog</ENAMEX> Prince  on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22</TIMEX>.
Auditions for the Missoula Theatre production for youngsters, ages 5-18, will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 17</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Allied Arts Center</ENAMEX>. Performance times will be at 3 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
Family Theatre Series tickets are on sale at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Council</ENAMEX> office by calling (509) 966-0930.
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

