


<P ID="1">Aquatic center proposal may be decided by voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next May</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - If the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> has its way, voters will take to the polls <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17, 2005</TIMEX> to decide the fate of the proposed family aquatic center set to be built at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the service area board met to get a consensus on when the election should be held, as well as go over the group's action plan for the proposal.
</P><P ID="6">   Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX> said he felt that the spring election date would be beneficial to the proposal.
</P><P ID="7">   "It's in spring when people are starting to think about water activities," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="8">   He added that if the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX> date is officially chosen as the date of the election, they board will have an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX> deadline to turn all of their election information over to the county.
</P><P ID="9">   "I completely believe that's the date we should use," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> told the board.
</P><P ID="10">   He said getting a consensus on the election date will put a lot of other things into motion, noting that he and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> Chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Copeland</ENAMEX> will bring the date to city council during their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1</TIMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="11">   Board member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Horner</ENAMEX> added that if the election takes place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> and the aquatic center measure is approved the facility could be up and running by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer 2006</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   Last time the board brought a proposal for a family aquatics center before the voters, the election was held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>. The measure failed.
</P><P ID="13">   During <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting, the board also took time to review its action plan, which includes a list of tasks to be completed before the proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> election.
</P><P ID="14">   The action plan includes educating community members about the family aquatic center project, addressing any concerns from the community and recruiting members for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPLASH</ENAMEX> campaign committee.
</P><P ID="15">   According to the action plan, the board will set up community meetings where voters will get a chance to see different designs for the aquatics facility, as well as ask any questions they might have about the project.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said one of the concerns that was raised through the surveys that the board distributed earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> dealt with the possible loss of soccer fields if the center is built at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said he spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Schools</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX> about the issue, and was told that it could be possible to move one of the soccer fields onto school grounds.
</P><P ID="17">   "So we won't lose that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="18">   He added that he has also been talking to representatives of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Youth Soccer Association</ENAMEX> about the possibility of putting in two youth-sized soccer fields at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   Board member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX> noted that one important thing to keep in mind when talking to people about the project is that according to the surveys the aquatics center is a project that most people want to support.
</P><P ID="20">   "This is a quality of life priority," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX> said. He added that in every community the board visited over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, the aquatics facilities that had been built had proven to be positive assets.
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




