
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> works with parents to ensure success
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When the school year started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX> there were 566 first grade students filling up elementary school classrooms throughout the district. However, when the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> walked down the aisle for commencement services just a couple of weeks ago, only 301 students graduated from high school. These are the numbers <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> is hoping to avoid for the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX>, which is why the organization is adopting the more than 400 students who will be moving into the fifth grade <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> held an informational meeting for parents of the students of the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX>. The meeting served as a time for committee members to learn what the parents are looking for in regards to ensuring their children graduate from high school, as well as concerns they have for their children.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Mana</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> explained that there are issues to be concerned about, sharing statistics that show when compared to state averages local students in grades six, eight, 10 and 12 are above average when it comes to lifetime alcohol consumption and illegal drug use.   "If this is not acceptable to you, then what we're asking is that you get involved," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> told parents <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> wants to find out what parents are doing at home to make a difference. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said the organization also wants to talk to parents to learn what they can do together as a group to help ensure success for the students of the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said in adopting the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> wants to work with parents to find out what leads to dropouts and low grades. He said the organization also wants to ensure that parent and student needs are being met, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> will work to connect families with any services they may need to succeed. He said if a child is at home alone after school, the organization might be able to get the child involved in groups like scouting and Camp Fire.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> explained that adopting the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2012</TIMEX> also means that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> will continue to hold informational meetings for parents over the years between now and graduation.   Following <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>'s presentation, members of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX> spent time talking to parents about concerns they have regarding their child. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Fairbairn</ENAMEX>, administrative assistant for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Promise</ENAMEX>, said parents listed a variety of concerns from who their child is hanging out with to the use of alcohol and drugs. One common theme that linked the different conversations, was that all of the parents hope to see their children graduate with their class.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

