
<P ID="1"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> awards presented
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Among the pomp and circumstance of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> celebration, four community members were honored for their commitment and contributions to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   In a ceremony that took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> Centennial Walk, at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Edison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Fifth Street</ENAMEX>, awards were presented in the youth and adult categories, as well as for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Living Pioneer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Past Pioneer</ENAMEX>.   The recipient of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Youth Award was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX>, who will be a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> and maintains a 3.5 grade point average, is a long-time member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Skate Park Committee</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> has received a variety of awards in recent years including the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> Youth Commissioner Award for Citizenship, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> he was recognized as one of six outstanding youths in the state, he has been awarded the Prudential Spirit of Community Award, and he has earned the bronze, silver and gold congressional award certificates, as well as the bronze and silver medal congressional awards.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny</ENAMEX> is also very active in his church," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> mayor and emcee of the event.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> is a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Life</ENAMEX>, the Order of the Arrow, Boy Scouts and is a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scout Venture Crew</ENAMEX> #632. He is also active in high school drama club, debate team and LINK crew.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Adult Award was presented to former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>.   "This individual definitely deserves the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> award for serving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for over 18 years," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said.   He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX>, becoming the community's first parks and recreation director. After serving in that capacity for a couple of years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, but was soon back in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> serving as the community economic development director.   "What a parks and recreation person knew about economic development was debatable, however, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> soon showed that he was multi-talented and became a great economic development director for our community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said.   It wasn't until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> became <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city manager, a position he held until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> noted that as city manager, he helped complete some of the projects he had started as the economic development director, including Centennial Square, the bronze program and the pathway park.   Being honored with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Living Pioneer Award was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Saras</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX>, who was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Shoshone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah State</ENAMEX>, taught two years in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Shoshone</ENAMEX> before coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 1952</TIMEX>. Once in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX> spent two years teaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendell Phillips School</ENAMEX> before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kamiakin Junior High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX> taught at the junior high school until the mid-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980s</TIMEX>, when he moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, where he taught for two years before retiring.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX> is deeply involved in the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, having served as senior warden of the Episcopal church for many years, is a past-president and current vice president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library Board</ENAMEX> and is the president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Historical Society</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX> also spends time driving the elderly to doctors appointments in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and the Tri-Cities and has volunteered to mentor students at the high school.   The final award was presented to the late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Ferrell Mottley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mottley</ENAMEX>, who was raised on land her father and grandfather homesteaded southwest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, received the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Past Pioneer Award.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mottley</ENAMEX> is remembered as a loving and devote wife and mother, as a community activist and as a futurist who carried a positive vision of the people and character of the community in which she lived.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mottley</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ren Ferrell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adelia Switzler Ferrell</ENAMEX>, started school at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riverside School</ENAMEX>, progressed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wendell Phillips School</ENAMEX> and then to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools. She went to college at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Whitman</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>, where she earned her teaching degree.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mottley</ENAMEX> was the first woman to be elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>, served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board for Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>, was a lifetime member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Association</ENAMEX>, Chapter L of the P.E.O. and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Trinity Episcopal Church</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mottley</ENAMEX> was dedicated to the establishment of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> museum and was instrumental in converting the former Ball's Funeral Home building into a permanent facility for the museum. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mottley</ENAMEX> also gave an original line cabin used by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Snipes</ENAMEX>' cowboys to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snipes Park</ENAMEX> and also instigated the refurbishment of the park by initiating a bronze statue of her father.   Recipients of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> awards received a certificate, a medallion and will be listed along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> Centennial Walk.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> award winners also received an honor. The plagues featuring their names were unveiled along the Centennial Walk. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s winners were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Slotemaker</ENAMEX>, who received the Youth Award; Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Schuler</ENAMEX>, who received the Adult Award; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John McMinimee</ENAMEX>, who received the Living Pioneer Award; and Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Taylor</ENAMEX>, who was honored as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Past Pioneer</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youth Award   Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adult Award   John Saras</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Living Pioneer Award   Ruth Ferrell Mottley</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Past Pioneer Award   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> ? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5, 2004</TIMEX> ? <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:31 PM</TIMEX>   Proofed_________ ? <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Corrected & Placed</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Folder_____________</ENAMEX>   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

