48 21 20 45 47 5
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  A boy can learn a lot from a dog: obedience, loyalty, and the importance of turning around three times before lying down.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Benchley</ENAMEX> (1889 - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>