
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Seniors invitedto <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> party
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Senior citizens are being invited to get into the spirit of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>, at a costume party scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 29</TIMEX>.
Sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> party will get underway at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> that day at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carl L. Stevens Senior Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> (410 W. 2nd). On the party agenda are lots of games, prizes and contests. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Park</ENAMEX> and rec officials are advising those planning on attending to begin thinking now about putting together a costume for the party.
All <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> senior citizens are welcome to attend.
Following the party, a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> meal will be served. Those planning on attending the luncheon are asked to call at least 24 hours in advance to make a reservation (882-9230).
</P> 
<P ID="4">Holiday bazaar planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Have an arts and crafts talent you'd like to share with others? Then plan on selling your handiwork at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s holiday bazaar, sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Senior Center</ENAMEX>.
Tables are presently available on a first-come, first-serve basis. The cost to rent a table at the bazaar to showcase your wares is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for a large table, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for a smaller card table. Table reservations can be made by calling the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> at 882-9219.
Proceeds from the table rentals will be used to benefit senior citizen programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
In past years, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> bazaar has featured such items as handcrafts, knitted items and baked goods. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s bazaar, slated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 6</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>, will again be held in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carl L. Stevens Senior Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, located at 401 W. 2nd St.
</P> 
<P ID="5">‘Concours de Maryhill’ to feature car show, race, wine tasting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ
GOLDENDALE</ENAMEX> - If you're a fan of classic and custom automobiles, you won't want to miss out on the sixth annual "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concours de Maryhill</ENAMEX>."
Scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 9-10</TIMEX>, the yearly event is again expected to attract hundreds of people. Visitors to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX>, located near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>, will have an array of mint condition vintage, classic and custom cars to admire on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. Refreshment vendors will also be on-site that day, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cafe Maryhill</ENAMEX> with a wide selection of menu items and Oregon Trail Candy, which will be offering fruit pies. Admission to the car show and outdoor sculpture garden, surprisingly, is free.
"The legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Hill</ENAMEX>, founder of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX>, was a car and road enthusiast," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Schafroth</ENAMEX>, executive director of the museum. "He would love this event," she added.
At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, approximately 40 vintage race cars will parade down <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scenic Route</ENAMEX> 14 into the car show at the museum. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930 through 1960s</TIMEX> vehicles will compete in a hill climb race the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following day</TIMEX>, on the museum's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Historic Loops Road</ENAMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>
"This is an open car show, so anyone with a special car may enter," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis Gray</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldendale Motorsports Association</ENAMEX>, the co-sponsor of the event. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> said collectors interested in showing their vehicle are encouraged to call (509) 773-3677 to make arrangements. He said the lawns at the museum are extensive, so there's space available for numerous automobiles.
Awards will be presented at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, following by a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ</ENAMEX> dinner on the museum's picnic grounds. Following that, a wine tasting session is scheduled at nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maryhill Winery</ENAMEX>.
Promotional support for the car show and hill climb race is being provided by Meadow Outdoor Advertising of The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, spectators can view the hill climb race from an overlook on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> 97, just three miles north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scenic Route</ENAMEX> 14. The race is organized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Vintage Racing Enthusiasts</ENAMEX>, and only their approved cars and drivers can compete.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX>, a castle-like mansion overlooking the Columbia River Gorge, is located just west of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> 97 on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s Scenice Route 14.
</P> 
<P ID="6">‘Impact’ <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">comingto Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland
Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> residents are being urged to celebrate the onset of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and the thrill of action sports at "Impact," the 55th annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Miller</ENAMEX> movie that is presently touring the country.
The film showcases <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> sports' top athletes and local heroes on the big screen as producers travel to fabled and exotic locations around the globe in search of the perfect ride, deepest powder and sickest lines. Promoters say each screening of the movie is a high energy event booked as a limited engagement.
The movie will be shown at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s Capitol Theatre on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 29</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 30</TIMEX>, the film will be shown at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland High School</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
Along with adrenaline-filled action and magnificent scenery, "Impact" delivers a high energy soundtrack on a state-of-the-art digital sound system.
Tickets for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> event are now on sale at Sporthaus, the Capitol Theatre box office and at TicketsWest (1-800-325-SEAT). Large groups wanting to sit together should call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Miller Entertainment</ENAMEX> directly (1-800-523-7117).
All who attend either the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> showing will receive free lift tickets to the White Pass ski area, as well as tickets to four ski resorts in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Silver Spur Rodeo dates to be switched
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Organizers of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> Silver Spur Rodeo—three days of rodeo action and a bull-o-rama—have applied to hold the event in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> as opposed to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.
Scheduled dates are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 24-26</TIMEX>, at the Yakima SunDome. In years past, the three-day event had been staged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.
"We want to move the dates to try to avoid any potential weather problems," said the chairman of the event, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Messer</ENAMEX>. "Dates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> would make it safer for travel for out-of-town contestants and rodeo fans."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messer</ENAMEX> explained that although the rodeo is held indoors, in some years past bad weather has impacted attendance because of ice and snow on the highways.
He added that the rodeo committee is looking at the possibility of creating a three-day entertainment event on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fairgrounds</ENAMEX> that is built around the rodeo.
"We think these new dates in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> will give us a better chance to grow the rodeo," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Messer</ENAMEX> said.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Seattle Symphony in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX> will present the Seattle Symphony on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 13</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, in the music education building on the Ellensburg campus.  It is one of the "Inaugural Season Showcase Performances" that will be held through the 2004-05 academic year in the university's new <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29 million</NUMEX> facility.
The symphony's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> performance is sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave B Estate Winery</ENAMEX>, Puget Sound Energy, Lydig Construction, Coca Cola and the associated students of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>.
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> and are available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Samuelson Union Building</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SUB</ENAMEX>) ticket counter, weekdays from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>, or by calling (509) 963-3513, weekdays from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX>  Remaining tickets will be available at the door.
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

