
<P ID="1">School problems focus of legislative dinner
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Administrators and school board members from school districts in the 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Legislative District</ENAMEX> addressed concerns they have when it comes to the future of education in the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>/Legislative Dinner.   15th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> and Representatives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> also talked about concerns they have with the WASL, school funding, charter schools and the future of education in the state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ian Grabenhorst</ENAMEX>, assistant superintendent for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105, listed some concerns the educational district holds. Amongst the educational priorities <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grabenhorst</ENAMEX> outlined were a focus on amply funding K-12 education. He suggested the state complete a comprehensive review of the finance system and establish a sustainable, predictable and fair state funded system for public schools.   Making a constitutional amendment that would allow school districts to pass a levy with a simple majority is also key to better education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grabenhorst</ENAMEX>.   He asked the state legislators to consider repealing unfunded mandates, which are difficult to implement without funding in place.   "We have requests that are set in front of our districts and no funding," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grabenhorst</ENAMEX>.   He also asked the legislators to oppose binding arbitration and to reinforce the state's "no strike" laws.   Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, in his opening comments, said one of the major issues facing the legislature this budget cycle is money.   "We'll have at least a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> deficit, plus collective bargaining. We'll probably be a billion-two upside down to start with," he said.   He explained that K-12 education receives about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">43 percent</NUMEX> of the state's budget and another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> goes to higher education. Corrections receives about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX>, leaving the state with about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of the money as discretionary.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said they have had difficulties getting the votes to make strikes illegal, but they are still working on it.   He said he believes that questions about the WASL will once again return to the state level <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this next year</TIMEX>.   "The WASL to some people is the holy grail to end education problems," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>. "I don't like it. It's terribly expensive for what we get."   Another concern is non-English speakers and the disabled taking the test.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> takes a different view on the test. He believes there has to be some kind of benchmark or test to see the educational growth.   "I believe at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the day</TIMEX> most students will achieve our expectations of them," he said. "If we expect great things they will rise to that."   He added that he believes there is a lot to be said for better than average students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said a K-12 task force has been looking at education in the state and one of the areas it found of interest is special education funding.   "In areas some districts are making money on it and others are in the hole," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said if Initiative 884 going before voters to help fund public education is passed it will be the highest tax increase in the history of the state. He said that if the initiative fails that most likely the legislators will be reluctant to increase taxes.   "If it passes it will probably be the only tax increase passed mainly because of its size," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>.   A concern <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> has with the initiative is that if the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> increase in retail sales tax for K-12 education is put in a fund and decided upon by a citizen oversight committee, he foresees the legislature having very little input on public education.   One of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>'s main concerns is the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX> being required to pass the WASL to graduate.   "There's concern about the dropout rate if we don't do anything about it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>.   But, some changes may be afoot at the state level.   Currently, there are 25 Republicans in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and 24 Democrats. With four close races, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> feels it's too close to call what it will be like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Representatives has 52 Democrats and 46 Republicans.   "That six-vote difference was determined in the last election by 1,700 people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> we expect voter turnout to exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ten percent</NUMEX> of voters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> could be new voters, which creates a lot of uncertainty."   Local pastor and a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s ethics committee, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Jetter</ENAMEX>, addressed the trend to combat obesity at the school level by banning certain foods and beverages from school grounds. He asked if the legislators anticipate a state law that would ban certain foods.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> two</TIMEX> bills in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> addressed child obesity. One of the bills would have banned certain foods from being sold on school grounds. The other, known as the "Fat Tax," would have taxed foods based on ingredients. The problem, he said, is that some candy bars would be taxed and others wouldn't.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> anticipates at least one proposal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, but he would much rather leave it at the school board level.   In all, the legislators are looking forward to an interesting session. They said they appreciated the input from those who are on the front line of education, which helps them in their decision making process in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>.   The light at the end of the tunnel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> added at the end, is that the economic downfall the state has been experiencing is expected to end in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2009</TIMEX>. He anticipates programs that have been neglected with funding, such as education, will receive more funding.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

