
<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Surprisingly, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX> has one of the largest Russian populations in the state. The small community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blaine</ENAMEX> also has a large Russian population, while the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX> area has a community of Ukrainian descendants and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX> has a large Asian population.   These are all groups served by the recruiters and trainers for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Student Data and Recruitment Office</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MSDR</ENAMEX>), which has its main office in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on the second floor of the Lincoln Building.   For 12 years <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Carrera</ENAMEX>, the daughter of migrant farm workers, has been a recruiter and trainer for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MSDR</ENAMEX>. Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX>'s parents worked the sugar beet fields before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX>.   It's children, not that unlike herself, she serves on a daily basis, providing them with information on services available to migrant workers and options for them to earn their education.   A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> native, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> moved back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX> after a year of living and working as a teacher and a nanny to 24 children living at an orphanage in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocozocoautla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chiapas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chiapas</ENAMEX> is the poorest state in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX>, adding that the state bordering <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guatemala</ENAMEX> is also the least educated in the country.   "When I left in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> they were building the first shopping center in the capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chiapas</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX>. "Most people didn't have refrigerators, stoves or running water."   She moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> after living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> for nine years.   "I wanted to serve the Lord in another aspect, so I sold my house, bought a car and left," she said.   "I had the only Toyota in the whole state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chiapas</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX>. "There were a lot of things about me that stood out."   After a year and a half <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   "My mother was growing older and she was concerned about me living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> by myself," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX>.   After a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> was preparing to move back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, where she had lived for nine years before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, when one of her brothers encouraged her to make her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   It was partially because of her recent experience living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> was chosen as a recruiter and trainer for the Migrant Student Data and Recruitment office, which serves a variety of migrant ethnic groups in the state.   As a recruiter and trainer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> is on the road three weeks each month.   She and the other recruiters in her office work with two different kinds of school districts, project districts, which receive federal grants for migrant students, and non-project districts, which do not receive any funds, she said. In project districts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> said they work as trainers, teaching home visitors and record clerks how to identify and recruit migrant students in their school districts.   In non-project districts, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> looks for migrant children who are not in school and encourages them to go back to school and earn their degree. She also talks to the district about applying for federal funds.   "I'm trying to work myself out of a job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> laughed.   In 2003-2002 there were 49,765 migrant youths identified. The youths are being served by both the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MSDR</ENAMEX> and home visitors.   The youth they serve are not just Hispanic. She said that numerous ethnic groups are served by her office, but Hispanic and Native American youths seem to get the most attention since they have the highest dropout rate.   "Our goal is to get them back in school and to persuade them to graduate," she said.   With 12 years working for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MSDR</ENAMEX> under her belt she has seen quite a few youths graduate from high school and move on to college who probably wouldn't have if she had not been there to encourage them to go to school.   As a recruiter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> has a protocol to follow before going into a school district.   She said they first contact the superintendent and ask for permission to work in their school district. If they are approved, they contact English as a second language teachers in the community and any agencies that might cater to the migrant population and be able to help locate the families, she said.   In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> months <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX>'s job takes a more proactive role.   She said because of the impact of people moving to the agricultural areas to work in the apples, cherries, pears and other agricultural industries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> actually goes to the labor camps and fields to find youth and their families.   "It's hard in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. I'll be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tonasket</ENAMEX> and it will be 108 degrees in the shade," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> said the educational services are among the most important the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MSDR</ENAMEX> program offers.   "We try to find programs such as the high school equivalency program (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HEP</ENAMEX>) and portable assistance study sequel (PASS) for they youth," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX>.   She said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MSDR</ENAMEX> also has free accident insurance available for migrant children living in the state.   "Letting them know what services are out there and what services are available so they can be successful, to me, that is what's important about my job," she added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

