
<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds beat <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, fall to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SELAH</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> played seven games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, sweeping past the Ellensburg Bulldogs in a three-game match, then falling to the Selah Vikings in a 3-1 match.   The Ellensburg team was the first team the Lady 'Hounds came up against <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, beating them by scores of 25-10, 25-12 and 25-11.   "We paid them back for the jamboree," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX>, referring to the season opening jamboree where <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> came out to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said one big difference between the jamboree match-up and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s competition was the addition of senior Danelle Cowan. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowan</ENAMEX> didn't play at the jamboree.   "We were a little different team," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.   He added that overall his dteam did very well against the Bulldogs.   "We played some very good volleyball, until we fell apart," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of the two matches.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX>, his team fell apart about halfway through the match-up with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>. The Lady 'Hounds managed to win the first game of the afternoon against the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>, 25-11, but never found their rhythm after that, falling to the Selah team by scores of 25-21, 25-11 and 25-15.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> was able to take us out of our game and we didn't make good adjustments," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.   He added that the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> were able to do a couple of things that took his team out of its offense.   "We got a little frustrated and played poorly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said he was happy with the girls' performance during the first four or five games of the afternoon.   "We're starting to get there, we're showing an increasing amount of promise," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> noted that both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tonhya Wysong</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowan</ENAMEX> played well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. Wysong had 46 digs for the afternoon, while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowan</ENAMEX> had 32 kills, 27 digs and 9 blocks. Also helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> with 6 kills and 29 digs, Kealey Johnston with 8 kills and 35 digs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> with 18 kills, 6 blocks and 8 aces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> with 8 kills and 7 blocks, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chante Bottineau</ENAMEX>, who had 68 assists.   The Lady 'Hounds (2-0, 3-1) will play again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at Ki-Be.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

