
<P ID="1">Voters say '<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX>'
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/4/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters gave their overwhelming support for two issues which will raise their property taxes, but in turn will bring in millions of dollars in state equalization funds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next four years</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> was the only district in the region to offer two measures on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> ballot, both of which were detailed and at points confusing to understand. But in the end, through the efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES Committee</ENAMEX> and district officials, voters apparently understood the economic soundness of the district's proposal, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Winfree</ENAMEX>, co-chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> group. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s approval of the district's proposals will mean the construction of two new schools in the district, as well as enhancement and expansion of current programs.   Voters passed the district's request for an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> bond with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">63 percent</NUMEX> "yes" vote. A four-year special levy proposition seeking <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> annually from district patrons received a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX> approval rating. The passage of both issues will mean local taxpayers will now pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.61</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> assessed property value, up from the current <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.41</NUMEX> rate.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfree</ENAMEX> said he and co-chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Miller</ENAMEX> are ..."extremely pleased with the results" of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfree</ENAMEX> said the percentage of "yes" votes is exceptional.   "Voters really looked at the district's economic justification for the measures and voted in the best interest of the kids," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winfree</ENAMEX> said.   The passage of both measures, coupled with the equalization and matching funds from the state, will generate more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45 million</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> maintenance and operation levy received 1,252 "yes" votes and only 662 "no" votes. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> bond measure received 1,190 "yes" votes and 687 "no" votes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> voters gave a more than adequate <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> approval vote for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195,000</NUMEX> school levy. The measure received 221 "yes" votes and only 53 "no" votes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School</ENAMEX> officials said the voters' approval will enable the district to receive nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$695,000</NUMEX> in state equalization funds each of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next four years</TIMEX>.   "We had great support for the levy from our patrons," said Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX>, who added the money will be used to maintain and enhance the district's curriculum, transportation and basic services available to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> students.   However, a similar levy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger School District</ENAMEX> has a less certain future. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$515,793</NUMEX> levy measure only received 274 "yes" votes, for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">56 percent</NUMEX> of the votes cast, well short of the necessary <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> super majority needed for passage.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

