
<P ID="1">'Hounds open CWAC play with 35-14 victory
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BENTON CITY</ENAMEX> - In its season opener two Fridays ago, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> football team committed more mistakes than it could overcome in a 32-25 loss to class 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the class 2A Greyhounds played nearly error-free. The end result was a 35-14 victory over the hapless Ki-Be Bears.   "We cut our mistakes down from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> first year coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Lamb</ENAMEX>.   The new Greyhound coach said his players also took advantage of what Ki-Be gave them.   "Ki-Be loaded the box to take away the run from us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said. "So we went to the air, and it worked."   All told, a total of six receivers caught at least one pass against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quarterback Brandon Artz</ENAMEX>'s favorite targets, though, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Concienne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX>. The duo combined for three touchdowns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX> gained 153 yards on four receptions, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concienne</ENAMEX> picked up 73 yards on his five catches. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Dill</ENAMEX> also hauled in a TD pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX>, a 36-yarder that got <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> on the scoreboard first.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> finished the night connecting on 11-of-17 passes, which netted 274 aerial yards for the 'Hounds. His four touchdown throws easily offset the one interception <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX> had against him.   When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> (1-0, 1-1) did go to the ground, it was senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX> who took the majority of the hand-offs from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> put the punctuation mark on the game for the 'Hounds with his 3-yard touchdown run late in the third quarter. His short scamper gave <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> a 35-0 lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> finished with 50 hard fought yards, coming on 14 totes. Teammate J.R. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camacho</ENAMEX> added six rushing yards on four carries.   Ki-Be, which was limited to 192 yards of offense, scored two fourth quarter touchdowns after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> began subbing freely from his bench.   The win over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX> came in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX> league opener. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, which was dropped from the 3A ranks to class 2A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, is making its debut in the CWAC this season, after having played in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> for several years.   But if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> fans think the 'Hounds are going to have a cakewalk through the class 2A CWAC this season, they might want to think again. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> hosts the perennially tough Connell Eagles this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> says his club has its work cut out for it.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> is huge, and very physical," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said. "They nearly knocked off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> is the top rated 2A team in the state."   To beat <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> the Greyhounds are going to have to win the war in the trenches, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>.   "Our line is going to have to play big against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX>," he said. "The game will either be won up front or lost up front."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> is hoping his linemen turn in as strong of an effort against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX> this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> as they did against Ki-Be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>. "Our line did a super job of protecting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>," he said.   The defensive line of the 'Hounds also excelled against Ki-Be, especially defensive end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody McMillen</ENAMEX>. Outside linebacker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mejia</ENAMEX> turned in a strong effort, as well, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX>. The Greyhounds' defensive secondary might have played even stronger against Ki-Be, as they limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX> to just 49 passing yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX>, playing cornerback, had an interception for the 'Hounds, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Emerson</ENAMEX> from the other cornerback slot also shined with excellent defensive run support.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">bstory@hawkpress.com   Grandview</ENAMEX> 7 21 7 0 -35   Ki-Be 0 0 0 14 -14   RUSHING - (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX> 14-50, J.R. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Camacho</ENAMEX> 4-6. (Ki-Be) 143 yds. total.   PASSING - (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX> 11-17-1 274, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Concienne</ENAMEX> 2-3-0 14. (Ki-Be) 49 yds. total.   RECEIVING - (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> 4-153, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Concienne</ENAMEX> 5-73, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Dill</ENAMEX> 1-36, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX> 1-12, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel Calvillo</ENAMEX> 1-8, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pedroza</ENAMEX> 1-6.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

