
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate would like to argue for a living
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Given her small physical stature, one could be a little taken back by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Durbin</ENAMEX>'s intent on wanting to argue in a courtroom some day. But, making a living as an attorney is exactly what the 16-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> junior wants to do.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> won't be arguing when she takes to the stage for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> is one of eight young ladies who will be vying for the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as part of the annual community Sunshine Days festivities.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill and Dolores Durbin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She is being sponsored in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s pageant by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gas Company</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Van de Graaf Ranches</ENAMEX>.   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> began working at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Gas Company</ENAMEX>.   At school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> is involved with numerous activities, including volleyball, basketball, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor Society</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Future Farmers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>. But cheerleading is something that has grabbed the attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>.   "Being a basketball girl, I didn't think the cheerleaders worked that hard," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>. "I have been proven wrong. It is a lot of hard work to be a cheerleader."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> also has another passion she enjoys and that is playing the piano. About <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">nine years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> learned the art of the piano from her sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi Nordberg</ENAMEX>.   "She always played the piano," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>. "I like playing the piano because it is a really good stress reliever. It is cool to be able to do something really well."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> will be performing a piano solo in the talent portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant.   When she is not cheering on the home team or trying to master <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX> on the piano, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> stays busy with her youth group at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Reform Church</ENAMEX>. She also enjoys spending time with her family and has taken up the aerobic workout of kickboxing. She is also an avid reader of classic novels and enjoys walking on the pathway and shopping.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> has also taken up learning the language of love, French. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said she has become versed enough in French to order a dinner, but isn't so fluid in the language she can carry on a prolonged conversation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said she has a dream of being able to tour <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>, which would include a stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paris</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said she decided to compete for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> title because she viewed it as a good way to become involved with the community.   "I thought it would be a good way to give back to the community I have grown up in my whole life," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> does have one momento from her childhood she is hoping will bring her good luck. When she was 3-years-old, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> went to one of the parades and then reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Mercer</ENAMEX>, gave the young spectator one of her gloves.   "Maybe it is a good luck charm," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>.   So far, preparing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant has been an enjoyable experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said all of the contestants have gone shopping together and went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tri-Cities</ENAMEX> pageant.   "It has been a blast," she said.   After she graduates from high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> wants to study law at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>.   "I think justice is really important. I want to make sure people get what they deserve," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>. "I am opinionated. I like to argue."   If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> is named to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, she would like to make working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice organization her community service project. She wants to work with the hospice agency because she knows what it is like to have a family member suffer with cancer.   "I know how much a family needs encouragement at this time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said she enjoys living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> because of the small, friendly size of the town.   "When you drive through town everyone is really friendly and willing to help you out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> did say she wishes there was more to do here.   "I think there needs to be more things to do on the weekends for teens," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>. "We need to do more community events like the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX>."   Besides working with Hospice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> would like to become involved in a project working with children if she is named to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court.   One of her other goals as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will be to work with her court to help make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a better place to live.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> she would strive to serve as a good role model for the younger children in the community, who look to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in admiration.   "I would like to be a good role model to all the younger girls around," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said she is looking forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant.   "I think it will be a lot of fun," she said. "The talent will be real diversified."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX> said she is looking ahead with hope at the opportunity to possibly serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court.   "I would be very honored to be on the court because it is a privilege," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durbin</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

