
<P ID="1">Yard sale benefit planned for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX> family
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, Gale and Cris Owsley plan to host a community yard sale, hot dog sale and bake sale to help benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX> family.   The sale will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at 905 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Ave.</ENAMEX>, which is located at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ninth Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX> across from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Elementary School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cris</ENAMEX> said she is asking the community to donate items for the yard sale. She said items can be dropped off at the site of the yard sale, which is her home, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday of this week</TIMEX>. She noted that items simply have to be clean and pre-priced.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cris</ENAMEX> noted that she is hoping to see community members come back to the sales event with their checkbooks in hand, ready to purchase what they can. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cris</ENAMEX> said she will also be taking credit card donations.   All of the proceeds from the sale will go to benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX> family, who lost <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie Shifflett</ENAMEX> in a car, bicyclist crash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

