
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s new director of learing formerly of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> is not a new and strange place to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Vegar</ENAMEX>.   Recently hired as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s Executive Director of Learning and Instruction, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> is a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> resident.   In fact, his father taught school in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser School District</ENAMEX> for 34 years before retiring to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Camano Island</ENAMEX>. Ironically, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> is moving back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Camano Island</ENAMEX>, where he was the principal at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camano-Stanwood School District</ENAMEX> high school for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past nine years</TIMEX>.   "My wife's family is also from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>," he added. Long-time Prosser area farmers, her parents recently retired to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, he explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> began his new duties <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> by settling into his office at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s Instruction and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Support Services</ENAMEX> office, located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Blaine</ENAMEX> building on Custer Avenue.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said making the move from being a building principal to the overseer of a district's network of learning and instructional activities was too good to pass up.   "I wanted to be in a position to serve teachers, administrators and students in a different way," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> expects to suffer some form of withdrawal come the first day of school. "This will be the first time in 23 years that I will not be in a school building," he explained.   But, eager to begin his work on the district level, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> brings a wealth of experience in school law, and a background in education reform.   "I've worked on education reform in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said. "I believe I have the talents for this job," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX>, who is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX>, earned his Master's at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Hawaii</ENAMEX>. He is now working on his doctorate.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> began his career in education as an industrial technology and electronics teacher. He has also worked as an athletic and activities director, taught college level classes and most recently taught school law at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Anitoch University</ENAMEX> in Seattle.   Saying he hopes to bring a sense of balance to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> learning environment, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said his biggest task will be focused on taking care of the students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said his job is to provide students with the tools necessary to meet the state-mandated assessment standards. Despite the current unrest among school districts regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) and the mandated Certificate of Mastery required of all students before they are allowed to graduate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> district will continue to do everything it can to help students and teachers meet that goal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said the reality is that the WASL and the Certificate requirement is the law. While the politicians deal with that issue, he will be making sure <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students have all they need in order to meet the state standards, he said.   "We take this very seriously," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said he is charged with making sure there is improvement in student learning each year, an issue made even more important in light of the implementation of President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s "No Child Left Behind Act."   "We also have to be accountable to the federal government for showing that our students are making academic progress," he said.   "We have to show yearly academic progress," he said, noting that the district has several assessment tools at its disposal for judging progress.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said the students' academic improvements are gauged by three assessment tools, including the Iowa Test of Basic Skills, the Iowa Test of Educational Development and of course, the WASL.   "I think also we have to remember that education goes deeper than testing, even though we do have to meet the letter of the law," he said.   To do that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> hopes to be able to maintain a balance between the No Child Left Behind mandates and the new state graduation requirements, while taking care of the children's needs.   "I realize that is a tall order," he said.   "But it is what we are going to do," he said.   "We just have to keep things in perspective," he said.   "Our first job is always to take care of kids. We have to give kids experiences in academics, activities, athletics, arts and citizenship," he said. "All of those experiences are needed to help prepare our kids to become contributing adults and good citizens," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

