
<P ID="1">Grizzlies in second after sweep of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Good pitching can keep just about any baseball team in a game to the very end. Bad pitching can make a team not even want to take the field.   Case in point, this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>'s home doubleheader for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> baseball team against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> rival <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.   The opening game pitted pitchers of opposing styles against one another. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Uberuaga</ENAMEX> got the best of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky Adams</ENAMEX> in a 3-2 decision. Not even utilizing four pitchers in the second game could help the Mustangs, as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s bullpen fell apart in a 14-1 loss.   The Grizzlies (4-1, 7-3) are tied with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> for second place in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>, heading into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s single game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> are a game behind 5-0 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.   One not so stellar inning was the only blemish on an otherwise stellar outing from Grizzly pitcher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Uberuaga</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> went the distance for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the opener, collecting 10 strikeouts while allowing only four hits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> did give up two walks and had one hit batter.   The Mustangs dinged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> for a pair of runs in the top of the fifth inning. In the frame, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> mixed in a pair of singles on top of the walk and hit batter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> had to score the pair of runs.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX> pitched a very nice game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Coach Dave Martinez. "He had some velocity going into the seventh inning."   On the opposing side, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> batters had trouble reading the pitches of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> still managed to tag <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> for eight hits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Esqueda</ENAMEX> were both 2-for-3 at the plate in the opener for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "We weren't adjusting to the slower pitchers again," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "We have to be able to make that adjustment from pitcher to pitcher."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> scored a pair of runs in the third inning. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Newberry</ENAMEX> singled to plate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Hazzard</ENAMEX> and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Johnson</ENAMEX> had a base hit to bring in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newberry</ENAMEX>. The Grizzlies' other run came in the fourth inning when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esqueda</ENAMEX> doubled to score <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sanchez</ENAMEX>, who was pinch running for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX>.   The nightcap was a debacle for the Mustangs. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> gave up 15 walks and hit four <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> batters in the 14-1 loss.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> scored its lone run in the top of the second off starting pitcher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah Zakahi</ENAMEX>, who put in a solid three innings of work.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zakahi</ENAMEX> had five strikeouts and scattered four hits. R.J. Elizondo worked a strong two innings of relief, giving up no hits and only one walk.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah</ENAMEX> pitched well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies had two runs in the first inning and exploded for eight runs in the second. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> added one more run in the third and three runs in the fourth.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s eight-run second inning, the Grizzlies took advantage of six <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> walks, a hit batter and strung together three singles and a double from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Uberuaga</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> had an interesting statistic in the second game. The Grizzly catcher went 0-for-0 at the plate, but had four walks and recorded four RBIs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Anderson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX> were both 2-for-3 at the plate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newberry</ENAMEX> had three walks in the second game to bring his total to a team high 10 on the season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newberry</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> lead <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in walks with 10 apiece.   "Our kids did a nice job of waiting for pitches," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "When they did throw a fast ball, our kids jumped right on it."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he isn't quite sure what to expect going into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said the Bulldogs have lost a number of players off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s squad, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> is still carrying some talent.      
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

