


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> re-appointed to planning group
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/4/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved the request of Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">re-appoint Raul Martinez</ENAMEX> to the city planning commission.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> has served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 31, 2000</TIMEX>. His new term will expire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 15, 2008</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   "This appointment is forwarded to you (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>) with my full confidence in the appointee's abilities to fulfill the duties of a planning commissioner," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> in his appointment letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="6">Webmaster
</P><P ID="7">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




