


<P ID="1">Cherry Festival means fun for everyone
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sun</TIMEX> was shining bright as the Granger Cherry Festival kicked off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> with a parade that included community floats, a local marching band and everything in between.
</P><P ID="5">   Taking home awards from the first parade of the season were the Harrah and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> community floats, with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrah</ENAMEX> taking first place and the Mayor's Award in the population under 5,000 category. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> took second place in the same category. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Service</ENAMEX> club winners were Tannewasha, which took first place in the category, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah Lions Club</ENAMEX>, which took second place. The first place winner in the commercial category was the entry from B&D Farms. In the category for community floats from towns with a population of more than 5,000, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> took first place and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> second. In the same category the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> float with its Midsummer's Night Dream theme was presented the Sweepstakes Award.
</P><P ID="6">   Besides hosting a colorful parade, the Cherry Festival also included plenty of activities in the park from carnival rides to different foods to try.
</P><P ID="7">   Across the street from the downtown park was the Cherry Festival Youth Art Show, which featured metal work, drawings and paintings by local youth.
</P><P ID="8">   In the pre-school through fourth grade category second grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Ramos</ENAMEX> took first place, first grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Ramos</ENAMEX> took second place and kindergartner Graciela Maldonaldo took third. In the fifth through eighth grade category seventh grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Rodriguez</ENAMEX> was awarded first place, eighth grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Camacho</ENAMEX> took second and eighth grader Adilene Caballero took third. In the ninth through 12th grade category the duo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vince Castro</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Quazada</ENAMEX> took first place, ninth grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Diaz</ENAMEX> took second and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nestor Quezada</ENAMEX> took third. The best of show winner was senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Qumones</ENAMEX>, J. Padilla and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Zungia</ENAMEX> with their scrap metal creation "Dragon." The winner of the art show drawing was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Marin</ENAMEX>
</P>





 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




