
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> student selected for visit to nation's capital
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Rather than watch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> fireworks from her home, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Lara</ENAMEX> will have the opportunity to see the sparklers light up the sky over the nation's capital <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> has been selected to attend the Presidential Classroom Scholars Program in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3-10</TIMEX>.   "In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of this year</TIMEX> I served as a Senate Page at our state capital," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX>. "I have recently been accepted to the Presidential Classroom. I am very excited to further my knowledge and interest in politics."   During the week-long program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> will interact with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> insiders, including members of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, presidential appointees, senior military officials, top business leaders and journalists. She will also have the opportunity to observe the U.S. Congress in action. And, she will have the opportunity to debate current issues with her peers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> and abroad.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> will also be able to visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>, which is by special invitation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of State and Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX>. She will also be briefed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Intelligence Agency</ENAMEX>, visit foreign embassies and participate in a mock presidential election.   "Our students meet and question the people who make and shape our nation's policies. No other program melds leadership, academics and current events in such an appealing combination," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Buechner</ENAMEX>, former congressman and CEO and president of the Presidential Classroom Scholars program. "Our students return home with a new perspective on American politics and the world."   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>, the Presidential Classroom Scholars program, a non-profit and non-partisan program, has hosted more than 100,000 of the best and brightest high school juniors and seniors from around the world.   The sophomore is active at her high school, participating in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">DECA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Club</ENAMEX>, the varsity cheer squad and the varsity golf team. She is also involved in her church and is a church volunteer. She also has interests in politics, current events, history, sports, music and martial arts.   She is looking for anyone interested in helping sponsor her trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. Those interested can contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX>, 882-8059.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

