
<P ID="1">Open Mike
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">This column follows <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s "EPIC ENCOUNTER" on the glorious grounds of Valley Lanes.   The epic encounter I am referring to is <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> bowling team and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucky Strikes-Darrell Stenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Stenberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Newhouse</ENAMEX> and Dusty Van Hollebeke. The Lucky Strikes won <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting and earned the right to be in a bowl off between other teams who won the different thirds in our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mixers League</ENAMEX> in hopes of winning the big money.   My partners on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> team are Rod Wells and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vickie Vanderhoef</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX> is also vice president of the league, which basically means he can get a cup of coffee real cheap with his administrative title.   We like to refer to our story as the "Miracle at Valley Lanes."   Bowling is something I have only been doing for the last couple of years when my boss, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>, brought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX> and I in a set of bowling bowls-matching I might add. A bunch of us down at the newspaper formed a team a couple of years ago. We didn't win the league championship, but we had fun. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX> was even named the bowler of the year.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, I wasn't able to bowl with our team because league play was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> nights and I had my weekly meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the league moved to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> nights and the rest of our prized team quickly abandoned ship on us. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vickie</ENAMEX> and I have held our own. We have even had a little help from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>, who saved our bacon one week late in this season and helped set up <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s epic encounter.   I have no great bowling style. In fact, at the start of the season the gutter was a place my ball called home. I just throw the bowl straight down the lane now and see how many pins I can pick up.   For the first two parts of this season we were every other team's homecoming game. For those of you who may not know, a football team usually schedules a weaker opponent for its homecoming game to help ensure victory. But by the latter part of the season, which stretches from fall until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX> when we finish up the league, we started picking it up. It doesn't hurt either that we have a combined handicap of something like 345 pins. Usually, we are 100 or more pins up on everyone before play actually begins. Recently, we have bowled like gods. I mean gods. We tore up the lanes. We went through a period where we climbed in to first place in the league. During the four-week stretch we swept our opponents I bowled my second 200 game. Sure, I only made it by one pin, but hey.   After a week off because of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> holiday, we were a bit rusty. We also were trying to figure out how much money we owed to the league since our teammates who committed abandoned us and left <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vickie</ENAMEX> and I to fend for ourselves.   We were a bit distracted this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Sunday</TIMEX> as we went up against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps</ENAMEX>. None of them really helped our cause as we made a run to secure our title. If we had been the Titanic at that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce</ENAMEX> would have been the icebergs that sank us. But we still held our own, the opposition only won the first two games by a combined 32 pins before we stormed back to a dominating third game victory to garner the split. Meanwhile the Lucky Strikes swept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Bieber</ENAMEX> and his team. Just so everyone knows, if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andi Bieber</ENAMEX> had bowled that final game, her team would have won and there wouldn't have been the need for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s epic encounter.   We took a three-person team into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s EPIC ENCOUNTER and nearly got it done. But, Van Hollebeke's 256 in the last game sank our chances of moving on for greater glory. Not even my best series ever, tossing games of 213-132-156, was enough to get us on the path to championship glory. The last game proved to be much like the seventh game of an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBA</ENAMEX> championship contest. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> won the first game by 73 pins. The Lucky Strikes come back and win the second game by 74 pins and then Hollebeke's 256 sank us in the last game. Of course, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Newhouse</ENAMEX>'s series didn't help us either. Nor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darrell</ENAMEX>'s or his wife's.   But now the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> knows what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Mariners</ENAMEX> feel like. The crushing agony of having a championship within your sights to only let it slip through your fingers like wet noodles.   But, as someone just told me, there is always <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

