


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARTHA ELAINE BRYSON-GILMOUR</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARTHA ELAINE BRYSON-GILMOUR</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Elaine Bryson-Gilmour</ENAMEX>, 68, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richland</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 25, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richland</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">She was born in a rural farming community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elsie and Vernon Bryson</ENAMEX>. She grew up with three brothers and two sisters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stanton</ENAMEX> until they relocated to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> and then to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. She graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>. She was employed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Old National Bank</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1954 to 1955</TIMEX>. She then moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richland</ENAMEX> and worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle First National Bank</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> she met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George G. Gilmour</ENAMEX>. They were married in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960</TIMEX> and made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richland</ENAMEX>. She worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nucleonics Alliance</ENAMEX>, which later became OCAW Local I-369 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1976 to 1994</TIMEX>. She later attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Basin Community College</ENAMEX>, where she received her Associate’s Degree in applied science and a certificate in chemical dependency counseling. After completing school she worked for Choices and Changes and was involved with Al-Anon, Al-Ateen and the Contact Help Line.
</P>

<P ID="7">She is survived by her husband of 44 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Gilmour</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland</ENAMEX>; four sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George F. Gilmour</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David M. Gilmour</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Renton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Allen Gilmour</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Robert Gilmour</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>; eight grandchildren; two great-grandchildren; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Fritts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bryson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8">She was preceded in death by her parents; three brothers; and two sisters.
</P>  
<P ID="9">Memorial services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 30, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bethel</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX>, 600 Shockley Rd, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richland</ENAMEX>. Graveside services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 30, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Cemetery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, under the direction of Jones Funeral Home. In lieu of flowers, those wishing to honor Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilmour’s</ENAMEX> memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-City Cancer Center</ENAMEX>, 7350 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deschutes Ave. Building A. Kennewick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX>.
</P>  
<P ID="11">99336. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P>





 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




