
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary</ENAMEX> leader praises <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>'s charity work
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A story about a little girl's view of the seven wonders of the world was part of visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotarian Derek Bottomley</ENAMEX>'s message during his visit with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary Club</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>.   "The little girl was asked to write what things she felt should be included as the seven wonders of the world," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomley</ENAMEX> explained.   "Her teacher, thinking the child would list such man-made marvels as the Great Wall of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China</ENAMEX>, was touched when the girl wrote the following: "The seven wonders of the world include the ability to see, hear, taste, feel, touch, laugh and love," explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomley</ENAMEX>.   "The little girl's version of the seven wonders of the world serves to remind us of the importance of our service to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rotary</ENAMEX>," said the Canadian, who now serves as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> Governor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rotary District</ENAMEX> 5060.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomley</ENAMEX>, a retired banker from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kelowna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>, was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as part of his tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rotary</ENAMEX> clubs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomley</ENAMEX> oversees a district which covers the central part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clearwater</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomley</ENAMEX>, who has been a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary International</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>, praised the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>'s 27 members for their support of such charitable projects as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">International Rotarian</ENAMEX>'s polio eradication program, Roto-plast, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary International Foundation</ENAMEX>, as well as the youth exchange program, which is a large part of the international relationships fostered by the network of businessmen and company executives.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomley</ENAMEX> encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Rotarians to continue to do good work and to continue to add to its membership.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottomley</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary International</ENAMEX> is preparing to celebrate 100 years of service <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and continues to be dedicated to programs involving eradication of illiteracy, unsafe water, diseases and hunger in developing countries.   "Most of us live comfortably in safe and clean environments," he noted. "We can celebrate our situation by continuing to help those who need our help," he said.   "I want to thank you (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> members) for your continued support of international projects, but also for your continued efforts centered on local projects, such as the swim team, your <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> giving and scholarships to area students," he said.   "I'm proud to serve this district which takes as its motto - "we are dependable, reliable and available," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

