
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> opts to make collective bargaining discussions open to public
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The public's right to know ended up superseding city employee's rights to privacy during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting.   For the past several months, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> has been lobbying to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> open collective bargaining sessions with city employees' union representatives. In a couple of instances before <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> rejected <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s idea of opening the collective bargaining sessions.   But with a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in place, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s vote went <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s way. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> were the only ones to vote against the measure, citing a need for the city to protect the privacy of its employees.   The new amendment to the Council Rules of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Procedure</ENAMEX> calls for all discussions and reports, except for the initial strategy session concerning collective bargaining, to be open to the public for discussion. The amendment also says the initial strategy session held in executive session will detail the city's plans for negotiations with the different union groups.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> provided some background for his reasoning as to why he has been pushing so hard to open the executive sessions to the public.   Under the former system the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had for negotiations, the governing body would meet in executive session to discuss the parameters for contract negotiations. The two sides would meet and discuss the proposals, followed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting in executive session again to go over the counter proposals. When the two sides reached an agreement, a contract would be devised and presented in an open public session for approval.   "There is no public input on any of this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said under the old system once the new contract comes before the public, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has no choice but to approve it without the benefit of public input.   "The public is just flapping their jaws (if they talk about the contract when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves it) because if we vote no, we have a problem here with unfair labor practices," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. "It is basically just a charade to bring (the contract) out here in public. The public has a right to know. It is their money."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>, saying he didn't realize when he was elected to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that he wouldn't be able to discuss what was going on to his constituents.   "There is a place for executive session," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>. "(But) we are spending the public's money. They have a right to know."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> explained to those in attendance the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is not able to discuss what is going on in collective bargaining, but the different bargaining units aren't prohibited from going before the public with their version of events.   "It is important for the public to know what is going on in these executive sessions," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX>.   One of the concerns voiced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> was opening collective bargaining discussions to the public there would be the likelihood that the process would take even longer than it does now. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said the overall process for bargaining wouldn't change, where each side meets with its representatives. The only area that would change would be receiving public input on the matter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> was also concerned about making the personal information of public employees common knowledge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said through his brief discussions with staff members, he found out they would not appreciate the discussions taking place in public.   "I just worry about staff and how they are going to feel about it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>.   "We need to be supportive of our staff," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said executive sessions serve a purpose, in this Sing it is to develop a strategy for negotiations.   "Executive session is for the benefit of the public," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said.   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> disagreed with the comments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.   "The public needs to know we are not doing anything secretively," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX>. "The public needs to know. They have a right to know. The public's right to know far outweighs our secrecy here."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> that during the executive session at the beginning of his term, he didn't know what was going on because the matters being discussed weren't public knowledge.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> further felt by making collective bargaining issues public it might relieve some of the pressures for city employees.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> was in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s proposal, but expressed concern the different bargaining groups would try to start talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members, once the matter became open to the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> wanted to make sure the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> left bargaining matters up to city staff.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> said it has long been his goal to make the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s business public knowledge.   "I think this is one area we can let the public know what we are doing," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>. "I think it is going to give the public an opportunity to see (how we work)."   Not everyone agreed.   "I think you guys are opening <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pandora</ENAMEX>'s Box," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firefighter Bob Johnson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that opening discussions to the public could come back to haunt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said the public might feel city employees aren't being paid enough if the matter became public knowledge.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clint Carter</ENAMEX>, who works for the city's public works department, said salaries of city employees are public knowledge, but warned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that if the citizens are going to talk about salaries, then city employees weren't going to sit back and do nothing.   "The public employees are going to stand up at this podium and comment as well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

