
<P ID="1">Day reporting helps juveniles return to school
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/18/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Moyer</ENAMEX> of the day reporting program spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> about the program, which is designed to help transition juvenile offenders back into school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said each student in the program is court mandated to attend classes as a part of the day reporting program. Students from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> are attending classes at the facility, located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The program is designed to have three adults working directly with the youths, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>, who is the teacher at the facility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vianca Herrera</ENAMEX> keeps order in the classroom and there is a position for a case manager in the classroom to help students work through issues. Currently, there isn't a caseworker at the day reporting school.   "This is not a permanent stop," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>. "This is a transitional program, where we get them working on earning some credits."   He said they also help socialize students and prepare them to return to the classroom.   Geared toward students ages 14 to 18 years old, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said some students who are 17-years-old haven't been in a classroom for three years.   "They have a hard time getting up in the morning," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrera</ENAMEX> work directly with students, providing them positive adult interaction and a means to reach goals.   Although some students require two to three months in the day reporting program, some are able to return to school in as little as two weeks, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>.   He said the program is designed to help troubled youths who haven't been successful in any other school environment, such as the regular high school or alternative school.   "A lot of these kids aren't only not having a whole lot of success in academics," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>. "There's not a whole lot of success in other aspects of their lives either. This is a last chance for a lot of these kids."   Since the start of the program four students have transitioned back into school and additional youths will be going back by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the month</TIMEX>.   Although the program is court-ordered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the students enrolled in the day reporting program want to go back to school and do everything they can to comply with the court order.   "Our recommendation goes a long way into getting them back into school," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>, who added that the program is a joint effort between numerous agencies, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> 105, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, Comprehensive Mental Health and the juvenile court system.   "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Twenty-five percent</NUMEX> don't want to be there, but are still required to attend," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>.   The first month <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood police</ENAMEX> officers were picking up students living at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> addresses who were not making it to class, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrera</ENAMEX>. After a few times, the students started attending classes on their own rather than having the police show up at their doorstep.   Students who choose not to behave or comply are put under electronic monitoring house arrest, but are still required to attend classes or will be sent to the juvenile detention center, he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said he is in search of service projects the students can work on to help tie the students to the community.   "We want them to feel good about giving," he said.   The students are volunteering at the National Wildlife Refuge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> will be working at the rose garden in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> is also seeking donations of old furniture that can be used in a reading corner in the classroom. He said his desire is to create a space that is comfortable for the students to relax and read.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

