


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PATRICIA FAY ATCHISON</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PATRICIA FAY ATCHISON</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia “Pat” Fay Atchison</ENAMEX>, 55, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 18, 2004</TIMEX>, at her home surrounded by her family.
</P>

<P ID="6">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13, 1947</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montebello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> to Vaudrey Todd and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ola Fay (Freeman) Boren</ENAMEX>. She received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Following her education she resided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hayden Lake</ENAMEX> area for 20 years, where she worked as a bartender and also on the family cattle ranch.
</P>

<P ID="7">She is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Gaither</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Gaither</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lawrence</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kan.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Gaither</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindie</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX>; four grandchildren; three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Gardner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Wright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie West</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Boren</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8">She was preceded in death by her parents; and one son.
</P>

<P ID="9">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, April 21, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 23, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at Prairieview Cemetery in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hayden Idaho</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MARIA JUANA ORNELAS RODRIGUEZ</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Juana Ornelas Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, 76, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> went to be with the Lord <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, April 19, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 a.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="12">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 27, 1928</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">San Luis Potosi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. She came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. She met and married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel B. Rodriguez</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1949</TIMEX> they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where they settled and raised their children.
</P>

<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX> was a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and was very devoted to her faith. She was in the church choir for many years. She loved life and all her children.
</P>

<P ID="14">She enjoyed gardening, music, sewing, knitting and cooking for all her family.
</P>

<P ID="15">She is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Rodriguez</ENAMEX>; 11 children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raquel Burgueno</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meadow Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda Melendez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Valdez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdon Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Castro</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Daniel Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and companion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Sanchez</ENAMEX>;
</P>  
<P ID="16">24 grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krystle</ENAMEX>, Ermalinda, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meadow Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benny</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conrad Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Catalina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricky</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abdon Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew and John Daniel</ENAMEX>; and seven great-grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony</ENAMEX>, Rhyen, Jorden, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Michael</ENAMEX> and Orian.
</P>

<P ID="17">She was preceded in death by her parents; and one granddaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Perez</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX> will be missed by all her family, but she will live in our hearts forever.
</P>

<P ID="19">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, April 21, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 22, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




