
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> dominates in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> frosh season opener
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - There is nothing quite like starting off the season on the right note. Just ask <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> freshman football player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Villanueva</ENAMEX> after his amazing performance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX>'s effort <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> was simply indescribable. He carried the ball 44 times for 321 yards and scored four touchdowns as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> posted a commanding 45-13 victory.   "He has awesome vision," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> freshman coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Braman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Villanueva</ENAMEX>. "He took it to another level <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. Some of the cuts and runs he made were awesome."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> also shined on special teams, racking up nearly 100 yards on kickoff returns.   The first score of the game came in the opening quarter when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibby Briones</ENAMEX> had a 25-yard interception return for a touchdown. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> scored next, punching it in for a touchdown from four yards out. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> missed both 2-point conversion attempts. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> answered with a 68-yard touchdown pass and then a one-yard touchdown run.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> scored both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s touchdowns in the second quarter, one from 12 yards out and the other from eight yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> made good on a two-point conversion off the last touchdown to go up 26-13 into the break.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> opened the second half with a 14-yard touchdown run. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Montelongo</ENAMEX> then scored on a 36-yard touchdown run to put <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> up 39-13 after a successful extra point attempt.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX> had the final touchdown of the game, coming in the fourth quarter on a 20-yard scamper.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX> had a nice night, as well, scoring two touchdowns on two carries for 56 yards. He also had one reception for 31 yards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said one thing he wasn't happy with was the penalties. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had some careless penalties that cost them points.   But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> was pleased with the work of his offensive line.   "They are gelling really well," he said.   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> was pleased with the first game of the season.   "We saw a lot of positive stuff <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> (1-0) hosts <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>'s freshman group <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX>, with game time set for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

