
<P ID="1">Superintendent spells out new bond/levy proposal
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">It basically boils down to what difference does 5¢ make to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents. Well, 5¢ could make a few million dollars difference, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> presented the forthcoming bond/levy proposal, which will go before <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> voters in the next few weeks, to his fellow Rotarians at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> Rotary meeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> patrons who don't vote by absentee ballot will head to the polls on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX> to decide the fate of a bond/levy proposal, which could bring as much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46 million</NUMEX> in funding for new construction to the school district. Absentee voters will receive their ballots in the mail <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 14</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   Of 15 school districts from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has the second lowest tax rate, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.41</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Adams School District</ENAMEX> has only a lower tax rate, at 84¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Adams School District</ENAMEX> receives a large amount of federal funding because it is on Yakama Indian Nation land.   Highland has the highest tax rate in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.49</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> is second at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5.11</NUMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> is third at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.92</NUMEX>.   Prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> never ran a levy, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>. The district only ran a series of bonds, which helped pay for construction at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> and the building of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> patrons started incurring bond debt for the high school construction in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.57</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value. The rate fell to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.27</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> when the bond passed for the construction of Pioneer.   Voters overwhelmingly passed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s first school district levy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">74.7 percent</NUMEX> voting in favor. The levy rate was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.53</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. The money from the levy goes to fund a variety of district activities, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   The district is seeking a small increase from the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX> levy approved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> levy is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX>. The bond issue before voters will be for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX>. If the bond issue is approved, the district will qualify for reimbursement monies from the state, which would make a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> available for construction and remodels.   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> explained, patrons are only paying for the levy, not the bond voters approved in the past. The district pays for the bond using excess revenue dollars from the general fund.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the district for years left untouched millions of dollars in untapped levy equalization money from the state because it didn't have a levy. The state provides school districts with levy equalization money to bring them up to par with funding received in the King <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> school districts.   The bond portion of what the district is proposing to the voters involves several different projects, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the bond issue will help in the construction of two new schools and the modernization of two others.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the district is looking to build a new middle school, sixth through eighth grades, and a new kindergarten through fifth grade elementary school. The bond will also cover the modernization of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the projects will be completed in the order above because of the funding cycle from the state.   With the new make-up, there will be two middle schools, which will be entirely separate from one another, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>. The high school will also be different as the ninth grade will be separated from the rest of the student body in a learning academy type setting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the freshmen will still be able to take part in all high school activities. The remaining buildings in the school district will then become kindergarten through fifth grade buildings.   The district opted to run a bond issue because of the increasing student population. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>, the school district had a head count (actual students in classrooms) of 4,508. The enrollment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> was 5,442 students. Enrollment is projected to increase to 6,291 students by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the district has increased by roughly 100 students every year for the past few years.   "Every time you have 100 kids that is five teachers and five classrooms," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   The district is also running a bond issue to get away from the use of portables to house students. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> currently has 47 portables, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>, many of which are more than 20 years old.   The district will generate about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.7 million</NUMEX> in equalization dollars if the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> levy is passed.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> uses the levy dollars to help pay for some unfunded district activities, such as athletics and safety and security issues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said one benefit of passing the levy is the district will be able to keep its student resource officers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> patrons are going to see a 15¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value increase to cover the bond indebtedness from constructing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer School</ENAMEX>. For a nickel more, pointed out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>, the district will gain a total of about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46 million</NUMEX> in revenues if voters pass both the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> levy and bond issues.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> explained district patrons would be saving money and getting a lot in return by approving the coming measure, since the school board has agreed to only collect the levy from voters. If the new bond cost were passed on to local patrons, the assessment would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.99</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the amount collected on the levy could actually be less if the valuation of the school district changes. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> has a current valuation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$844 million</NUMEX>.   The interesting part to the whole bond/levy issue is that if it fails, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>, district patrons will see their taxes go up 15¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value to pay for the bond debt the district already has on the books. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the district can't afford to pay for the existing bond debt without the levy passing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said for an additional 5¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value the school district will be able to meet its needs and better serve students for years to come.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

