
<P ID="1">Grizzlies get win in double overtime to open season
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s non-league encounter between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> high school football teams pretty much had the look of a season opening game.   The Grizzlies needed two overtime sessions to get by the Greyhounds, 32-25.   "It was quite a game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Mark Marro</ENAMEX>. "We did just about everything to lose it and so did they."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the contest was characteristic of a season-opening game.   "We had a lot of mistakes," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>) made less mistakes than us."   The two teams traded jabs back and forth on the scoreboard.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> got on the board first when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Pacheco</ENAMEX> scampered in from 30 yards out. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s J.R. Camacho countered with a five-yard TD run to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s lead to 7-6.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX> then picked up the first of his three touchdowns on the night in the second quarter with a four-yard touchdown run. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> missed the extra point. The Greyhounds tied the game going into the half when quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX> connected on a 40-yard touchdown pass to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> took a short-lived lead at the opening of the second half when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> punched the ball in from one yard out. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX> came right back for the Grizzlies when he scored on a four-yard touchdown run.   The game would remain tied at 19-19 to end regulation play as neither side could find the end zone in the fourth quarter.   The Greyhounds laid it all on the line in the first overtime session. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> scored the first touchdown of overtime when on 4th and 15, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX> connected on a 27-yard pass play in the corner of the end zone for the touchdown.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> answered right back. The Grizzlies strung together a game-tying drive that ended with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> scoring on a one-yard touchdown run.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> duplicated his feat in the second overtime, scoring on another one-yard touchdown run. The Greyhounds couldn't piece together a touchdown drive, bringing an end to the game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> excelled when the Greyhounds were able to run a couple of fade pass plays that resulted in some big yardage being gained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> was pleased with the way his defense held up against the powerful running attack of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> was held to 58 yards on 23 carries.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> struggled offensively, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   "We weren't clicking real well," he said. "We weren't really up to speed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't throw the ball a lot on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Grizzly quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cantu</ENAMEX> was 5-for-14 for 63 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't put the ball up that much was because <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> was bringing tremendous defensive pressure. He also said that his team was having a lot of success pounding the ball on the ground.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> really stood out running the ball for the Grizzlies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> had 113 yards off 21 carries while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> racked up 96 yards on 12 totes.   One area <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> felt <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> stood out in was its special teams play. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said it was nice to have his special teams unit play well in the first game of the season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> especially noted the play of kicker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> really didn't have a kicker coming into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s game and noted how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> came to the forefront, hitting 2-of-5 extra point attempts.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> also had a lot of praise for the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Garza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucas Ramos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Escobar</ENAMEX> on the left side of the offensive line. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said those three players were able to open up a lot of different options on the field for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> did miss a couple of opportunities to score. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said early in the game, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> stopped the Grizzlies from scoring from the one yard line.   "We will get better," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "I am not completely disappointed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said it was huge for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to open the season with a win.   "It is big for us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "Even with our success <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, we came out of the blocks slow."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> will be looking to build on this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s success. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> (0-0, 1-0) will host <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in the Grizzlies' home opener. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX> lost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Timberlake</ENAMEX>, a team from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Idaho</ENAMEX>, 32-18. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said on the tape he has watched <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX> likes to run a lot of spread offense and they also like to throw a lot of short routes.   "They look like real big guys," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "We will just see how we match up."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

