


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">REC meeting set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">The Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 24</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 p.m.</TIMEX> in the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> conference room.
</P>

<P ID="6">The Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> office is located at 520 S. Seventh St.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> seeks district court
judge applicants
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners are seeking applicants for the position of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County District Court</ENAMEX> Judge. Those interested in the position must be registered voters of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> and admitted to practice law in the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">According to county commissioners, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Bar Association</ENAMEX> will conduct an intitial review and ranking of applications. Following the Bar's screening, the top applicants will be interviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of County</ENAMEX> Commissioners in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, with the successful appointee taking office as soon as possible thereafter. The appointee will have to stand for election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2004</TIMEX> to complete the remainder of the term.
</P>

<P ID="10">Interested applicants are asked to submit a resume and statement of qualification, which includes the applicant's experience working with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> (300 words maximum).
</P>

<P ID="11">Completed applications should be sent directly to Abeyta-Nelson, Attn: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Nelson</ENAMEX>, 1102 W. Yakima Ave., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98902 or via email to rnelson@abeytanelson.com or rarcher@abeytanelson.com.
</P>

<P ID="12">Applications must be received by no later than <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 27</TIMEX>. For more informtion contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner's office at (509) 574-1500.
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




