
<P ID="1">Knowledge Bowl league new <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> has long participated in the KYVE-TV's Apple Bowl, a kind of knowledge pop quiz bowl. But <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, the school will also have a team competing in a different type of athletic event for the mind.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> will compete in the brand new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District 105 Knowledge Bowl</ENAMEX> league, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> team coach.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, who has coached an informal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> team for the past several years, said this will be the first time the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> team will compete in league play, facing 15 teams from 11 school districts.   "In the past, our team has competed with schools outside our region, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> we'll have our own league within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105," he said.   The league held its first meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 11</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> team placing second in total points, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> said.   "We won two oral rounds, so you could say in "direct" competition, we are undefeated," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> explained the Knowledge Bowl contest consists of a timed oral round of 60 questions and a timed written round of 50 questions. The team with the highest score is the winner.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> will host its first home meet after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> break, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> said. The meet will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> said the high school students will compete in a number of rounds, answering chLofferging questions covering science, astronomy, literature, math, current events, history and a wide array of subject matters.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>' four-person team includes seniors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX>, as well as junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Kilian</ENAMEX> as a team alternate.   The rounds encourage the students to use speed and intuition to answer questions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> said league play will include a third meet at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>. A regional meet will be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late February</TIMEX>. The winners from the Regional meet will advance to a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> bowl in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jSmart@hawkpress.com   Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Daily News   Speed and intuition are key to the success of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Knowledge Bowl</ENAMEX> team. The four-person team includes (L-R) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

