


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WAYNE RICHARD POWELL</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WAYNE RICHARD POWELL</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Richard Powell</ENAMEX>, 40, of Moxee passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7, 2004</TIMEX>, of an apparent massive heart attack.
</P>

<P ID="6">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 1963</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, the youngest of eight children of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard and Mary Powell</ENAMEX>. He graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> and then moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. There, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> met and eventually married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Sare</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. Shortly after they moved to Moxee, where they have lived for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 12 years</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> was a good and honest person, a devoted and loving family man and to many, many people a good friend. He loved spending time with his family, especially his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX>. He enjoyed gardening, camping, working in his shop and parachuting. His hobby was wood crafting, at which he excelled. Wood crafting was Wayne’s way of showing off his creative side, which he loved to share with his family and friends.
</P>

<P ID="8">For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past seven years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> was also an intricate pat of Six <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chuter, Inc.</ENAMEX>
</P>  
<P ID="9">Powered Parachutes. As much as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> enjoyed working with wood he found that working with aluminum and steel also satisfied his creative side. In his job <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> touched so many people around the country with his helpfulness and his constant jovial attitude. He truly enjoyed his job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> was a valuable contributor to the design and building of the aircraft. He enjoyed flying and participating in the weekend “fly-ins” throughout the states.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> was a loving husband, father, son, brother, uncle, son-in-law, brother-in-law and friend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> was the one everyone knew they could count on. He was always the first to be there to offer his help to anyone. He had a quick wit, a quick smile and always the first one to laugh at his own jokes; and always able to find the humor no matter what the situation. One of Wayne’s favorite quips., which embodies both his humor and his life was “if you aren’t living life on the edge, you’re taking up too much space!”
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> will be greatly missed by his family, extended family, friends, co-workers and all who knew him.
</P>

<P ID="12">He is survived by his wife and son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX>, both of Moxee; his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Powell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymund Powell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sacramento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Powell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX>; four sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Goetz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Danville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine Tull</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Kamlschke</ENAMEX> of Seattle and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Riel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>; and many nieces and nephews.
</P>

<P ID="13">He was preceded in death by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard L. Powell</ENAMEX>; and sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Powell</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="14">Viewing will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 10, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> chapel of Valley Hills Funeral Home. Recitation of the rosary will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 11, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrement Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Interment will follow in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Cemetery</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15">In lieu of flowers the family has set up a benevolent college fund for Wayne’s 13-year-old son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan</ENAMEX>. Donations may be sent to Valley Hills Funeral Home, 2600 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Business Lane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98901.
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX>, you are barely gone and already we <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> you!
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




