
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> score late to oust Greyhounds from Regionals
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WEST VALLEY</ENAMEX> - Victory was within the grasp of a determined <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> boys soccer team this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>.   But, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> rallied past the Greyhounds in the second half to come away with a 3-2 Regional tournament victory, in the process bringing an end to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s season.   "We could smell it (victory)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Anne Holden</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> compared the game to catching butterflies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said when her Greyhounds took the lead in the second half it was like they caught a butterfly in their hand. She said the game then took a turn like when a person opens their hand to look at the caught butterfly to only watch it fly away.   "We have absolutely nothing to be disappointed about," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. "We played very, very well. In fact, both teams played very well. It was a good game. We had our chances."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> took an early 1-0 lead on a goal at the 29th minute off a set play from a free kick.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said statistically the game was tightly played in the first half. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley outshot Grandview</ENAMEX> 4 to 3 on goal in the first half.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> had the better of the first half," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> gave a fiery talk at the break, telling her team that this would be the end of its season if it couldn't respond.   The Greyhounds must have liked what they heard from their coach, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> came out sizzling in the second half. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s main offensive threat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Alvarez</ENAMEX>, had both of his club's goals in the second half. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> scored at the 61st and 67th minutes of the game to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> a 2-1 lead.   But the always resilient <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rams</ENAMEX> made their usual run and found a way to score a pair of goals within a five-minute span to get the win and move on to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s winner-to-state game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cheney</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> scored at the 71st minute when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> missed its tracking assignment on one of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> players. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said the problem she had was with what her team did after the goal was scored, basically a breakdown in communication. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said most of her players didn't react well to the game-tying goal and kind of let down, not realizing they were still in the game.   "It doesn't matter that you made a mistake," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. "It is what you do after you make the mistake that matters."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> fed off the momentum from the game-tying goal and attacked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s line.   What worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> most of the second half was the Greyhounds were able to take field position away from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX>. Through some repositioning of players, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>'s team was able to pound the ball at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>.   "We had them rocked," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. "We had them on their heels."   Just how effective <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>'s strategy was is reflective in the offensive statistics for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>. The Greyhounds had seven corner kicks in the second half to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>'s one.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> did say there was one opportunity late in the game where a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> defender brought down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> when he was driving on goal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said she felt <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> would have had a good chance at scoring, but the official didn't make the call. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>, though, pointed out again that the game wasn't decide by the officials. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said both she as a coach and her team weren't used to being at that level in the postseason, which came into play in how they reacted to situations.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley outshot Grandview</ENAMEX> 8 to 6 on goal for the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Pacheco</ENAMEX> had five saves as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> keeper in his return after a head injury.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said it was a pleasure for her as a coach to play in a game like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s contest.   "You could smell it (victory). You could taste it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. "We gave it everything we had. We played our guts out."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> finishes its last season in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> with a 7-8 record, which includes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s postseason loss. The Greyhounds, who return to the 2A ranks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, finished 9-8 overall.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This summer</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> boys program will be taking part in four tournaments, including defending its Bulldog Bash title the Greyhounds won at a Pasco tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

