
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">JOHN E
 JOHN E. RAYBURN
John E. Rayburn, 81, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 24, 2004</TIMEX>.
He was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deepwater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles and Nellie Mae Rayburn</ENAMEX>. He graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deepwater High School</ENAMEX>. After graduation he went into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Coast Guard</ENAMEX> and served on the USCG Cutter Mojave. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> he came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, where he met and married his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Palmer</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 1950</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. They made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> for 17 years. He worked for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> Nursery as a foreman until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>. He began his law enforcement career in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>, working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato Police Station</ENAMEX> for eight years. He also worked as a sheriff deputy recruit for one year. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX> he began working for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Sheriff’s Department</ENAMEX>, becoming a sergeant of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> department. He worked there for 22 years.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> he moved with his family to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, where they have made their home. After retiring from his law enforcement career, he became a salesman for Fergies and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderson Motors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his wife of 54 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geraldine Rayburn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Schab</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Seyler</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clay Rayburn</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; five grandsons; 13 great-grandchildren; one great-great-grandson; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leona Delozier Yakima</ENAMEX>; one brother-in-law; and numerous nieces and nephews.
He was preceded in death by his parents; five sisters; and one brother.
Viewing will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 28, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 29, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Interment will follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Hills Memorial Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
In lieu of flowers, donations may be made in Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayburn’s</ENAMEX> name to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Sheriff’s Department</ENAMEX>, Search and Rescue, P.O. Box 1388, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98907.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AROLDO TREVINO
Aroldo Trevino</ENAMEX>, 53, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Regional Hospital</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21, 1951</TIMEX> in Mission, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ildefonso Trevino</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consuelo Falcon</ENAMEX>. At the age of two, he and his family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, graduating with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. He attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> for two years. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14, 1978</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Perez</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. They together have made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.  He worked as a car salesman in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> for a number of years.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Trevino</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Erica Trevino</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ildefonso Trevino</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>; two grandchildren; his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Consuelo Trevino</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estella Trevino</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Trevino</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>; and numerous nieces and nephews.
He was preceded in death by his father; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnaldo</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 28, 2004</TIMEX>, from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be recited at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at Wells Funeral Home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 29, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Wells Funeral Home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>,  is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JOHN R. ASHER
John R. Asher</ENAMEX>, 70, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, June 27, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 14, 1933</TIMEX> in Outlook to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Myrtle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Asher</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, graduating with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX>. Following his high school education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> enlisted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>. Following his military service he returned to Outlook to farm with his father. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 8, 1957</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Fox</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. They made their home and farmed in Outlook, until moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> later began working as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> postal clerk for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Post Office</ENAMEX>, then transferred to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Post Office</ENAMEX> until retiring after 37 years in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of 2004</TIMEX>.
 He enjoyed watching sports, especially watching his children and grandchildren participate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> was also a very loyal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seahawk</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mariners</ENAMEX> fan.
He is survived by his wife of 47 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Asher</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>; five children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Asher</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bakersfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Asher</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minerva</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta Mirelez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenneth Asher</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolanda</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Asher</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanca</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>; 19 grandchildren; five great-grandchildren; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Gentry</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Katy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his parents.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 30, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 1, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HANS THEODORE KOENEN
Hans Theodore Koenen</ENAMEX>, 94, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 25, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
 He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6, 1910</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kaldenhausen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolph and Johanna Koenen</ENAMEX>.  The family came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1926</TIMEX> and located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans</ENAMEX> worked for farmers.  He later moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, where he continued his work on various farms.  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13, 1940</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna Caroline Ogg</ENAMEX>.  They later moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans</ENAMEX> worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Milk Products Company</ENAMEX> for 21 years and then <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bar S. Feedlot</ENAMEX> for nine and half years before retiring.  
He enjoyed traveling, hunting, fishing and spending time with his family.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hans</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna</ENAMEX> of 64 years; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX>; three daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Thomas</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ross</ENAMEX>, Corki Wilcox and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Sundstrom</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>; 17 grandchildren; and 15 great- grandchildren.
He was preceded in death by his parents; two sisters; two brothers; and one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Koenen</ENAMEX>.
Funeral services were held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 28, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial was held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor Hans’ memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of God.
</P>

 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

