
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> earns trip to International Science Fair in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/18/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KENNEWICK</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> has earned a trip to the International Science and Engineering Fair to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>.   The young scientist earned the right to represent her high school at the international event by claiming grand championship honors at the 49th annual Mid Columbia Science and Engineering Fair held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>.   In addition to earning regional championship honors, the petite blonde also claimed a number of special awards offered by the many science-related associations affiliated with the regional competition.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> claimed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Nuclear Society</ENAMEX>'s first place award, a U.S. Air Force Certificate of Achievement, a U.S. Navy/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps Naval</ENAMEX> science award, and a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA Agricultural Research Service</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Potato Foundation</ENAMEX> 12th grade certificate of merit.   Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> earned the Intel Outstanding Achievement in Environmental Science certificate, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Council on System Engineering Outstanding Systems Approach</ENAMEX> recognition and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tri Cities</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sigma Xi</ENAMEX> chapter's Excellence in Use of Scientific Method award.   Also earning top honors at the regional science fair was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kacee Jo Bootsma</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, one of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s regional fair grand champions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bootsma</ENAMEX> took second place honors in the senior division at regionals. In addition, she collected first place honors from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman Institute of Neuroscience</ENAMEX>, as well as a U.S. Air Force Certificate of Achievement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bootsma</ENAMEX> was also named the most outstanding 11th grade exhibitor in computer science, engineering, physics or chemistry by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yale Science</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Engineering Association</ENAMEX>. For the second year in row she was named the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stockholm Junior Water Prize</ENAMEX> winner, which is offered by the Water Environment Federation and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Clean Water Association</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earning</ENAMEX> third place honors in the regional senior division were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias Wise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> also earned the best program in chemical engineering award offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Institution of Chemical Engineers</ENAMEX>. She claimed third place honors offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Nuclear Society</ENAMEX> and a U.S. Air Force Certificate of Achievement.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX> also brought home a second place award offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman Institute of Neuroscience</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earning</ENAMEX> honorable mentions in the high school division were <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Cornelius</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addy Hernandez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> received first place honors from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Mary Medical Center</ENAMEX> for her project, as well as a U.S. Air Force Certificate of Achievement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> also claimed first place in environmental sciences from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, and an honorable mention from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Women Engineers</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halley Rodriguez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was honored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Association of University Women</ENAMEX> with the fair's Outstanding Woman's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Science Project</ENAMEX> award.   In the Mid-Columbia Regional Fair's junior division, two <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> students earned third place honors in their science categories. Eighth grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Barrios</ENAMEX> earned third place honors in the eighth grade life sciences division, while seventh grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Abbott</ENAMEX> earned third place honors in the physical sciences division.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrios</ENAMEX> received special recognition from the Discovery Channel. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbott</ENAMEX> was also recognized for having the outstanding structural engineering project at the fair, designated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Structural Engineering Association of Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Central</ENAMEX> chapter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> student Naomy Velasco received an honorable mention for her project from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Society of Mechanical Engineers</ENAMEX>. Middle schooler Tony Louie received an honorable mention from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Classmate Jessica Clements</ENAMEX> received an honorable mention from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Women Engineers</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> seventh grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Winters</ENAMEX> earned a certificate of excellence from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Apple Education Foundation</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Earning</ENAMEX> honorable mention honors in the eighth grade division of physical sciences were <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Cleghorn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aarika Hernandez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> science fair exhibitors are now preparing to travel to a state competition during spring break, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Stark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> science teacher.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said she will be taking 32 middle school students and 10 high school students to the Washington State Science and Engineering Fair.   The state event will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bremerton High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX> and 3.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

