
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seahawks</ENAMEX> holding football camp in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Seahawks</ENAMEX> kicker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Brown</ENAMEX> will be overseeing two four-hour clinics being sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NFL</ENAMEX> franchise, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX> will be joined by several local coaches for the clinic.   The first of the clinics will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 8</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasco High School</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Seahawks</ENAMEX>' camp will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser High School</ENAMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>   The camps are open to children ages 8 to 15.   For more information on the camp call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garrett Thiemens</ENAMEX> at (206) 381-7902 or visit seahawks.com.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

