
<P ID="1">Young Life growing
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young Life Director Tom Sacher</ENAMEX> had the opportunity to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joni Erickson Tada</ENAMEX> speak to 3,000 Young Life staff members and spouses. The woman, who has been a quadriplegic for 30 years due to a diving accident, attended Young Life activities as a high school student. She shared with the Young Life staff and spouses that it was Young Life kids and leaders that helped her get through more than a year in the hospital, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> told members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> guest speaker spoke to the service club at a time when Young Life is growing in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.   "Young Life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> is at a point where the dam is about to burst," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX>.   The group is two months away from sponsoring its first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyldlife Club</ENAMEX>, which is a group for middle school-aged youth. This will be the first time a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wyldlife Club</ENAMEX> will be available to middle schoolers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.   He said the group already has five adult leaders and a student leader to start <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wyldlife</ENAMEX>, who are beginning to meet middle school aged kids.   "We got permission to go into the middle school and meet kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX>.   He said there has also been interest in starting Young Life clubs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, and he added, he hopes that clubs starting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> are just around the corner.   In looking ahead to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> months, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> said that about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Young Life</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> camp spots have already been spoken for.   "That's huge for us to have middle school and high school kids already thinking about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX>.   The Young Life annual fund-raising brunch is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 20</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navarro's Community Center</ENAMEX>. A silent auction begins at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> with the brunch beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> Youths who have benefited from Young Life will be speaking at the brunch.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> said one of the ways to expand into other areas of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> is to increase the donor base and to develop more volunteer leaders.   "We need 100 people willing to give <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> a month," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX>. "Giving up two Whoppers a month will help us. It's the committed monthly gifts that makes Young Life happen."   For more information about Young Life or to attend the Young Life brunch contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sacher</ENAMEX> at 840-4448.      
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

