


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/10/2002</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

 


<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> cancels <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX> meeting
</P>

<P ID="5">This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> canceled the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 17</TIMEX>, meeting for lack of agenda items. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> usually meets on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, but was scheduled to move the meeting to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> because of President's Day on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 16</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is next scheduled to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Feb. 23</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="7">Also at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> and Councilman John Torch were absent. The two councilmen had received an excused absence at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="8">Councilwoman wants to change way city implements ordinances
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> brought up the issue this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of changing the way the city deals with businesses when implementing new ordinances.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> had brought up the issue of the city contacting businesses directly before implementing any new ordinances during a discussion that resulted in the passage of a new graffiti ordinance banning the sale of such material to anyone under 21. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> felt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> or city staff should check and see what kind of effect new ordinances would have on businesses and gain their input before passing any such ordinances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she also expressed similar concerning dealing with mobile vending and landscaping ordinances. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she wants to have letters sent directly to business owners instead of relying just solely on newspaper articles to get the word out to business owners telling them of any new ordinances.
</P>

<P ID="11">"It values the business owners," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>. "I think we need to talk about the process."
</P>





 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




