


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benedicto</ENAMEX> dominates Sunshine Days tennis tournament
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/23/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wapato</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Khalid Benedicto</ENAMEX> proved to be the man to beat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> in the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Sunshine Days tennis tournament.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benedicto</ENAMEX> claimed the men's open singles title. After advancing through the field, he picked up a forfeit win over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Snook</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tampa Bay</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fla.</ENAMEX> in the finals. In the consolation finals, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eric Town</ENAMEX> blanked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Ruiz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, 6-0, 6-0.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benedicto</ENAMEX> also teamed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Villegas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> to win the men's open doubles crown. The duo cruised through round-robin play unscathed. Their victories included wins over the eventual runners-up, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Oswalt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Robbins</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benedicto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villegas</ENAMEX> also defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seth Debord</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Ruiz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Perkins</ENAMEX>, the third place finishers in men's open doubles play.
</P><P ID="6">   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Sunshine Days tennis tournament women's open champ was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justine Hays</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. Playing a round-robin format, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX> knocked off the second and third place finishers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Sanchez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luz Garza</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s mixed open doubles champions were Alenka Plesha of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Buckingham</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Desert Aire</ENAMEX>. The pair won four matches in round-robin play. The vanquished foes included the eventual second place finishers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Thomas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin Snook</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tampa Bay</ENAMEX>. Plesha and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckingham</ENAMEX> also defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Ramos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the third place finishers, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad and Kimberly Selph</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Wilson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacy DeLeon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Swan</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Ramos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Howell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s men's 3.5 doubles champs. In the finals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howell</ENAMEX> picked up a 6-2, 6-3 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Gapuz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Cerna</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>. The consolation champs in men's 3.5 doubles play were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart Howell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX>, who defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eric Town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryan Weed</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> by a 6-2, 7-5 score.
</P><P ID="9">   Desert Aire's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Buckingham</ENAMEX> was victorious over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan Ta</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> in the boys 16&under singles championship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buckingham</ENAMEX> claimed a 6-3, 6-2 decision. In the 16&under consolation finals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Howell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Apanasov</ENAMEX> 6-3, 4-6, 7-5.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan and Ali Ta</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> were the boys 16&under doubles champs. They ran their record to 4-0 in round-robin play. The second place finishers in that division were Desert Aire's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Buckingham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas McGloughlin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben Nguyen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Apanasov</ENAMEX> placed third.
</P><P ID="11">   The boys 14&under singles titlist was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Carlson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. He knocked off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ryan Town</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX> in the finals by a 6-0, 6-3 score. In the consolation finals, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Porter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> decisioned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Averell Rennie</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> 6-2, 6-0.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Selph</ENAMEX> won the girls 14&under singles championship. She defeated three opponents in round-robin play. The runner-up was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kiana Ramos</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regina Mendez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> placing third.
</P><P ID="13">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> tournament drew a field of 55 players.
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




