
<P ID="1">Cold snap hits <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">With nightly temperatures dipping well below zero, to a new record low on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4</TIMEX> of -9 degrees, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents are preparing for cold days and icy roads.   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> bus drivers arrived to work they found that half of the buses wouldn't start.   "The cold weather wreaks havoc on the buses," said school district spokesperson <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Kaplicky</ENAMEX>.   Some of the schools in the district have only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the students in the classrooms, she said.   She added that parents can expect delays when their children are being dropped off <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> is planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, but depending on the bus situation, that could change, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplicky</ENAMEX>. She said the final determination will be made by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.   After the New Year's Day snow storm, snow shovels, sleds and ice-melt disappeared from the shelves of Ace Hardware in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Now, heaters, both electric and kerosene, have been selling like hot cakes, as well as torch kits, heat bulbs and gloves, according to store manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Dean</ENAMEX>.   "They're buying anything that will look like it will thaw a pipe," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>.   With a variety of heat tapes and small heaters used to thaw pipes available, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> said those who've had pipes freeze over the past few days have been looking at different ways to get water flowing again at their homes.   "They started coming in on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Year</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> a little bit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>.   As the temperatures dropped, more came to the store looking for additional heat sources.   "It's just plain cold," he said.   In fact it's so cold that the company is having a hard time getting the supply trucks from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> started.   "We're sending a truck up just for kerosene and electric heaters," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>.   With expected additional snowfall <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> said Ace employees want to be prepared for the next wave of expected bad weather.   "We're bringing in more snow shovels and more ice-melt," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Cook</ENAMEX>, who records <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s temperatures for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX>, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s temperature of -9 degrees shatters the record for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 4</TIMEX> of -2 degrees set in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1924</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Works</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Ott</ENAMEX> has not had any calls on city pipes freezing.   "I'm not too worried about it right now," he said, adding that the city's pipes are buried deep and have a layer of insulation and the weather is supposed to warm up.   "If it breaks and it's our pipe, we're going to take care of it," he said. Everything up to and including the water meter is the city's responsibility.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department Battalion Chief Adam Dent</ENAMEX> said that those who bring heaters into their homes for extra warmth need to remember a few simple steps to ensure safety during the cold.   "Most importantly, if you use a heater you need to make sure you keep them a good distance from everything," he said.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This weekend</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> was called to a mattress fire, he said. The fire was out on arrival, but it was determined that the mattress was too close to an electric heater and caught fire.   "Not all heating devices are appropriate for indoor use," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX>. Some are for outdoor use only because they put off toxic fumes and burn oxygen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> said people can die from carbon monoxide poisoning.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> said it's also a good idea to change your furnace filter when it's cold.   "Changing the filter helps them run more efficiently," he said.   For those with freezing pipes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> said, "Getting under your house with a torch is probably not the best idea. Pipes conduct heat and if hot enough can go into walls and catch them on fire."   With snow and ice still on many of the roads, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> encourages caution when driving, but, he said, the majority of the accidents the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> has responded to have been on the freeways.   "Those accidents have slowed down because the freeways have cleaned up," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> added.   Although <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>) continues to be cold, according to a spokesperson at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX>, the temperatures should be rising over the next few days.   After <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> tonight there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> chance of snow. It is expected that 2 to 4 inches will accumulate. Temperatures should increase to the 20s, he added.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> there is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> chance of more snow, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Weather Service</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> along with snow, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> should expect light freezing rain, rain and snow.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

