


<P ID="1">McTeacher Night on tap <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX> at McDonald's
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next Thursday, May 20</TIMEX>, McDonald's in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will host McTeacher Night.
</P><P ID="4">   Approximately 30 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> teachers will be manning the fast food restaurant from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> McDonald's has agreed to give <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> of all sales during that time to the school. The money raised will be spent on establishing classroom libraries at the school.
</P><P ID="5">   Also, now through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 20</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> McDonald's restaurant is selling paper apples as a fund-raiser to help fund the project.
</P>   
<P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> takes disciplinary action against health
</P><P ID="7">   care providers
</P><P ID="8">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Health</ENAMEX> has taken disciplinary actions against two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> health care providers.
</P><P ID="9">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> the state's unlicensed practice program issued a notice of intent to issue a cease and desist order against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alejandro</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guzman</ENAMEX>. He allegedly offered and performed massages to the public for a fee. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> officials say <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guzman</ENAMEX> does not have a license to practice as a massage practitioner.
</P><P ID="10">   Also in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, the state's pharmacy board charged pharmacist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Wolfe</ENAMEX> with unprofessional conduct. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolfe</ENAMEX> is being charged with diverting controlled substances and legend drugs from her work place for her own use.
</P>   
<P ID="11">   School board
</P><P ID="12">   in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="13">   has vacancy
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School Board of Education</ENAMEX> is now accepting applications from qualified persons to fill a vacancy. Appointees must be a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> citizen and a qualified, registered voter living within the open director district.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Director District</ENAMEX> #3 is open due to the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, who served on the board for 10 years.
</P><P ID="16">   A map of the district in question is available by calling 882-8500.
</P><P ID="17">   Those interested in being appointed to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> should submit a letter of interest to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Ott</ENAMEX> at 913 W. 2nd St. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="18">   Musical melodrama auctions scheduled
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - The Toppenish Creek Players will continue to conduct auditions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> for their upcoming production of "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little Mary Sunshine</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="20">   Especially needed for the musical melodrama are men and women who can play 18 to 25-year-olds.
</P><P ID="21">   Auditions will be held at the Toppenish Masonic Lodge building (12 E. Third Ave.) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 13</TIMEX> and 14 at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> both nights.
</P>   
<P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board
</P><P ID="23">   to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 25</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="24">   The Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) board of directors will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 25</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 p.m.</TIMEX> meeting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX> is open to the public.
</P>   
<P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> parade winners named
</P><P ID="27">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Cinco de Mayo Parade winners have been announced.
</P><P ID="28">   They include: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Arriaga</ENAMEX> - 1st for equestrian clubs; Rancho Viejo - 1st for charro associations; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco de la Torre</ENAMEX> - 1st for individual charro, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector Lopez</ENAMEX> - 2nd for individual charro; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> float - 1st for large community floats, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> float - 2nd for large community floats; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> royalty court - 1st for small community floats; Paleteria La Nortena - 1st for commerical floats; Country Carriage - 1st for organization floats, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlee Zieger</ENAMEX> - 2nd for organization floats; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panda Bear Child Care Center</ENAMEX> - 1st for marching youth units; Mayela de la Cruz - 1st for antique cars; and Lowered II Perfection - 1st for custom cars, Xplicit Performance - 2nd for custom cars.
</P>   






 










<P ID="29">Webmaster
</P><P ID="30">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




