
<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX> marks the one-year anniversary since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Ramirez</ENAMEX> and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX>, purchased the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mini Mart on the corner of Sixth Street and Harrison Avenue.   In that time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa</ENAMEX> has become very well acquainted with her customers, who begin steadily streaming into the store at about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX> every morning and are faithful throughout the day.   Many of the customers walking through the door <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> knows by name. She knows their idiosyncrasies, what they buy, how they like the money in their wallets arranged and what time they will walk through the door every day.   "I have a lot of customers who come in every day," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX>.   Most of her customers live in the neighborhood, but she said that she also has numerous out-of-town visitors coming to her business.   She said that people from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX> and other states come to her store looking for directions or a place to eat. Some have even asked for directions to the hospital.   "It's amazing how many people visit this town," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX>.   "I get a lot of people here asking where the Dairy Fair is or how to get to the winery," she added.   Despite all of the visitors, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mini Mart is still a neighborhood store.   When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> first bought the business, it was slow, but with a few changes, including ripping the signs out of the windows, she saw an increase in business. Through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> there was a steady stream of business, she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> had a desire to own her own business for a number of years. A former medical transcriptionist and assistant for a lab, she decided then, that one day she would work for herself.   "I used to have to pick up specimens and take them to the lab," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX>. "One time I had a leg. It was in the back of my car and I was afraid it was going to come back to life," she chuckled.   She took some time off before her youngest went to school, but when he stated attending classes full-time, she knew it was time to get out of the house.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> opened a book and Bible store before she bought the corner market from a friend. She had worked occasionally at the mart to help her friend, so she knew the ins and outs of the business.   "I knew she worked a lot, but I had no idea how much," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> said.   She said it was a difficult decision to close the bookstore, but when the opportunity to purchase <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mini Mart opened up she and her husband decided to try their hand at grocery retailing.   Since purchasing the market <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> has expanded the amount of products she carries. She has also expanded the lunch items and added breakfast tacos to the menu.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

