
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> takes the helm of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - It has only been a few weeks since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX> moved into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> and started his new position as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> superintendent. However, since taking on the position <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said he has been busy working to learn the history and the traditions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>.   "That's the biggest curve," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said. "You really need to know what has been done before, what is the precedent."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said the only way to do this is to sit down and talk to people.   Coming into the school district, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said one of his goals is to improve instruction in every classroom, every day throughout the district.   "It's my belief that student achievement comes from interaction, interaction between teacher and child," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said. "Every child deserves to benefit from excellent instruction."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said he has been pleasantly surprised in his first few weeks in the district, noting that everything he has heard about the district is true. He noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> has everything from an involved community to excellent curriculum.   It was nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">20 years ago</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> started his foray into the field of education. He started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> as a vocation agriculture teacher in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said his father was a big reason he decided to go into teaching, noting that his father spent 30 years teaching agriculture in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   However, eight or nine years into his teaching career he decided it was time to get his Master's degree. After some thought <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said he decided to get his Master's in administration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said he had several friends at the time who had made the transition from teaching to administration and he saw it as the next step in his career.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, who is married with two children, said the decision to leave the classroom was a tough one, noting that he enjoyed being involved with the students through things like <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX>, but he knew it was time.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>'s first administration position was as vice principal of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, his alma mater.   "That was fun," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said, noting that he learned a lot during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this three years</TIMEX> at the school.   After putting in time at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> was hired as the assistant superintendent in charge of federal programs and curriculum instruction for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>.   "It was a very different atmosphere," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said.   He noted that at the time, one of his friends was superintendent of the district and had previously held <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>'s position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said it made for an easier transition to have someone who had held the position still be in the office and be able to show him the ropes.   "He was able to guide me through that full year," he said.   One year was all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> would hold that position. He said at the end of his first year in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> his friend left the district and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> was hired as the superintendent.   "That was a big learning curve," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said. He added that it was the people in the district office, as well as the district principals who helped him get situated in his new position.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> maintained his position in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> until just a few weeks ago, when he became superintendent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

