


<P ID="1">Council rakes over issues at retreat
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/12/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">What to leave off the plate and what to go after head-on was a point of major discussion by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> at its retreat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> at Whistlin' Jack Lodge.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> went over a list of about 30 items of concern to address in the upcoming year with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="6">   One of the first issues on the list was the Monson feedlot matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has been trying to figure a way to buy the feedlot in Outlook for the past couple of years, citing several different concerns ranging from curbing odor problems to clean air. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he will be coming back shortly to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with a report on the matter.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also wants to further expand on a new landscaping ordinance the city adopted for commercial developments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it is also important for the city to be consistent in its residential requirements for landscaping. Currently, R-1 zones require new homes to install lawn and sprinkler systems within the first year. But no such requirements exists for new homes constructed in R-2 zones. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also wants to give the planning commission the opportunity to expand the landscaping ordinance to industrial and residential locations.
</P><P ID="8">   A significant discussion that took place at the meeting had to deal with the matter of privatizing wastewater and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> services.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> immediately expressed her opposition to the proposal, but the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> thought privatization was at least worth a look.
</P><P ID="10">   "I think we should pursue anything to make the organization more efficient," said Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> offered <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> a suggestion to pursue the privatization matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> should put out a request for proposals from various firms, while asking at the same time that city staff from the different departments issue a similar <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RFP</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> would get a good idea of what can be offered from both sides under this process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said similar approaches have worked in such cities as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">AZ</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   Another discussion dealt with how the city should approach the possibility of tax guru <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Eyman</ENAMEX> reintroducing Initiative 864 to rollback property tax fees. The matter failed to make it on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> ballot because it didn't gain enough signatures, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eyman</ENAMEX> will more than likely be rewriting the issues for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he felt it is important for the city to prepare itself for any money shortages caused by the possibility of residents passing the issue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   "We have to have a more balanced approach," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> felt it was important for the city to take that step while educating citizens on where their tax dollars are spent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> added that residents need to realize the city actually receives a very small portion of their tax dollars. He added the figure could be even smaller with a sales tax streamline issue that will be coming to a head soon. Under this issue, money from sales tax will be sent from the east side of the state to the west.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> was against the idea of raising taxes, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> suggested as a possible solution to help build a nest egg in reserves in case any <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eyman</ENAMEX> initiatives do pass. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will be able to discuss the matter more as budget time nears.
</P><P ID="17">   Downtown parking was another discussion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to be sure that the fines being issued for violating downtown parking regulations cover the cost of enforcement.
</P><P ID="18">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also discussed the idea of drafting ordinance requirements that would limit what sort of manufactured homes could be placed in the community. This is an issue that the planning commission will be discussing in the near future.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also discussed with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members the advantages of owning city vehicles compared to leasing. However, he said it is important to leave the equipment reserve fund untouched to ensure the city has enough money to properly replace its vehicles when needed.
</P><P ID="20">   Other discussion items included installing some sort of sound buffer for residents along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> once the reconstruction project is completed. The city leaders also want to look at expanding the fire department facility and improving the entryways into the community.
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




