
<P ID="1">Entertainment
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
to all children
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GOLDENDALE</ENAMEX> - From 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum of Art</ENAMEX> visitors can participate in a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mexican Dia de los Muertos</ENAMEX> (Day of the Dead) program.
Featured activities will include musical performances by Los Temerosos and guest artists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armando Olveda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristina Acosta</ENAMEX>. There will also be traditional Mexican folk dancing, plus the Viva la Cultura performers.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> program is open to all ages, and children under 17 will be admitted free with one paid adult.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s event at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX> area museum has been organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Spousta</ENAMEX>, assistant director for student activities and multi-cultural programmer at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Portland</ENAMEX>.
"Bring your entire family for an afternoon of fun activity and exploration," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrie Clark</ENAMEX>, curator of education at the museum. "Try your hand at painting your own papier-mache skull and watch folk dancing.
"It'll be a great day for families to learn about this tradition that honors ancestors with colorful art, food, music and altars," she added.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dias de los Muertos</ENAMEX> has its roots in ancient Mexican traditions. Families share stories about their ancestral loved ones, prepare traditional foods, create elaborately decorated altars and creatures, play music and dance.
Through the afternoon <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hood River Mexican Folk Dance 4-H Club</ENAMEX> will demonstrate traditional Mexican dancing. Los Temerosos will perform traditional Mexican mariachi music, and Viva la Cultura will present folk tales through song, dance and acting.
"Alebrijes, or images and creatures from the realm of the dead, are also a large part of festivities," said artist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armando Olveda</ENAMEX>. He will show children how to make and decorate their own papier-mache fantasy skulls. All supplies will be provided free.
Special <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> treats will be provided by the Casa El Mirador restaurant in The Dalles and by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ayutla's Family Restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, a castle-like chateau overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX>, is located on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Scenic Route</ENAMEX> 14, just west of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> 97. General admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">‘Get Lit’ festival ticket sales start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SPOKANE</ENAMEX> - Individual tickets to one of the region's premier literary arts festivals, "Get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lit</ENAMEX>," go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday, Nov. 1</TIMEX>, at all TicketsWest locations.
Ticketed events include award winning poets <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Dove</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Bly</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 17, 2005</TIMEX>, satirical commentator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Sedaris</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 21</TIMEX>, broadcast journalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Edwards</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 22</TIMEX> and novelist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salman Rushdie</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23</TIMEX>. All shows will be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spokane's Metropolitan Performing Arts Center</ENAMEX>, except <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX>, who will appear in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Showalter Auditorium</ENAMEX> on the campus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cheney</ENAMEX>.
The seventh annual Inland Northwest Literary Arts "Get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lit</ENAMEX>" Festival will include more than 20 events in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> during the seven-day festival. In addition to the four ticketed performances, the festival will feature readings by dozens of regional writers, children's events, writing workshops, literary panel discussions and youth poetry slams. Most events are free and all are open to the public.
For more information about the "Get <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lit</ENAMEX>" festival, schedules or tickets, visit the festival website: www.ewu.edu/getlit.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

