


<P ID="1">USDA investigating possibility that infected cow came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/29/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">In a press conference held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron DeHaven</ENAMEX>, the chief veterinary officer with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, announced that investigators are now looking into leads that the Mabton Holstein infected with mad cow disease came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   With the new information, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said, the USDA now believes that the infected cow came to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> as a part of a group of 74 dairy cattle entering the country at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastport</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>. The dairy cows are believed to have come from a herd in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 2001</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "There is some discrepancy in the records that we have and the records that we obtained from the index herd owner and the Canadian records on the particular animal," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> records would indicate that the animal was 4 to 4-1/2 years old. The Canadian records indicate that she was born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'97</TIMEX>, making her a 6-1/2-year-old animal."
</P><P ID="7">   The USDA is implementing DNA testing to determine if the animal is the same one that entered the country in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said that if it is the same cow, she had a calf in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> and semen is still available from the animal believed to be the sire of the infected animal, which could help with the matching.
</P><P ID="8">   But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said, there is a question as to how old the cow was when it was purchased for the 4,000-herd <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dairy.
</P><P ID="9">   "Initially, we had a verbal report from the herd owner of the indexed farm saying that based on his memory this particular cow came into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2001</TIMEX>, as a 2-year-old springer," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>. But in talking with the manager of the same farm, not the owner, he recalls this cow being a dry cow, which would suggest that she was an older animal and soon to give birth to her next calf, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   According to a report released <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>), the Mabton owner of the Holstein cow found to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> has located documents indicating the cow was an older animal, not a 2-year-old springer as initially thought, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   The cow is now believed to be 6-1/2 years old, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "Information now indicates that the animal was born before the feed bans were implemented in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>. "Only DNA tests will confirm that the cow is from a farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   The USDA was turned onto the possibility that the cow originated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> when a small metal tamper-proof tag was recovered from the slaughter house in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said the tag is similar to ones used in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   He pointed out that just because the one animal has tested positive for mad cow disease, doesn't mean the other animals that entered the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> with the infected animal had the same disease.
</P><P ID="16">   After crossing the border, the animal was taken to a dairy cow finishing facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>, which is where it was purchased for the Mabton dairy.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said the quarantine on the Mabton dairy and a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area bull calf feeding operation continues.
</P><P ID="18">   The bull calf operation was quarantined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX> after it was determined that the infected cow's most recent calf went into feed pens with about 400 other calves. Although, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>, there is no research that indicates that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> can be transmitted from cow to calf, the operation was quarantined as a precautionary step.
</P><P ID="19">   "The purpose of that quarantine or hold order is not to stop the spread of the disease," he said. "It's important to realize that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> is not a contagious disease. It's not spread by direct contact, animal to animal."
</P><P ID="20">   He said the quarantine is to help prevent the movement of animals, making it easier in the investigation.
</P>   
<P ID="21">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




