


<P ID="1">Annexation vote means more reading materials, local services for patrons of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">With <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9th</TIMEX> approval of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Public Library annexation into the larger Yakima Regional Library System, local library patrons can expect to see many changes at the local facility.
</P><P ID="5">   But many of those changes won't come until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, when the regional system takes over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Weyhe</ENAMEX>, executive director of the regional library system.
</P><P ID="6">   "We thank the voters for their vote of confidence," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters approved the library annexation proposal with an overwhelming <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> "yes" vote during a special annexation election held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "Now begins the process of asking the library patrons what additional services they want at their library, "she said.
</P><P ID="9">   Currently, classes in computer use, in English and Spanish, are among the popular services utilized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> community, she said.
</P><P ID="10">   "I can see us doing more of those, she said.
</P><P ID="11">   The local patrons will also see more books, videos, CDs and other materials available in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the coming months, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="12">   "We also plan to make a number of improvements to the building, which will be turned over to the regional system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   "What those improvements will be exactly will be determined after regional library officials have an opportunity to further survey the facility," she said.
</P><P ID="14">   Currently, popular services at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library have included more than 71,865 requests for books, videos, magazines and music CDs, as well as 18,364 sessions on the library's bank of computers.
</P><P ID="15">   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library computers are among the busiest in the regional library's system," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   The present library board members appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> mayor to serve as an advisory board is expected to be disbanded as a result of the annexation. When the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library becomes a part of the regional system, it will be governed by the regional board.
</P><P ID="17">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next week</TIMEX>, the local library board will meet to begin the transition of the local leadership to the regional system, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Saras</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   "The local library board will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 23</TIMEX>, to make a decision about what will become of that board," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   "I expect a new Friends of the Library group will be formed at a later date," he said.
</P><P ID="20">   The group that worked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library annexation has already expressed an interest in helping with the transition, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Kezele</ENAMEX>, who was the ballot chairman.
</P><P ID="21">   "We are looking forward to forming a 'Friends' group as a local advisory body to the regional system," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezele</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Rinz</ENAMEX> said the city had budgeted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> for the local library <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, but with the passage of the annexation, the regional library system will be helping to maintain the library through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   "We expect to begin the transition talks with the regional system soon," he said.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said she expects surveys will be distributed to the library patrons at a later date to determine what future services patrons would like to see at the library.
</P>   






 










<P ID="25">Webmaster
</P><P ID="26">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




