
<P ID="1">Science enthusiast vying to represent community at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Science is one field <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Cornelius</ENAMEX> excels in right now. But the 17-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior most desires to study the science of the mind.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> is one of eight young ladies vying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> title. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s pageant will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Patrice Cornelius</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She is being sponsored in her quest for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> title by Bleyhl's and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>'s Repair and Rental.   At <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Cornelius</ENAMEX> is involved with Link Crew, which is a group of students involved with helping the incoming freshmen class make the transition from middle school to high school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>' love in school is studying science. It began piquing her interest in the seventh grade.   "I thought it sounded interesting," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>.   Her budding fascination with science took her to the next level, becoming a science fair contestant, under the keen guidance of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> science teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Stark</ENAMEX>.   "It is a real learning experience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> of the science fair. "You learn to work hard. You are kind of on your own to do everything."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> said science fair involves a lot of hard work and dedication. She said in preparing for science fair it is not uncommon to be working into the wee hours of the morning.   When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> isn't trying to figure out the ways of the world through her science projects, she stays busy with sports. She has played school soccer for several years and during her freshman season in high school turned out for cross country and tennis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> first became involved with soccer through the parks and recreation department in the second grade.   "It is kind of how I vent my anger," joked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> is also involved with her youth group at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran Church</ENAMEX>.   Science fair has taken <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> to many new places. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of this past school year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> boarded a plane to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denver</ENAMEX> to take part in the Stockholm Junior Water Prize Fair.   "I really got to know some people there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> has also competed at the state and national science fairs, earning a variety of different honors.   But while science has taken up many an hour for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>, she wants to delve into another type of science after graduating from high school, psychology.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>' interest in psychology can be traced back to a book she read about girls who were suffering from cancer. In the book the girls received counseling and were able to deal with the disease better.   "Counseling really helps," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>.   The kind of counseling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> wants to work in is directly linked to her community service project if she were selected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, which is being involved with Children's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Village</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> said she wants to work with children and their families.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>, who is a life-long resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, likes living in a town the size of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "The town is the right size," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>. "We have things to do."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> said one of the best parts about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is the friendly people who help out one another. And she also likes that living in a small town people get to know everyone.   "Almost everybody has a story," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>, who describes herself as talkative, likes to have fun, is friendly, works hard and enjoys being successful. She decided to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> because she felt it would be a good, positive community activity.   If <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> is selected as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> or to the royal court, one of her first goals will be to find more ways to get the community involved with activities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> suggested the possibility of having a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>-sponsored family day in the park. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> also said as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> she wouldn't want her court performing just the community service project she selects. She said she would want to make sure each of the other members of the court would have a chance to be involved with service projects of their own choosing.   "That way we could get out and get more involved with the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> said she is looking forward to the chance of serving on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> said she has a goal of wanting to be involved as much as possible with the community to make it a better place to live.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> said she would be honored to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "If I was named <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, it would feel like all my hard work paid off," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX>. "It would give me a chance to help out in the community and be more involved."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

