
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MHS</ENAMEX> senior sets 'Human Trap' on the internet
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - When you ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Guzman</ENAMEX> how he came to be a one-man-band, his answer is typical of most 18-year olds...he wanted to try something new.   However, one thing that separates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> from other students at his school is that he has taken his talent and put it out there for others to hear and critique.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX>, who calls his project The Human Trap, can be heard on the website GarageBand.com. The website offers bands and musicians a chance to put their music on the internet and get feedback from others.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said he first heard about the website through a motivational speaker. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said he then visited the site and decided it was something he wanted to try. He explained that letting others hear his music wasn't something new to him. In the past he had put songs on CDs and given them out to friends.   However, before he could submit his song to the website he said he had to complete 15 reviews of other songs that were already posted. He explained that when reviewing a song you are not told the name of the band, where they're from or the type of music they play. Instead, you just hear the song and then review it, which helps remove bias.   "That's what I wanted people to do for my song," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said.   And that's exactly what people have been doing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX>'s song "Mabtonites," which since being placed on the website has received so many favorable reviews that it was highlighted as a track of the day on GarageBand.com in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late February</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said the track, which is an up tempo hard rock song, is one he created in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2003</TIMEX>, but re-recorded later in the year before posting it on the internet.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said trying to find a genre for this song was difficult because he doesn't quite fit into the metal category but wasn't like the other hard rock songs on the website.   "I expected people to slam it because it didn't sound like the other hard rock songs," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said. "I was surprised by the first few reviews."   In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said his first few reviews were so positive that overnight his song went from being ranked number 600 to being ranked number 120.   "The highest I got was number 71," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said, noting that the ranking takes in about 700 songs.   As for how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> came to provide the vocals on "Mabtonites," as well as play rhythm guitar, bass, drums and lead guitar on the track, he said it all came from the purchase of a new piece of equipment. He explained that he also plays in the band Dysphonia with his father and brother, so writing music and playing instruments isn't anything new to him. However, when his family purchased a piece of equipment that is like a mixing board and disk recorder in one, he figured he could try creating a song where he did everything.   He said after recording his first song like that and liking how it sounded he just kept going with the idea until he had a mix of eclectic tunes.   "Every song has its own sound to it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said.   And "Mabtonites" isn't the only song Guzman plans on putting up at GarageBand.com. He said he plans on submitting another song soon.   "It's about mad cow disease in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guzman</ENAMEX> said. "I don't like to write songs about love and breaking up because I can't relate to that."   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

