
<P ID="1">Grizzly boys coach encouraged by early season marks
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/22/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> boys track and field <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Wally Shearer</ENAMEX> is rather optimistic about the season following this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>'s Cadet Invitational.   The Cadet invite is a non-scoring affair hosted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eisenhower High School</ENAMEX>. The meet featured such schools as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thorp</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kittitas</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> said he has 40 boys out for track <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>, 10 more than he had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, and many of them are participating in the sport for the first time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> said his first time participants showed good marks this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> while his returners are right on target from where they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   "We did well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX>. "It is still early. We have good numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. They are a great bunch of guys to work with."   The top mark on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> boys went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> took first in the shotput with throw of 44-9-1/2. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> said what made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s mark for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> even more notable is that he is nursing an injured shoulder.   "That is a great mark to start out the year with," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Schilperoort</ENAMEX> had a third place finish in the 100-meter dash with a time of 11.8 seconds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> was fifth in the event with a clocking of 12 seconds flat while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester Wells</ENAMEX> took sixth with a time of 12.2. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Arevalo</ENAMEX> was seventh with a time of 12.4 seconds.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> was also impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Graham</ENAMEX>, who nearly hit the marks he had at the end of last season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> took fourth in the 110-meter high hurdles with a time of 18.2 seconds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> was also fifth in the 300-meter intermediate hurdles, 47.7 seconds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graham</ENAMEX> also took seventh in the javelin with a throw of 123-10.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange</ENAMEX> student Branimir Janjev was another athlete on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> that caught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX>'s attention. Janjev took fourth in the triple jump, clearing 26-3. He was also fifth in the long jump with a distance of 16-11.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Davis</ENAMEX> also did well in the triple jump, taking sixth with a mark of 36-1-1/4. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> didn't even break a sweat hitting that mark. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> was also fifth in the 800-meter dash with a time of 2:09.5.   Also placing in the long jump for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Sambrano</ENAMEX>, who placed sixth with a mark of 16-6-1/2. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Heckert</ENAMEX> was seventh, clearing 16-6.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heckert</ENAMEX> also had a top 10 finish in the 800, placing ninth with a time of 2:15.1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casey Wells</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the discus with a throw of 97-7, placing fourth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Aguirre</ENAMEX> placed fifth with a throw of 91-3. Hunter Van de Graaf took sixth in the discus, 86-11. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX> was eighth for the Grizzlies with a mark of 78-6.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendan Scott</ENAMEX> grabbed seventh in the pole vault, elevating 9-6.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Howat</ENAMEX> took seventh in the 200-meter dash with a clocking of 26.2 seconds.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s 4-X400-meter relay team of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heckert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> took third with a time of 3:43.4.   The Grizzlies 4X100-meter relay team of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sarmiento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arevalo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Palomarez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Martinez</ENAMEX> was fourth with a clocking of 49.9 seconds.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> travels to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

