


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area legislators review work in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Sixty days may seem like a long time to some people, but ask local legislators and you'll get an entirely different answer. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX>, Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> and Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX> about just how much they were able to accomplish during the last 60-day legislative session.
</P><P ID="5">   "I never realized in a short session, how much work [there] was," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said going into the last session, which is considered short compared to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s budget session, there were several issues that had to be tackled, including writing the supplemental budget and putting together the state's transportation budget.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> explained that the state's supplemental budget makes up approximately <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of the two-year budget cycle. He said one of the good things that came with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s supplemental budget was that it did not require a tax increase.
</P><P ID="8">   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said the supplemental budget does have several drawbacks, including that it spends more money than will be coming in. He said this will make budgeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> more difficult. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> explained that not only will budgeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> be more difficult due to the amount of money being spent in the supplemental budget, but also due to several initiatives that will take effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, as well as some collective bargaining that has yet to be done.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> two</TIMEX> initiatives dealing with education will come back into play, initiatives 728 and 732, one of which gives teachers across the state a cost of living increase. As for collective bargaining, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said this will be the last duty of Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX>'s administration and it could possibly have a dramatic effect on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s budget.
</P><P ID="10">   When the initiatives and collective bargaining are grouped together, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said the two issues could mean as much as a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">15 percent</NUMEX> increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s budget. "Which is pretty significant," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   There were other issues state legislators also took on during the session, including several bills that came in response to the discovery of a dairy heifer infected with Mad Cow disease.
</P><P ID="12">   "I think we can feel good that the legislature could respond in such a timely matter," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said, noting that six pieces of legislation were passed dealing with the issue. He said the legislation dealt with everything from the transportation of downer cows to cattle identification.
</P><P ID="13">   An issue that has faced the legislature for some time also saw some action during the short session. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said legislation that would make it possible for school districts to pass levy and bond issues with a simply majority is something that has been on the table for years. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> half of that legislation made it through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> before it was killed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. That piece of legislation would have made it possible for school districts to pass levies with a simple majority, instead of the super majority that is currently needed.
</P><P ID="14">   A piece of education legislation that did pass through both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and was recently signed by Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> dealt with charter schools. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> explained that the piece of legislation allows for the creation of 45 charter schools across the state over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next six years</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   At a more local level, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said several things happened during the session that will help the local agriculture industry. He said more money was put into the budget to help the asparagus industry mechanize their warehouses, as well as to conduct research on the mechanization of the hop industry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said the study would look at mechanizing the process of taking the vines off the trucks and bringing them into the warehouses for production.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




