


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Democrats back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> for President
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">More than 750 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Democrats took part in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s statewide precinct caucuses, taking time to voice their opinions on who the Democratic presidential nominee should be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul George</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Democratic Central Committee</ENAMEX>, at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the day Saturday</TIMEX> local Democrats favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> by a 2-to-1 margin. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> supporters will send 245 delegates to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Dean</ENAMEX> supporters will send 123.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> received 419 votes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX> recieved 178 and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX> was a distant third with 65 votes and 32 delegates to the county convention.
</P><P ID="6">   Precinct caucuses are the first step in selecting a presidential nominee. The caucuses, which took place at 10 sites from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX>, offered people a chance to discuss who they would like to back for president. Those taking part in the caucuses simply had to sign in at the door to one of the local sites and acknowledge they are both a registered voter and a Democrat.
</P><P ID="7">   Once everyone was signed in, representatives from each of the precincts within a certain area met at the caucus, discussed the issues and then broke up into their individual precinct groups. The precinct groups then selected their delegates who will represent the precinct and the candidate they support at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Convention.
</P><P ID="8">   A total of 752 Democrats signed in at the 10 sites. The three <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> sites accounted for 509 of the total votes, with the remaining 243 votes coming from sites such as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph's Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Both churches served as caucus sites <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




