48 29 23 6 14 43
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Underlying the whole scheme of civilization is the confidence men have in each other, confidence in their integrity, confidence in their honesty, confidence in their future.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bourke Cockran</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>