
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> wrestler doesn't let pain pin him down
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Watching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> wrestlers practice after school, one would never guess that among the more than 20 athletes is one who is working through a painful disease.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Benavidez</ENAMEX> has been living with rheumatoid arthritis since he was diagnosed at age eight. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benavidez</ENAMEX> said because of the disease there are days when he can't practice and other days when he can't compete.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisa Benavidez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>'s mother, said her son was diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis after several visits to the doctor as a young boy. She said when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> was eight, one of his ankles started swelling and hurt to the touch. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisa</ENAMEX> said she and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX>, took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> to the doctor, who told them it was most likely a spider bite.   However, when their son's ankle continued to swell off and on every few weeks they decided to get a second opinion. She said there were times when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>'s ankles would hurt so badly that his parents couldn't even touch him. The need for a second opinion led the family to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX> in Seattle, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> was diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisa</ENAMEX> said at the time doctors said the disease is heredity, but could also be from an old sports injury.   However, for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, being diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis at a young age didn't stop him from being an active child.   Instead, he jumped right into wrestling as a fourth grade student. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> said he started competing in a children's league after his father introduced him to the sport. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisa</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy</ENAMEX> has always been a wrestling fan.   So when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>, whose older brother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> also wrestles, made it to high school, being a member of the wrestling team seemed like a natural thing to do.   "I like the competition, and it keeps it me in shape," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> said of wrestling.   Although this is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>'s second season with the high school team, it hasn't always been easy for the 140-pound wrestler.   He said there are mornings when he wakes up and his ankles are stiff and painful and he knows he won't be able to practice. He said the pain comes at least once every two weeks.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> wrestling coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Sevigny</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> missed about half the season <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> due to his arthritis flaring up, and so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> has missed about half of the season.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevigny</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> is a hard working member of the team, and has a lot of talent on the mat.   So much talent and dedication that when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> decided at the beginning of the season that he wasn't going to try out for wrestling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevigny</ENAMEX> approached him.   "He's a great kid," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevigny</ENAMEX> said.   This season <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sevigny</ENAMEX> said he has made some allowances for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX>. When the other wrestlers are running on the hard gym floor at practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> is using a stationary bicycle, which means less impact on his ankles.   Wrestling isn't the only sport <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> has participated in during his two years in high school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisa</ENAMEX> said as a freshman he also played football. However, on his doctor's recommendation he didn't try out for the football team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   "The doctor said it would be easier to do one sport," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> said.   So he chose wrestling.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> said he enjoys the competition that comes with the one-on-one sport. He is 9-8 this season, and likes that it helps keep him in good shape.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisa</ENAMEX> said one difficult thing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> over the years has been being able to tell when his rheumatoid arthritis is acting up in his ankles, to the point that he shouldn't be practicing or playing on it.   She said she can now tell, after living with the disease for eight years, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> is feeling pain. She said she can often see it in the way he walks.   "Only he knows his pain tolerance," she said, although she noted that it is very high. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisa</ENAMEX> noted that if he tells you he is in a lot of pain, his ankles are usually hurting him pretty badly.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> said although he is taking medication for his rheumatoid arthritis, there are still days when he can't walk on his ankles. Despite this, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael</ENAMEX> said he is planning on continuing wrestling throughout his high school career.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

