
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate looks at the colorful side of life
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rayann Van Beek</ENAMEX> enjoys things that bring color into her life. Things that make each day bright and filled with joy. With this in mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> is looking at a possible career in interior design after she graduates from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> in a couple of years.   The 16-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian junior will be hoping to add her shade of color to the 2004-05 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>. She is one of eight young ladies vying for the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> during the annual pageant held in conjunction with the community's Sunshine Days festivities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>. The pageant is being held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma and Alan Van Beek</ENAMEX> of Outlook. She is being sponsored for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s pageant by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>.   At school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> has been involved with volleyball since the seventh grade. She has also been a cheerleader since she was a freshman.   "It was kind of like a spur of the moment thing," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> of her decision to become a cheerleader.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said she wasn't sure at first if she wanted to try out for cheerleading, but quickly changed her mind once she became more involved.   "It is a great experience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>. "We have lots of fun. It (cheerleading) has helped my confidence level a lot."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> also likes to showcase the animals she raises, in particular her pigs. She has been involved with various shows since the sixth grade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> enjoys showing particularly at the Toppenish livestock fair and the Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "I just like working with animals," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>. "They (pigs) are not as messy as people might think they are."   Besides being involved with the Future Farmers of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX>) program at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> is involved with the school's governing body.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> is also heavily involved with her youth group at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah Faith Community Church</ENAMEX>.   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> has been a working young lady. She has held down a job in the kitchen at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "I like getting to talk with the residents," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>. "They are really funny. They have a lot of history."   Running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was something <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> has been wanting to do for a long time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> received a boost of encouragement from former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Jacobsen</ENAMEX> about competing for the title. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said she has always had an interest in representing the community in the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said she also decided to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> because she viewed it as a good experience.   "It will be a good way to give back to the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>.   The experience of competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has been a memorable one so far, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>.   "It is a lot of what I thought it was going to be," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said it has been memorable getting to know the other girls competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, as well as learning all the proper etiquette that goes along with the pageant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said what she enjoys about the community is the ever-changing scenery.   "I also like the fact you can go so many places and know so many people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>. "It is very beautiful with all the land. The people are so friendly."   If selected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>, one of the community service projects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> would like to adopt is working with the local fire department. One of her brothers and her dad are volunteers with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and Outlook fire departments. Another of her brothers is a fireman with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Richland</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said she knows how much help the fire department needs in protecting the community and she wants to do whatever she can to help.   "I know what a big community it is," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>. "I know how much time they (fireman) devote."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said another program she was thinking about tackling is the Toys For Tots program.   As far as issues facing the community, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said the major problem is there is nothing for teenagers to do in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said that's why the community encounters some of the problems it does with youth from time to time because there needs to be more activities.   After high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said she isn't quite sold on what she wants to do yet. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said she is leaning towards interior design or some other field of fashion.   "I am really into fashion things," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>. "I really like that."   A passion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>'s is playing the piano.   "My mom made me (play)," she smiled.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> has been playing the piano since the second grade and has never looked back.   "I just like to sit down and play the songs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>. "I could do it for hours at a time."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said being able to play the piano is sort of therapeutic, giving her time to relax from the hustle and bustle of the day.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> said she is looking forward to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant.   "I think it will be a very busy day, a very nervous day," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Beek</ENAMEX> is looking towards her chance to shine on the stage at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, and the possibility of representing the community on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

