


<P ID="1">Varying opinions on I-297, which addresses clean up of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford Nuclear Reservation</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A recent poll shows that seven out of 10 likely voters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state will vote in support of Initiative 297, which deals with the clean-up of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford Nuclear Reservation</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   However, not everyone in the state is getting behind I-297 and the clean-up efforts it suggests. In recent months, Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> "Doc" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, who traditionally refrains from commenting on state initiatives, has come out against I-297.
</P><P ID="6">   "I'm making an exception because the political effect is so profound that I felt I had to come out against it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="7">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Means</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Cooper</ENAMEX> of the Yes on I-297 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, the initiative will prevent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Energy</ENAMEX> from using the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford Nuclear Reservation</ENAMEX> as a national radioactive dumpsite and will require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Department</ENAMEX> to properly clean up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> before dumping more radioactive waste at the site.
</P><P ID="8">   According to the Yes on I-297 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> is already one of the most contaminated places in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Hemisphere</ENAMEX>, housing two-thirds of the country's high-level nuclear waste.
</P><P ID="9">   If Initiative 297 is passed by voters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, it will require the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> to clean up the radioactive contamination at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> before additional waste can be dumped at the site. It will also prevent the use of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> as a national radioactive dump site. Another issue the initiative tackles is the use of unlined soil trenches for the storage of nuclear waste. I-297 will make it illegal for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Energy</ENAMEX> to dump waste into these trenches.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said one of the reasons he is opposed to I-297 is because the regulation of radioactive waste is something that has always been handled by the federal government. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> noted that if I-297 is passed by voters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, the initiative will be regulating waste.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said he has no doubt in his mind that if the initiative is passed it will be challenged in court and if it is upheld in court, then there is nothing from preventing other states from passing similar legislation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> explained that if this happens, it will mean only one thing - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> will get stuck with the high-level nuclear waste that is already at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> site. He added that it will also mean that all of the money being spent on the vitrification plant, which transforms volatile nuclear waste into a more stable glass-like substance, will end up being used to transform the chemical make up of the nuclear waste, only to have it housed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "It could all stay here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> is not the only person who has come out in opposition to Initiative 297. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-City Industrial Development Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TRIDEC</ENAMEX>) has also come out against I-297. According to TRIDEC, there are plans to ship the high-level nuclear waste out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> to storage sites in other states. On the other hand, more waste will be shipped into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> for storage at the local site, but according to TRIDEC and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, the waste coming in will be low-level and mixed low-level waste.
</P><P ID="14">   The Yes on I-297 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> claims that the passage of the initiative will not lead to other states not accepting any more nuclear waste because, according to the committee, the only standard a state can use to block waste is that it can be barred from contaminated sites that do not meet standards. The committee notes that there is no provision in the law that would allow the blocking of deposits in deep geological repositories. According to the Yes on I-297 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX>, processed waste from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> is currently being sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Waste Isolation</ENAMEX> Pilot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Project</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, which is a deep geological repository.
</P><P ID="15">   At this point, I-297 has been endorsed by a wide range of groups and individuals, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Representative candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Mason</ENAMEX>, a Democrat running for office in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fourth Congressional District</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Representative cadidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Zesifer</ENAMEX>, a Republican in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eighth District</ENAMEX>; the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lung Association</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Women Voters</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




