


<P ID="1">Workers at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Foods</ENAMEX> unionize
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The employees of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Foods, LLC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrett Business Services</ENAMEX> have voted to unionize.
</P><P ID="5">   The plant, which is located near the corner of Grandridge and Second streets in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, has exchanged new ownership several times over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX>, according to Teamsters Local 760 secretary/treasurer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Parks</ENAMEX>. He said in the past the employees working at the plant have been unionized, but this is the first time they have been organized since the most recent ownership switch.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> said the majority of the people working at the plant have worked there under a union contract before. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> said the workers still voted 97 to 4 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> in favor of unionizing, despite attempts by the owners to stall a vote.
</P><P ID="7">   The unionization campaign began early <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>. He said a group of employees contacted the union, asking to be organized. Some of the concerns, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>, are wages, working hours, working conditions and seniority.
</P><P ID="8">   Under the way the company is operated, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barrett Business Services</ENAMEX> employs the production workers, and janitorial and management are employees of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Foods</ENAMEX>. He said that during processing nearly 300 people work at the plant.
</P><P ID="9">   He said 273 people are on the excelsior list, which was created after four days of hearings by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Labor Relations Board</ENAMEX>. The excelsior list is the number of employees on the payroll when a decision is made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Labor Relations Board</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   He said that the people on the excelsior list were allowed to vote in the election. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> said 170 ballots were cast in the election, but the company challenged 69 of the votes because the employees had been laid off two days prior to the election.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> said the 69 votes were not enough to change the vote, which was 94 in favor of unionizing and 4 against it.
</P><P ID="12">   "Even if all 69 votes were for the employer, it wasn't enough to change anything," he said.
</P><P ID="13">   Currently, the union is waiting for the end of a five-day appeals period. Once the unionization has been certified, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> will begin looking at how business is done at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Foods</ENAMEX>, so that the negotiation process can begin.
</P><P ID="14">   "The workers at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Foods</ENAMEX> have spoken loudly and clearly," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parks</ENAMEX>. "We are now going to negotiate a contract that will honor their trust in the union."
</P>





 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




