16 33 30 2 41 50
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  To be able to fill leisure intelligently is the last product of civilization, and at present very few people have reached this level.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertrand Russell</ENAMEX> (1872 - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>), Conquest of Happiness (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>) ch. 14
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>