


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/31/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Mad cow disease
</P>

<P ID="5">It is really important that all communities support the Mabton and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> farms, ranches, families and businesses involved with the recent case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">We must not let this situation hurt our neighbors. There are experts and caring professionals dealing with the cause and effect of one confirmed case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX> will take all actions necessary to protect animal health, consumers and the food supply.
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> is not known to spread from animal to animal according to latest science. The most critical animal health control measure—a ruminant feed ban—has been in place since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. They can quickly contain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> and eliminate it.
</P>

<P ID="9">The real issue is how people react to this situation. It is important that all communities support our neighbors and do everything possible to make certain their businesses and the health of their economy is protected.
</P>

<P ID="10">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loran Hickton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">President</ENAMEX> & CEO</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salmon Creek Public Relations</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>
</P>

 






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




