
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> school budget <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9.1 million</NUMEX> in 2004-05
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>'s new superintendent, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>, attended her first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, learning her budget for the coming year will be slightly smaller than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s.   Saying a number of the district's funding sources would be contributing smaller amounts to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX>'s treasury, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Plesha</ENAMEX>, the district assistant superintendent, said the district has budgeted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9,105,435</NUMEX> in the general fund, down from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9,658,227</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX>, who presented the budget to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>, said the district is losing funds from the Century 21 grant, as well as some levy equalization funds.   "We also have several grants which are ending, reducing our revenues," he told the board.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> also predicts revenue losses of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> in other high school programs.   Like other districts, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> will be paying more for special education <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, which is also taking away from the district's budget.   "We will be expected to pay nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> of special education costs, which will be a hardship for us," he said.   "The budget, while being a bit smaller than the 2003-04 budget, still covers all programs, just a slightly smaller degree than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, " he explained.   The district is reapplying for a number of the available learning grants, he added.   "We had hoped to do better in the funding, but some of grants are just up in the air," he said.   "We will probably know if we will be receiving them by mid- <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>," he explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said the district is coming to the end of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> grant, which provided the district with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$271,872</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for after-school activities.   "We hope to receive that amount again," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>, noting the district hasn't yet heard yet if <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s request will be approved.   He said the district will be operating it own GEAR-UP programs next school year, budgeting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$141,000</NUMEX>, which is less than if <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> allowed for an outside agency to operate the program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said the district will be receiving funds for its advanced placement programs in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> to be distributed over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next three years</TIMEX>.   "We are moving into the second year of our Reading First budget, which will give us <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX>.   In other funding areas, the transportation budget has been set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$112,000</NUMEX>, which includes money for a new bus. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> won't be undertaking any capital projects in the coming year, so just <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$525,000</NUMEX> has been funded in that budget. Funds have been set aside in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$147,550</NUMEX> to cover payments on two bonds in the debt service fund. The district's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASB Fund</ENAMEX> has been allotted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$78,000</NUMEX> for student activities. The budget covers the needs of an enrollment of 850 students.   "We expect to be up by 70 students (from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>)," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

