
<P ID="1">Nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">60 years later</TIMEX>, World War II vet will get his high school diploma
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Sitting in a sea of black caps and gowns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Culver</ENAMEX> looked as nervous as any of the 270 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> 17 and 18-year-olds seated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> bleachers for graduation rehearsal.   In the mid-<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940s</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> left school in the middle of his senior year to join the thousands of the American men who enlisted to fight in World War II.   Now 80-years-old, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> will finally receive his high school diploma from his hometown high school.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX>, originally a member of the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, will be presented his diploma as part of "Operation Recognition," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Hellner-Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior class advisor.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> introduced the former soldier to the 270 members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Class</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> at the recent rehearsal, who applauded his presence. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> told the class he had asked to walk with them. "I'm very honored to be leading you onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clem Senn Football Field</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> ceremony," he said.   "Thank you for allowing me to be a part of this class," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> told the graduates.   He was presented an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> blanket and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> senior mug, as well as an invitation to attend the senior graduation party <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s graduation ceremony.   Unlike the rest of the class, who must wear their gowns free of any decoration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> will be allowed to adorn his graduation gown with his war medals.   Among those medals earned while serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Czechoslovakia</ENAMEX> are his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Theater Service</ENAMEX> medal, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European-African Middle Eastern Service</ENAMEX> medal, a Good Conduct Medal and his World War II Victory Medal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX>, who was sharpshooter with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army Company D</ENAMEX>, 10th Infantry, now lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>, where he has been active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland VFW Post</ENAMEX> for 56 years.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX>'s opportunity to finally receive his diploma is thanks in part to state legislation created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> to honor those in the state who were forced to discontinue their high school education due to service in the war.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> said it was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW State</ENAMEX> Commander <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Rasmussen</ENAMEX> who told him about "Operation Recognition."   "He got me the forms and even mailed them in for me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX>, who retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> and from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX>, said he is pleased to be walking with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.   "They've even asked me to join them at their 10-year class reunion," he said.   "I'll try to be there," he smiled.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

