
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Parent info center schedules two family math nights
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parent Information</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Resource Center</ENAMEX> has planned two fun nights for local families that will focus on improving mathematic skills.
The first will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Oct. 25</TIMEX>, at the center, located at 800 E. Custer Ave. The 6:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> fun night is open to the families of students attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luz Fajardo-Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, one of the organizers, said families will be shown fun, family math activities they can use at home. Also to be presented is information on learning how to work with schools and teachers. She said there will also be snacks and fun activities designed for the entire family.
A second fun night will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resource center on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 26</TIMEX>, from 6:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> That night is reserved for families of students attending Chief Kamiakin, Pioneer and Outlook elementary schools.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Flu shotsfor military vetson tap for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jonathan M. Wainwright Memorial VA Medical Center</ENAMEX> staff members will be at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX> post <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 10</TIMEX>, to give flu shots to military veterans.
Veterans are asked to bring their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">VA</ENAMEX> identification card or military discharge DD214 form as a form of proof of military service. The flu shots will be given to veterans based on guidelines issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Centers for Disease Control</ENAMEX>. Those who are eligible for the vaccinations include veterans 65 years of age and older, all veterans who suffer froma chronic medical condition and female veterans who are pregnant during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this winter</TIMEX>'s flu season.
The vaccinations will be given on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> at the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX> post, located at 615 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

