
<P ID="1">Hospice Talent Show bigger, better than ever
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">No need to stay at home this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and watch the same old stuff on the boob tube. Instead, some real entertainment will be offered at the fifth annual Hospice Talent Show.   Sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> leadership class, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s talent show will feature everything from saxophone and piano performances, to clogging and jazz dance routines, to vocalists performing rap, as well as catchy standards and original compositions.   "We're hoping we have enough different kinds of acts that will interest all ages and all types of people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Durfey</ENAMEX>, who along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> is chairing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s talent show.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>, admittedly nervous about co-chairing such a large production, quickly adds that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s talent show is a bargain for local residents, as well.   "Tickets are only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> apiece," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX> said. "They'll be available at the door that night."   As tradition dictates, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s show will again be staged in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium. The curtain officially rises at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Proceeds generated from ticket sales will benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice agency.   Emcees for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s show will be Alaina Hull and Isley Gonzalez.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s organizers have opened the talent show, a competition really, to teachers and administrators in the school district. Several advanced through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>'s auditions and will be joining the student performers on stage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. All of the young performers, ages 12 to 19, will be competing for trophies and cash prizes, with the top prize <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> being <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>. The adult performers will compete for a trophy.   New to the talent show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will be an art competition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX> said the entries will be showcased in a special display, with cash, trophies, ribbons and certificates being awarded to the top artists.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Denton</ENAMEX>, the artist who's been involved with creating the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s statues for the last couple of years, will be our art judge," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durfey</ENAMEX>.   She said the judges for the on-stage performances will include M'liss Bierlink, Bill Flower, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Baker</ENAMEX>, Catalina Espindola and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Stephens</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

