
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> could be without library services if annexation vote fails
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">It was revealed during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> budget workshop the city could very well be without library services if voters fail to pass an annexation measure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   With the city facing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$365,290</NUMEX> operating deficit in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX> has been exploring options to bring before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to reduce that amount. One of the options has the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> public library becoming part of the Yakima Valley Regional Library System. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library would become part of the regional library system if residents approved an annexation measure in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2004</TIMEX>. If approved, residents would pay 50¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value directly to the regional library system to operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> facility. The levy would generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$235,000</NUMEX> in funding for the regional library system. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents pay nothing directly for the operation of the city library. Rather, money for operation of the library comes from city taxes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> the city would save in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140,000</NUMEX> if the regional library system took over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> facility.   But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s budget workshop revealed some confusion about funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> and where the facility would stand in the future if voters failed to pass the annexation measure.   No official funding decisions by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will be made until the end of the budget workshops <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Weyhe</ENAMEX>, director of the Yakima Valley Regional Library System, was in attendance at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s budget workshop. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the regional system would take over complete operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> if the annexation measure passes.   In regards to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with some statistics regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> facility.   "We consider it the regional library for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has the second most used library facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>, behind <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 12 months</TIMEX> a total of 1,140 people have registered for a library card in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> of the 8,447 card holders at the facility live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Six percent</NUMEX> of the remaining card holders live in Outlook with another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> living in each community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library also has card holders who live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Valley</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, people at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library checked out 70,484 items, ranging from books to videos, up <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">19 percent</NUMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> also has the newest computer system in the county. On average at least five computers are in use at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library every hour.   The total operating budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$369,825</NUMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>. The majority of those costs are for personnel, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$145,630</NUMEX> for what equates to just under four full-time employees. There is also <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$98,000</NUMEX> reserved for material purchases in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. The regional library system subsidizes the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> facility.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said regional library directors have agreed to hold the fee for the city at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> level of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,500</NUMEX>. The city budgets around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140,000</NUMEX> for the operation of the library, but the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> goes directly to the regional system. The remaining money is used for maintenance and operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> facility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said the regional library has agreed to reduce the city's amount for funding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>, but only if the annexation measure passes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.   City Finance Director Chad Stotz, though, explained to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> he has already removed the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> from the library's allocation and put it in the current expense fund. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> clarified for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> he is recommending the city pull the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> from the library regardless of what happens with the annexation vote.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> was concerned about whether the library could operate if the city took away the funding. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said she couldn't say what will happen with less funding. The regional system would be bound to live up to its contract with the city for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, but after that, with reduced funding, the future of the library could be in question.   "If the vote fails that means the citizens have voted to not tax themselves for library services," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said if the citizens and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opt to not support funding for the library she doesn't see how it could afford to operate after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> wanted additional information on how much money the library system would gain from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents if the annexation is approved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> wanted to make sure that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents weren't subsidizing library services for other communities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said the library doesn't allocate its funding in that matter.   "We don't dedicate funds," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>. "Our funding is county wide."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> asked for city staff to provide a report on how much money the library would generate from residents living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and the school district boundaries.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Matson</ENAMEX> couldn't understand why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wants to burden the taxpayers with funding the library directly when the current system is working.   "I am having a hard time understanding why it is a good system for taxpayers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX>. "It is a cost increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> to the local taxpayers and you guys could do it for half the amount."   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

