
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rotary</ENAMEX> speaker charter school advocate
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When voters step into the voting booth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> there is a very good chance that they will be asked to make a decision on the fate of charter schools.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Blomgren</ENAMEX>, founder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christa McAuliffe Academy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and candidate for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County Commissioner, spoke to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX> about the concept of charter schools.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blomgren</ENAMEX> described charter schools as a "new kind of public school" that is paid for by tax dollars, run by a non-profit organization and is freed from many of the regulations that public schools are typically held to. He added that charter schools do not charge tuition.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blomgren</ENAMEX> there are currently more than 3,000 charter schools in operation throughout the country. He added that 40 states in the nation, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. have laws that allow for the creation of charter schools.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blomgren</ENAMEX> added that the referendum involving charter schools that will likely be on the ballot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> is a very modest proposal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blomgren</ENAMEX> said the referendum would allow for five new charter schools to be created across the state each year for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next three years</TIMEX>, then 10 a year for the three years following. He also explained that charter schools have to either be sponsored by the local school district or by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction (OSPI). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blomgren</ENAMEX> said OSPI will oversee all of the charter schools in the state, closing them if they do not meet the requirements of their charter after five years.   "One thing I like about charter schools is the accountability," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blomgren</ENAMEX> said.   He said charter schools also help create more high quality public school choices. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blomgren</ENAMEX> said he feels charter schools are good for students, parents and teachers.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

