3 19 31 34 14 16
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  One's first step in wisdom is to question everything - and one's last is to come to terms with everything.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georg Christoph Lichtenberg</ENAMEX> (1742 - 1799)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>