


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> support staff gets new contract
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved its final in a series of recent collective bargaining agreements.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approved a new three-year agreement with the support staff of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>. Support staff at the police department includes dispatchers, jailers and corrections officers.
</P><P ID="6">   "We have been negotiating some time on this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Councilman Alex de la Cruz excused himself from voting on the matter because of his involvement with the police department's reserve program.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> added the approved three-year agreement is retroactive to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2003</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   One of the areas the city has been looking at, which is addressed in the new agreement, is cross training staff. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> used as an example that the cross training would involve dispatchers being able to the job of a corrections officer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said there are "tons" of benefits to the city in being able to cross train employees to perform multiple tasks.
</P><P ID="10">   Under the terms of the contract, police support staff will receive a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> retroactive pay increase dating back to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of last year</TIMEX>. Support staff will receive an additional <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> pay increase for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, which will conclude with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> pay increase in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the city is not quite ready to begin cross training employees. Once the program is in place, employees will be given a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">7 percent</NUMEX> pay increase.
</P><P ID="12">   One of the highlights of the agreement includes employees being compensated for unused sick leave. Under the contract, employees may incur and roll over up to 960 hours of sick leave. Employees will be paid <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of their current salary for any unused sick leave in excess of 960 hours. Employees in this department are also eligible for vacation buy back.
</P><P ID="13">   The contract also points out that sometimes dispatchers, data entry clerks and receptionists will be required to search prisoners when no other staff is available. Training will be provided to these employees. The employees will receive an extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> for each individual prisoner they search.
</P><P ID="14">   There is also an education incentive for members of the bargaining unit if pursuing an Associate of Arts, science or applied science degree. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Mana</ENAMEX> if anyone was taking advantage of the education incentive program, which allows for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.5 percent</NUMEX> pay increase for every 45 college quarter credits earned. The incentive pay will not exceed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> of the base pay. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said there are only two of the 14 support staff members taking advantage of the education incentive program.
</P><P ID="15">   Also under the terms of the contract, the city will contribute up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$761</NUMEX> per month towards health insurance plans in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. Beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2005</TIMEX>, the figure will increase to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$811</NUMEX> per month per employee for health insurance.
</P><P ID="16">   The agreement between the police department support staff and the city will expire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="18">Webmaster
</P><P ID="19">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




