
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Sunshine Wine Festival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Winners of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX> wine competition will be announced at the annual "Sunshine and Wine Festival," slated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 26</TIMEX>.
The actual judging of the competition will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4-6</TIMEX>. The 23rd annual event drew 356 different wine entries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> from 88 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state wineries, including a majority of the state's top 25 wine producing wineries. The annual fair competition is the only such event that judges <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state wines exclusively.
"This will be our largest competition ever," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Anglin</ENAMEX>, activities manager at the fair.
"We've never had this many entries or this many wineries involved before. It is very exciting to see this competition grow," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anglin</ENAMEX> said.
For the first time ever, because of the large number of entries, the judging will be done by four panels of five judges. Each panel will consist of a moderator and four panel members. The moderator will assist the process of translating the panel's judging skills into gold, silver and bronze medal awards.
The awards will be presented at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26</TIMEX> Sunshine and Wine Festival at the Yakima fairgrounds. Although the wine judging is a closed event, the public can buy tickets for the festival,where the winning wines will be served. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s festival will also feature foods from 15 area restaurants, and wine selections from 53 different wineries.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> imitatorset to perform
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - "The Illusion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>," a show presented by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Vernon</ENAMEX>, will take the stage at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">YVCC Kendall Hall</ENAMEX> auditorium <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 16</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
The county's Retired Senior Volunteer Program is hosting the show as a fund-raiser. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Limited</ENAMEX> reserve seating tickets are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. General seating tickets are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>. Tickets can be ordered by calling (509) 574-6858.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon</ENAMEX> is an award winning <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis Presley</ENAMEX> tribute artist. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2003</TIMEX> he was named best <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX> impersonator at a competition in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Palm Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> The judging panel at that competition included the likes of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>' bodyguard, Sonny West, a back-up singer for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Estelle Brown</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>' band members, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Hodge</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvis</ENAMEX>' personal hairdresser, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Parry</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon</ENAMEX>'s website can be found at: www.dannyvernon.com.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Pasta luncheon, fashion showon tap for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNION GAP</ENAMEX> - The Kamiakin Kiwanis and Retired Senior Volunteer Program groups will present an Italian pasta luncheon and fashion show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 12</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ahtanum Youth Park</ENAMEX> barn.
In addition to the luncheon and fashion show, the afternoon activities will include a silent auction and raffle, including such items as framed wood carvings, afghans, Seattle Symphony tickets and a wine basket.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12</TIMEX> luncheon is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>, to be followed by the fashion show at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> Dress wear from Gottschalks will be featured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s show.
Tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>, are available by calling the Retired Senior Volunteer Program office at (509) 574-6858.
</P> 
<P ID="6">ABATE spring opener comingto Toppenish
Toppenish - The 26th annual ABATE of Washington Spring Opener will be held at the Toppenish rodeo grounds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17-20</TIMEX>.
The four-day event will include activities such as a parade of bikes, music, raffles and a poker run.
The gates open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 17</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> with music beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> Music will be provided by Point of Entry of Yakima Shipply of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid Life Crisis</ENAMEX> of Seattle.
Tickets in advance are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> at the gate. Advance tickets are available by calling (253) 475-4944 or by visiting the ABATE web site at www.abate-wa.org.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Grandview winery  hosts spring event
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Quixote Winery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manchego Real</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guerra</ENAMEX>'s Gourmet Cooking will present a special spring dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 22</TIMEX>, at 604 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elm St.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
A seafood dinner, served with wine will be available at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> per person from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> For more information call the winery at 882-6111.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> concert planned              in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
The public is invited to attend a free concert being presented by the Yakima Valley Community Band <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 2</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium.
The band is under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Schactler</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
 
<P ID="9">College journal writers' reception planned
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Student contributors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> literary journal, Prism <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, will be guests of honor at a reception to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 2</TIMEX>, on the Grandview campus.
The reception, scheduled from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>, will introduce the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> writers, artists and photographers who submitted their work for inclusion in the magazine. Also as part of the event copies of the magazine will be presented to the young artists, as well as  special awards for the top contributors.
Similar receptions are planned for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> campus students on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX> and 3, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima YVCC</ENAMEX> campus.
</P> 
<P ID="10">‘No Haters’ program scheduled in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton
MABTON</ENAMEX> -  The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> ninth and 10th graders are in rehearsal for a special end-of-the-year variety show to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, May 27</TIMEX>, at the high school gym.
Under the direction of high school English teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Thomas</ENAMEX>, the students will celebrate their differences under the theme "No Haters Allowed."
The young performers will present programs for their fellow students at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12:30 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
They are also scheduled to give an evening performance for their families and the community at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> said.
The evening show will be held in conjunction with a fund-raiser dinner to benefit the school football program. Cost for the  dinner and show is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX>, payable at the door.
</P> 


 




<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

