
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Students shouldbe allowed to defend themselves
Disruption of the educational process, what does this mean to those who administer discipline at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>?
I'm writing as a concerned parent to voice the troubles I've had concerning one of my children who attends the high school. My son is a senior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Since the ninth grade he has had nothing but trouble with other students harassing him and instigating fights. In every situation he was told to walk away and try to find a teacher to help, which he has done before but still received a punishment.
First of all, how many teachers do you think are going to be on top of the situation if they're not aware of the problem?
Just recently my son was harassed again at school by another student. We were not notified. My son told us of the problem. He was pulled from class on one occasion and was told by an assistant principal that it was only the second week of school and he had already been in the office three times.
In our eyes his problem was being ignored by the same people we think should be concerned with the safety of our children when in school. I've had phone conversations with one of the assistant principals and let him know of the concerns I had for my son, and that I was to be notified in the future if any problems occurred, and that I wanted this problem solved with the other students. I was assured it had been resolved.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two days later</TIMEX> my son was assaulted from behind. He turned around and defended himself, and tried to walk away but was pursued again. My son was suspended from school for five days because he didn't walk away. The assistant principal's way of looking at it was he should of turned around and walked away. I don't know about anybody else, but doesn't that sound just a little bit strange that if you're being attacked from behind, you should walk away? Maybe if you're Superman, but there are no super heroes here, because if there were we wouldn't have to deal with people like the assistant principals at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.
You can't close your eyes and pretend you're living in a perfect world. Instead, you should keep your eyes open to reality.
My point in all this is, what are we teaching students at school? I'll tell you what, we're teaching them, no matter what the circumstances are, there will still be consequences for all parties involved. Where do you draw the line?
I will continue to teach my children to walk away as I have always done in the past. But I do believe that when put in a situation beyond your control, you will and should defend yourself.
We will, of course, go through the proper channels as we've done in the past, to try to appeal the suspension ruling. But here is where things get really odd. You see, your're allowed to appeal a suspension, but that does not stop the suspension. By the time you go through the appeal process, his five days will already be served. So even if you win an appeal, your child will still have missed school. Shouldn't they wait to see if the suspension is upheld? Does it matter if a suspension is served right away or in a week or two?
This type of system needs to change and I can only hope it is changed before my other two children attend <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High. Maybe by then there will be a better system. Until then we will have to continue to deal with ignorance.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Dorsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Complaint needs to be investigated
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX> the U.S. House of Representatives <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> on Standards and Official Conduct, also known as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Ethics Committee</ENAMEX>, must make a decision vital to our democracy. Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state is one of the 10 committee members. This group must decide whether to investigate the serious ethics complaint it received against Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom DeLay</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.
According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> rules, no other group or party has the power to investigate a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> representative. The charges are serious. They involve outright fraud, money laundering and the illegal use of federal troops to push through the redistricting of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>.
Unfortunately, four of the representatives who are members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s own <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX>, have taken money from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> or from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PAC</ENAMEX> in recent years.
What does it say for our government when a man charged with engaging in "pay-to-play" politics can also pay off the members of the jury that must decide whether to investigate him?
If the charges are groundless, let an investigation put them to rest. If, however, members of the committee who have been paid by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeLay</ENAMEX> lack the integrity either to recuse themselves or appoint special counsel to look into the charges, then <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s representative democracy suffers a terrible blow. What confidence can we then have that our representatives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, such as Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, will actually represent the people whose votes sent them there, instead of representing those who fill their pockets?
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celeste Pagano</ENAMEX>, Houston, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Blood drawing
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> blood drawing held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX> was sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>. Yolle Widdows-Guizar was the chairperson.
We had 79 presenters and four first-time donors.Thirteen were unable to give, leaving 66 units collected. Because of their efforts, 198 people will have another chance at life.
Many thanks to the sponsors for donating the cookies and juice, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> for the use of its hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX> for publicity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> Corrugators for displaying the banner at Centennial Square.
And then there are the volunteers whose services are always appreciated: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Benedetti</ENAMEX>, Myrtis Lange, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona Meek</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ella Mae Lochner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Morris</ENAMEX>.
A very special thank you to the donors, who are the lifeline for the flow of blood in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX> to see everyone at the next blood drawing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 2</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Handy</ENAMEX>, blood drawing chairperson
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

