
<P ID="1">Kiwanians draw inspiration from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Man</ENAMEX> competitors
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Several years ago Coach McCarthy of the Colorado Buffaloes was looking around a stadium filled with screaming fans and wondered what would happen if a stadium could be filled with men who came together to praise God.   Promise Keepers, a non-denominational men's group was born from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McCarthy</ENAMEX>'s inspiration, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Browning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> member and speaker at the breakfast meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, there are Promise Keepers conventions held across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX> said he didn't start attending the meetings until later, but he said, he has attended the past five of six years.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the program focused on issues between fathers and sons. He said that although it isn't a problem he deals with personally, he learned that there are a lot of fathers and sons who are alienated from each other.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Browning</ENAMEX> played a video for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Kiwanians, the same video shown to the men attending a Promise Keepers conference that told the story of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick and Rick Hoyt</ENAMEX>, who competed in the 25th <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iron Man</ENAMEX> competition in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>.   The video showed images of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Hoyt</ENAMEX> pulling a boat carrying his son as he swam one leg of the race. It showed him riding a bicycle with his grown son riding in a seat attached to the front of the bike, and it showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoyt</ENAMEX> pushing his son's wheelchair in the running portion of the race.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoyt</ENAMEX> tells how on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10, 1962</TIMEX> he and his wife knew something was wrong with their son. He was born with his umbilical cord wrapped around his neck, cutting off oxygen to the brain.   Doctors encouraged him and his wife to institutionalize the youngster at 8 months of age, because they believed the youngster would always be a vegetable. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoyt</ENAMEX> and his wife said, "No, we're going to take him home."   Seeing a sparkle in their son's eye, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoyt</ENAMEX>'s knew that he wasn't a vegetable. They knew there was someone trapped inside his body.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoyt</ENAMEX> and his wife had a computer made to help their son communicate with them. He said that when family and friends came to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX>'s first words, they expected "Hi, Mom" or "Hi, Dad." But the words <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> chose to share were "Go <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bruins</ENAMEX>," referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston</ENAMEX> hockey team.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Team Hoyt</ENAMEX>'s first race was a charity run for a paralyzed athlete, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> talked his father into running.   "We came in second to last," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>, "But when we got home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> wrote, 'When we run, it feels like my disability disappears'."   It was after that race that the two started competing in other races and triathlons.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> said it is an awesome experience to see the support when they reach the finish line.   The elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hoyt</ENAMEX> also tells in the video that if his son was physically able, he believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> would probably play basketball, football or hockey. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> says if he was able he would run, pushing his dad in his chair.   Competing in races is not the only accomplishment <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> has made. He graduated from a regular high school, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boston University</ENAMEX>.   "You can do anything you want to do if you make up your mind to do it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX> added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

