
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">PAID <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OBITUARY
BERTHA CURFMAN
Bertha Curfman</ENAMEX>, 100, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. 
She was born <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha Bates</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oklahoma’s Indian Territory</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1904</TIMEX> to cotton farmers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha</ENAMEX> moved with her family to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>, where her father filed for a homestead adjacent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curfman</ENAMEX> family, which she later married into. The Santa Fe Trail divided the two homesteads. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> day 1921</TIMEX> she was married to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Curfman</ENAMEX>. They moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1930s</TIMEX> during the Great Depression. Drought drove them from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. Curfman’s family located in the Outlook area in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX>. They leased 160 acres of Indian land for a dairy and later an egg business. After her husband’s death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha</ENAMEX> moved into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where she has made her home until the time of her death.
 She is survived by her daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bemma Lue Floyd</ENAMEX> and husband <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clair</ENAMEX>; her three sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifton Curfman</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Avis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin Curfman</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlotte</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Curfman</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen</ENAMEX>; 16 grandchildren; 41 great-grandchildren and 17 great-great-grandchildren. 
She was preceded in death by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence</ENAMEX>; and one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilford</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 28, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> until the time of the funeral service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cemetery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements. Those wishing to honor Bertha’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Association</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">THEODORE C. WRIGHT JR.
Theodore</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Wright Jr.</ENAMEX>, 57, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kent</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 22, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Buren</ENAMEX> after a hard fought battle with various health complications. 
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 21, 1947</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore and Pearl Wright</ENAMEX>, who both had been residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasco High School</ENAMEX>, where he lettered in track. He retired early after working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> for more than 30 years.
He was an avid bowler and a pool player, earning numerous trophies. 
He was a long-time member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moose Lodge</ENAMEX> and the Eagles Lodge while earning awards on the rituals team. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted</ENAMEX> was a big Seattle sports fan and spent many a night enjoying professional wrestling.
He is survived by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearl C. Wright</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clifford Wright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Troy Wright</ENAMEX>; two grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Makenzi Wright</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedi Wright</ENAMEX>; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolene Sandwick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Johnson</ENAMEX>; and numerous other relatives and friends.
He was preceded in death by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theodore C. Wright Sr.</ENAMEX>
You could hear him say with playful conceit as he struts through the gates, “The good lookin’ one is here!”
A graveside service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 28, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at Mountain View Cemetery in Auburn. There will be a small banquet following the service at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Nazarene at 1225 29th St. S.E., Auburn, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98002.  
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

