


<P ID="1">Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/17/2002</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Presidential address to be heard by members of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">An oration on the trials and tribulations, as well as the successes, of past American presidents will be presented by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Hale</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX> will serve as guest speaker at the women's club meeting, scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairway Restaurant</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="7">Men’s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">slo-pitch</ENAMEX> meeting on tap
</P>

<P ID="8">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Men's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Slo-pitch Association</ENAMEX> will hold an organizational meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Tuesday, Feb. 24</TIMEX>, at Chompi's Sports Bar in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">All teams interested in playing organized men's softball this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> are invited to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> meeting.
</P>

 


<P ID="10">New legislation would open venues to challenge rules
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Senate</ENAMEX> voted 48-1 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in approving Senate Bill 6491, which opens up the state's superior courts in four counties to citizens wishing to challenge government rules and regulations.
</P>

<P ID="12">"The bill provides a more equal access to justice," said Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Roach</ENAMEX> (R-Auburn), the prime sponsor of the legislation.
</P>

<P ID="13">"In the past individuals challenging administrative rules could only do so in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thurston County</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roach</ENAMEX> said. "Many citizens had to travel for hours and at great expense because they were paying for not only their travel, but that of their attorneys.
</P>

<P ID="14">"When the bill is signed, people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellingham</ENAMEX> can have access to their local superior courts," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roach</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

<P ID="15">She added that Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> has indicated that he will sign the bill.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




