
<P ID="1">More cold temps, snow invade <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/6/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">With <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools missing as many as <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of their students the first day back after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> break, the second day back was a bit smoother.   "Several of the elementary schools each had 200 or 250 students absent (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Kaplicky</ENAMEX>, community relations coordinator for the school district.   About half of the school district buses wouldn't start the first day back to school, but according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplicky</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> only six of the school district's 24 buses wouldn't start.   "Things went better <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplicky</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District Transportation Director David Taylor</ENAMEX> said his department is working on getting the rest of the buses started.   The buses were unable to start because of the dipping cold temperatures that fell below zero <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.   "Our diesel fuel was gelling up on us and then the batteries didn't want to work," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>. "When diesel get so cold it gels. The buses will sit there and idle, but they won't move."   Currently, transportation employees are putting antigel agent in the fuel and are replacing batteries.   What helped the school district stay on schedule <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> was having bus inside overnight.   "We don't have enough room to house all of the buses inside," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplicky</ENAMEX>.   So, the school district contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Speck Motors</ENAMEX>, which offered to house six of the diesel machines in their shop, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>.   "We had several offers in the community to house other buses," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplicky</ENAMEX>.   The school district was unable to take up other business on their offer because they couldn't get the last six buses started, but now that additional buses are running, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> said they may be calling businesses <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this afternoon</TIMEX>.   To help with the bus shortage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, the school district combined two routes and borrowed two buses from other school districts.   "We borrowed a bus from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> and we borrowed a bus from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah School District</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaplicky</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105 helped us find the Zillah bus, she added.   Now that the buses are running, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s main concern, as the snow continues to fall, is slick roads.   "We're concerned about how much snow we're getting," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>.   As snow falls in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, there is still another day of inclement weather expected before a break in the cycle the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of this week</TIMEX>. Rain, freezing rain and snow is called for on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>.   By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the weather is expected to warm to a high of 40 degrees with a low at 34 degrees. Warmer weather is also expected for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.   To help remove snow around the county the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Department of Transportation</ENAMEX> is ready to first focus on the main thoroughfares and then on some of the less traveled roads, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSDOT</ENAMEX> spokesperson <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Briggs</ENAMEX>.   Highway maintenance crews in six <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WSDOT</ENAMEX> regions, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>, are on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> schedules providing around-the-clock coverage when poor driving conditions are forecasted. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briggs</ENAMEX>, crews will first focus on the interstate freeways and other highways with the highest traffic volumes.   Anti-ice, de-icer and sand will be applied to bridges, hills and curves where snow and ice can cause hazardous driving conditions.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

