
<P ID="1">Five teens named <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> fire cadets
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Five <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> teens ages 16 and 17 have been selected to participate in the newly formed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department Cadet</ENAMEX> program.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Roe</ENAMEX>, the coordinator for the program, two of the students, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Aguirre</ENAMEX>, attend <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>; two cadets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Groenewold</ENAMEX>, attend <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia Muñoz</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> student.   "They all had good interviewing skills," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> said of the five students selected to participate in the program. "And when they were asked to show up they were all there, if not early."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX> added that the students each have career aspirations that the cadet program can help enhance.   "They all expressed a strong desire to help the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>.   There is room for one additional cadet.   The students each completed the five components making up the physical ability test to make the cut.   They each had to carry a roll of hose, drag hose line 100-feet, lift rolls of hose, drag a dummy and complete a quarter mile jog, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roe</ENAMEX>.   He said the cadet physical agility test is based on the test potential firefighter reserves have to complete.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, 16, has an interest in becoming a nursing after high school. She is already preparing to get her certified nurses assistant license and looks forward to the opportunities the cadet program will open up.   "Being an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMT</ENAMEX> (emergency medical technician) is different than being a nurse," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. "They get to be there first and help at the emergency scene."   Besides learning more about the work of EMTs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said she wanted to be more active in the community.   "This will be a learning experience of how the fire department and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMT</ENAMEX> works," she added.   A high school sophomore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aguirre</ENAMEX>, 16, is the third generation in his family that's been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>.   His grandfather was a volunteer for about 25 years and his father volunteered with the department for 14 years.   "I figured this would be a good experience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aguirre</ENAMEX>.   During the application process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aguirre</ENAMEX> said the hardest part was the interview portion with a panel of firefighters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aguirre</ENAMEX> has aspirations of becoming a pharmacologist.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bos</ENAMEX>, 17, a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian, plans to attend college in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> and study aviation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   He said he feels participating in the cadet program will gear him up and provide opportunities to volunteer with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moses Lake Fire Department</ENAMEX>, which has a resident program. The resident program allows volunteers to live at the fire department.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Groenewold</ENAMEX>, 16, a sophomore in high school, has aspirations of either being an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMT</ENAMEX> or working in search and rescue for his career.   He hopes to be able to learn the basics of the fire department while participating in the cadet program, which will include responding to calls to assisting in a supporting role.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Muñoz</ENAMEX>, 17, would like to study medicine and possibly be a doctor safter she is finished with high school.   She is currently working on her senior project, which is on the fire department and cadet program.   The cadets will begin training <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>), when they will learn <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX> and first aid.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

