
<P ID="1">Nearly two dozen earn 4.00 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>'s at middle school
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/24/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Approximately two dozen students at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> aced their grades the final quarter of the 2003-04 academic year.   Of the 23 straight-A students, 18 were girls.   The eight seventh graders who earned perfect 4.00 grade point averages were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Bridger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susana Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Palacios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey Rollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Salmeron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristal Sandoval</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler</ENAMEX>.   From the eighth grade class at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX>, 15 students were named to the all-A honor roll. They included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Barrios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Brandvold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Burgard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashlie Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Estudillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Flodin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Herndon</ENAMEX>, Jordyne Jaquish, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Razey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Southern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Stiteler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Wedam</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joceline Wynn</ENAMEX>.   Numerous other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> students have been listed on the regular honor roll, for maintaining at least a 3.00 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last quarter</TIMEX> of the academic year.   Regular honor roll students from the eighth grade included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Abundiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anjelica Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Alanis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Alanis</ENAMEX>, Alondra Alarcon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Alejandre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica M. Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittney Amaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Amaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe Avalos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Baldovinos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Ballesteros</ENAMEX>, Matthew Barr, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Benitez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Benitez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Bobadilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norberto Bobadilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Boboth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacy Bogart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Boogerd</ENAMEX>, Aristeo Borges, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Bott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Camacho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deyma Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianeli Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatriz Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petra Carrillo</ENAMEX>, Araceli Castaneda, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Castellanos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogelio Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriana Cisneros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Cornelius</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Cornwell</ENAMEX>, Rachel Corona, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Dawson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela De La Barrera</ENAMEX>, Challea DeCann, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuel Delgado</ENAMEX>, Derrick Denson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dacia Drollinger</ENAMEX>, Maegen Elizondo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Araceli Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Estrada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kassandra Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell Gabino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriana Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Garibaldo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Garza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Gonzales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Graham</ENAMEX>, Kassaundra Guillen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, Diedree Hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Haringa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Harvey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Henry</ENAMEX>, Yesenia Herrera, Jordan James, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaitlin Jeske</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Jongsma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Kaiser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Lain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Leon</ENAMEX>, Araceli Lepez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Licona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Linde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Longoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guillermo Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Macias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Macias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelita Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Marin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanca Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christella Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paloma Mata</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah NcNerney</ENAMEX>, Kelsea Means, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Melendrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maritza Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Messmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Moncada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Montero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Olivarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Palomarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Pearson</ENAMEX>, Araceli Peralta, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pina</ENAMEX>, Beverleigh Quenan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Radach</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catalina Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvia Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Ramos</ENAMEX>, Jeronimo Rangel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brice Rinehold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Ritchey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianna Robert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahna Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damariz Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanci Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Roehl</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kayla Rollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelica Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Sabedra</ENAMEX>, Lucerito Salcedo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Samaniego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Santoy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, Mayra Serna, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Shuttleworth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandro Solis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dora Sosa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Stamschror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Talbert</ENAMEX>, Mayra Tapia, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Tellez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jovan Vargas</ENAMEX>, Marisol Vazquez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Velazquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Vidales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilberto Villalobos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Villanueva</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erick Vizguerra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyson Waddle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Watts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigel Weenink</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Wolfe</ENAMEX>, Kraig Wyatt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shana Zamarron</ENAMEX>, Anika Zamora and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Zijlstra</ENAMEX>.   Seventh graders named to the regular honor roll were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Abbott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alma Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Almeida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catalina Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Anderson</ENAMEX>, Lupita Arriaga, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baltazar Avalos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Araceli Baldovinos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Ballesteros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Barcenas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebeca Barrios</ENAMEX>, Daysi Bautista, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Bieber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Bonilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Bonny</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Bridges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Bueno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubi Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvira Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Cleghorn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Correa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Cuevas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Cuevas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Del Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy DeRuyter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Dolan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashleigh Emery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fermin Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Frausto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsie Gabino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivonne Galindo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Galindo</ENAMEX>, Maritza Godines, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maribel Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracen Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Gudino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Guizar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levi Hagert</ENAMEX>, Antassia Hammond, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Autumn</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hathaway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aarika Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moises Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Isquierdo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Jensen</ENAMEX>, Mayra Juarez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kilian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Louie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kassandra Luther</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad Martinez</ENAMEX>, Kathia Medina, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yesenia Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Meza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio Mojica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Murrey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Myers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis Nash</ENAMEX>, Udi Nassar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Navarro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haydee Navarro</ENAMEX>, Nelida Ochoa, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Pacheco</ENAMEX>, Shianne Partida, Thailee Paxton, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Pearson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Picazo</ENAMEX>, Yesenia Quiroz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julio Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocio Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Reihs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Reyes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georgena Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karina Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Rubalcava</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Sambrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katya Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Saucedo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Serrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Slinker</ENAMEX>, Jerica Wells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krystal Snyder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Solis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hali Soto</ENAMEX>, Henedina Tavares, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsee Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Vargas</ENAMEX>, Naomy Velasco, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Verduzco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Seeger</ENAMEX>, Katelyn Wutzke, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Zamorano</ENAMEX> and Yesenia Zaragoza.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

