
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/26/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> Sunrise service planned
A community <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> sunrise service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 11</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football field, South 16th Street. The bilingual service will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastor Mike Henry</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Methodist Church</ENAMEX> will deliver the morning message. A number of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> churches will be participating in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter Sunday</TIMEX> program, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Reformed Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iglesia Evangelica</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of God. A continental breakfast will follow at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Reformed Church</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Jubilee dancers   to be featured      at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>  worship service
"The Gift of the Cross" will be presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First  Baptist Church</ENAMEX> congregation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 28</TIMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> service will feature scripture readings, communion, and a worship dance by the Jubilee dancers of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin School of Dance</ENAMEX> as a part of a presentation by the church choir.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

