


<P ID="1">Outlook man new fire chief
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/1/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Being a firefighter is a unique occupation. Even more unique is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Vogel</ENAMEX> is fire chief of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County Fire District</ENAMEX> #5, the largest fire district in the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   "I am pretty excited about it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> of his new job.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>, 43, took over the duties of chief <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>), replacing the retired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Kimm</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimm</ENAMEX> officially retired from the fire district <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, leaving behind a 33-year career, nine of which was as the chief.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> is a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and currently lives in Outlook with his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheryl</ENAMEX>. The couple has two children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jordan</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fire</ENAMEX> fighting sort of runs in the blood for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. His father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, retired from the fire management office of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bureau of Indian Affairs</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> first became involved with the county fire district, which covers 700 square miles, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, volunteering in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> station. While he volunteered at the county station, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> continued working at Safeway in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, a job he had held since he was 16 years old.
</P><P ID="10">   "It was a good job," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "But I knew it was not what I wanted to do with the rest of my life."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> wasn't initially interested in a career in fire fighting. He went to college and took some pre-law classes with the desire of going into law enforcement. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> joked that he decided to switch careers because he didn't like the idea of shift work.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> earned his break with the fire district in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, starting out as a firefighter, then moving to zone chief for the county's station in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Due to some reorganization, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> was promoted to the position of battalion chief, where he oversaw the day-to-day operations for four fire stations-Grandview, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and Outlook. The position of battalion chief has since been changed to captain. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> was named to the position of deputy chief, who works directly under the fire chief. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> replaced the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Donaldson</ENAMEX>, whom he considers one of his mentors in the firefighting profession.
</P><P ID="13">   "He was a good teacher," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "He was a very professional fireman. I had a lot of good teachers. I had a lot of good mentors."
</P><P ID="14">   In his role as deputy chief, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> oversaw the four captains that look over the operations of the 16 fire stations within the district.
</P><P ID="15">   "It was more of an administrative role," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> decided to apply for the position of fire chief because it was the next step in his career.
</P><P ID="17">   "It was just a career goal of mine from the day I started," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "It is something I am looking forward to doing."
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> doesn't expect things to change all that much since he has taken over the lead role in the district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> said one of the important aspects of the job he learned from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimm</ENAMEX> was to involve the rest of the staff.
</P><P ID="19">   "He made an effort to give everybody a voice," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "That didn't mean he would always agree with you, but he gave everybody an opportunity to be heard."
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> said he wants to continue the tradition <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimm</ENAMEX> had in the district of including everyone in the decision making.
</P><P ID="21">   "Hopefully, everybody still feels their opinion is valuable," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "It is going to be a group effort."
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimm</ENAMEX> left the fire district in great shape, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   "The district has moved light years ahead of where it was," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> hopes to keep that momentum going in his new position, but he also has some other goals he wants to address.
</P><P ID="25">   "I would really like for the people of our district to know who we are," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "A lot of people don't really realize there is a fire district that protects them."
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> said there have been several occasions where he has gone out to fight a fire and people think that the county personnel work for one of the cities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> said the fire district has been working hard over the last few years to establish its own identity, and he wants to keep that momentum going. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> is also hoping that increased publicity will help boost the number of volunteers in the district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> wants people to see volunteering with the county fire department can lead to a good career.
</P><P ID="27">   "Within our district, most people who come to work here stay here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>, though, is expecting to face some tough decisions if any more tax cutting initiatives pass. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> deals with a nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3 million</NUMEX> budget that comes strictly from property tax revenue. With that money, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> oversees 20 paid staff, which includes administrators, firemen and dispatchers, and 16 different fire stations within a 700 square mile area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> said the fire district has always prided itself with never having to go to the voters with a special bond or levy to pay for services.
</P><P ID="29">   "We still don't want to go to a bond issue," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "But, it is going to come to the point where we won't have much choice."
</P><P ID="30">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX> is looking forward to a prosperous career as the new chief.
</P><P ID="31">   "The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> I am going to be learning the little things that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> did," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vogel</ENAMEX>. "I love my job. There haven't been any days that I have woke up and haven't wanted to go to work."
</P>





 










<P ID="32">Webmaster
</P><P ID="33">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




