
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage University</ENAMEX> celebrates milestone
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - Staff, students and friends of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX> gathered to celebrate as the four-year institution received its new recognition as a university.   The school, which has been serving the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, has about 800 students attending classes each week.   Students attending the college can study business and accounting, English and humanities, math and computer science, the sciences and education and psychology. Students can also study for Associate of Arts degrees and Master's degrees.   Since the inception of the college, there has been major improvements to the grounds, including the addition of the library and learning center and the student services center. In the future, Heritage, along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>, will be adding a business and community training center to the campus.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

