


<P ID="1">Sheriff seeks councilmen's support for county law and justice sales tax
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">What was basically a sales pitch to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> turned into an interesting discussion between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Sheriff Ken Irwin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> stood before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to market the need for a sales tax increase he is proposing to help fund law and justice services in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said he was seeking the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with a letter of recommendation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners for the measure to be placed before voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The tax calls for an increase of 3/10th of a penny. The tax would be charged on all items sold in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> with the exception of groceries, medical services and automobile sales and leases. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> explained that if a county resident spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> shopping, the sales tax will basically amount to an additional 30¢ being charged.
</P><P ID="8">   "That is not a huge tax," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>. "We are going to put it to good use."
</P><P ID="9">   Under the proposal, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> would receive <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the revenue from the sales tax, estimated to be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.7 million</NUMEX> in its initial year. The other <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> would be split among the 14 cities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> on a per capita basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> would receive the largest part of the funding, an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX>, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$279,873</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> would gain an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$165,869</NUMEX> under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s proposal. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> would see an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,024</NUMEX> in revenue.
</P><P ID="10">   "You could put that to good use in your law and justice system," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> he was looking for some sort of solution to address decreasing revenue the county is experiencing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said with the tax cut initiatives voters have passed, the county and cities are operating on shoestring budgets and it is expected to only get worse if voters pass a property tax cut initiative being proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Eyman</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   The sheriff's department serves 90,000 residents in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> oversees a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.9 million</NUMEX> budget and has 65 commissioned officers and 34 clerical/dispatch personnel on staff. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> ranks 37th out of 39th counties in the state in regards to the ratio of officers to residents. Under the proposal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> would hire eight more deputies and two detectives.
</P><P ID="13">   "We just plain need a few more law enforcement officers out there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>. "You can just do so much with the amount of deputy sheriffs we have on the road."
</P><P ID="14">   If voters pass <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s proposal, the money will also be used to fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> prosecutor, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> and juvenile court offices. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County plans to dedicate money to re-establishing a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   "It is the whole law and justice system we are trying to help out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Prosecutor Ron Zirkle has a desk load of felony cases ready to go to trial, but he doesn't have the staff to prosecute. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said this tax would help relieve some of that burden.
</P><P ID="17">   "This is a fair tax," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>. "This is spread out amongst the whole population."
</P><P ID="18">   If passed, the life of the tax measure would be for six years. The measure would then be put before voters again, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>. The sheriff said his plan is to keep the public as well informed as possible about where the money from the sales tax is being spent.
</P><P ID="19">   "I want that accountability to the public," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> had some questions about where the money would go from the tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said the sheriff's department would receive about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">32 percent</NUMEX> of the county's portion of the funds with that amount declining each year. The prosecuting attorney's office would gain about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> with the rest of the money being split by different departments.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> that he felt money from the tax shouldn't be split on a per capita basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said if one community was generating much more sales tax revenue than another, that city should be reimbursed accordingly.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> did agree that probation services need to be located in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> also wanted the county to put more pressure on the Yakama Nation to provide funding.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX>, in attendance at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting, said he was in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s measure and told the sheriff he wished the amount he was requesting was higher than 3/10th of a penny.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, though, wasn't as agreeable with the proposed tax by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he had concerns, especially with the property tax initiative coming before voters, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s proposal wasn't solving any funding issues.
</P><P ID="26">   "It does not solve the underlying revenue problem that exists," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he was worried about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s proposal passing and then in six years voters aren't for it and people end up being put out of work or the sheriff's department is left trying to find another way to fund the positions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eyman</ENAMEX>'s initiative passes, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will lose <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$380,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, which comes out of the general fund. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the money coming from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s tax proposal wouldn't totally replace all of the money lost.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> disagreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>'s observations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said the people need to decide what sort of law enforcement services they want.
</P><P ID="29">   "We have to look the people in the eye and say if you want this level of service then you are going to have to pay," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the state needs to find permanent lines of funding, so city and county agencies aren't constantly looking for ways to fund programs. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he will vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s tax because it is the only option he can foresee.
</P><P ID="31">   "This is not the solution," stated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. "The problem has not been solved (with this proposal). This system is flawed."
</P><P ID="32">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said he understood what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> was saying, but until the legislature changes the way it does things, there is a need to be proactive to address funding shortfalls.
</P><P ID="33">   "Shame on us if we don't take positive steps," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="34">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> asked staff to do more research on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s proposal and how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eyman</ENAMEX>'s property tax initiative would play into the scenario. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will address providing its support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>'s proposal at a meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="35">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="36">Webmaster
</P><P ID="37">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




