


<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/30/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">   DON <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. BRUNELL</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   Some critics of the American economic system point to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> as the model we should emulate: shorter work hours, longer vacations, generous employee benefits, and in some cases, an employer has to get the government's permission to fire a worker.
</P><P ID="5">   "Money isn't everything," these people say. "Europeans have a better quality of life." Really? Let's take a look.
</P><P ID="6">   According to a recent report by two economists at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sweden</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timbro Institute</ENAMEX>, the quality of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is pretty bad. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Great Britain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> have lower per capita <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GDP</ENAMEX> than all but four of the states in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. In fact, if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX> were a state in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, it would be among the poorest, on a par with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arkansas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mississippi</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Virginia</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   It is true that most Europeans work less than Americans. It is also true that they have less to show for it. The average house in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> is about half the size of the average American home. In fact, the average European home is smaller than the homes of Americans who live in poverty.
</P><P ID="8">   Speaking of poverty, the percentage of poor people in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> has diminished over the past several decades. For example in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">22 percent</NUMEX> of all Americans lived below the poverty line. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Conditions also have steadily improved for minorities. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">55 percent</NUMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">African Americans</ENAMEX> lived in poverty. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, it's <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24 percent</NUMEX>. Not great, but better.
</P><P ID="10">   But what is poverty in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>? The Swedish authors surveyed poor Americans to get a picture of how they live. They found that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45 percent</NUMEX> of poor Americans own their own homes, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">73 percent</NUMEX> own a car, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">97 percent</NUMEX> own a color television, and more than half own two or more color TVs. Two out of three poor households in American have cable or satellite TV and one in four has a wide screen television. As the authors remarked, "It is better to be poor in a rich country than in a poor one."
</P><P ID="11">   How does this compare to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>? According to the authors, at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> of all European households would be considered poverty-stricken in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   So, what does this tell us? It tells us that despite all our problems, we're on the right track. Conditions are better here than in most of the rest of the world, and they're getting better for the poorest among us.
</P><P ID="13">   The study confirms that high taxes and burdensome regulations strangle initiative and economic growth. When that happens, it is the individual who suffers. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Italy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">France</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spain</ENAMEX> all have unemployment rates <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> higher than the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>, and many of the jobs in those countries and other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EU</ENAMEX> members are actually public-sector jobs that "produce" nothing.
</P><P ID="14">   Europeans may have an easier time at work, but shorter work hours, longer vacations and great benefits don't matter if you don't have a job.
</P><P ID="15">   Since jobs are the focal point of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s presidential campaign, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Timbro Institute</ENAMEX> study ought to give us something to think about.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don C. Brunell</ENAMEX> is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




