
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">PAID <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OBITUARY
ZACHARY WALTER BRUCE ANDEREGG
Zachary Walter Bruce Anderegg</ENAMEX>, 17, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Jan. 14, 2004</TIMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 1986</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Bruce Anderegg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McGuire</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anderegg</ENAMEX>. He received his early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tillamook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, later moving with his family to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>. He was currently a junior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton High School</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Verdene Anderegg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>; his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Anderegg</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerrilee</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Anderegg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eugene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; and his grandfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Anderegg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Troutdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>
He was preceded in death by one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Mae</ENAMEX>.
A memorial service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Jan. 18, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at the Native American Building, 710 S.W. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Jan. 19, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton High School</ENAMEX> gym. In lieu of flowers, memorials may be made to the Bickleton Hilltoppers (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4-H Group</ENAMEX>), c/o <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Miller</ENAMEX>, 50 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Rd.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX>., 99322. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GEORGE HALMA
George Halma</ENAMEX>, 73, long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> dairy farmer passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Jan. 14, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Providence Hospital</ENAMEX>. 
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Halma</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 1930</TIMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattie</ENAMEX> (Dijkstra) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Halma</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> received his education in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>. At the age of 17 he with his family migrated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, settling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1948</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> as a sergeant during the Korean Conflict. Following his honorable discharge from the military <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattie Van Grouw</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2, 1953</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Inwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattie</ENAMEX> farmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX> for three years before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> worked for various farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> before starting his own dairy in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX> his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin</ENAMEX>, took over the operation of the dairy.
He enjoyed the daily coffee time with his many friends at the Outpost, solving all the world problems.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife of 50 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattie Halma</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; five children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Johnson</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlin Halma</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelly</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ardis Hollmeyer</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harlan Halma</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Halma</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merri</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nampa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>; 13 grandchildren; three great-grandchildren; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Halma</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hudsonville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>; three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eunice Jonkman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jenison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Diedering</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kentwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Horstman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sparta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>
He was preceded in death by his parents.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 16, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 17, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HILDA S. LADD
Hilda S. Ladd</ENAMEX>, 89, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> went to be in the arms of her Savior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Jan. 15, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14, 1914</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX> (Plowman) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santjer</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Renville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX> She received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, graduating with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmer Ladd</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mahnomen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX> Following their marriage they moved to Seattle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda</ENAMEX> worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>. The Ladds later moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Jose</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, where she worked for Lockheed Aircraft. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX> they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmer</ENAMEX> owned a rabbit farm. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda</ENAMEX> also worked for Nor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tech</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> until her retirement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. Following her retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilda</ENAMEX> moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where she made her home until the time of her death.
She was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Assembly of God Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She enjoyed time spent with her friends and family. She loved helping people and sharing her talents with others.
She is survived by her three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Santjer</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Della</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Enumclaw</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester Santjer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Santjer</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramona</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>; and numerous nieces and nephews.
She was preceded in death by her parents; husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elmer Ladd</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hattie Hoekstra</ENAMEX>; and one brother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Santjer</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Jan. 19, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 20, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at Wells Funeral Home, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

