
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> man serves up full-length feature film starring local faces, locations 
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KENNEWICK</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Charboneau</ENAMEX>'s life-long dream to be a filmmaker is finally a reality.   The Promise, a film written, produced and directed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX> man, will premiere in the Tri-Cities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday</TIMEX> and will feature a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> faces.   The most visible face will be that of 9-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Serrano</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, the leading character in the hour and 30-minute movie.   The adorable, little <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Heights Elementary School</ENAMEX> fourth grader plays 6-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX> in a role <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charboneau</ENAMEX> said he patterned after his own daughter.   "She is one of 12 little girls who auditioned for the part," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charboneau</ENAMEX> said. "And she was best suited for the part."   The young actress was encouraged to audition for the part by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Theater Company</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Mears</ENAMEX>, who saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serrano</ENAMEX> perform in the chorus of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser High School</ENAMEX> senior play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   Also appearing in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charboneau</ENAMEX>'s film are two other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Theater</ENAMEX> veterans, Candance Andrews of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> as an extra in scenes shot at Seattle's Pikes Place Market, and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick James</ENAMEX>, who plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serrano</ENAMEX>'s movie father in The Promise.   The Promise is a low-budget, family film shot entirely in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, featuring many landmarks familiar to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> residents. One of the scenes was staged at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hisey Park</ENAMEX> featuring what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charboneau</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dinosaur</ENAMEX> Days. "The scenes feature many <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> residents as extras," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX>'s father, constantly makes promises he is unable to keep. He is finally able to secure a position that will allow more time with his family. Before leaving for the job interview, he promises his daughter a trip to the Seattle Aquarium upon his return.   Due to a tragic accident, the father is killed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX>, being too young to understand the finality of death, refuses to accept the fact that he is gone. Thus, she goes off on a cross-state adventure to meet her father at the Seattle Aquarium. As she states, "A promise made is a promise kept."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX> is aided in her travels by various individuals, including a Mennonite farmer, the Celtic band Skweez the Weezle, and a homeless man from Seattle. The fun ensues as she innocently stays one step ahead of the authorities while finding her way to Seattle.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serrano</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX> shows undaunting faith and innocence which serves as the perfect character traits for her cross-state adventure.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX>'s movie mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katrina Roberts</ENAMEX>, is originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tieton</ENAMEX>. Now living in the Tri-Cities, she plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Bailey</ENAMEX>, a protective mother who unconditionally loves her family.   Also featured in the film are Tri-Cities actor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Roy</ENAMEX> as Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hall</ENAMEX>, the detective investigating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX>'s missing child case: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Bean</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clarisse</ENAMEX>, an elderly woman who befriends <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX> on a bus; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Cummins</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louise</ENAMEX>, a female truck driver; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Salaba</ENAMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Samuel</ENAMEX>, an elderly Mennonite farmer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Actors Joseph Deines</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Waddell</ENAMEX> play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX>, a mid-twenties couple who discover <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX> as a stowaway on a car trip to Seattle, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montgomery Stevens</ENAMEX> portrays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX>, a homeless man who assists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX> in Seattle.   Skweez the Weezle appear as themselves, a Tri-Cities Celtic band traveling to perform at a concert for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>'s "Dinosaur Days."   The film will premiere in the Tri-Cities on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 19</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the Richland Uptown Theatre. A limited number of tickets are for sale by calling 509-943-ARTS   The Promise will also be presented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 12</TIMEX> and 13 at the Battelle Auditorium in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>. Tickets may be obtained from the above number. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charboneau</ENAMEX> said he is also in talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Theater</ENAMEX> owner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Hallett</ENAMEX> to see if a showing might be presented at Grand Way Cinemas in the near future.   "I made this film for my children because I wanted to do something suitable for family viewing," he said.   The Promise is his feature directorial debut, but he is no stranger to the creative process. He is a national award winning producer of television programs and has received recognition for his efforts from such organizations as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Association of Telecommunications</ENAMEX> Officers and Advisors. He is also the recipient of a New York Film Festival Award.   He is an avid writer and has developed five additional screenplays he plans to produce. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charboneau</ENAMEX> is currently the cable communications coordinator for the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, overseeing the daily operations of its governmental access channel.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

