


<P ID="1">County budget <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$58 million</NUMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> Commissioners held council in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to take public input on county funds for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget year.
</P><P ID="5">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Chopin</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> county budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$58,266,128</NUMEX> balances at this time. The budget is an increase from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$55,696,403</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chopin</ENAMEX> said county officials were hoping to build the reserves by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, but they are short. Instead, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$371,433</NUMEX> will be placed in reserves.
</P><P ID="7">   "It will leave us short of the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> we'd like to have in reserves, but the cuts were already pretty severe," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chopin</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Chief Financial Officer for the county, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cary Wainwright</ENAMEX>, explained that the county was hoping to have <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> in reserves to help during the peaks and valleys during the budget year. He explained that the majority of the county's funds are received twice a year and they need to have cash on-hand to pay the monthly bills. Without cash on-hand, the county would have to borrow money to pay the bills.
</P><P ID="9">   Not part of the budget is the 3/10's of a cent sales tax increase for law enforcement, which was approved by voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chopin</ENAMEX> said it will be several months before the county begins to see the tax money, which will be going into a special dedicated fund for law enforcement. A supplemental budget change will be made later in the year, which will allow the funds to be spent on law and justice. He explained that the county may give law enforcement an internal loan to keep people from being laid off.
</P><P ID="10">   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget will eliminate 26 positions within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wainwright</ENAMEX> said that half the positions are currently vacant.
</P><P ID="11">   Among the positions that are being eliminated are 3-1/2 positions with the county's parks department. Two of the positions are currently vacant and one full-time position will be going to half-time. The parks director position held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Veley</ENAMEX> is also being eliminated, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wainwright</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   He said that the county will no longer be having any outreach or future planning for parks at this time, which were part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veley</ENAMEX>'s duties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wainwright</ENAMEX> said the county is hoping to be able to absorb <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veley</ENAMEX> into another department.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wainwright</ENAMEX> said a cut in law and justice across the board from the sheriff's office to the prosecutor's office is also being made.
</P><P ID="14">   The budget doesn't call for cuts in the number of sheriff's deputies, but two dispatchers will be laid off. There will also be cuts in the number of prosecuting attorneys in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, some of which were planning to retire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   One member of the audience, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Fleming</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, spoke out in favor of the county's support of 4-H. The county only reduced the budget of Cooperative Extension, which 4-H falls under, by <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,348</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleming</ENAMEX> said her daughter went through the program and was able to learn about government as part of the program.
</P><P ID="17">   "We think 4-H is important," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Camay</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   Retiring Commissioner Tim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> said that it will be important for 4-H supporters to sit down with commissioners <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> and talk about some funding sources for the program.
</P><P ID="19">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> said that while coming up with the county budget, the commissioners thought long and hard about cuts to non-essential programs, which he added there was a push to make cuts in.
</P><P ID="20">   He said it is frustrating to see the criminal justice system suck up all the tax dollars.
</P><P ID="21">   "We have to house them, delouse them, try them and defend them," said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   At <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> a day for a juvenile offender and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49</NUMEX></NUMEX> for an adult offender, much of the county budget is used in criminal justice.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleming</ENAMEX> said part of the problem is the growth of towns and cities.
</P><P ID="24">   "The cities are taking away from the county," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleming</ENAMEX>. "They're getting larger and larger."
</P><P ID="25">   She believes the cities should have to pay something to house criminals in the county jail.
</P><P ID="26">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> said the county has asked the cities and the legislature about the financial responsibility, but hasn't found any relief because of budget crunches.
</P><P ID="27">   "Everybody has a budget crunch," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleming</ENAMEX>, who added that programs like 4-H can help keep kids out of trouble.
</P><P ID="28">   She added that part of the reason she and others voted for the tax increase for law enforcement was so that it will relieve some of the financial pressure and keep what is currently operating in place.
</P><P ID="29">   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget will see an increase in the budget for public safety. While most areas, such as the coroner's and sheriff's office and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Security</ENAMEX> saw budget reductions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Corrections</ENAMEX> budget will be increased from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17,481,150</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$19,693,050</NUMEX>. Also increasing is the amount of revenue expected to come from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Corrections</ENAMEX>. Revenue is expected to increase about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.1 percent</NUMEX>, slightly less than the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.65 percent</NUMEX> budget increase for the corrections department.
</P><P ID="30">   Increases have also been budgeted for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX>, which will jump from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,944,538</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,141,171</NUMEX></NUMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> increase. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District Court</ENAMEX> revenues, on the other hand, are anticipated to decrease by nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="31">   Also to increase is the budget for the county's planning department. The planning department budget will increase from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,669,506</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,902,616</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="32">   The commissioners are scheduled to adopt the budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 18</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> in the commissioners hearing room in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="33">Webmaster
</P><P ID="34">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




