
<P ID="1">Where's the beef...from?
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Where's the beef" was one of the most clever TV advertising campaign lines of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last quarter</TIMEX> century. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, American consumers are asking, "Where's the beef from?" You could ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>. Unfortunately, some members are too busy producing congressional "pork".   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Farmers Union</ENAMEX> released the results of a national survey that show consumers want mandatory country-of-origin labeling (COOL), prefer U.S.-labeled food and are willing to pay for it. The poll, conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Penn, Schoen & Berland Associates, Inc.</ENAMEX>, found that consumers overwhelmingly support country-of-origin labeling. The following questions were asked:   Do you think food should be labeled with country of origin information? <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82%</NUMEX> said "yes".   As a consumer, would you be more or less inclined to buy food produced in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">85%</NUMEX> said "yes".   Would you be willing to pay a few cents more for food products grown and/or raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>? <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81%</NUMEX> said "yes".   The results are as striking as they are urgent.   When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> passed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> farm bill, COOL was included. Funding of this important provision still required congressional appropriation. Sadly, it has been delayed for two years by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>' failure to appropriate the necessary funds.   The omnibus appropriations bill, passed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 22, 2004</TIMEX>, did not include funding because certain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> members opposed funding COOL. Despite consumer concerns, agriculture producer support for COOL, and the suspension of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> beef imports by foreign governments, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> has failed to deliver.   As <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Farmers Union</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Frederickson</ENAMEX> has said, "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> farmers want COOL, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82 percent</NUMEX> of American consumers request it, and the U.S. Senate directed conferees not to include the COOL delay in the omnibus spending bill. It is unfortunate that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and the administration would ultimately ignore the will of so many Americans to benefit a handful of companies."   At a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2, 2003</TIMEX>, USDA listening session in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, I testified on behalf of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farmers Union</ENAMEX>. Many cattle producers and other agriculture producers also testified that day. The testimony was overwhelmingly supportive of COOL. The hotel parking lot was full of pickup trucks just like mine. They came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>. The corporate participants' jets parked at the airport down the street offered a sharp contrast, just like their opposition to COOL.   Rest assured, the issue is not resolved. Producers and consumers are united and we will not give in to congressional indifference. COOL remains an issue in the countryside; a top priority issue with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Farmers Union</ENAMEX>; and we will make sure it continues to be an issue in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Davis</ENAMEX> is a resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coulee City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>., and is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Farmers Union</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

