
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln School</ENAMEX> kindergarteners in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">While the long lines of adult voters waited to cast their votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln School</ENAMEX> gym <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, the students in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Downing</ENAMEX>'s kindergarten classroom were also making choices.   The 5- and 6-year-olds took turns casting their votes for presidential candidates and for their favorite foods.   "It was a way for the children to experience the excitement of the electoral process," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX>.   The youngsters had their own ballots with photographs of President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> and Challenger John Kerry, as well as pictures of grapes, apples, pizza, hot dogs, gloves and mittens.   When the votes were counted, the young voters favored <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kerry</ENAMEX> by a 10-6 margin, following the national trend.   By the way, they also prefer grapes to apples, gloves to mittens and pizza to hot dogs.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

