


<P ID="1">Voter turn out requirement already met in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Although the official election is slated to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX>, many ballots have already been received by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Elections Department</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, 1,632 absentee ballots had been received for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> bond and special levy election.
</P><P ID="6">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, those people who didn't mail away their votes will have a chance to cast their vote in person for the bond and levy at one of two polling places in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln Elementary School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Elementary School</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Elections Department</ENAMEX>, in order for the bond and special levy to pass in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> there has to be at least a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> voter turnout from the last general election, and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of the votes need to be in favor of the bond and levy.
</P><P ID="8">   At this point, elections officials noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has already met the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">40 percent</NUMEX> voter turnout needed by absentee ballots alone. This means the school district just needs to wait and see if <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> of those votes will be in favor of the bond and levy.
</P><P ID="9">   The bond and levy being voted on by residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> are two issues. The bond the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> is asking voters to approve is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX>, and the special levy is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,422,595</NUMEX>. The special levy will go into place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> and continue through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>. The new levy will replace the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,246,000</NUMEX> special levy that was approved by voters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, if both the new bond and the special levy are approved by voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> property taxes in the district will go up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.41</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.61</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX>. This means the owners of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> home will pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> more in property taxes if the levy and bond pass. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">20 cent</NUMEX> tax increase per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed value would ultimately pay for the current <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> bond, as well as the proposed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> bond and the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,422,595</NUMEX> special levy. However, with state matching funds the district plans to do a minimum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> in school improvements, including the construction of a new middle school.
</P><P ID="11">   Votes, both absentee and those cast <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, will be calculated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> with initial results due by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




