
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Campaign sign theft questioned
On my property just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, I have the honor of displaying many signs for people running for office. All are for Republican candidates.
Just a few days ago a fellow citizen stole my 4'x8' "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> for President" sign in an attempt to, I guess, hide the fact that some people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state will be voting for the President. I am hoping that the person, who undoubtedly is a proponent of free speech as am I, will return the sign with no questions asked.
I also trust that Democrat supporters are not so insecure in their beliefs that they have to resort to theft to get Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> elected.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman te Velde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Dinner organizers appreciate help
We would like to express our appreciation to everyone who helped with and donated to our cancer aid and research seafood dinner and auction held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17</TIMEX>. With your help we were able to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,450</NUMEX> to help fight this dreaded disease. We do hope we have not left anyone out of the list but if we did please accept our apology.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SunnyView VFW Post</ENAMEX> #3482, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ladies Auxiliary VFW Post</ENAMEX> #3482, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AM VETS Post</ENAMEX> #3733 and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Men's Auxiliary VFW Post</ENAMEX> #3482 wish to thank all of you for your support of this very worthy cause. Besides the personal efforts of individuals who helped with this project, we would like to thank the following businesses and individuals that donated to our raffle: C. Speck, Hinzerling <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vineyards</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Pre Mix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bieber Bros.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s Drive In, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hall-Sunfair</ENAMEX>, Standard Paint, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSR</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thurston Wolfe</ENAMEX>, Yakima Bait, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW Women</ENAMEX>'s Auxiliary, Benchley Fruit, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDO</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerry Goedhart</ENAMEX>, Kestrel Vintners, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerda Warmenhoven</ENAMEX>, JC Penney's, Melange, Snoqualmie Vineyard, DK Bain, The Paper Tree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Rosendaal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Johnson Fruit Co</ENAMEX>, APEX Winery, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bauerle & Cook</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Lund</ENAMEX>, Chukar Cherries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jo Goodwin</ENAMEX>, New Reflections, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ria Goedhart</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cook</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J.R</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry</ENAMEX>'s Barber Shop, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Beauty School</ENAMEX>, Cactus Juice, Commercial Tire, Salinas Hair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Cycling & Fitness</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Schwab Tires</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Holenworth</ENAMEX>.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Bones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Tourney sponsors aid cancer cause
This letter is to thank the contributors to the second annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society Golf Tournament</ENAMEX> held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> at Cherry Hill Golf Course.
I would like to thank the hole sponsors: Blehyl's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Service</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smitty</ENAMEX>'s Conoco, Mid Valley Chrysler Dodge, Prosser Record Bulletin, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Herald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bell & Bridges CPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Speck Motors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tri-Star Distributors</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Ridge Golf Course</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Rock Creek Golf Course</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cliff</ENAMEX>'s Septic, Wal-Mart, Clear Channel Communications, and last but not least, Cherry Hill Golf Course, which was behind this <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> and does more than its share to support our golf tournament each year. Hole sponsors donated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> or more in cash or merchandise.
I would also like to thank C&H Hardware of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit Union</ENAMEX> for their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> donations each, and the following businesses for their donations of merchandise that was used for prizes for the players: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">C&H Hardware</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit Union</ENAMEX>.
I would like to thank the players who took part.
We raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,539</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACS</ENAMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> tournament will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17, 2005</TIMEX>. If you wish to be a contributor or participant, call me at 837-8984.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clyde Robinson</ENAMEX>, event coordinator, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">Pre-school helpers receive thanks
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> was a wonderful and very busy month for us at Calvary Lutheran Pre-school. We would like to extend a special thank you to all of those who helped with the Sunshine Days Parade float—Dave Waller, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kari Bliesner</ENAMEX> and numerous parent volunteers.
We would also like to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastor Nick Paulakis</ENAMEX> for his outreach at our open house and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Ladies Society</ENAMEX> for their help.
God bless.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran School</ENAMEX> staff
</P> 
<P ID="7">Rekindle spiritin Sunshine Days
I wish to thank everyone who was involved with the honor of my being elected grand marshal of the Sunshine Days Parade <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. I do not think you can realize what that meant to me and my family.
It was a long time ago when I arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1937</TIMEX> to be exact. A skinny 11-year-old boy and not knowing anyone here. My dad died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months later</TIMEX> at age 50 after getting pneumonia from working in the fields, and Mom took her bunch of hungry kids and made a living any way we could. We worked in the fields and it did not hurt us any more than it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
I have seen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> bloom forward into a proud community by the sweat of many brows, the constitution of the dedicated, the blood of so many young men and faith of what it could become.
I have also seen these dreams die and waver, being replaced with desires of others and overshadowing the original ones. I have seen a community lose its faith in the past and uncertain of its future. I remember the days when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Color Guard</ENAMEX> and service men marched proudly down our streets in front of our high school band in great spirit and pride. The whole town cheering and waving and having a day of family fun.
It is sad to think that the era of community spirit is coming to an end. The meaning and memory of how our town was built and why it was built will soon be forgotten and replaced with new ideas not familiar to the founders and their families.
I thank you again for this wonderful honor you gave me for it means more to me than you can imagine. And with this, I want to plead with you to find the community spirit that is still alive in the hearts of those who live here and keep our Sunshine Days alive. Give our kids something to remember in later years. Find the reason it was started and use that as the basis to rekindle the interest. I do not think you will regret it.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don and Ruth Bones</ENAMEX> and family, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="8">Harvest Dancea huge success
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and Recreation wants to thank all those who helped make the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Harvest Dance, held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 3</TIMEX>, a huge success.
Thank you to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Birr</ENAMEX>, the high school principal, for the use of the school gym. Thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VICA Club</ENAMEX> members who attended, served refreshments and danced with the guests. Special thanks go to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VICA</ENAMEX> advisors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Schrontz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Paulakis</ENAMEX>.
A big round of applause to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Holden</ENAMEX> and his four-piece band for their great dancing music.
Additional thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> senior group and to volunteer Sherre Ott-Holden for all her help, not only on this program but many parks and recreation programs.
And last but not least, thank to all 94 paricipants who attended the fourth annual Harvest Dance.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Stiles</ENAMEX>, director, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recreation Department & Joan Niemeyer</ENAMEX>, assistant
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

