23 7 41 44 35 24
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  No matter how rich you become, how famous or powerful, when you die the size of your funeral will still pretty much depend on the weather.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Pritchard</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>