
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pharmacist earns Doctorate degree
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Working full time and studying for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX> has resulted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thuha</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bac</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen</ENAMEX> earning the right to add doctor to his name.   But the title doesn't mean he will be seeing patients as a physician, he explains.   "I do, however, have a very extensive knowledge of drug therapy and will be of service to doctors and their patients in helping to monitor their medications," he explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen</ENAMEX>, who has worked in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> pharmacy since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, recently earned his Doctorate of pharmacy from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Idaho State University</ENAMEX>.   He completed the two-year doctorate program over the course of four years, working as a part-time student while maintaining his job working with fellow hospital pharmacist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arie Van Wingerden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen</ENAMEX>, who came to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, earned his pharmacy degree from St. John's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York State</ENAMEX>, before moving to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen</ENAMEX> said since coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> he has worked to be of value in society. "It is the most important thing to me," he said. "I took the opportunity to pursue an education so I could be of value to others," he said.   In order to earn his doctorate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen</ENAMEX> had to take training, known as clerkships, outside of the classroom in six-week intervals. As a doctor of pharmacy, he doesn't actually prescribe medications to patients, but serves as a resource for physicians and hospital staff.   With the additional training, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen</ENAMEX> said he is now more qualified to aid physicians with drug therapy and drug monitoring.   He said living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> suits his lifestyle. A Grandview resident, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nguyen</ENAMEX> said he worked in Seattle for about six months at a Payless pharmacy.   "I didn't like living in the city," he said.   "I wanted to work in a hospital in a rural setting. This area and the hospital setting suits me," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

