


<P ID="1">Recall expands to eight states, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guam</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The recall of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">10,000 pounds</NUMEX> of beef slaughtered at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vern</ENAMEX>'s Moses Lake Meats the same day the bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>) infected cow was slaughtered has been expanded to include eight states and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> territory of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guam</ENAMEX>, according to Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Petersen</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture Food Safety Inspection Service</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The recall was sent out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>, as an "abundance of precaution," despite infected portions of the cow, including the brain and spinal cord, having been removed from the animal at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vern</ENAMEX>'s Meats.
</P><P ID="6">   "Because the meat leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vern</ENAMEX>'s did not contain these high-risk materials, the recalled beef represents an essentially zero risk to consumers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petersen</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The cow was then sent with 20 other cows to Midway Meats in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Centralia</ENAMEX>, where it was deboned before it was shipped to Willamette Valley Meats in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interstate Meat Distributors</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clackamas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ore. Petersen</ENAMEX> said about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of the meat shipped to Interstate Meats has not been distributed.
</P><P ID="8">   Beef from the two plants in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> were sold primarily to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nevada</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petersen</ENAMEX> said that trimmings from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Willamette Valley</ENAMEX> were sold to three dozen mom and pop Asian and Mexican facilities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nevada</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petersen</ENAMEX> said it has been learned that some of the consignees had additional distribution to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Guam</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   Most of the meat from Interstate Meats was ground up and some made into ground beef patties. All of the ground beef and patties from Interstate Meats was sold within <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>. He said already meat is being returned as a part of the recall.
</P><P ID="11">   Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Sundlof</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Administration Center for Veterinary Medicine</ENAMEX> said they have also gained control of all of the renderings from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vern</ENAMEX>'s Moses Lake Meats and Midway Meats.
</P><P ID="12">   'We are trying to trace down any products, any byproducts from the processing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> indexed cow, to try and keep it from getting into any products the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> regulates, including animal feed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petersen</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="13">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




