


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Sunshine Days
a disappointment
</P>

<P ID="5">I was disappointed with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s festival of Sunshine Days!
</P>

<P ID="6">There were no booths. I love the booths and I know all the kids, at least most, do too. It takes the fun out of it. I think you should have them up.
</P>

<P ID="7">I can work on posters and signs. I can help. I can get more people to help, too. Please call back (839-8890).
</P>

<P ID="8">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendall Platsman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="9">Sunshine Days help appreciated
</P>

<P ID="10">On behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> board of directors, I would like to recognize and thank the individuals who took valuable weekend time away from their families to assist with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Sunshine Days celebration. Volunteers are the most valuable asset the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> has, and each person and "man hour" is appreciated.
</P>

<P ID="11">The day's festivities began with the first ever Sunshine Days community breakfast, which means that we started cooking at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 a.m.</TIMEX> The bright eyed, busy tailed breakfast crew included Elner Becker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Schlieve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhoda Giffen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Friend</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Sidwell</ENAMEX>, Brezzi Campos, Barb Wells and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Ganser</ENAMEX>. Very special thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Schaneman</ENAMEX>, who worked with us in the high school kitchen, and to Ret Stewart of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zillah</ENAMEX>, who helped us with ideas and organization. Thanks also to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tami Silva</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dairy Fair</ENAMEX>, who donated the milk and yogurt.
</P>

<P ID="12">The parade line-up volunteers stepped up next. This group included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Leonard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Phinney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Doak</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom and Dawn Gaulke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Gonzales</ENAMEX>. People who volunteered to judge parade entries were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginny Staggers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Dorsey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marge DeLorme</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Newhouse</ENAMEX>, Sabio Lara, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso Santos</ENAMEX>, Brezzi Campos and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>. Our apologies to everyone who waited for judging, in particular the pre-schoolers, their parents and their instructors. Apparently, we had a breakdown in communication, and the judging was delayed. We will endeavor not to make the same mistakes in the future.
</P>

<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Southern</ENAMEX> graciously agreed to announced the parade entries, and after the parade
</P>  
<P ID="14">several young ladies from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panda Bear Childcare Center</ENAMEX> danced and sang for the crowd at Centennial Square. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> the air was filled with sweet sounds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Community Band. Many thanks to Bill Flower, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> for the Community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Daybreak Rotary</ENAMEX> for the roles they played in making this concert happen.
</P>

<P ID="15">The Sunshine Days festivities concluded with another spectacular <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Pageant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Golden</ENAMEX> has the annual pageant running like a well oiled machine, and she and the pageant committee deserve a standing ovation. Congratulations to the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX>, and to Princesses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline DeRuyter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Durbin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Cornelius</ENAMEX>. As always, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> looks forward to working with them in the coming year.
</P>

<P ID="16">Many thanks to the city employees for their hard work and support. We said "tables," and they said, "How many?" The police department served their community well in their assistance with the parade.
</P>

<P ID="17">Thank you ladies and gentlemen!
</P>

<P ID="18">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tourism & Promotions</ENAMEX> Director, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="19">Nethercutt vote encouraged
</P>

<P ID="20">I support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> for U.S. Senate, and I encourage voters to vote for him this coming general election.
</P>

<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> will support and vote for well qualified federal judge nominees. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> has voted against well qualified federal judge nominees whom President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has nominated. It has been disgusting to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> vote for filibusters to block the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> from votong on excellent nominees.
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> has worked directly with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Administration</ENAMEX> to keep veteran hospitals open in our state. In her ads, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> likes to take the credit.
</P>

<P ID="23"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> is a strong leader. He has supported Medicare prescription drug benefits; whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> voted against them. He has supported tax relief for job creation; whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has voted 282 times in favor of higher taxes. He has supported a stronger military to defend our homeland; whereas <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has voted against our military more than 30 times.
</P>

<P ID="24">Let me clear up the discussion about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s residence. He has not moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX>. He is renting an apartment there for when he campaigns on the west side of the state. He has spent much time in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX>. But his home is still in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="25">We need stronger <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state representation in the U.S. Senate. I urge you to vote for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> for U.S. Senate. He has represented <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> well in the U.S. House of Representatives and will do so in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> also.
</P>

<P ID="26">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lydia Lommers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


 






 










<P ID="27">Webmaster
</P><P ID="28">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




