


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> losing councilman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> market 
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">After proving himself to be a progressive, energetic businessman and community leader, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> has attracted the national attention of one of the country's most popular leading fast food chains.
</P><P ID="5">   As franchise owner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&W</ENAMEX> restaurant on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the 21-year-old businessman finds himself being promoted to manage a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX>/A&W restaurant located in one of the fastest growing regions of the country.
</P><P ID="6">   The restaurateur announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> he will be accepting a promotion to manage a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX>/A&W franchise in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX> effective immediately.
</P><P ID="7">   "I fly out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>). He said he knew his company, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harman Management</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Altos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, was considering him for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> position for several weeks.
</P><P ID="8">   "They offered it to me this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> and I accepted," he explained.
</P><P ID="9">   "It's a great opportunity for me to advance within the company and to take part in the rapid growth in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> market," said the young businessman, who has operated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX> franchise for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past eight years</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   He, along with his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey</ENAMEX>, relocated their new and expanded restaurant on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2002</TIMEX>, after managing the downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX> store for six years.
</P><P ID="11">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past March</TIMEX>, the couple was presented the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Chamber of Commerce Outstanding Community Beautification Award.
</P><P ID="12">   In addition to turning his restaurant over to a new manager, he will also be resigning his seat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, who was elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2003</TIMEX>, informed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> of his decision to resign from the council.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said he would be informing his fellow council members of his resignation and will be submitting a letter to the council within the next couple of days.
</P><P ID="14">   "I have grown so much during my six months as a councilman. It has been a great privilege to serve the community as a councilman," he said. "It has been a very rewarding opportunity to serve the community from the council."
</P><P ID="15">   "We are losing an intelligent and enthusiastic member of our council," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   In the meantime, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said the he will begin accepting applications to replace the youngest city councilman, who is serving his first term.
</P><P ID="17">   "We're losing a great asset to our community, not just as a city leader, but as a progressive businessman," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>, who added that council has 30 days in which to appoint a replacement for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   "Whoever is selected to fill the now vacated position will be expected to stand for election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> to fill the remainder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>'s term," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="19">   Those interested are encouraged to pick up applications at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Hall, 820 E. Edison Ave.
</P><P ID="20">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>, the family and friends of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> will hold a "going away" party at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snipes Mountain Brewery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant</ENAMEX>. The public is welcome to attend and add its well wishes for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> family.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">??Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="22">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> photo
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> to leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to relocated to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX>
</P>





 










<P ID="25">Webmaster
</P><P ID="26">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




