
<P ID="1">Sports Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX> football players to begin practices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 26</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> football team will begin practicing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday, Aug. 26</TIMEX>. The team is open to all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> seventh and eighth graders.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX>'s girls volleyball, boys soccer and cross country squads will hold their first practices <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 1</TIMEX>, immediately following classes that day.
Each athlete at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> must pass a physical exam, fill out WIAA and eligibility forms, pay an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASB</ENAMEX> fee and have proof of insurance before they can begin practicing. Sports information packets can be picked up now at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Scholarship scramble winners at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black Rock Creek</ENAMEX> announced
Carding a 13-under 59, the foursome of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Harle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Harle</ENAMEX> won the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Prosser Scholarship Scramble at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Black Rock Creek Golf Course this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>.
The net winners (actual score minus handicap) in the one-day fund-raising tournament was the squad of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Holt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Hair</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Benson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Moore</ENAMEX>. They posted a handicap-aided 53.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

