
<P ID="1">Funding decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> explained to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Basically, it came down to the fact the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> wanted all of the money in the pot and the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) didn't want to give all of its remaining funds to just one entity.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> heard this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> a brief report concerning its request for all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds that were recently presented to several <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> entities. The city was looking to obtain the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> pot to install parking meters at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> and help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX> build a skate park there.   Instead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board of directors divided up the approximate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> it had at its disposal and gave it to several groups for various projects. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was left holding an empty bag.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Late last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> solicited proposals from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> groups for the more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> the group wanted to disburse in this area. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> which projects it had funded. Some of the projects included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> going towards playground equipment for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> and money for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to help with the construction of the wine education center at the former Safeway store.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> received a letter from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hill</ENAMEX>, who oversees the management of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX>. The letter informed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> wasn't able to fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s request. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> about the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>'s decision shortly after receiving the letter.   "I didn't learn much from the conversation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said he is expecting to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board of directors meeting with Parks and Recreation Director Don Stiles, and hopefully learn more about why the city didn't receive any money for its request, which initially was one of the top two picks of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> in its initial phase of selecting proposals.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> expressed his curiosity about why <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't receive any funding at all from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>, which he pointed out is heavily represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he was concerned that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> received a majority of the funds from this situation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>, who sits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board, said the directors deliberated for more than an hour on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> project, which was one of seven proposals before them. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, who advocated for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s proposal, said it didn't work out in the end when it came to allocating funds for projects.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastor Mike Henry</ENAMEX>, who is a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> representative on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, offered some clarification on why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s project was not funded.   "We made a couple of decisions as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> said the board decided to not look at what was best for the communities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> in terms of evenly receiving the funds, but rather what would benefit the entire county in the long run. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> said the last of the projects to be considered for funding were <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> and the college's wine education center. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had made it perfectly clear as part of its project proposal it wanted all of the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> said when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board looked at the request it couldn't fulfill what the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wanted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> said since the board couldn't meet the entire request of the city, it opted to give its support to the wine education center, which would greatly benefit the entire areas with training for jobs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, though, countered by saying <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> substantially benefits from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>, which <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> took over from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>. He said he couldn't see why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s proposal wasn't funded. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> explained that the city's request included installing parking meters at the park, which wasn't seen as a great benefit to residents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> said the end decision boiled down to jobs, via the wine education center, versus recreation.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

