


<P ID="1">Off-premise signs approved on 3-1 vote
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">With a vote of 3-1, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> approved a conditional use permit for two All-City Bail Bonds signs for off-site advertising.
</P><P ID="5">   The signs have already been erected along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Homer Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Homer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">First</ENAMEX> streets. They are located on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Bootsma</ENAMEX>'s property.
</P><P ID="6">   "Our code does provide a conditional use permit for off-premise signs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>. "We told the person who wanted the signs that they need permits and they understand if it's not approved that they will have to take it down," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the signs will be required to be maintained. He added that the city staff recommended the approval of the signs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> added that in the stipulations, the city would require that the owner of the signs would comply with city codes, if ever a sign ordinance was developed in the future.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> added that currently the city does not allow new billboards to be built in the community.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> Chairperson <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terrie Williard</ENAMEX> voted against allowing the off-premise signs.
</P><P ID="10">   "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has become a clean town, and what we've got here is almost a miniature billboard," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williard</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   She added that she doesn't like that the city could easily slip back to a city that allows billboards.
</P><P ID="12">   "This isn't a directional sign," she said referring to an off-premise sign approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. "It's just a miniature billboard."
</P><P ID="13">   "The property is such an eyesore to begin with. I have a problem putting more there when we're trying to get <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> clean to begin with," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williard</ENAMEX> added.
</P><P ID="14">   Board member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX> said that it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX>'s job to make sure the signs comply with current codes. He said that with nothing currently on the books prohibiting an off-premise sign, he would have to vote for it.
</P><P ID="15">   "I would have a difficult time not to support this without compelling reason," he added.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Berk</ENAMEX>, a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX>, said he sees both sides. In the end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berk</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel and Craig Miller</ENAMEX> voted in favor of the conditional use permit for the off-premise signs.
</P>   
<P ID="17">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="18">Webmaster
</P><P ID="19">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




