


<P ID="1">New bill gives citizens leverage for challenging state agency rules
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Citizens affected unfairly by state agency rules and regulations will have an easier time challenging those rules, thanks to a new law ushered in by state Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janéa Holmquist</ENAMEX>, R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>. The governor signed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Bill</ENAMEX> 2598 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, which will allow citizens to file suit against state agencies in one of four counties throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   Until now, state law required all such legal challenges against the state to be filed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thurston County</ENAMEX>. The new bill will allow citizens to file cases against the state in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Whatcom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thurston</ENAMEX> counties, depending on where they reside.
</P><P ID="5">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> agencies have really enjoyed a home-court advantage," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX> said. "This move to open up new venues to challenge agency rules will take many cases out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> and into other jurisdictions, where there may be a greater understanding of the plight of the private sector and less bias in favor of state government."
</P><P ID="6">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX>, this bill will help ensure the voices of families, property owners and small business owners are given due consideration when state agencies draft regulations, knowing they may have to defend them in courts throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "If nothing else, it will allow citizens to have their grievances heard closer to home," she said.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Rothlin</ENAMEX>, public information officer with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Republican Media Services</ENAMEX>, explained that under the old law when an agency adopts a new rule, the only way that rule can be challenged is for a person to file a suit in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thurston County</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX>'s bill opens those filing locations up to include three other counties across the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rothlin</ENAMEX> said agencies often draft new policies and rules ranging from the Shoreline Rule to the ergonomics rules, which were repealed by voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   The governor vetoed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House Bill</ENAMEX> 1530, a similar measure co-sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX> and approved by the legislature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>. The bill would have allowed legal challenges in five counties in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX> and other supporters of the proposal worked out a compromise with the governor, opening venue options to four counties as a pilot project through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2008</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   "This is what the governor has agreed to for now, but my goal is to make this a permanent option and expand it to all counties," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX>. "Our objective is to raise the level of accountability in state agency rule making, and if the governor's administration is using its rule-making authority in a fair and responsible manner, then the agencies should not be worried about making it a little more convenient for citizens to challenge those rules."
</P><P ID="12">   HB 2598 takes effect 90 days from the end of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> session, which adjourned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




