
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> fly past G'view gridders
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - A 13-yard touchdown pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Emerson</ENAMEX> was the only scoring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> football team could muster against the visiting Connell Eagles <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> scored just two TD's and a lone field goal, but they were enough as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX> hung on for a 17-7 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX> victory.   "We had good field position three times in the second half," said first year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Dustin Lamb</ENAMEX>. "But we couldn't muster a drive."   The big reason for that is because <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> stuffed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s rushing attack. The Greyhounds' leading rusher on the night, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX>, was only able to pick up 31 yards on 10 carries. On <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s seven other rushing attempts, the 'Hounds netted just nine yards.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> has some big boys on the line," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>. "They're tough to run against."   The win boosted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX> to 1-1 in conference play. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> slipped to 1-1 with the loss. The 'Hounds get a break from league play this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, as they travel to take on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> opponent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> (0-3).   The two teams played to a scoreless tie in the opening quarter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> grabbed the lead in the second period on a pair of TD passes. Eagles QB Dan Nance lofted a 57-yard scoring strike to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Knight</ENAMEX> for the first score, then found <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevor McKay</ENAMEX> on a 17-yard touchdown pass.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> cut <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX>' lead to 14-7 in the third quarter when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emerson</ENAMEX> on a 13-yard TD toss. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> finished the night with 196 yards through the air on 18-of-35 passing. His two favorite targets were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX>, who hauled in eight passes for 74 yards, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX>, who had three receptions for 56 yards.   All told, the 'Hounds only managed 236 yards of offense. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX> got 234 yards through the air and another 104 on the ground.   "Actually, we did pretty good against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX>'s rush," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>. "Their leading rusher gained 130 yards, but we held the other two kids who ran the ball to minus yardage.   "Pretty much, we stuffed their run. But they went to their next option, the pass, and that did us in," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> never did cough up the ball to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX>, in terms of fumbles and interceptions, but 10 penalties whistled against the 'Hounds made sustaining offensive drives tough.   "It seemed like we were facing first-and-15 the whole second half," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said.   Defensively for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, defensive end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody McMillen</ENAMEX> posted the biggest numbers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McMillen</ENAMEX> registered two quarterback sacks and was credited with seven tackles.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

