
<P ID="1">New heroes, vets honored by students
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - Toughened by memories of violence, military veterans living in the Granger community were visibly moved by the sound of more than 300 youngsters reciting the "Pledge of Allegiance" during a school assembly held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>) at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelt Elementary School</ENAMEX>.   "I don't think there is anything sweeter than the sound of children saying the "Pledge" or singing patriotic songs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Russell</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> war veteran and long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> resident.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, along with fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX> members <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyle Bergstrom</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, was on hand for the school's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Veteran's Day</TIMEX> ceremony. The men, who served as a color guard for the children's assembly, were later presented with certificates of appreciation from the students. The children also presented tokens of their respect and appreciation to a number of other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> residents who served their nation in past wars.   But the veterans weren't the only heroes honored during the assembly. A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School</ENAMEX> girls were also singled out for their selfless deeds.   "The girls voluntarily cut their hair in order to provide human hair wigs for cancer patients suffering hair loss," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Wheaton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roosevelt Elementary School</ENAMEX> principal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheaton</ENAMEX> introduced the young women, who each allowed more than 10 inches of their hair to be sacrificed for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX>-based charity.   The girls, all members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School Young Authors Club</ENAMEX>, decided to cut their hair at the suggestion of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Rice</ENAMEX>, whose grandmother died of cancer.   "We celebrate these girls and our veterans for all of their humanitarian acts," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wheaton</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

