
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> moves ahead withnew signals
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Grandview Public Works Director Cus Arteaga reported to city council <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, that work is currently being done on the design phase of the signalization projects at both the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elm Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandridge</ENAMEX> roads.
The project will include some changes to the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandridge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country</ENAMEX> roads. The corner of the intersection where Lucky Seven is located will be widened to create a larger turning radius.
According to the report given to council, the signals at both intersections will likely be installed later <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Daycare makes donation to playground project
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> city council chambers were filled with children waiting their turn to give something back to the community. The children all attend <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Bear Corner</ENAMEX> daycare center and were at the meeting to donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,600</NUMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX> playground project.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Charvet</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddy Bear Corner</ENAMEX> said the children and their families sold 712 pizza kits to raise funds for the project. She said this is the most money the children have ever helped raise for a cause.
"There was not a person who thought it was a bad idea," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said of the idea to raise funds for the playground project.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavazos</ENAMEX> recognized for 25 years of service
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cavazos</ENAMEX> was recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> for 25 years of service to the community.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cavazos</ENAMEX> has worked with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks Department</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>.
"I think really highly of this fellow," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Parks</ENAMEX> and Recreation Director Mike Carpenter. "He always comes to work with a positive attitude."
</P> 
<P ID="6"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Homesof the Month recognized
GRANDVIEW - Five homes and one business were recognized by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> as the recipients of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Homes of the Month award, as well as the Beautification Award.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> Homes of the Month include the homes of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Myrleen Storms</ENAMEX> at 1808 Beacon St., Issac and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Perez</ENAMEX> at 1202 1/2 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rainier</ENAMEX> Dr., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel</ENAMEX> and Estela Ledesma at 622 E. Second St., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon and Delores Telander</ENAMEX> at 306 Avenue G, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus and Ofelia Roman</ENAMEX> at 503 Armas Crt. The Beautification Award was presented to Westside Family Dental at 210 Euclid St.
</P> 
 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

