
<P ID="1">Spring athletes honored at awards ceremony
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Ending a successful spring sports season on a high note with state berths in tennis, golf and track, and strong finishes in soccer and baseball, the young athletes were honored at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Spring Sports Banquet</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletic Club</ENAMEX> presented the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spring Athletic Scholar Athlete academic awards to the students with the top grade point average in their sports program. First time recipients of the honor were presented with a patch and those who had earned the honor before were presented a pin. To be eligible for the award students must be enrolled in at least three classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>.   In soccer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Galvan</ENAMEX> was awarded a patch for having the highest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> for the varsity team and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Velez</ENAMEX> for the jr. varsity team.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girls</ENAMEX> varsity tennis player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizeth Chiprez</ENAMEX> received a pin as did jr. varsity player Brionna Hughes. Jr. varsity player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne Cohan</ENAMEX> earned a patch.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Beals</ENAMEX>, boys varsity tennis player, earned a pin and jr. varsity tennis player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Alquicira</ENAMEX> received a patch.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girls</ENAMEX> golfer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Kim</ENAMEX> earned a patch and boys golfer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Lick</ENAMEX> received a pin.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Girls trackster Isley Gonzalez</ENAMEX> received a pin.   In boys track there was a four-way tie, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>. Pins were awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brendon Scott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX> earned a patch.   Varsity softball player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Wells</ENAMEX> received a pin. Jr. varsity player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Taylor</ENAMEX> earned a patch as did C squad player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Aguiar</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> soccer coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Pineda</ENAMEX> started off presenting the individual team awards to outstanding athletes.   With <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of the team scoring points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said the team had "glorious moments this season."   Receiving the award for Most Inspirational Player was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Hernandez</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> nicknamed late in the season "the octopus."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> is a goal keeper who worked hard in past years to get better even when he wasn't able to give him a lot of playing time.   The award for Most Improved was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said brought a lot of height to the team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> was able to bring the ball down and that he was an asset to the team.   Described as "a quiet player with magic in his feet," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Galvan</ENAMEX> was awarded the Captains award.   "He made a lot of decisions on the field when I can't be there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>, adding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galvan</ENAMEX>'s quick thinking is part of the reason the team made it to the quarterfinals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   The Coaches Award was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael Diego</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said is the type of player that radiates a lot of humbleness.   "He has a humble spirit and is always ready to apply or do the functions we ask him to do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "He's an all-around player, great on defense and great in forward positions."   Receiving the award for Most Valuable Player was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior Martinez</ENAMEX>.   "He was born with a special gift in his feet," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "He needs to use his feet for more than just getting on the bus."   Head baseball coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Martinez</ENAMEX> described the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> baseball team as having desire, commitment and hard work, which is what made the team successful <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   The team tied the school record for the most wins and advanced to the Regional play-offs for the first time in school history, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   The Coaches Award was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah Zakahi</ENAMEX>, who has been part of the varsity baseball program for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX>.   "He's the guy we went to when we wanted a win," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   Receiving the Inspirational Award was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Sanchez</ENAMEX>, a four-year veteran of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> baseball program.   A player with hopes of becoming a coach in the future was the winner of the Captains Award. R.J. Elizondo has led the team for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX> both on and off the field, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   The winner of the Most Improved award was presented to high school junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Newberry</ENAMEX>, who raised his batting average 200 points in one year, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newberry</ENAMEX> was one of the lower batters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, but is now the number 3 batter on the team.   The Most Valuable Player award was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Uberuaga</ENAMEX>, who nailed a two-run homer late in the season giving the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> team the lead needed to move forward in their quest for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girls track and field coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Bryson</ENAMEX> presented the Most Inspirational Award to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniela Rivera</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryson</ENAMEX> said is always smiling and willing to step up and do whatever is asked of her.   At <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Regionals</ENAMEX>, she was asked to step up and run the 4x400 relay and also run the 4x200, which are run with, at the most, 30 minutes between races.   Most Improved was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatima Ruelas</ENAMEX>, who ran the 100, 200, 4x100, 4x200 and ventured into long jump and triple jump this season.   Outstanding Performer was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> for her four years of consistent performance for the track team.   The Coaches Award was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isley Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, who <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryson</ENAMEX> said, "over the four years she's never ceased to amaze me."   As a freshman she placed second at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> and quickly became the person to beat in 3A distance running. With extra training in the off season, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> was able to win the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> cross country title this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past fall</TIMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> track title <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>.   Third year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">trackster Brenden Scott</ENAMEX> was presented the Most Inspirational Award by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Wally Shearer</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> was disqualified at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> meet and was very upset and disappointed, but filled in on a relay the same day.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Exchange</ENAMEX> student Branimir Janjevic was presented Most Improved. Competing in the high jump, long jump and triple jump, for the first time, Janjevic qualified for the Regional track meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>.   The award for Outstanding Performer was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, who accumulated the most meet points for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   The Coaches Award was presented to senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Davis</ENAMEX>, who "...was always about the team," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX>.   "He was always willing to step in and help in a relay," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shearer</ENAMEX>, "even if it was going to hurt his individual record. It was never about him, it was about the team."   Varsity golf coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Braman</ENAMEX> presented the award for Most Improved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Schutt</ENAMEX>, who spent hours on the green chipping and putting outside practice.   Spending almost as much time on the green in contests with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Lick</ENAMEX>, who was named Most Valuable Player. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lick</ENAMEX> qualified for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> golf tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for the third year in a row.   Assistant Coach Gary Rohde presented the award for Most Improved girl golfer to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Downing</ENAMEX>, who won the same award in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Downing</ENAMEX> will be the veteran golfer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>.   Most Valuable Player was awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jensie Hernandez</ENAMEX>, who qualified for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>.   Awards for Inspirational and Most Valuable Player in varsity tennis were voted on by the tennis team and awarded to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Plesha</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Plesha</ENAMEX> ended his season with a record of 28-2, according to tennis <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Troy Whittle</ENAMEX>. His brother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Plesha</ENAMEX> received the award for Most Valuable Player in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. The duo took fourth place in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> doubles tennis.   In girls tennis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizeth Chiprez</ENAMEX> was presented the Inspirational Award. The girls team was very coachable and competitive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whittle</ENAMEX>. They finished fourth in league. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiprez</ENAMEX> was always smiling and extremely happy.   The Most Valuable Player Award was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX>, who had a 10-5 doubles record.   "She was consistently there at every match and every practice," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Whittle</ENAMEX>.   With a strong group returning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX>, only one player will be graduating, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">fast-pitch Coach Kris Gonzalez</ENAMEX> is excited about the future of the softball program.   She said the girls were on a six game winning streak when they lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> by one run, a game they should have won, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.   The Coaches Award was presented to four-year player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Taylor</ENAMEX>.   Most-Improved was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacey Yanez</ENAMEX>, who moved from first to third base and excelled.   The Golden Glove award was given to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devina Martinez</ENAMEX>, who had 48 plays and only four errors in the season.   The only senior on the team, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Wells</ENAMEX>, who acted as a second coach on the field and was an example to the team, was presented the Captain award and Inspirational.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

