


<P ID="1">Southern Californian finds <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> to her liking
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer L. Johnson</ENAMEX>, who passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> bar in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, is now working from the Garrison Law Offices of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The young lawyer, originally from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern California</ENAMEX>, hopes to specialize in family law. For now she is taking cases as they come in, she said.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> studied law at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Southwestern University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, after earning her undergraduate degree in political science from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California State University</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fullerton</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Before going into private practice, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> served a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> internship in the Los Angeles County Prosecutor's office, specializing in domestic violence cases.
</P><P ID="8">   She and her husband, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Johnson</ENAMEX>, currently live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. Originally, the Johnsons had moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> in order to purchase the vision practice of the late Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren Meadowcroft</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said her husband has instead opted to go in a different direction.
</P><P ID="9">   "He is now the owner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Center Vision Clinic</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>," she explained.
</P><P ID="10">   The young couple recently purchased an older home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. "We are spending most of our free time working on it," she said.
</P>





 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




