
<P ID="1">Highway name change pitched to city leaders
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/21/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Director Marshall Doak</ENAMEX> stepped before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to discuss a proposal of changing the name of Yakima Valley Highway.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> is taking the lead role in promoting the changing of the name of Yakima Valley Highway to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said the name change would connect <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with the neighboring communities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. The main stretch of the highway in both Grandview and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> is named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>.   "We have had some support and some negative comments," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said he is busy working with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> officials on the project.   Any name change, proposed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX>, would coincide with street improvement work the city has planned along Yakima Valley Highway.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce Board</ENAMEX> of Directors has already approved a resolution of support for the project.   The business community has expressed a desire to bring in tourism, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said changing the name of Yakima Valley Highway to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> might strengthen the tourism industry.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said he will be back before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with more information as the project develops.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

