
<P ID="1">Nineteen <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">HMS</ENAMEX> students get all A's
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/13/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">A total of 19 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> students in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> earned perfect 4.0 grade point averages for the third quarter of the 2003-04 academic year.   The straight-A students include seventh graders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alberto Barcenas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elvira Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Palacios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsey Rollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Salmeron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomy Velasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Winters</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Zamorano</ENAMEX>; and eighth graders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Barrios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Boogerd</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Brandvold</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Herndon</ENAMEX>, Jordyne Jaquish, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claire Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Stiteler</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joceline Wynn</ENAMEX>.   Eighth graders named to the regular honor roll for the third quarter of school include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Abundiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Alanis</ENAMEX>, Alondra Alarcon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Alejandre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittney Amaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melinda Amaro</ENAMEX>, Sadelle Arevalo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Ballesteros</ENAMEX>, Matthew Barr, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Benitez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Benitez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Bermudez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Bobadilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norberto Bobadilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Boboth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacy Bogart</ENAMEX>, Aristeo Borges, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Bott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittney Bower</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Burgard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diego Burgueno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Cambron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deyma Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Cardenas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arianeli Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatriz Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Petra Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Castellanos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rogelio Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriana Cisneros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashlie Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Cornelius</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Cornwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Corona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Corona</ENAMEX>, Challea DeCann, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela DeLaBarrera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmanuel Delgado</ENAMEX>, Derrick Denson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dacia Drollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Duarte</ENAMEX>, Maegen Elizondo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Escareno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Araceli Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Estrada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Flodin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kassandra Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitchell Gabino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bertha Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Martinez Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Garibaldo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Garza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Gonzales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocio Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isidro Granados</ENAMEX>, Kassaundra Guillen, Diedree Hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Henry</ENAMEX>, Yesenia Herrera, Jordan James, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaitlin Jeske</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Jongsma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clara Justo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Kaiser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Lain</ENAMEX>, Araceli Lepez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judith Licona</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Longoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Luna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Macias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelita Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zachary Mains</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Marin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanca Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelica Mata</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paloma Mata</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah McNerney</ENAMEX>, Kelsea Means, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Melendrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genesis Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maritza Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Mercado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Messmore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Moncada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Monterrey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Ortiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Palomarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Pearson</ENAMEX>, Araceli Peralta, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Armando Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Pina</ENAMEX>, Beverleigh Quenan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Catalina Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvia Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Ramos</ENAMEX>, Jeronimo Rangel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Razey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brice Rinehold</ENAMEX>, Mayra Rios, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Ritchey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julianna Robert</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dahna Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kayla Rollinger</ENAMEX>, Josaphina Roman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isaac Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Sabedra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucerito Salcedo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celeste Salinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Samaniego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Santoy</ENAMEX>, Mayra Serna, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Shuttleworth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Southern</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Stamschror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Talbert</ENAMEX>, Mayra Tapia, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Tellez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Trevino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Valencia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jovan Vargas</ENAMEX>, Marisol Vazquez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ali Velasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Velazquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilberto Villalobos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Villanueva</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erick Vizguerra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyson Waddle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Watts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Wedam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nigel Weenink</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Wolfe</ENAMEX>, Kraig Wyatt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shana Zamarron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anika Zamora</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellie Zamora</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Zijlstra</ENAMEX>.   Seventh graders earning regular honor roll accolades for the third quarter of the school year include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Abbott</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Alaniz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Alvarado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Anderson</ENAMEX>, Araceli Baldovinos, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebeca Barrios</ENAMEX>, Daysi Bautista, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geneda Benitez</ENAMEX>, Nathen Bennett, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Bieber</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Bonilla</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson Bonny</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Bridger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Bridges</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Briones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatriz Campos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susana Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Carrillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melodie Casas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Castillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubi Chavez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Comstock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Correa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tarah Cruz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Del Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Molly Dolan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashleigh Emery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexis Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fermin Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgina Frausto</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maribel Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Gudino</ENAMEX>, Elidio Guillen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Guizar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carina Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levi Hagert</ENAMEX>, Antassia Hammond, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Autumn</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hathaway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aarika Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Isquierdo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Johnson</ENAMEX>, Mayra Juarez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Kilian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Louie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kassandra Luther</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad Martinez</ENAMEX>, Kathia Medina, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regina Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio Mojica</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Moreno</ENAMEX>, Udi Nassar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Navarro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haydee Navarro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Pacheco</ENAMEX>, Thailee Paxton, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Pearson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Perales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carla Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joaquin Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Picazo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damian Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocio Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Reihs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Rivera</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Rogers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasper Rubalcava</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Salcedo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Sambrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katya Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristal Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Saucedo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Serrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Slinker</ENAMEX>, Jerica Wells, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Solis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hali Soto</ENAMEX>, Henedina Tavares, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelsee Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Valencia</ENAMEX>, Teagan Van Gundy-Carlson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Verduzco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Seeger</ENAMEX> and Katelyn Wutzke.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

