
<P ID="1">Weekly Bowling Report
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/26/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
</P> 
 
<P ID="4">Valley LanesWeek #25
Early Birds
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-17-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 556 (194), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Duim</ENAMEX> 498 (208), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Jenson</ENAMEX> 495 (169), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Kline</ENAMEX> 491 (184). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Kline</ENAMEX> +110. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 169. LL: Valley Lanes 20-16.
Sunny Valley Women
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-17-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deania Guy</ENAMEX> 586 (214-214), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruthie Lynch</ENAMEX> 574 (203-203), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise James</ENAMEX> 556 (196), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Schlieve</ENAMEX> 526 (184). Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicky Charvet</ENAMEX> 216. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Cromwell</ENAMEX> 193. LL: Valley Asphalt & Sealing 21-15.
Late Ladies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-17-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Dorsey</ENAMEX> 521 (194), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Langworthy</ENAMEX> 489 (174), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Langworthy</ENAMEX> 488 (179), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Dorsey</ENAMEX> 463 (189). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Arteaga</ENAMEX> +52. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Dorsey</ENAMEX> 168. LL: 10-4 Cafe 153.5-46.5.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> Mixers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-18-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Tilley</ENAMEX> 592 (209), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Van Boven</ENAMEX> 514 (181), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Wilson</ENAMEX> 507 (187). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cory Blount</ENAMEX> +63. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 516 (198), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Lopez</ENAMEX> 514 (192), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deania Guy</ENAMEX> 503 (188). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Lopez</ENAMEX> +133. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Rice</ENAMEX> 224. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 170. Winner second third: Pinbusters 24-20.
Inter-City
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-18-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 673 (257-229), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Bieber</ENAMEX> 653 (219-237), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph LaClair</ENAMEX> 635 (216-215-204), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frank</ENAMEX> 629 (244). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eddy Perez</ENAMEX> +95. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Berg</ENAMEX> 236, Elray Compo 236, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Guy</ENAMEX> 234, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Carl</ENAMEX> 226, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Puyear</ENAMEX> 224, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Norem</ENAMEX> 222, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gress</ENAMEX> 221, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sr. 220</NUMEX>. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 226. Winner second third: Valley Lanes 203-127.
Coffee Trio
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-19-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 547 (191), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Brown</ENAMEX> 527 (198), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Tucker</ENAMEX> 493 (233), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Padgett</ENAMEX> 483 (173). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Springer</ENAMEX> +67. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 176. LL: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daffy Daffodils</ENAMEX> 16-4.
Commercial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-19-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cavin</ENAMEX> 777 (256-264-257), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> 654 (232-201-221), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Peton</ENAMEX> 647 (246-209), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mashburn</ENAMEX> 640 (232-217). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Cavin</ENAMEX> +180. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX> 269, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Schlenker</ENAMEX> 258, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Poteet</ENAMEX> 253, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mitoff</ENAMEX> 246, Brad Morrow 246, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Ulmer</ENAMEX> 246, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Huth</ENAMEX> 238, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Story</ENAMEX> 235, Dusty Van Hollebeke 232, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Huth</ENAMEX> 226, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gustafson</ENAMEX> 226, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hill</ENAMEX> 226, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Newhouse</ENAMEX> 222, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Seifert</ENAMEX> 221. High average: Brad Morrow 210. LL: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Hicks Concrete</ENAMEX> #1 49-11.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> Fun Bunch
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-20-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Haggerty</ENAMEX> 623 (242-232), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Whitefoot</ENAMEX> 622 (219-215), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute Jr.</ENAMEX> 615 (212-222). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Whitefoot</ENAMEX> +121. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 554 (198), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Luke</ENAMEX> 534 (190), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Lallashute</ENAMEX> 522 (181). Highest women's series over average: Shilo Kelly +81. Single game highlights: Redfern Mardel 226. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Haggerty</ENAMEX> 207. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 199. LL: Beer Dogs 8.5-3.5.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preps & Bantams</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-21-04</TIMEX>
High boys series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Sarmiento</ENAMEX> 419 (174), Dillan Sheets 402 (153), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Rice</ENAMEX> 354 (135). Highest boys series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Stanton</ENAMEX> +110. High girls series: Jadelynn Howard 423 (151), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Pacheco</ENAMEX> 365 (130), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Cruz</ENAMEX> 356 (146). Highest girls series over average: Jadelynn Howard +54. High boys average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Rice</ENAMEX> 128. High girls average: Jadelynn Howard 124. LL: 3 Muskateers 25-11.
Jrs. & Majors
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-21-04</TIMEX>
High boys series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Schaneman</ENAMEX> 639 (214-214-211), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Huth</ENAMEX> 589 (204-203), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Allison</ENAMEX> 552 (224). Highest boys series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Allison</ENAMEX> +108. High girls series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Cruz</ENAMEX> 510 (171), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Huth</ENAMEX> 500 (185), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleshia Langworthy</ENAMEX> 479 (182). Highest girls series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aleshia Langworthy</ENAMEX> +38. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake Bonesman</ENAMEX> 241, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane Huth</ENAMEX> 207. High boys average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Schaneman</ENAMEX> 204. High girls average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Huth</ENAMEX> 156. LL: Team #7 142.5-82.5.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> Mixers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-22-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sr. 700</NUMEX> (255-229-216), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 672 (248-211-213), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 657 (226-247). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute Sr.</ENAMEX> +121. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Orr</ENAMEX> 595 (203-214), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Hill</ENAMEX> 552 (231), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Lallashute</ENAMEX> 551 (232). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maria Hill & Debbie Stenberg</ENAMEX> +102. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Guy</ENAMEX> 234, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabe Rodriguez</ENAMEX> 225, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Cruz</ENAMEX> 221, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cruz</ENAMEX> 213. High men's average: MitchCruz 222. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cruz</ENAMEX> 180. LL: Lucky Strikes 9-3.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Scratch
(5 games)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-23-04</TIMEX>)
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Huth</ENAMEX> 1239 (223-248-279-256-233), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Guy</ENAMEX> 1154 (255-243-268), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 1117 (268-206-203-258), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph LaClair</ENAMEX> 1089 (236-212-219-240). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Huth</ENAMEX> +194. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frank</ENAMEX> 276, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Abrams</ENAMEX> 260, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sr. 259</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 257, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 256, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute Jr.</ENAMEX> 251, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hill</ENAMEX> 248, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Schlenker</ENAMEX> 245, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Colley</ENAMEX> 244, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hicks</ENAMEX> 244, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> 238, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Golob</ENAMEX> 235, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Van Boven</ENAMEX> 232, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bert Gilbert</ENAMEX> 231, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Alvarez</ENAMEX> 227, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 212, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Cromwell</ENAMEX> 211. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 221. LL: Valley Lanes 68-22.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

