
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran School</ENAMEX> celebrates 25 years of teaching pre-schoolers
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/27/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy Bunch</ENAMEX> doesn't remember too much about her year as a student at Calvary Lutheran Pre-School, although she does remember the names of a few of her classmates. "My teacher's daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie</ENAMEX>, was in my class," she recalls.   "I also remember wearing dresses all the time and having my hair done up in ponytails," she said. "I was happy there," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunch</ENAMEX> was among the first 40 children to attend Calvary Lutheran Pre-school when it opened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1979</TIMEX>, and is now looking forward to observing the school's 25th anniversary of its founding.   Now grown and a mother of two, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX> and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle</ENAMEX>, believe their children will also be happy attending the private school.   The Calvary Lutheran school, located at the corner of Harrison Avenue and South 11th Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, will mark its 25th anniversary during <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran School</ENAMEX> Week, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7-12</TIMEX>. The week-long celebration will include the children singing for their families and the church congregation during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> services, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Kilian</ENAMEX>, the school director.   Married in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Lutheran Church</ENAMEX>, the Bunches feel sending their son to the Lutheran-sponsored school will help build his confidence.   "It (the school) has such a warm and caring environment," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bunch</ENAMEX> said, adding her son, who is a bit shy, is warming to the loving care of his teachers.   "He is starting to break out of his shell," she said.   Under the auspices of the Missouri Synod, the pre-school started with two classes of 3- and 4-year-olds, with just one teacher. Since its opening, the school, which now includes a kindergarten class, has seen 2,200 children past through its doors, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said.   According to current enrollment figures, 80 children attend pre-school classes and 10 children attend the fully-accredited kindergarten class, she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>, who has been involved with the school since its inception, now sees her grandchildren attending pre-school classes.   "I also see the children of my former students, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tracy</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>, who served as a teacher's aide during the early years of the school.   According to school history, a pre-school for the Lutheran families was the dream of a long- time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwoodr Henry Miller</ENAMEX>, who promoted the pre-school concept for more than 40 years. His dream became reality in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>, under the direction of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwoodr Linda Puttler</ENAMEX> and Karolyn Rippy, the school's first certified teacher.   Rippy, who retired a few years ago, helped direct classroom activities for 3 and 4-years-olds, and the kindergarten classes for most of the school's history, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeri Paulakis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky Gant</ENAMEX> serve as teachers for the school's 90 young students, leading them on adventures in academic, social and spiritual development. They are assisted by Lucy Rice and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Ward</ENAMEX>.   During the week-long celebration of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lutheran School</ENAMEX> Week, the children will host a salmon dinner following church on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 7</TIMEX>. Proceeds from the dinner will be used for scholarships. Other activities during the week will include game, t-shirt and P.J. days, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>.   "We have had steady enrollment growth over the years," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>. "We are now making preparation for our next expansion," she added.   The school will be extending its kindergarten classes by one hour per day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> explained. Kindergarten students now attend classes from 8 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX>, five-days-a-week.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next year</TIMEX>, classes will be held from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>, she said.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

