
<P ID="1">New traffic signal ok'd for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - After just recently completing the installation of a new traffic signal at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> and exit 73 off of westbound Interstate 82, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> is ready to do it again.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> approved a resolution that will put the wheels in motion for another signalization project.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> will begin work on the design phase for the addition of a traffic signal at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elm Street</ENAMEX>, near Safeway.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Public Works Director Cus Arteaga</ENAMEX> said funding for the project will come from both a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Improvement Board</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIB</ENAMEX>) grant and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Transportation</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX>). The city will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$201,287</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TIB Arterial Improvement Program</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$76,418</NUMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DOT</ENAMEX> in the form of T-21 funds. Some funding for the project will also come Safeway. He explained that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> was paid by the store when it was first constructed at the site, as part of mitigating costs associated with the additional traffic movements the store would bring.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Helen Darr</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> how it had been decided that a signal was needed at that intersection.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> explained that in the past the city had an engineer come out to the site and do a traffic study on the intersection. It was the engineer who determined there was enough traffic to warrant a signal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> added that passing through the intersection at busy of times of day, such as <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> or right after work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, it can be hard to merge from one road onto the other.   "There's a lot of traffic at that intersection," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said.   He also noted that this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past summer</TIMEX> a pedestrian was hit crossing the street at that intersection.   Work on the signalization of the intersection will likely begin after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1, 2004</TIMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

