


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Car show
</P>

<P ID="5">On behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classic Knights Car Club</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, we would like to thank everyone who in any way helped to make the Classic Knights car show such a success this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">Many thanks to all those who sponsored trophies, to all the businesses who so generously donated items for both the "goody bags" and the door prizes, and a special thanks to Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Closner</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> class for filling the bags.
</P>

<P ID="7">We'd also like to thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> communities for all their support, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>, Grandview Herald and Prosser Record Bulletin for their excellent promotional stories.
</P>

<P ID="8">To all the participants, thanks for bringing your beautiful vehicles and we hope you enjoyed yourself enough to return <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy and Merv Dykstra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="10">Will they be remembered?
</P>

<P ID="11"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past weekend</TIMEX> is the first in 56 years I have decorated graves of family and friends without my mom along to share memories as we go about our yearly journey. Each year the numbers have grown, more cemeteries to visit, as well.
</P>

<P ID="12">I am a baby boomer, being born after World War II, the oldest of my cousins. I still have my mom, but she is very ill, so was unable to go for the first time in 74 years.
</P>

<P ID="13">We are fortunate that we each have flowers in our yards, so each bouquet is filled with color and love; as well as memories of each and every person who has touched our lives.
</P>

<P ID="14"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, my husband, daughter and I went out to put flags on the graves of veterans with other volunteers, then we were treated to breakfast by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ladies Auxiliary</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX>. What a sight to see, so many volunteers, most with touches of gray and white hair, doing this in remembrance of all those heroes who served our country. It made me think about the generations who are in their 30's, 40's, and all the children even younger. Will they be devoted, committed and carry on the traditions of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Memorial Day</TIMEX> that I grew up learning the importance of: respect, compassion and sharing?
</P>

<P ID="15"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, we removed all the flags, put them away until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, but remember those who have fought and died for our freedoms. I know that as long as I am alive I will continue to decorate the final resting place of all those that I can, and hope that my family will continue the tradition.
</P>

<P ID="16">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="17">Equestrian
fund-raiser
</P>

<P ID="18">The Back Country Horsemen of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> would like to thank all the businesses that donated items for our fund-raiser <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 14-16</TIMEX>:
</P>

<P ID="19">Mid-Valley Chrysler, Outback Steakhouse, Apex Cellars, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Schwab</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RDO Farm Equipment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX>'s Mower Repair, Hall's Chevrolet, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Catalina</ENAMEX>'s Hair Care, Food Pavillion, Rite-Aide, Aqua Tropics, Prosser Food Depot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel Ford</ENAMEX>, Catch Pen, Bleyhl's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Service</ENAMEX>, Horse Heaven Hills, Old Country Buffet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Chism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Big R Store</ENAMEX>, Jumpstart Espresso, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">I-Hop Restaurant</ENAMEX>, M&E Grain, Desert Eagle Ranch, Chukker Cherries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Beck Jewelery</ENAMEX>, Welco Farm Supply and several silent donors.
</P>

<P ID="20">It's much appreciated.
</P>

<P ID="21">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marti Chism</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




