


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN NEWHOUSE DANLEY</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELLEN NEWHOUSE DANLEY</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Newhouse Danley</ENAMEX>, 78, of Willows, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, May 26, 2004</TIMEX>, in Willows.
</P>

<P ID="6">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1922</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. She was the third of 10 children in the family of Dutch pioneers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Tina Newhouse</ENAMEX>. She graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. She received her RN from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Elizabeth School of Nursing</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>. She received a certificate in public health nursing from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. She continued her education in later years receiving her credentials in school nursing and earning a Bachelor of Science, both from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSU</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="7">Near the end of World War II, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> served as a lieutenant in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> Corps</ENAMEX>. She then moved to Willows to work as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Glen County School</ENAMEX> nurse, a position she held until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carmon Danley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> and raised four children. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> was the school nurse for the Willows <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Unified School District</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8">She was a past or current member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Delta Kappa Gamma</ENAMEX>, the Afternoon <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lutheran Church</ENAMEX> of Willows LWML, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faith Bible Church</ENAMEX> of Willows and Bible Study Fellowship.
</P>

<P ID="9">She enjoyed traveling, gardening, flower arranging, country living, reading, current events and the fine art of conversation.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen</ENAMEX> is survived by her husband of 56 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newland Carmon Danley</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Williams</ENAMEX> and husband, Than, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loree Stephen</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thad</ENAMEX>, all of Willows; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Danley</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenycce</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Danley</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Andrea</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Delevan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> She is also survived by her brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfred</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John E. Newhouse</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Newhouse</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Jane Swynenburg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX>; 11 grandchildren; three great-grandchildren; and numerous close friends.
</P>

<P ID="11">She was preceeded in death by four brothers; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irving</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berry Bechtold</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>.
</P>   


<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Services</ENAMEX> were held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 4, 2004</TIMEX>, at the Opengate Christian Fellowship in Willows. Memorial contributions may be made to the ministry of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill and Robin Harris</ENAMEX> who are serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Russia</ENAMEX> with the Inter Act Ministries and sent in care of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Faith Bible Church</ENAMEX>, 403 Vine St. , Willows, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, 95988.
</P>

 


<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. EDWIN WALLER</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Edwin “Ed” Waller</ENAMEX>, 88, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> went to be with his Lord and Saviour, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 2, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crescent Convalescent Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 20, 1915</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ephrata</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ida (Wyles) Waller</ENAMEX>.
</P>  
<P ID="16">He was raised and educated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX> and graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wenatchee High School</ENAMEX>. He then attended business school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> worked for the Wenatchee Daily World for 15 years, starting with delivering newspapers and working his way up to a typesetter.
</P>  


<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> and went into partnership with his two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrett Trucking Company</ENAMEX>. After 18 years, he left <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herrett Trucking</ENAMEX> and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellingham</ENAMEX>, where he owned and operated a Coast to Coast Hardware store. Years later, he moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missoula</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> and was manager of the wholesale department of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Montana Wholesale Grocery</ENAMEX>.
</P>  
<P ID="18">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX> he moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Juneton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, where he worked for his brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zirbel Trucking Company</ENAMEX> as a foreman for 10 years before retiring and moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> was deeply loved and admired by his family and friends. He was a very hard working man, and a loving husband, father and grandfather.
</P>  
<P ID="20">He will always be well remembered in our hearts.
</P>  
<P ID="21">We will miss him.
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> is survived by his loving wife of 58 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paradis</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morales</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Camano Island</ENAMEX>; three sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin “Buddy” Waller</ENAMEX> of Seattle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenda</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greenleaf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>; 12 grandchildren; one great-grandson; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer Waller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Main</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Little Rock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ark.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="23"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> was preceded in death by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean and Ida Waller</ENAMEX>; and a brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melvin Waller</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="24">At his request, no funeral services will be held.
</P>  
<P ID="25">In lieu of flowers, memorials may be made to Child Evangelism Fellowship, in care of Langevin-Mussetter Funeral Home, 1010 W. Yakima Avenue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>,
</P>  
<P ID="26">98902.
</P>





 










<P ID="27">Webmaster
</P><P ID="28">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




