


<P ID="1">Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> muzzle <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scotties</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">COWICHE</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> ladies soccer team defeated the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highland Scotties</ENAMEX>, 6-3, in a non-league game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Injuries yet again plagued the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> team as top stopper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatima Ruelas</ENAMEX> was injured in the opening minutes of the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Kathy Jolliff</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX> went to make a turn and her body turned while her foot stayed planted.
</P><P ID="6">   Although her injuries have not yet been determined, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX> said most likely she will be healing for a while.
</P><P ID="7">   The first goal of the game was scored by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> player Yanet Candido in the 15th minute of the match-up. Yanet was open and scored an unassisted goal, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Two minutes later in the game <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highland</ENAMEX> stepped up and scored, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "It wasn't part of the plan," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   Playing in a non-league game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX> took seven junior varsity players to give them some play time in a varsity game.
</P><P ID="11">   Going into halftime knotted up at 1-1, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX> said she told her girls they needed to step up.
</P><P ID="12">   "We started the game out strong and at about 15 or 20 minutes I started working in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">JV</ENAMEX> players," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   At the 42-minute mark in the game <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> scored its second goal.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Jolliff</ENAMEX> crossed the ball to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Garza</ENAMEX>, who then fed the ball to Araceli Morales, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   Two minutes later, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highland</ENAMEX> scored a second goal to tie it at 2-2.
</P><P ID="16">   In the 51st minute of the game <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Benitez</ENAMEX> crossed the ball to the far post and Yanet picked it up and fed it into the goal, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "It was a really pretty play," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   In the 59th minute keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Solis</ENAMEX> collected the ball in the penalty area and kicked it out into center field, where Candido was able to pick it up and score a goal.
</P><P ID="19">   "That was kind of a neat play because the keeper had the assist," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   In the 61st and 63rd minute of the game <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Jones</ENAMEX> scored back-to-back goals. With the first goal <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morales</ENAMEX> fed the ball to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>, who was able to put it in the back of the net. Next, Candido had the assist to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>. The two goals were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX>' first of the season.
</P><P ID="21">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scotties</ENAMEX> were able to score their third and final goal of the game in the 66th minute. "We had a slight breakdown on defense," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   "It was fun to have some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">JV</ENAMEX> players at the game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>. "It was good for them to see how much they have to step up to play varsity."
</P><P ID="23">   Some of the slip-ups that allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highland</ENAMEX> to score were due to misreading plays, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jolliff</ENAMEX>, who added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">JV</ENAMEX> girls will grow better with experience.
</P><P ID="24">   The win against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Highland</ENAMEX> brings <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s record to 3-3 overall.
</P><P ID="25">   The girls will be playing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




