
<P ID="1">Sunshine Days celebration plans coming together
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s Sunshine Days celebration, set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, may only be limited to a single day, but event organizers are packing a lot of activities into the one-day celebration.   As a one-day event, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> hopes to recreate the celebration into an all-community, family event.   The day will include food, a parade, the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Pageant, and music to be staged at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Centennial Park</ENAMEX> gazebo in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.   "We plan to kick off the day with a community breakfast to be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, prior to the start of the grand parade," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>'s director of promotions and tourism.   She said the Sunshine Days community breakfast will be served from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> and will include pancakes, eggs, ham and beverages. The cost is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for youth ages 10 and under. Tickets are being pre-sold for the breakfast at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> office, 520 S. Seventh St., and at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> office, 600 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. Sixth St.   Corliss</ENAMEX> said the breakfast will be an excellent time for high school students to earn a few community service hours. "Interested teens may call me at 837-5939," she said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> is now taking applications for parade entries, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said. She encourages local groups and political candidates to participate in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> procession.   The judging of floats and other entries begins at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m.</TIMEX> The parade line-up will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High school parking lot.   The parade route will be slightly different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX>. The route will run along E. Edison Avenue from 16th Street to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>.   "We believe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s parade will be spectacular with at least nine community floats and a minimum of two marching bands," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said. "In addition, this will be the community's last chance to see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s community float and reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Skyles</ENAMEX> and her princesses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Epps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celeste Loffer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Stroh</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> added.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> will be on hand following the parade to introduce visiting royalty at the Centennial Square gazebo. The royal introductions will be followed by performances by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Panda Bear Daycare Center</ENAMEX> dance troupe.   At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>, the Yakima Valley Community Band will perform at the square. The community is invited to bring a picnic lunch and blanket to relax and enjoy the afternoon as the band members serenade the crowds.   "We are encouraging local non-profit organizations who may be interested in preparing and selling lunch items to the public at the park," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said. Interested groups may call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> for details.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s festivities will conclude with the crowning of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, during the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Pageant to be staged at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium. Tickets for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> event are available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> office at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> each.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s community celebration will also feature a carnival. Paradise Amusements will be offering rides for three days as a part of the 38th annual community event. The carnival will be set up between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX> avenues, along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Fifth Street</ENAMEX>.   Ride tickets for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17-19</TIMEX> carnival are being presold at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> office at 520 S. Seventh Street.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com      Search on for parade marshal   Know anyone who should be honored for his or her exemplary community spirit? Consider nominating that person to be the grand marshal of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Sunshine Days Parade.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> is now accepting letters of nomination for the honor.   The chosen parade marshal will head the annual Sunshine Days Parade set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>'s director of promotions and tourism.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said letters may be mailed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> office at P.O. Box 329 or dropped off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> office at 520 S. Seventh St., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

