


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Citizen</ENAMEX> feels minutes should be amended
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/16/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Leeds</ENAMEX> came before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> asking the governing body to formally amend its meeting minutes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeds</ENAMEX> felt the meeting minutes of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX> were incomplete. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeds</ENAMEX> said the minutes do not reflect the direct comments made by Councilman John Torch concerning allegations of civil rights activist Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> being an adulterer.
</P><P ID="6">   The discussion in question stemmed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s plans to rename <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street Ronald Reagan Boulevard</ENAMEX>, in honor of the deceased former president. During the sometimes heated discussion, which included naming other streets in town after significant people in history, Torch made the comment that he wouldn't want to rename a street after a known adulterer, referring to Dr. King.
</P><P ID="7">   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX> meeting minutes make no reference to Torch' comments. One of the excerpts from the minutes states that political overtones were brought into the conversation.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeds</ENAMEX> said he felt the meeting minutes should be in complete written form for citizens to see what is happening. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeds</ENAMEX> said he wasn't sure how long the city was required to keep the tapes of the meeting.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said the city is required to keep the tapes from each meeting for up to six years.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> pointed out to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeds</ENAMEX> and the rest of the audience there is no requirement for the meeting minutes to be written verbatim. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it is unusual anywhere to find meeting minutes written verbatim.
</P><P ID="11">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> can elect to amend the minutes to reflect the concerns of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leeds</ENAMEX>. However, none of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members made a motion to do so.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> did confirm that the tapes are available for citizens to review.
</P><P ID="13">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




