
<P ID="1">Networking, socializing enjoyed at first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> after hours event
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">After many attempts to create the perfect marketing strategy for their specialized product, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd and Ellen Phinney</ENAMEX> have discovered two important things.   Men are the big ticket buyers in most families and most Alderwoodrs are unaware that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knothole Gallery</ENAMEX> on Yakima Valley Highway offers one of the few places in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> where the popular <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Kinkade</ENAMEX> paintings can be purchased.   Those two important points were discussed during the first of a new series of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> after hours events held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the Phinneys' business, located next to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">China Grove Restaurant</ENAMEX>.   "Our target demographic is men, especially those who watch golf," said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phinney</ENAMEX>.   "Women look at our paintings. They love them, but it is the men who come in and buy the large ticket pieces," she said.   "Women always tell me they have to ask their husbands before they can spend upwards of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> per painting," she explained.   "They do buy a lot of our smaller, less expensive items," she added.   The couple told the more than 25 people attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> event they launched a number of advertising campaigns before settling on a television advertising campaign, which is finally yielding the desired results, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phinney</ENAMEX> said.   "We get our best response from our spots which run closest to sporting events, like golf, and new programs, such as 'Good Morning America'," he explained.   The couple said they get a lot of business from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tri Cities</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> areas. "But we continue to hear a lot of people say they were unaware we were here," said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phinney</ENAMEX>.   "We are happy so many of you decided to come and see us at this event," she added.   Choosing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knothole Gallery</ENAMEX> as its first host for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> after hours event was a matter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> wanting to help promote a local business and the need to launch its new membership program, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>'s director of promotions and tourism.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd and Ellen Phinney</ENAMEX> came to us asking what they could do to make more Alderwoodrs aware that they are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Kinkade</ENAMEX> dealers in town. Asking them to host this event also fell right into our plan to reinstate the after hours program," she explained.   "I'm pleased to see so many new faces at this event," she added.   The long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> couple originally opened their business in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mini- Mall, but soon found they needed a location with more curbside exposure. Their current Yakima Valley Highway location offers the couple that exposure, as well as additional room for larger displays of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX>'s paintings and related products. Open six-days-a-week, the couple also makes use of the Internet to help advertise their business. They also make use of an extensive mailing list, said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phinney</ENAMEX>.   "We currently have 1,200 people on our mailing list, who can look forward to getting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thomas Kinkade Gallery</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> catalog in a few weeks, she added.   In addition to learning more about the Phinneys' gallery and the extensive line of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Kinkade</ENAMEX> projects, those who attended the after hours event learned a little more about other events being planned in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizeth Chiprez</ENAMEX> asked the chamber members and guests for support of her senior project. The enterprising young woman has developed a tutoring program for students preparing to take their college entrance exams.   "So many of our students need additional study with such things as vocabulary and literature in order to pass their SATs," she told the group.   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiprez</ENAMEX> created a plan to offer after school tutoring to college-bound students using <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX> students as mentors.   "But I need your help to purchase the necessary study books," she said.   She said she has made arrangements to purchase the books, at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> each. "I'm hoping you will be willing to donate to this important cause," she explained.   "We plan to serve 80 students in the first year," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chiprez</ENAMEX> said, adding she hopes the program will expand in the future."   "This type of networking is exactly what we hoped the after hours program would encourage," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Gaulke</ENAMEX>, president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> board of directors.   "We are hoping all of those who attended this first event will be come <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> members, if they aren't already," he added.   The next <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> after hours program will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Worksource office in the Mid Valley Mall on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 28</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Hernandez</ENAMEX> will provided a short program on estate planning, following a tour of the state employment and training service office.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

