
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> embraces people, challenges
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">One personal attribute <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candidate Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> is known for is how she gets along and wants to help people. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>, a 17-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior, has been putting her people skills to an entirely new use lately.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> is one of eight young ladies who'll be competing for the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, as part of the community's Sunshine Days activities.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yolanda</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Krys Phillips</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She is being sponsored in the pageant by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Beach</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Edward Wells Investment</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Bliesner</ENAMEX>. She also received assistance from Fashion Corner in purchasing her dress for the pageant.   At school, she is involved with several sports, including volleyball, basketball and tennis. Outside of the sporting relm, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> is involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor Society</ENAMEX>, leadership class, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX>, Fire Squad, Associated Student Body business manager and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spanish Club</ENAMEX> president.   Away from school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> keeps busy in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> lifeguarding at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pool and is an active member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>.   After high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> wants to attend a college and study to become a psychologist.   "I want to be there to help people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "I am interested in helping troubled youth."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> credits her family with providing her with support in everything she sets out to do.   One of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> favorite sports to be involved with is basketball. She is a starter on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> girls basketball team.   "I love playing basketball," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "Basketball is also a place where I can meet new friends."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> tells an interesting story about how she became involved with basketball. She has been playing the sport since was in the fourth grade, attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic School</ENAMEX>. However, in her class at St. Joseph's, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> was only one of four girls. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> smiled, saying the other three girls weren't interested in basketball at all.   "I have always been around boys. They sort of shaped me into the athelete I am," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "I am kind of a tomboy."   A devastating injury occurred to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> a couple of years ago at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> basketball tournament that helped mold her perspective about life <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. At a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> tournament in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White River</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> tore her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACL</ENAMEX>. This injury sidelined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> for many months.   "That was the toughest time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "I am just not used to sitting around."   The injury did test <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>, who was sidelined for four months.   "I became lazy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACL</ENAMEX> injury made her more leary about competing like she used to because she was afraid of being injured again.   "It held me back in my sports," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said she is looking to a prosperous senior year and isn't going to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACL</ENAMEX> injury stand in her way.   "I think it will be good," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "You are in high school only once."   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ACL</ENAMEX> tear also forced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> to miss an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> basketball tour camp abroad. But never to leave unfinished business, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> was able to take the two-week tour later, through the British Isle, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25 to July 11</TIMEX>.   "I loved it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "I got to meet new friends, experience new cultures. I got to find out a lot about myself."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said she decided to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> because it is a once in a lifetime event.   "This is a really big responsibility," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was part of a list of "things" she has always wanted to try. She has already done one of them in being a lifeguard. One of the other professions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> would like to try out is being a waitress.   "Wouldn't that be a fun job," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "Look at all the people you would get to meet."   One aspect of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> enjoys is how helpful the community is. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said that the community has never hestitated about helping with school functions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said she feels that the community wanting to help one another is what creates that bond.   Running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has been an interesting experience so far, admitted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   "It has been really fun," she said. "I have gotten to know a lot of the girls."   One of the projects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> would like to work on if she is named to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> is a kindergarten literacy program at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX>.   "I think helping kids at this level is important," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> feels that some younger children struggle in the classroom because of their self-confidence.   "Kids always fall behind because they are shy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said other community service projects she would want to do would be with something involving youth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said it is especially important for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court</ENAMEX> to serve as role models in the community because the royalty is looked up to by younger children.   "We are just kind of setting the example," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> said she has also already obtained a lot of personal success from just being involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant.   "This is a big step for anyone to take," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX> enthusiastically stated that she would "love" to be <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, or even just be on the court.   "I would really like that position," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillips</ENAMEX>. "It is a big role and you need to stand by it. You are not there to represent yourself. You are there for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, to represent the community."   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

