


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> newest <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> councilman
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Planning Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX> has been appointed to position #5 on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   His selection comes following <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s special council meeting held to interview six candidates all seeking the council seat left vacant by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, who resigned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The candidates were each given 10 minutes to explain their interest in serving on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and to answer questions from the seating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members regarding their abilities to address issues facing the city.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, who has served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, has been a part of the panel to help develop the city's recent and most controversial ordinances, including the recently adopted landscape regulations.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> also had a hand in formulating the city's mobile vending ordinance, and has been vocal in helping to formulate new zoning rules for the city.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, who was reappointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past January</TIMEX>, said his qualifications to be a good councilman includes his ability and desire to be involved and to be a part of the process.
</P><P ID="10">   Saying he will give the city the benefit of his willingness to listen and to keep an open mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he wants to be a part of the process to make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a better community. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has tremendous potential and its future is bright. "But that effort takes planning, foresight and citizen involvement, for which I feel I am qualified and am prepared to accept," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   Citing a need to make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a more attractive place for businesses and citizens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said more needs to be done to improve the look of the city's entrances.
</P><P ID="12">   He said his priorities as a potential councilman would be to help make improvements along the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway corridor.
</P><P ID="13">   "We are the largest city in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> and in order to remain the largest, we need to create an environment that is attractive to all," he said.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, along with candidates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ermenejildo Rodriguez Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Drysdale</ENAMEX>, was also asked what talents he could bring to the table.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, who has also served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Rehabilitation Committee</ENAMEX>, said his ability to work well with others, yet keep an independent outlook on topics is one of the skills he would bring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. He said his biggest asset as a councilman is his willingness to make things better by becoming personally involved. I am prepared to accept the challenge and to commit my talent and time to make things better," he said.
</P><P ID="16">   When asked how he would react to being the sole dissenting vote on any given issue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said, "Sometimes you have to stand alone.
</P><P ID="17">   "But once the decision has been made, as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, it becomes time to stand together for the community," he said.
</P><P ID="18">   Another priority issue for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> is the need for improvements to be made to the downtown business corridor.
</P><P ID="19">   He said of the decisions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has recently made which he agreed or disagreed with, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he was in favor with the adoption of the mobile vending and landscaping ordinances.
</P><P ID="20">   "But I also feel that ordinances that restrict youth should be well thought out. We have to make decisions that are viable for all. There has to be balance," he said.
</P><P ID="21">   In favor of pursuing the proposed purchase of the Monson feedlot, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said although he wants the feedlot removed, it depends on the city's ability to finance the issue. He said the removal of the feedlot at the western entrance of the city would go a long way toward improving the city's attractiveness and environment.
</P><P ID="22">   Prior to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>'s appointment the council heard statements from the other candidates, including community volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, who said her priorities for the city included seeing that the community has more affordable housing. She said she'd like to see more jobs which provide the city's young people with livable wages. "I'd like to see our kids return here to work and live," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="23">   "I think the water and sewer treatment plant upgrades are very important to the city. I also think the street improvements benefit the safety of motorists and pedestrians alike," she added.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>, who serves on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Accountability Board</ENAMEX>, said she has worked hard to make herself aware of the issues facing the city. "I believe I'm <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> qualified to be on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>," she said.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> businesswoman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX> said she also believes in the importance of being involved. The owner of the Funny Farm, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> has served on Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gary Locke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retail Liquor Task Force</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Contract</ENAMEX> Manager's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Advisory Committee</ENAMEX>. She also serves on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Rock Creek Golf Course Board</ENAMEX> of Directors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> she has no particular agenda in seeking to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member.
</P><P ID="26">   "I think I can bring my common sense to the table, as well as my desire to make sure all citizens are served," she said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said she has approved of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s recent decision to regulate the amplified noise from cars. "But I was disappointed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s decisions regarding the 'ice cream man," referring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> move to eliminate the ice cream vendors' music.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said her priority issues center on improved infrastructure, bringing more businesses to the city and the overall improvement in the attractiveness of the city.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, the youngest of the council candidates, said he believes his ability to be held accountable would serve him in good stead as a councilman. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, who works for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallett Enterprises</ENAMEX>, said he felt more should be done to bring employment to the community. "I also think more outlets for youth are needed," he said.
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX>, who is employed as facility manager for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority</ENAMEX>, said his background in construction and with budgetary issues would benefit the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   "The budget is my top issue. We have to work to regain sustainable levels in the city reserves," he said.
</P><P ID="31">   A retired <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> businessman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drysdale</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to take time to think about change before making it. Saying he approved of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s decisions to regulate the mobile vendors in the community, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drysdale</ENAMEX> suggested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> occasionally seek the help of the county government.
</P><P ID="32">   "Don't be too proud to pass the buck," he said.
</P><P ID="33">   Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s 15- minute executive session, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> announced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s choice to serve on the city's highest governing board.
</P><P ID="34">   Thanking all of the candidates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> urged them to get involved in other areas of city government.
</P><P ID="35">   "We have vacancies on several city commissions, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX>. I encourage each of you to consider volunteering your energies there," he said.
</P><P ID="36">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, who is a supervisor for a Richland company which manufactures nuclear fuel assemblies, will be sworn in at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="37">   He will serve until the next election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, when he may seek to fill the remaining two years of the existing term for position #5.
</P>





 










<P ID="38">Webmaster
</P><P ID="39">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




