19 26 40 48 46 38
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  The trouble with fighting for human freedom is that one spends most of one's time defending scoundrels. For it is against scoundrels that oppressive laws are first aimed, and oppression must be stopped at the beginning if it is to be stopped at all.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">H. L. Mencken</ENAMEX> (1880 - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>