


<P ID="1">Setback change approved for Grandview Avenue home
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Excusing himself from the bench of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Miller</ENAMEX> requested the board consider his request for a variance to the side-yard setback at his 1018 Grandview Ave. home.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> members voted unanimously <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to approve the variance, which will allow him and his wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl</ENAMEX> to construct a two-car garage, a canopy roof for RV storage and a storage area on the west side of their home.
</P><P ID="6">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s made the request for a five-foot variance for their side yard, which is located on the corner of Grandview Avenue and Upland Drive. Their house, which is on a corner lot, is required by city ordinances to have two 20-foot setbacks from the street, one from the front yard and one from the side yard.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said that the original encroachment on the setback was much greater than the five-foot variance presented <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   He explained that the city's requirement for corner lots to have in essence two front yards, is what keeps the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s from proceeding with building plans without asking for a variance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> added that the unusual shape of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX>'s corner lot is part of what makes their exceptional circumstances qualify for a variance.
</P><P ID="9">   After studying the proposed variance and construction project, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> added that city staff recommends approval of the variance, adding that the neighborhood would not be adversely affected.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Berk</ENAMEX> questioned whether visibility around the corner would be blocked if approved, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said because of the odd angle of the property corner, there shouldn't be any visibility issues.
</P><P ID="11">   The variance was approved pending an approved site plan. Also, a stipulation for approval was that curb, gutter and sidewalk and any necessary street improvements be made. The structure to be constructed must also comply with city R-1 zoning requirements.
</P>   
<P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




