
<P ID="1">Warm, caring words to describe <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> health care award winner
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Raising three children, managing a small farm and working long hours at the local hospital would sap the strength of a lesser woman. But not <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Barry</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The dedicated nurse, mother and grandmother of two has found time to share her abundance of nursing skills with not only her co-workers at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, but future nurses.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>, who has spent the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 17 years</TIMEX> on duty as a full-time registered nurse at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, is also a clinical nursing instructor at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>. In addition, she also is the nursing assistant instructor at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, helping student nursing assistants become certified, licensed care givers.   The warm and friendly woman places her emphasis on patient care and encourages students and co-workers, alike, to be patient advocates at all times.   Honest and kind nursing care are the trademarks of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Health Care Person of the Year award winner. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>, who received the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> award this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past March</TIMEX>, was shy about being singled out for the honor.   "There are a lot of nurses who deserve this honor. I'm touched they decided to honor me in this fashion," she said.   Born and raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> attended nursing college in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>. She graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX> with Bachelor of Science degree in nursing in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. For a time she was employed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX>, but a decision to move back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1987</TIMEX> resulted in her becoming a fixture at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX>, who encourages her students to work hard, often is in charge of preparing hospital employee in-service training sessions. She also volunteers her time to educate young people about trauma prevention.   "I've loved working in a small hospital," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> said.   "We have become a family. We all know each other's children and look out for one another," she said.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, her daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristy Ann Wells</ENAMEX>, is following in her mother's footprints, studying nursing.   Meanwhile, her sons are both attending college. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellen</ENAMEX> will graduate from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> before beginning work on his Master's in accounting," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> said.   Her youngest child, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenton</ENAMEX>, is a sophomore at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>, where he is also majoring in accounting.   "But I think he really wants to be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Patrol</ENAMEX> officer," she smiled.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry</ENAMEX> shows no sign of retiring anytime soon, but looks forward to spending more time with her two young grandchildren.   For the time being, she is content to continue to teach and maintain her nursing assignment with the local hospital.   "I love my work," she said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

