


<P ID="1">Friends of the Library prepare for annexation election in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library will be decided in a special election set to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 9</TIMEX>, and a group of volunteers calling themselves the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Friends</ENAMEX> of the Library aren't about to sit idly by and wait to see what the community decides will happen to the annexation proposal.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> the group devoted time to ensuring everyone in the community is aware of the upcoming library annexation proposition, getting informational mailings ready to send out to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters.
</P><P ID="6">   Bill Flower, one of the volunteers involved in the library group, said there are more than 30 people involved in spreading the word about the upcoming election, including the group's chairman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Kezele</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> the volunteers, including community members <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose A.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrice Villanueva</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Frank</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bettie Siliano</ENAMEX>, gathered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Trinity Episcopal Church</ENAMEX> to get flyers ready to mail out to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters. The flyers detail information about the library, including details about its history.
</P><P ID="8">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> currently contracts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Regional Library for library services. The upcoming election will determine whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Regional Library will completely take over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library, not only offering library services, but also taking over day-to-day operations.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Weyhe</ENAMEX>, director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Regional Library, noted if the annexation occurs the regional library will likely put some money into the library's current building, as well as work to purchase more books for the facility.
</P><P ID="10">   "It would provide a more stable source of funding," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   The cost to annex the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Regional Library system will be 49.6¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed valuation, which translates to a cost of roughly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.13</NUMEX> per month for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> home. Property owners living within the city will pay the tax directly to the rural library district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> noted it's important to remember that those people living outside the city limits are already paying this tax.
</P><P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




