
<P ID="1">Grandview youths place first at science fair
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/20/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">BREMERTON - Three students from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harriet Thompson Elementary School</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> to compete at the Washington State Science Fair.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maryjane Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tabitha Veiga</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harley Hurst</ENAMEX>, who represented their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> after-school classmates at the science fair, brought home first place and "Best of Show" honors.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teachers Tiffany Wise</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucy Prieto</ENAMEX> have been working with a group of 25 students every day after school for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past eight weeks</TIMEX> on a science presentation on crystals. Their project was titled "Which substance will grow the biggest crystal and in what environment."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, a second grader at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harriet Thompson</ENAMEX>, said in the class she has learned that crystals can be different colors and sizes.   "Some crystals weigh more than others," piped in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX>, who is also in the second grade.   To make crystals, the students used epsom salts, salt and sugar and mixed the solutions in a pan on a stove. They made crystals and kept them in a variety of locations, including the refrigerator, to see how they would grow in different environments.   "My favorite part of the project was making the crystals," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   "I liked going to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Science Center</ENAMEX>," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX>.   Both students also liked their trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX> to make the presentation to judges.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veiga</ENAMEX> auditioned for the opportunity to present the project at the state science fair, representing the other students in the class.   "The whole class worked on the project," she added.   As a part of the project the students had to write their own hypothesis, methods used when conducting the experiment, a conclusion and application.   They also researched crystals before starting on the project to gain background knowledge on the subject.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

