


<P ID="1">Local couple encourages salute to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> lawman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Evans</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The American flag is flown proudly at the home of long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Bermudez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reeves Way</ENAMEX>, 365 days a year.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This week</TIMEX>, after having learned of the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergeant Steve Evans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermudez</ENAMEX> has decided to lower his flag to half staff in honor of the 27-year veteran of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, who died of an apparent heart attack while on a hunting trip this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>, could always be relied upon to respond in a caring way to any calls in the Reeves Way neighborhood, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermundez</ENAMEX>'s wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ofilia</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "We knew him as an officer, and he was always very nice," she said.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermudez</ENAMEX> said he feels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' memory needs to be recognized by the lowering of the flag. "I'm doing this as a sign of honor and respect to him and to all policemen," he said.
</P><P ID="9">   "I think all citizens who fly the American flag should lower the flag in his memory and as a show of support to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' wife and family," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bermudez</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Earlier this week</TIMEX>, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> ordered the lowering of flags at all city buildings in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' honor.
</P><P ID="11">   Funeral services for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> are planned to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 6</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>
</P>





 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




