


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">PAID OBITUARY
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GERALD BLUNK</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Blunk</ENAMEX>, 70, a long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> resident died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 16, 2004</TIMEX>, at his home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 3, 1933</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alta</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morgan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blunk</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Blunk</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane McDaniel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>; two grandchildren; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Blunk</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8">At Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blunk’s</ENAMEX> request there will be no formal funeral services. Those wishing to honor Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blunk’s</ENAMEX> memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Pathway, P.O. Box 736, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98930. Jones Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

 


<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ROBERT G. CLARKE</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert G.</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX>, 61, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Federal Way</ENAMEX> died suddenly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 13, 2004</TIMEX>, at his home in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Federal Way</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="11">Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarke</ENAMEX> is survived by three sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Clarke</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Clarke</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Clarke</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy</ENAMEX>; three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Clarke</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Clarke</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rusty Clarke</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila</ENAMEX>; seven grandchildren; and numerous nieces and nephews.
</P>

<P ID="12">He was preceded in death by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack and Irene Clarke</ENAMEX>; and one grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">Memorial services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Jan. 22, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yahn & Sons</ENAMEX>, Auburn.
</P>

 


<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BETTY JEAN FRANK</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Jean Frank</ENAMEX>, 77, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 16, 2004</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24, 1926</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ind.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Lila Hennis</ENAMEX>. She married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roscoe “Buck” Buckles</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1942</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Danville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ind.</ENAMEX> In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX> they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> and later to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>. They farmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> from 1950-1955. They then moved to their farm on King <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tull</ENAMEX> road in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roscoe</ENAMEX> died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1968</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17">She married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Frank</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> and together they lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> until his death in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1996</TIMEX>. She then returned to the farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="18">She is survived by one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lois Graham</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indianapolis</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Buckles</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Buckles</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jodi</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Snyder</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Birch Bay</ENAMEX>; two step-sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Frank</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delores</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Frank</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; a daughter-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Frank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>; and 39 grandchildren and great-grandchildren and step-grandchildren.
</P>

<P ID="19">Memorial services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at the Prosser Kingdom Hall, 330 Nunn Rd.
</P>

<P ID="20">Prosser Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

 


  
<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HENRY FRANK</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Frank</ENAMEX>, 90, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Jan. 18, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Health Care Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="23">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 27, 1913</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Laurel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Marie</ENAMEX> (Haaz) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Frank</ENAMEX>. At an early age he with his family moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, where he received his education. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 1937</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Van Ness</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>. Following their marriage they lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> for 10 years before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. He worked as a custodian for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur H. Jones School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> for 26 ? years until his retirement in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="24">He is survived by his wife of 66 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Frank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine M. Koch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Frank</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karma</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Burden</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>; a daughter-in-law; 10 grandchildren; 14 great-grandchildren; one great-great-grandson; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Frank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Frank</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puyallup</ENAMEX>; and two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lydia Payton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Valentine</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="25">He was preceded in death by his parents; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Frank</ENAMEX>; three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Weeks</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="26">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 20, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Jan. 21, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Burial will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Cemetery</ENAMEX> under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank’s</ENAMEX> memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Health Care Center</ENAMEX>. Memorials may be left at Jones Funeral Home at the time of service. 
</P>

 


<P ID="27"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KEITH L. MATHENY</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="28"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Laverne Matheny</ENAMEX>, 64, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anatone</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Jan 11, 2004</TIMEX>, from an automobile accident at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grande Ronde River</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asotin County</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="29"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith</ENAMEX> was born to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalind Porter Matheny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Asa Matheny</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 22, 1939</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asotin</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="30">He was raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asotin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grouse Flats</ENAMEX> and the Pomeroy area, where he attended school. After high school he was a laborer and ranch hand in the Pomeroy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anatone</ENAMEX> area.
</P>

<P ID="31"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn M. Brockway</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3, 1970</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clarkston</ENAMEX>. They divorced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9, 1991</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="32">He started logging and became a sawyer for the McGregor Triangle company, clearing the area for a power line through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1967 to 1968</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1969 until 1983</TIMEX> he worked in construction starting as a powder monkey at Dworshak Dam, then at The Dalles, Lower Granite Dam, Little Goose Dam and at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford Reservation</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>. He then worked as a ranch hand in the Mabton and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area. He moved to Seattle to work construction and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> was injured on the job and became disabled.
</P>

<P ID="33">He had lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anatone</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 11 years</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="34"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith</ENAMEX> enjoyed hunting, fishing and outdoor activities.
</P>

<P ID="35">He is survived by his sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Keith Matheny</ENAMEX> of the Tri-Cities and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodrick James Matheny</ENAMEX> of Anchorage, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>; Keith’s former wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Brockway Matheny</ENAMEX> of Anchorage; brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Matheny</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mace Matheny</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Starbuck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allar Matheny</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pomeroy</ENAMEX>; sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise Martin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clarkston</ENAMEX>; brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matheny</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aberdeen</ENAMEX>; sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Merideth Huff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wilma</ENAMEX>) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seitz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mich.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Hallam</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Evans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Brown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenino</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzie Saditoshi</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Muncie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenn.</ENAMEX>; granddaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sativa Matheny</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Juneton</ENAMEX>; and aunts, cousins, nieces and nephews.
</P>

<P ID="36">He was preceded in death by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalind Matheny Seitz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Asa Matheny</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="37">A memorial service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Merchant Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clarkson</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="38">Memorial donations may be given to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital</ENAMEX>, 501 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St. Jude Place</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memphis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TN</ENAMEX> 38105-1905.
</P>

 


<P ID="39"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JAGDISH LULLUBHAI PATEL</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="40"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagdish Lullubhai Patel</ENAMEX>, 61, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kent</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Jan. 14, 2004</TIMEX>. His wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Patel</ENAMEX> and daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nisha</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neha Patel</ENAMEX>, along with their mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pragna Patel</ENAMEX>, were by his side. Also present were friends, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy M. Johnson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Sundance Dempsey</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="41"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagdish</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5, 1942</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gujurat State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India</ENAMEX>. He spent his early years attending school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India</ENAMEX> before coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagdish</ENAMEX> earned his Bachelor of Science degree in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">India</ENAMEX> and then came to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> to finish his education, earning his Master’s in systems engineering. He then pursued a career in the aerospace industry working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes Aircraft</ENAMEX>, McDonnel Douglas, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lockheed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>. He retired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. He spent time painting, reading, bird watching and astronomy which he enjoyed very much. 
</P>

<P ID="42">His greatest love was for his family which he treasured the most.
</P>

<P ID="43"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagdish</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Patel</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nisha Patel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neha Patel</ENAMEX>; one brother; three sisters; and numerous nieces and nephews.
</P>

<P ID="44"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagdish</ENAMEX> was preceded in death by his parents; one brother; and one sister.
</P>

<P ID="45"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jagdish</ENAMEX> was a very strong advocate of organ donations, and any memorials towards this cause would be greatly encouraged. Marlatt Funeral Home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent</ENAMEX> is in charge of arrangements. 
</P>





 










<P ID="46">Webmaster
</P><P ID="47">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




