
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council admonishes Angel</ENAMEX> (again)
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/8/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> didn't leave the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting of the year unscathed.   For the second consecutive meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> was chastised by her peers for her efforts in the community.   At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> was admonished for her representation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>). The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is seeking all the money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> group has available, to help operate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>.    <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> was scolded for her efforts perceived in forming an Hispanic chamber <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of</ENAMEX> commerce in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilmen John Torch</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>.   At this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>'s meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> brought forth some concerns he has in regards to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s request from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> for all of its remaining funds to help in the operation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board members are currently reviewing applications from those seeking the nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX> the agency has left. Some of that money has already been allocated for other projects, such as community outreach programs in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, who is involved with the outreach efforts.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> reiterated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had requested all of the remaining money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has available, and that it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s job to relay that to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board, which she also sits on.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Don Stiles</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> project was one of the projects the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board approved looking at in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late November</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board is looking to fund the proposal for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said he will be making the city's presentation for funding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, though, wanted to know why the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board wasn't making available all of its remaining money.   "It doesn't seem we were represented fairly," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, who also made a motion to remove <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> as the city representative on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board, and nominated Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> explained that the city's proposal was a one-page letter, highlighting its request. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she brought forth the issue of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> grant programs director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hill</ENAMEX>, who helps oversee the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> that the city would have to make its request for available <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> money known in its proposal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that only the money the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> was putting out for proposals, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>, would be made available. She said the board's remaining dollars are already allocated for other programs, such as community outreach.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX>, past president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board, confirmed what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Angel</ENAMEX> was saying. He said he spoke with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX>, who said only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> was available to fund projects.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> said he remembers asking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> to relay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s wishes for all of the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> money.   "Our representative is representing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, not an individual," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, though, said she couldn't understand the strategy in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wanting all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>'s remaining money, which includes <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> set aside for outreach efforts in the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

