
<P ID="1">20 graduates say good-bye to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian High
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Before the members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School Class</ENAMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> marched to their seats at the front of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of the Nazarene in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, guests were invited to take a look back at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> through the eyes of the 20 graduating seniors.   A video filled with important and memorable moments from the students last school year together gave those in the audience a glimpse of just how close the graduates are to each other.   "Here before you is the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, each of us unique in our own way," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valedictorian Vanessa DeJong</ENAMEX>.   She said together the students make up a very outspoken and adamant group.   "We bent and broke many rules," she said. "[But] we hope to be remembered for our determined personalities."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeJong</ENAMEX> said the class wants to forget mistakes they made in the past as they get ready to go their own separate ways and prepare for the future.   "The class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> asks for your continued prayers and support," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> history teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russ Smies</ENAMEX> served as the class speaker, noting that the student's freshman year was his first year teaching.   "We've both learned quite a bit together," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> said.   He said one thing he will miss about the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> is that he found them to be a challenge in many ways. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> said they have challenged themselves in every way, from doing better in school to chLofferging each other in the weight room with their personal bests.   "I've noticed you are capable of rising to the challenge," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> said.   He told the graduates that although their thoughts are a million miles away from that nervous feeling they felt on their first day of the high school, it is important not to forget all of the memories they have made over the years.   "Do not throw away all those precious memories of your high school career," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> said.   He then told the graduates to continue to challenge themselves and to continue to stand up for what they believe in.   "Aim high," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smies</ENAMEX> said. "The most important thing is that whatever your goal is...your highest goal is the prize God has laid before you in life."   Before the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> received their diplomas, they made a contribution to the school many of them have attended for four years. The class presented the school with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400</NUMEX> for audio visual equipment, which will be used to purchase a 27-inch flat screen television.   As each of the 20 members of the graduating class stood and walked across the stage to receive their diploma, they were introduced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Principal Dean Wagenaar</ENAMEX>, who read a little bit about each of the graduates, including their favorite high school memory and their plans after graduation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholarship</ENAMEX> recipients were also recognized during the ceremony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Aleman</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> Future Educator's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholarship</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Bonny</ENAMEX> received an All Saints Scholarship from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Carroll College</ENAMEX> in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX> over four years; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,000</NUMEX> in awards and grants from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bend Community College</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeJong</ENAMEX> received an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX> scholarship from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitworth College</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9,470</NUMEX> grant from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitworth College</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> Yakima Valley Dairy Scholarship, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> Yakima Federal Savings and Loan award for academic excellence and a Washington State Honors Award; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek DeVries</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Apple Education Foundation</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wilbur Ellis Company Scholarship</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington Dollars</ENAMEX> for Scholars matching grant, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> Yakima Federal Savings and Loan award for academic excellence, a Washington Promise Scholarship and a Washington State Honors award; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Fennell</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court Scholarship</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Groenewold</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitworth College Salutatorian Scholarship</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin College Presidential Scholarship</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Pacific University Phillip W. Easton Scholarship</ENAMEX>, an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Pacific University Trustee</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scholarship</ENAMEX> and a Washington State Honors Award; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Haak</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> Seattle Pacific University Provost Scholar Award; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Hughes</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Columbia B League Academic Athlete Scholarship</ENAMEX>, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Nazarene University Athletic Scholarship</ENAMEX> for Soccer, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,750</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Nazarene University Academic Scholarship</ENAMEX> and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$900</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tacoma Community College Athletic Scholarship</ENAMEX> for Soccer; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucas Kilian</ENAMEX> received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,460</NUMEX> Montgomery GI Bill award from the United States Navy.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

