48 16 18 6 42 14
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Washington</ENAMEX> had a vision for this country. Was it three days of uninterrupted shopping?  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Melvoin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northern Exposure</ENAMEX>, Bolt from the Blue, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>