


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Council</ENAMEX> continues to hash out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> is going to have some tough decisions to make as it gets ready to hash out the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members listened and asked questions about the proposed current expense fund budget, which includes the municipal court, planning and economic development budgets.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> marked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s second budget session. During the budget sessions <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members have been listening to department heads and other city employees explain the budgets being proposed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. As the budget sessions continue through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will begin to decide how it will try to make up the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$190,000</NUMEX> budget shortfall the city is facing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Looking at the current expense fund, the areas where the proposed budgets for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> are seeing the most significant increases include municipal court and planning.
</P><P ID="7">   The proposed budget for the municipal court for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is set to see a more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> increase, going from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$132,010</NUMEX> budgeted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$154,790</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. That's a difference of more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22,000</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that the most significant changes in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget for the municipal court fall under professional services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Clerk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Posse</ENAMEX> said professional services include the cost of everything from a public defender to an interpreter. She added that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> will be working to find a new interpreting service, which will likely cost more.
</P><P ID="9">   Posse added that about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> was added to the municipal court budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> to cover the cost of a process server. She noted that currently when the city needs to serve papers the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX> is called in to do it, which can be a conflict of interest.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that over the last few years there has been a strong push as far as municipal courts are concerned to forge a separation between the court and the local police department.
</P><P ID="11">   "Municipal courts are another one of those unfunded mandates," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said. "The rules are set and you have to play by their rules."
</P><P ID="12">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> if the cost of a process server was something that could come out of the funds that will be available to the city thanks to Proposition #1, which was passed by voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that it would fall under the law and justice category.
</P><P ID="13">   Another council member asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Treasurer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Myers</ENAMEX> how much revenue the municipal court has been generating. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> noted that over the years the revenue being collected through the municipal court has continued to gradually increase with more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX> in fines and forfeitures being expected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   The other area that saw the most significant increase in the proposed budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is planning. The planning budget was set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,850</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, but is scheduled to see an increase to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$29,740</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, which is an increase of more than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">42 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that the increase in the planning budget is due to the volume of planning activity the city has seen over the course of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> or so. He noted that the city has seen a lot more annexation and subdivision activity recently.
</P><P ID="16">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>, year-to-date revenue generated through the planning department in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> is just under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,000</NUMEX>. He noted that the objective is to have the city's planning activities pay for themselves, adding that city officials are currently looking at adjusting fees for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "That should hopefully take care of that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the city currently contracts out for planning services, utilizing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Conference of Governments. He noted that if the city continues to grow there could come a time in the future when it will be more budget-savvy to hire a city planner. He added that is something that could still be five years away.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that at this point in time the city isn't seeing any evidence of development slowing down.
</P><P ID="20">   There were areas of the current expense fund budget that are proposed to see decreases in their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budgets, including the areas of city council and the city treasurer.
</P><P ID="21">   The city council portion of the budget is looking at a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">2.84 percent</NUMEX> decrease from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> the city council budget was set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$28,560</NUMEX>, a number that is proposed to decrease to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$27,750</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that city council is an area of the budget that typically remains about the same from year to year.
</P><P ID="22">   The decreases in the city council budget come under the categories of communications, travel and advertising.
</P><P ID="23">   When it comes to the city treasurer, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> the budget was set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,880</NUMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> that number is proposed to decrease by just under <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59,090</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> explained the decrease comes from a slight change in the wages and benefits coming out of the budget area, as well as the elimination of professional services. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,700</NUMEX> was budgeted for professional services and to date none of the funds have been used.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> will take another look at the city's budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 15</TIMEX>, during the study session preceding their regular city council meeting. The study session will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>





 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




