
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> schools make improvement plans
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Cross grade collaborations, improved teacher-student-parent communications, and strengthening of staff training towards improving classroom instruction are high on lists of goals being examined by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> building improvement teams.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Team</ENAMEX> leaders met with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to explain early drafts of their school improvement plans.   The plans, which are part of a three-year improvement study and implementation program, must be submitted to the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 31</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s board presentations by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School Principal Julie Schmick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> Junior/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior High School Principal Keith Morris</ENAMEX> focused on early data collection regarding students' academics strengths and weaknesses, as well as strategies for student improvements.   The building team leaders told the board their first aim is to shore up their goals with logical rationale.   As part of the data being collected at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX>, the improvement plan team is collecting assessment scores from all tests, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX>.   "We want to look at all testing as one piece," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX>. "We want to see what the programs are doing and how they are chLofferging our students," she said.   "We also want to be able to show the actual number of students who are less than five points from passing the state WASLs," she added.   Strategies being proposed by the Artz-Fox team include increasing communication between teachers and parents, increasing the number of school-wide activities, and implementing plans to have people trained in using data-driven instruction. Artz-Fox goals also call for holding monthly grade level meetings in an effort to customize instruction to meet individual student needs.   Peer coaching, K-12 collaborations and teacher self-assessments are also among the issues being examined by the Artz-Fox team.   At the junior/senior high school, the improvement team is focused on the areas of reading, math and supportive environment, commonly called school climate.   Among the team's goals is the improvement of student motivation by improving student-to-teacher, teacher-to-student relationships, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer LeRose</ENAMEX>, a member of the high school team.   She said the team's rationalization for focusing on the improved student/teacher relationships is based on research. "Research points toward students being more engaged in school when they know there is an adult at school who cares about them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeRose</ENAMEX> said.   She said the supportive environment team hopes to begin building a foundation for the improved relations via a myriad of avenues, including teacher-student surveys, journal entries and shared activities for teachers and students.   She said one way this might be accomplished could be through academic excellence assemblies or through other types of personal success assemblies and classroom acclamation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Simpson</ENAMEX>, who is team leader of the math portion of the secondary building improvement team, said his group is collecting data regarding student development and growth in the area of math literacy.   He said, for example, the middle school level teachers are researching student math scores as far back as fifth grade to determine where gaps may have developed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simpson</ENAMEX> said the team is also seeking to increase math communication by examining the instructional weaknesses.   "We will also be using both WASL and other tests to monitor student improvements and other areas in need of instructional intervention," he explained.   Her team's portion of the building improvement study is still in a draft form, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Junior</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior High School</ENAMEX> English Teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara Steen</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> said among the reading team's strategies will be to increase reading through parental involvement, via homework hotlines, increased utilization of a literacy coach to improve classroom instruction and aligning of all reading and writing requirements across the curriculum topics.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> said teachers have to be passionate about teaching reading and writing. "We have to do a better job of teaching kids," she said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steen</ENAMEX> said reading, listening and writing are all related and must be addressed in all subject areas.   The reading team also has set as one of its goals the increased utilization of existing technologies for expansion of students' literacy skills.   "Programs such as the accelerated reading programs are helping students to improve their reading and writing skills," she explained.   "We have begun to share our enthusiasm and we are seeing improvements," she added.   A lot of the areas being examined by the three high school teams overlap, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Washam</ENAMEX>, the high school building improvement facilitator.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washam</ENAMEX>, who is working with the high school teams, is a school improvement plan specialist from the state OSPI. She said working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> Junior/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior High School</ENAMEX> staff has been "wonderful."   "They have already established student achievement mission statements. We are only in the preliminary discussions, compiling data, research and developing actions plans," she told the school board.   "It's a big effort to pull together all of the threads. Everyone here is very committed," she said.   The building improvement teams meet each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> to work on the various components of the improvement study, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX>, Superintendent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Schools</ENAMEX>.   The next steps in the school improvement plan will include creating steps for implementation of goals and ongoing monitoring of the plans, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

