


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> concedes Presidential race <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">It looked as if the country was heading for a repeat of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> Presidential election, but there will be no exhilarating counting of the chads or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> battles this time around.
</P><P ID="5">   President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> won a second term <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> when Democratic challenger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Republican</ENAMEX> just after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Standard Time</ENAMEX> to concede the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> election, according to a report from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Press</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Voters across the country went to bed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> without knowing who would be the next president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, the outcome of the Presidential election looked as if it would hinge on the outcome of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> challenging the election results in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX>. Many political consultants <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> were guessing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> would challenge the results of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX> election, demanding that the estimated 140,000 to 200,000 provisional ballots cast be counted. As of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> had <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50.96 percent</NUMEX>, or 2,783,655 votes, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> had 2,653,005 votes, or <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">48.57 percent</NUMEX> of all ballots cast.
</P><P ID="7">   Many of the election problems in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX> had to do with the number of new voters registered for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> election, which numbered more than one million residents, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX> secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   It can be surmised that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> probably conceded the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> election because many political figures felt that even if the provisional ballots were counted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> couldn't make-up the difference he trailed by.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> and his vice presidential running mate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX> did quite well in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, winning the state's 11 electoral votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> nabbed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">52.5 percent</NUMEX> of the vote in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> won <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, a heavily Republican area, with 28,663 votes, compared to the 19,220 ballots cast for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>. The President was also a huge winner in neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton County</ENAMEX>, where he garnered 31,611 votes to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>'s 15,432. Much like <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> Presidential candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> won the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> thanks in large part to election results in King <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> had 347,025 votes in the Seattle area compared to 182,011 for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cheney</ENAMEX> ticket.
</P><P ID="11">   Independent candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX> received 13,729 votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> was able to secure a second term in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> thanks in part to winning the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX>. A large Latino turnout in that state supported the President.
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




