


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood police</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX> seek 'most wanted'
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/16/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">With new technology available to law enforcement officers, the Washington State Patrol has launched a link to their website dedicated to the agency's "most wanted."
</P><P ID="5">   The website lists 23 of the most wanted people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state, who are believed to have been involved in vehicular homicides, hit-and-runs and vehicular assaults.
</P><P ID="6">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> alone the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX> investigated 178 felony collisions state-wide. Of the 178 collisions, 45 were vehicular homicides where one or more citizens died as a result of someone else driving drunk, according to Capt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Ursino</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Patrol Criminal Investigation Division</ENAMEX>. One hundred and two were vehicular assaults in which citizens were seriously injured due to someone else driving drunk, and 21 were felony hit-and run collisions where persons were injured and the suspects left the scene.
</P><P ID="7">   "We are seeking help from the public to find these people who have fled police and have left numerous families with pain, loss and grief," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ursino</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Cases stem back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Recently, two persons listed on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX>'s most wanted were arrested.
</P><P ID="10">   Armondo Posadas Hernandez was arrested in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denver</ENAMEX>, Col. and is being returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, where he faces charges of vehicular assault. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hernandez</ENAMEX> is believed to have caused a two-vehicle accident at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lateral</ENAMEX> 1 and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lateral C</ENAMEX> roads in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 23, 1997</TIMEX>. Both Hernandez's passenger and an occupant in the other vehicle were seriously injured, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This month</TIMEX> Jacquelyn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Jim</ENAMEX> turned herself into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Walla Walla County Jail</ENAMEX> authorities. She was arrested a year to the date of a one-vehicle collision on State Route 124 that seriously injured her passenger. A warrant was issued for her arrest regarding a vehicular assault charge.
</P><P ID="12">   Four men are still being sought by the Washington State Patrol for cases originating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. They are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio Rios-Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rigoberto Serrano Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandro Sanchez Flores</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo Angel Figueroa</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rios-Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, 22, who was last known to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, is wanted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX> for vehicular homicide.
</P><P ID="14">   The suspect was allegedly driving eastbound on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lateral 1 Road</ENAMEX> when he ran a stop sign at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lateral</ENAMEX> A and struck another vehicle. His passenger died in the accident. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX> officials determined that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rios-Gonzalez</ENAMEX> was drinking at the time of the crash.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, who was last known to be living in the Yakima area, is also wanted for vehicular homicide. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1999</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> had been drinking when he was involved in a one-vehicle rollover on State Route 24, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX>. His passenger died as a result of injuries. The suspect, who has identifying scars on his head and face, was also seriously injured. He fled after being released from the hospital.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandro Sanchez Flores</ENAMEX>, 32, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Newburgh</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NY</ENAMEX>, was involved in a motor vehicle accident <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October of 1994</TIMEX> on I-82 near milepost 39. The suspect had been drinking, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX> officials. His passenger was seriously injured and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flores</ENAMEX> fled after his court appearance.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figueroa</ENAMEX>, 42, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>, was involved in an all-terrain vehicle fatality collision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17, 1992</TIMEX>. The wreck happened on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thacker Road</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. Investigators determined the suspect had been drinking and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Figueroa</ENAMEX> fled during the investigation. He is wanted for vehicular homicide.
</P><P ID="18">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> also has a most wanted list of its own.
</P><P ID="19">   On the list are suspects the department has been unable to locate, many of which have failed to appear for court or comply with the court's ruling, according to officials.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Arce</ENAMEX>, 21, is wanted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood police</ENAMEX> for his alleged involvement in an unattended hit and run accident, which has three counts of failure to appear and failure to comply tacked onto it.
</P><P ID="21">   He is also wanted for failure to appear or comply with court rulings on cases of malicious mischief as well as for driving under the influence and first degree driving while license suspended.
</P><P ID="22">   39-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Rodriguez</ENAMEX> has five warrants for his arrest issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Municipal Court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> is wanted for four counts of failure to pay a fine on third degree driving while license suspended charges. He is also being sought for failing to pay a fine on a third degree theft charge.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Martinez</ENAMEX>, 21, who was last known to live in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area, has warrants for his arrest on failure to appear in court and failure to pay a fine on charges of violation of a no-contact order, giving false and misleading statements to police, fourth degree domestic violence assault and two counts of third degree escape.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon P. Martinez</ENAMEX>, 22, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is wanted for failure to comply with court orders on a charge of third degree driving while license suspended and a failure to pay a fine for a charge of minor in possession and/or consumption of alcohol. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> is also being sought on charges of possession of marijuana, disorderly conduct, minor in possession and/or consumption of alcohol and third degree driving while license suspended.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert Vela Peralez</ENAMEX>, 34, last known to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is being sought on warrants for domestic violence, violation of a no contact order and third degree malicious mischief. He is also wanted for two counts of fourth degree domestic violence assault, four counts of violation of a no contact order and possession of marijuana.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica M. Fuentes</ENAMEX>, 22, is wanted on three charges of minor in possession and/or consumption of alcohol, obstructing a law enforcement officer and fourth degree assault.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luciano Cortez</ENAMEX>, 22, last known to have lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is wanted for failing to appear in court on charges of resisting arrest, possession of marijuana, fourth degree domestic violence assault and second degree driving while license suspended. He is also wanted for failure to appear and failure to pay a court fine on a charge of possession and/or consumption of alcohol. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cortez</ENAMEX> is also wanted on two counts of first degree driving while license suspended and operating a motor vehicle without an ignition lock.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Ray Wilcowski</ENAMEX>, 25, is being sought by local police on charges of fourth degree domestic violence assault and violation of a no contact order.
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humberto Miranda Linares</ENAMEX>, 25, has warrants for his arrest on charges of failure to appear in court for a driving while under the influence hit and run charge and a separate charge of driving under the influence.
</P><P ID="30">   Those wanting information on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSP</ENAMEX>'s "most wanted" list can find the listing by going to the Washington State Patrol website, www.wsp.wa.gov or by accessing the website directly at www.wsp.wa.gov/crime/wanted.html. The website features information on the suspect, photos, distinguishing marks or tattoos and their last known address.
</P>   
   






 










<P ID="31">Webmaster
</P><P ID="32">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




