
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/31/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESTHER EVA BARNSmart
ESTHER EVA BARNSmart
Esther Eva BarnHart</ENAMEX>, 77, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 29, 2004</TIMEX>, at the Prosser Memorial Nursing Home.   
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 29, 1926</TIMEX> in Mound, S.D., the daughter of Eva (Mitzel) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karl Vollmer</ENAMEX>.  She received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Dakota</ENAMEX>, later moving with her family to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August of 1942</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip BarnHart</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.  Together they farmed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and raised seven children.  Following the death of her husband in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX> she made her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tri-Cities</ENAMEX> for a short time before returning to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>.  
Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BarnHart</ENAMEX> is survived by seven children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Neil BarnHart</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thelma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles BarnHart</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob BarnHart</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mesa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Williams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clearfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Lou Bryant</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael BarnHart</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robyn</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pina</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>, of Moxee; 18 grandchildren; 21great- grandchildren; four brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Vollmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salem</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Vollmer</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Vollmer</ENAMEX>, both of  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Vollmer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grand Coulee City</ENAMEX>; and two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clara Kirks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Neugebauer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">  She was preceded in death by her parents; her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phillip BarnHart</ENAMEX>; two sisters; and several brothers.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 1, 2004</TIMEX>, from 5:00 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:00 p.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 2, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:00 a.m.</TIMEX> until time of service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:00 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  Burial will follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Cemetery under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NEDDRA MERCER DELANEY ANDERSON
Neddra Mercer Delaney Anderson</ENAMEX>, 86, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 28, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17, 1917</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Powder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank and Bessie Wilson Mercer</ENAMEX>. She graduated from high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Condon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and received her Bachelor’s and Master’s Degree of education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corvallis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> She married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Delaney</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>. She later married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Anderson</ENAMEX>, who was also an educator, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10, 1956</TIMEX>. They taught 33 years all over the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jacksonville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ontario</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boardman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willamina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brownsville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salem</ENAMEX>. Upon the death of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, she moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to be near her brother and family in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>. She became known to all in the community as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">“Aunt Dee Dee.”
Neddra</ENAMEX> enjoyed world travel, bridge, knitting, reading and water aerobics. She was a life member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Education Assoc.</ENAMEX>, Chapter Ex of P.E.O., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nouvella</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>.
She is survived by her brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Mercer</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerrydean</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; granddaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kelley Stacy</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew</ENAMEX>; two great-grandsons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan and Blake</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Australia</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Anderson</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX>, and grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philomath</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; step-daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rena Bowes</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodney</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amherst</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Hampshire</ENAMEX>; step-grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonnie Bowes</ENAMEX> and her children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay</ENAMEX> and Will of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bowes</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX> and children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trevor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tatum</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Fairfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Conn.</ENAMEX>; nephew, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lin Mercer</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana</ENAMEX>, and their sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Micah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermiston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; and niece, Mischelle Booth and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, and their sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
She was preceded in death by her son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Delaney</ENAMEX>; her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>; and step-son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Anderson</ENAMEX>.
Memorial funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 2, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>. Inurnment will follow at a later date in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Condon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="6">HAZEL <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RUTH BLADES GREER
Hazel Ruth Blades Greer</ENAMEX>, 88, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident, went to be with the Lord <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, March 25, 2004</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 1, 1916</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blades</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX>. Her father died when she was four and the family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hillsboro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, where her mother taught school until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel</ENAMEX> was a junior in high school. They moved back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel</ENAMEX> graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldendale High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>. She then attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Junior College</ENAMEX> one year and transferred to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington State Teacher College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cheney</ENAMEX> and graduated in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> she married Thad Walen, had one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX>. She bought and operated the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wheeler Auto Court</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wheller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> for three years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel</ENAMEX> was employed as a civil service typist at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> Depot</ENAMEX> in Seattle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>. She then moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry</ENAMEX> to teach school in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. She taught school full-time for two years and did substitute teaching for many years after that.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX> she met and married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer W. Greer</ENAMEX> and together they built an excellent Home Lumber business. They enjoyed 57 years of marriage. She was very active in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Christian Church</ENAMEX>, where she attended <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1948 to 1981</TIMEX>. She served as a deaconess, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX></ENAMEX></ENAMEX> board, church clerk for nine years, church choir and various other committees. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel</ENAMEX> was very active in community work, serving as president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junior Women’s Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garden Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Novella Club</ENAMEX> and vice-president of the District Junior Federated Women’s Clubs. She had been a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camano Chapel</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>.
She is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Homer W. Greer</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Terry Greer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma Jean Blades Miller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>; one granddaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimberly Christenson</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everett</ENAMEX>; one grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cameron Morris Greer</ENAMEX>; great-grandsons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Wesley Christenson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Loffer Christenson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian Shoman Greer</ENAMEX>; and several nieces, nephews, grand-nieces and nephews.
A memorial service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, April 1, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at Camano Chapel, 867 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S. West Camano Drive</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Camano Island</ENAMEX>. Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 4, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, April 5, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of Wells Funeral Home.
Those wishing to honor Hazel’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Lung Association</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camano Chapel</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SAMUEL VERNON RICHARDS
Samuel Vernon Richards</ENAMEX>, 60, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dallas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident, lost his life to cancer <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 26, 2004</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> was raised in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> area and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1957</TIMEX>. He left school after the 10th grade and became an apprentice machinist in the navy shipyards. He moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> and was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX> for eight years. He was a machinist, while living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>. He moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dallas</ENAMEX> and bought a farm and raised emus and rhea birds. He was a diversified farmer. In recent years, he worked as a machinist for NW Machine in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salem</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Acufab</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corvallis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, which later became Automated Tooling Systems of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>. He married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Howe</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2002</TIMEX>.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Richards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dallas</ENAMEX>; daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Richards</ENAMEX> and grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Richards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dallas</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Richards</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cari Domas</ENAMEX> and son-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Domas</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>; step-children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shawn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garold Howe</ENAMEX>; mother and step-father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjorie and Maynard Huenefield</ENAMEX>; sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcella</ENAMEX> and brother-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lloyd Brice</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fontana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif</ENAMEX>; and brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> and sister-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie Richards</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Keizer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.
Memorial</ENAMEX> services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 4, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dallas</ENAMEX>. For service information please call 503-949-6098. Arrangements by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crown Memorial Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Milwaukie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>
</P>

 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

