
<P ID="1">Hefty increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> property tax rate OK'd
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Years of not raising property taxes has finally caught up with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   In a 4-3 vote during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members approved raising the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> property tax by 42¢ per thousand of assessed property value from the current rate. The new property tax for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.1334</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value, up from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.71</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value.   The approved property tax increase will raise an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195,556</NUMEX> for city coffers.   The city will raise an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$625,970</NUMEX> in General Obligation Bonds. The payments on the bonds are being made from when the city refinanced together the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX> and the pool measures voters approved.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was split on the matter, with Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilmen Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX> wanting to scale back the property tax increase to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilmen Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX> took the collective stance that the city needs to do something to raise money to prevent further reductions in city services.   But not everyone agreed with the thoughts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Johnson</ENAMEX> said he felt <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> should stick to past practices of not raising taxes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said that with the cost of living and water and sewer rates continually increasing, now is not the time to burden residents with an extra tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> it will probably be seeing a lot of vacant homes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> if property taxes are raised.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX> expressed concerns that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was raising property taxes to pay for the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.2 million</NUMEX> purchase of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Monson</ENAMEX> feedlot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> also said she didn't want to see property taxes raised because she felt it might encourage the city to spend additional money for items not needed.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps</ENAMEX> scolded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> for what he perceived as a mismanagement of the city's budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> said because <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> hadn't raised property taxes in a number of years that it backed itself into a corner, where it had no choice but to do so <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   "You have mismanaged the budget. You have overspent," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX>. "If you had done your jobs along the way, you probably wouldn't be at this point."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> sided with some of the concerns expressed by residents, but felt the city had no choice but to raise property taxes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said that when the city is dealing with a budget the size <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has to make some tough decisions.   "We are at the point where we have to do something," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, saying that if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> didn't approve the property tax increase the city would be faced with having to make more cuts to balance the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget. The mayor also explained the city receives minimal dollars from the property tax, with the county receiving a majority of the money.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he wasn't in favor of property tax increases, but said there is a need to raise rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, though, said he would like to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> go back to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX> rates of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value for the property tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he felt the city could "hold the line" and manage best what it has with his proposed rate.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he was approached by residents over the weekend who were concerned with the personnel cuts proposed for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he saw the need to raise property taxes to help pay for needed city services.   "We do have to provide the basic services to our community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> about his thoughts on taxes, saying he would also like to see the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> rate. The mayor pro-tem said he felt the city has to do something to raise money to prevent further service cuts. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents have been lucky for the past several years with seeing no property tax increases, while other communities haven't been as fortunate. He said the city has also taken money out of reserves to pay for mistakes that have been made by the county so as not to burden the local taxpayers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farmer</ENAMEX> said he believes the city could be creative with how it uses city funds after receiving the money from the 3/10 of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> sales tax county voters recently approved for law and justice services to address some budget matters.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> was quick to point out that the Monson feedlot purchase has nothing to do with the budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said the money spent for the purchase of the Monson feedlot will be replenished as soon as the property is sold.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> was also in favor of raising property taxes to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> rate. He said he feels the city has been doing fine with providing services, citing what the fire department has been doing without having two staff members available.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

