
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
WASL unreliable
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Board of Education</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBE</ENAMEX>) and your legislators are about to "marry" the state's children to an abusive partner, the WASL—a high stakes but unreliable, invalid test that will unfairly determine which kids move up and which will be pushed aside.
All who testified at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBE</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12</TIMEX> meeting objected to the impending nuptials, including parents, minority educators and parents representing Hispanics, Asians and Native Americans, the teachers union, special educators, parents of special education students and the non-union <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Professional Educators</ENAMEX> that focuses on students and professionalism.
Instead of calling off the wedding before anyone gets hurt, officials plan to tell your children to go back to their abusive partner, not once, not twice, but four times! Not only that, WASLs are being piloted in additional grades, promising further reductions in students' instructional time.
A messy divorce is inevitable, but only after the state wastes millions of dollars and lives too precious to count.
Parents and taxpayers must demand that officials can the WASL for cost effective, reliable performance measures that help children, not hurt them. They can call legislators at 800-562-6000, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SBE</ENAMEX> at 360-725-6025 or go on-line to sbe@ospi.wednet.edu.
Prevent this ceremony or soon you'll be searching for your nearest shelter for the educationally abused.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Omlin</ENAMEX>, Executive Director, Northwest Professional Educators, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spokane</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Blood drawing
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> blood drawing held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX> was sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Food Services Association</ENAMEX> - chapter 56. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose Nesmith</ENAMEX> was the chairperson.
We had 64 presenters and two first-time donors. Fourteen were unable to give, leaving 50 units collected. Because of their efforts, 150 people will have another chance at life.
Many thanks to the sponsors for donating the delicious cookies and juice, and the Yakima Valley Dairy Women for the ice cream bars. Thanks, too, to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> for the use of its hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> Corrugators for displaying the banner at Centennial Square and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX> for publicity in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>.
And then there are the volunteers whose services are always appreciated: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Benedetti</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myrtis Lang</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ella Mae Lochner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxine Means</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Murray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee Murray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tana Brotherton</ENAMEX> and Accordia Horn.
A special thanks to all the donors, who are the lifeline for the flow of blood in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hope</ENAMEX> to see everyone at the next blood drawing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 6</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie Handy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX> blood drawing chairperson
</P> 
<P ID="5">School record
For 18 years I've skimmed the local sports section with an eye out for the girls track results. Being a highly competitive person I like to see how race times during my "glory days" match up with our current speedsters.
At the beginning of each season I'm curious about which young lady might race by my old times. I'd always hoped that when my 300 hurdles record was shattered, and it was demolished, that the new record holder would be someone that I know. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last weekend</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> not only won the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> title in the 300 low hurdles, a grueling race, but she established a new school record—and left me in the dust!
Way to go <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX>! I'm proud to have such a well deserving young lady take my place in the record books.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erika Barrom</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">SVID water
Since I don't do very well speaking to a public group, I am giving my thoughts about the latest development by "some" of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> on the subject of irrigation water through SVID (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> story).
Obviously, some of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> haven't read all the letters the DSN has received on the subject. They may recall, I have written a few of these letters concerning SVID and its practices, including the takeover of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snipes Mountain Irrigation District</ENAMEX>. I really think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> needs to do more research into what they are proposing to do with SVID.
First of all, I do agree that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> charge for hook-up is not a bad price. But, even so, you have to have more than one hook-up in an area to get on their priority list. So, while you may have the  funds to hook up, your neighbor may not, and you will not get priority over an area with more than one hook-up.
Second, I priced all of the equipment necessary to complete getting the water from the outlet provided by SVID to your existing irrigation system, whether it be automatic sprinklers or hoses. Here are a few of the costs: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$254</NUMEX> for a one-horsepower pump, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62</NUMEX> for a filter, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11</NUMEX> for a screen, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX> for pipe (may vary for each lot), <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> for fittings (may vary for each lot), <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> for a meter (available only from SVID) and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38</NUMEX> in taxes. The total: <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$527</NUMEX>. This is provided I do all the work myself.
What about the cost for those who can't do it themselves? Plus, you must buy a backflow prevention unit so that city water and SVID water do not mix—that's at least another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX>.
I agree you would save money in the long run, maybe, or until SVID raises its rates again.
Please get more information before jumping into this.
Another point, Councilman de la Cruz brought up the raise in the assessment from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snipes</ENAMEX> to SVID. SVID has the practice of charging for a minimum of one acre, no matter how small your parcel is, it is charged at the one-acre rate. Yet, if you have 1.1 acres you are charged 1.1 times the 1-acre rate. Most of the parcels on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Hill</ENAMEX> are less than one acre. This unreasonable minimum charge is what prompted me in the first place to try to change SVID's practice. But, as with any bureaucracy, my attempt was futile, though I believe the hook-up rate is, in part, attributable to my and my fellow property owners' attendance and comments at SVID meetings. Thank you again to all those who accompanied me to those meetings.
Finally, "We all have to pay for some things we don't get," a quote from Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Trull</ENAMEX> in reference to SVID charging a minimum 1-acre charge for all parcels: this quote was in an article written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna Luft</ENAMEX> when she was a reporter for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>. Many thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanna</ENAMEX> and the Daily <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> for their coverage of those meetings and this subject.
One last thought, I hope this letter again angers the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Having to pay for more than what you receive, as stated by Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trull</ENAMEX>, really doesn't cut it. You should only have to pay for what you are entitled to receive, and, if that is less than one acre, so be it. Charges should be based on parcel size only.
/s/ a disgruntled citizen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hansen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

