
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/10/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Read-a-thon
The fifth grade students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX>, rooms 302 and 303, would like to thank sponsors for donations during our read-a-thon. The event was a huge success.
More than 50 students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> in the comfortable Wal-Mart patio chairs and read for 2 to 4 hours. Wal-Mart was wonderful. Not only did they donate their location, but also provided us with cookies and cool drinks.
Another special thank you to Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hicks</ENAMEX> for supplying us with homemade cookies.
Thank you <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for helping us raise money for our field trip, art projects for our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hillcrest</ENAMEX> grandparents and the local Relay for Life.
/s/ Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erika Barrom</ENAMEX>, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Peters</ENAMEX> and students
</P> 


 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

