


<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/8/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Fairbairn</ENAMEX> was at a crossroads when the job as administrative assistant for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise group fell into her lap.
</P><P ID="5">   She wanted to be involved in her son's classroom at school and still be able to work. Volunteering her time at her church, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> native, learned of the position with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise, a group devoted to providing opportunities for youth.
</P><P ID="6">   After being hired for the part-time position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> began organizing and planning all of the meetings and special events sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise.
</P><P ID="7">   "I work directly with the board to make decisions on what kinds of projects will work," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   The group is devoted to five promises it has made to local youths-providing educational opportunities, developing marketable skills, establishing safe places, making available caring adults and ensuring for kids there are opportunities to serve.
</P><P ID="9">   "I make sure there are no holes or duplications when it comes to meeting the goals," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   One of the activities <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> has helped organize is the annual Promise to Read event, including Book the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Chief day</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   Heavily focused on reading, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise recently donated 1,200 books to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook School</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise also partners with other activities as a way to pool resources and be more visible in the community, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>. She said the group helps on activities such as National Night Out and Red Ribbon week.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise is planning a Promise to Succeed event for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 14</TIMEX>. She said the group will be bringing in comedian <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Huffman</ENAMEX>. The group will also be holding an open mic night in conjunction with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huffman</ENAMEX>'s evening performance.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> said the group's always looking for new ways to involve youth.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> said she has worked in a variety of different settings, including floral shops and for a while she worked with her brother, who was the first person to have ice cream trucks in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. But she considers her work with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise the most rewarding.
</P><P ID="16">   "It's about quality of life for the kids in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "My son's young and if we don't try to correct the problems we have now, what's it going to be like when he gets to high school?" she asked.
</P><P ID="18">   For as many obstacles as are facing the youth of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> said there are also wonderfully caring adults and young people with great ideas.
</P><P ID="19">   "These kids have awesome ideas and we just need to listen and to give them a chance," she said.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> feels she is lucky to be able to help the youth of the community and still have the time to volunteer at her church. She added that her schedule also gives her the opportunity to help in her 8-year-old son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank</ENAMEX>'s, classroom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fairbairn</ENAMEX> also has two adult stepsons and will be a grandmother <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="21">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




