


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> does away with ambulance household tax
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/11/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">If you paid your water bill recently, you might have noticed you didn't have to dig quite as deeply into your pocket.
</P><P ID="5">   That's is because the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> has discontinued a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> fee to help pay for the community's ambulance service.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> said the city decided to discontinue the ambulance household tax, which was being billed monthly as part of residents' water bills because of a state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruling that occurred against the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Kennewick</ENAMEX>. The ruling involved an apartment owner who challenged the city's right to implement the fee. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> ruled that the ambulance tax <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> had was unconstitutional, resulting in the city repealing the tax.
</P><P ID="7">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wisdom</ENAMEX> said we should stop since ours was adopted under the same framework," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Several cities have the ambulance tax, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. He said that the state legislature allowed cities to put such a measure before voters. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has had the ambulance tax since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 1989</TIMEX>. The money from the tax generates about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$140,000</NUMEX> per year. The money is used to help subsidize city ambulance service.
</P><P ID="9">   "It goes towards all kinds of expenses," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   Right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is busy looking at ways to address the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s ruling. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the ruling provided some guidance for cities, but no one is really sure why the state high court banned the tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said usually it is easy to figure out the direction the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> wants to take on the ruling it hands down.
</P><P ID="11">   "This is one where I just don't get it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. "Everybody is just kind of scratching their heads."
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is expecting to have a recommendation before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on how to address the issue within the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next three weeks</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   To make up for the shortfall in revenue from the tax, which is between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7-9,000</NUMEX> per month, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the city will turn to a reserve fund within the fire department budget if needed. The reserve is rather healthy at about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said that money can't be tapped for long because it is used to help purchase such items as ambulances and other needed equipment.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it is important for the city to address this loss of tax revenue. The city already subsidizes the ambulance service, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, and can't really afford to provide much more. Later in the year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the issue of how to operate the ambulance service will come before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, but right now he is trying to figure out a way to address the loss of revenue from suspending the utility tax. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, though, wants to assure residents that they will continue to have a quality, uninterrupted ambulance service.
</P><P ID="15">   "The ambulance service will continue as it has," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. "We need to fix this (revenue problem). It is a service that has to be available."
</P>   






 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




