


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds push past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wapato Wolves</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> managed to keep the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wapato Wolves</ENAMEX> at bay <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, winning over the visiting team 63-55.
</P><P ID="5">   However, despite what may look like a close game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Adolfo Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said it wasn't until the fourth quarter that things got heated. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>, going into the fourth quarter the Lady 'Hounds had a comfortable double-digit lead, then the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolves</ENAMEX> let loose.
</P><P ID="6">   "The middle of the fourth quarter they cut the lead to two," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="7">   But the Lady 'Hounds weren't going to let the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wapato</ENAMEX> team walk away with a win. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team fought back and finished with an eight-point lead.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said he was happy to see the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wapato</ENAMEX> team charge back in the fourth quarter, noting that it's good practice for the 'Hounds. Especially, going into a week that includes games against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   One of the ways <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> was able to stay ahead of the Wolfpack was the team did some things a little differently <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said offensively he put one of the team's guards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, in as a post.
</P><P ID="10">   "She really picked it up," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said. "She kind of dominated the inside."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> proved she was ready for the challenge of changing positions, and was happy with the results.
</P><P ID="12">   On the defensive side of things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said during the first quarter the team experimented with a new defensive strategy, one the team hopes to put to use against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "We tried it during the first quarter, then we went back to what we do," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said, noting that the team typically relies on a full court press throughout the course of the game.
</P><P ID="14">   Helping the team with rebounds during the match-up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wapato</ENAMEX> was senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meghan Waddle</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> had seven rebounds and really controlled the boards for the team.
</P><P ID="15">   Scoring for the Lady 'Hounds were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> with 24 points and eight rebounds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> with 11 points, senior Keitha Robertson with 10 points, and junior Danelle Cowan with 5 points and five rebounds.
</P><P ID="16">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team has two games to make up, after inclement weather canceled two games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. The Lady 'Hounds will play <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 13</TIMEX>, at home and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 20</TIMEX>, at home.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said he is looking forward to the match-up against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>. He said he wants his team to be able to control the tempo during the game, and noted that the team has been working on its transition defense.
</P><P ID="18">   "I think it will be a good test for us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said. "They will be physical with us."
</P><P ID="19">   He said it will be good for the Lady 'Hounds (2-0, 6-2) to play a physical team, especially now that the team is getting into the middle of its season.
</P><P ID="20">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




