
<P ID="1">Educator ready for new adventures
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/3/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">After 28 years of going to school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Davis</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is ready for a change of direction.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> principal will turn in his keys and close the door of his principal office that has been his daily destination for nearly 18 of those 28 years.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, who started his education career in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser School District</ENAMEX>, started teaching fourth graders in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">27 years ago</TIMEX>.   "I only taught fourth grade for two years," he said.   It wasn't long before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> realized he much preferred the classroom interaction with sixth graders. "I like that grade the best," he said.   "You can get sixth graders to do anything, if you let them think it's their idea," he grinned.   But being a classroom teacher wasn't the only area of education which interested the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Indiana</ENAMEX> native. He began his move to administration in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1980s</TIMEX>, serving his administrative internship under then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School Principal Kieth Miller</ENAMEX>, who retired a short time later.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> settled into his new duties as the principal of Chief Kamiakin Elementary school, where sixth, fifth and fourth graders were greeted by his sunny smile each day for 10 years.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> moved to the newly constructed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX>, where he greeted a younger group of students. Pioneer is home to kindergarten through fourth grade students, but the friendly, daily greetings to students by "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>" have remained the same.   His easy-going personality and rapport with the students, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> teaching and office staff, resulted in his recent nomination as one of two outstanding educators honored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past March</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said he was pleased to share the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>'s Outstanding Educator Award with one of his favorite teachers, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rose Hall</ENAMEX>, a fourth grader teacher who also works at Pioneer Elementary.   "It was a shock when they announced my name and a great honor to be recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> and my staff," he said.   Now looking forward to a well deserved retirement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> said he won't be spending all of his time golfing, one of his favorite hobbies, or traveling.   "I expect I'll find something to keep me busy. I think I'm ready to try something different, some new career challenge," he said.   Accepting new challenges is has kept <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> interested in education all these years, he said.   "I love working with the teachers, the administration and of course the students.   "It's just now time for a change," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

