


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds run over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser Mustangs</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - Walking into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser High School</ENAMEX> gym <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls' basketball coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolfo Hinojosa</ENAMEX> didn't think the Lady 'Hounds would be able to simply walk away with things. However, after coming out and taking the early lead, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> team was never able to catch up.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady 'Hounds rallied past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> using both an aggressive defense and teamwork to finish with a 50-39 victory.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said before the game he thought the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mustangs</ENAMEX> were going to keep a tighter reign on the Grandview team and keep the score a little closer.
</P><P ID="7">   "I thought it would go back and forth," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="8">   Instead, the Lady 'Hounds adjusted to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s flow and adapted to what the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mustangs</ENAMEX> gave them.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the key to the Grandview win <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was the teamwork on the court. He said the Lady 'Hounds really came together. He noted that the Grandview team also showed great fundamental footwork against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>, as well as a lot of quickness.
</P><P ID="10">   Defensively, he said the team was able to do a lot rebounding, as well as maintain a full court press throughout the game.
</P><P ID="11">   "I don't think they realized how quick we were," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said, noting that the Grandview team was able to easily break <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s press.
</P><P ID="12">   Scoring for the Lady 'Hounds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> were junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Rodriquez</ENAMEX>, putting up 17 points, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Arteaga</ENAMEX> with 7 points and senior Keitha Robertson with 6 points.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said junior Danelle Cowan had an excellent night <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, scoring a double/double with 12 points and 12 rebounds.
</P><P ID="14">   "That's good to see," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowan</ENAMEX>'s efforts.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> also noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> did a great job during the game.
</P><P ID="16">   "She really made some great decisions out there," he said.
</P><P ID="17">   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said he was happy to see the Lady 'Hounds take the lead early in the game and hold onto it.
</P><P ID="18">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> is an aggressive team," he said.
</P><P ID="19">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> team (4-2, 8-4) will take to the court again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="20">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




