16 47 27 5 33 25
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Be not angry that you cannot make others as you wish them to be, since you cannot make yourself as you wish to be.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> a Kempis (1380 - 1471), Imitation of Christ
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>