
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">HERBERT MILTON HAAS
HERBERT MILTON  HAAS</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 27, 1900</TIMEX> – <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 29, 2004</TIMEX>
103 years, 6 months and 2 days
</P> 
<P ID="4">You are joined with your Beloved wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernice</ENAMEX>,
In a leap year which gave us an extra day with you.
Now take her by the hand, fill your dance card with her name,
And dance with her forever.
You were always giving kindness.
Never stopping to judge a man or a woman.
Open to each new experience with fresh eyes.
Teaching the world Brotherly Love in your acceptance of all.
Lending yourself to the child in each of us with your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Winnie</ENAMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pooh</ENAMEX> innocence of heart.
Respecting people for their goodness and honest work.
Being tender, caring, steady and hardworking so as to earn your sleep at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the day</TIMEX>. 
Patient and lenient, fair and forgiving. Stable and stalwart, laughing and tearful.
You reminded us to ‘use our heads,’ to wake up in the morning and ‘work our day’s work out,’ to not hold jealousy  or anger in our hearts. You may have not seen the 9th grade, but you never once stopped seeking to learn life’s lessons and sharing them with others.
Beauty did not escape your sight: a landscape, a lady, an act of good deed, a well-oiled
machine, a nice suit, an infant, an animal, a planet, a star, an opportunity to give and to teach and to learn and receive.
Your life was a painting: a tableau of seasonal rebirth and death.
You palette was the rich earth itself.
Your paint: the unplanted seed. 
Your brushes: your two agile hands.
Your religion was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brotherhood</ENAMEX>.
Your place of worship, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masonic Temple</ENAMEX>.
Your spiritual grounds were the asparagus farm, the task at hand, the garden you tend, and
the person before you in the moment.
You loved to travel and visit with family, and you equally received us all in your home with opened arms. You appreciated a good, balanced meal with your black coffee, and a bowl of vanilla ice-cream to top it all off.
You maintained your independence by your willfulness. Not wanting to burden anyone by your need. Always saying ‘Thank you,’ recognizing when people went out of their way to return a kindness. Being ever gracious.
Your serenity was balanced by being happy within your own thought and sharing companionship in every way. Solitaire, the game you loved to play: turning over a card, to see what it was, and looking to see where it would fit into the whole picture before you. Playing, clearing the table, reshuffling, dealing again anew. Endless contemplation. Myriad possible outcomes. Always eager to see what was next. Patient to accept the hand. Such was your life.
Everyone who met you has felt your love: “An extraordinary man.” “A good man.” “A fair leader.” “ A true companion.” “A wonderful asparagus farmer.” “A loving father.” “The best Grandpa.” “My sign of courage.”
You are father to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carole</ENAMEX>'s husband. Your are Grandpa to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva</ENAMEX>, Jon’s wife.
You are Great-Grandpa to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meghan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily</ENAMEX>. You are Uncle, Great-Uncle and Great-Great Uncle to a family line of more than 400 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX>. You are friend to countless the world-over in how you ‘live and let live.’
One of your wishes, before you closed your eyes for the last time, was ‘to get better so you could help others’.
You have blown the candles out. We will fulfill your wish by keeping your light shining strong in our deeds. Though we speak of you in the past tense your legacy will always live in the present with us. As you said so many times: “I’ve had a wonderful life.” You will be remembered and loved for always. Let us carry you to the dance hall, you sweet, sweet man.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 3, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, March 4</TIMEX>. Burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Garden. Gathering in remembrance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masonic Temple</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Memorials may be made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shriner’s Hospital</ENAMEX> and the Orthopedic Guild.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JOHN MARK LANSFORD
John Mark Lansford</ENAMEX>, 47, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> went to be in the arms of his Savior, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb. 25, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 7, 1956</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Douglas O’Bryant</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> received his early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waco</ENAMEX> before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> received his Associate degree in auto mechanics from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Basin College</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 18, 1998</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Marshall</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> was a missionary for the First Love Ministries in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, and was currently employed by Community Living and Adult Care in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> enjoyed spending time in the out of doors with his dogs, working on cars, reading his Bible and talking with people. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> had an out going personality and made friends easy.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Lansford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; step-son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levi Johnson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kirkland</ENAMEX>; his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Sawyer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcia Pringle</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by his grandmother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bessis Adams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waco</ENAMEX>; one aunt; and two nieces.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mark</ENAMEX> was preceded in death by his grandfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Adams</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 5, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with an evening service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 6, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at Cleveland Cemetery in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> area. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements. Those wishing to honor his memory may contribute to the First Love Ministries, P.O. Box 10, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98935.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

