
<P ID="1">Grandview police have busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> weekend
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police were kept busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> answering calls involving burglaries, auto thefts and vehicle prowls.   The weekend got underway <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police dispatchers received a call that a black Honda Civic had been stolen from the 400 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Fifth Street</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Ware</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> said the vehicle, which reportedly had two occupants, eluded the combined efforts of the Grandview police, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Patrol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Sheriff</ENAMEX> deputies, before being abandoned at a crash scene.   The car thieves were headed west on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Forsell Road</ENAMEX>, when the missed a curve at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puterbaugh Road</ENAMEX> before crashing into a fence near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stover Road</ENAMEX> and I-82, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> explained.   The two suspects fled the scene on foot and officers were unable to get a description of the suspects, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> said.   Two burglaries reported within minutes of each other on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> found that someone had broken into an apartment building in the 900 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Second Street</ENAMEX>, where the walls were vandalized with gang-related graffiti, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> explained.   However, in the second reported burglary in the 500 block of Avenue "H", two male juveniles, 14 and 15, were apprehended and taken into custody on suspicion of breaking and entry, vandalism and malicious mischief. They were taken into custody.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX> said charges against the two males were sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> juvenile authorities.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, a vehicle prowl near <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division Avenue</ENAMEX> resulted in the theft of a car stereo from one vehicle, while a would-be thief in the 100 block of Arikara Drive was scared away when the owner of the vehicle surprised him.   "The descriptions for the suspects in both cases were again sketchy, " said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX>.   "We're not sure if the two vehicle prowls are related," he said.   A burglary at a storage unit in the 100 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> was reported <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. According to the police report, the break-in resulted in the theft of a bike.   'There was plenty of other stuff in the storage unit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ware</ENAMEX>. "But only the bike was taken."   The Grandview police are also investigating a burglary in the 100 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Birch</ENAMEX> and a reported theft in the 100 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>, both of which were reported on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, but as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, details were unavailable.      
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

