
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> arrested for using fake <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ID</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sumner</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert E. Ford</ENAMEX>, 38, was arrested <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> after he reportedly attempted to cash a fake <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> unemployment check at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Valley View Market, 107 W. Lincoln Ave.   A store clerk thought the check was fraudulent and called the police, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Hernandez</ENAMEX>. Officers arrived within minutes and found <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> running from the market through the Apex winery property. He was chased down on foot by two police officers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Police</ENAMEX> said the check at first looked to be good, however upon closer examination officers determined the check to be a fake. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>'s identification was also fake, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> was booked into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail on charges of forgery, criminal impersonation and resisting arrest. He is expected to be arraigned in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Superior Court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> said store owners should be on the lookout for more fake checks. It is believed that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> had an accomplice driving a blue <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990s</TIMEX> model Windstar van. The van left when officers arrived on scene to apprehend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX>.      
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

