


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> campaign rolling
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Boosted by a recent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> campaign contribution by Republican boosters, incumbent mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> looks to have considerable momentum entering into the final weeks of his campaign for re-election.
</P>
<P ID="5">By comparison, challenger John Torch has raised only <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$33,000</NUMEX> and spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,634</NUMEX>.  Since the recent Starbucks scandal, Torch has all but disappeared from the mayor race.
</P>
<P ID="6">Although no independent campaign committees have registered with city yet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, it's likely they'll swing into action before the season is finished. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League of Women</ENAMEX> voters president <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally Partridge</ENAMEX> promises their organization will also mount an aggressive get-out-the-vote effort <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, targeting everyone from fence sitters to registered homeless. 
</P>








<P ID="7">Webmaster
</P><P ID="8">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




