


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> muffles the ice cream man
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The original discussion this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was to center around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> amending the city's noise ordinance. But the discussion took a 180-degree turn and quickly focused on the friendly neighborhood ice cream man.
</P><P ID="5">   The original discussion item about amending the city's noise ordinance to address unnecessary noise from vehicles stemmed from the recent discussion of illegal street racing in the community.
</P><P ID="6">   The amendment to the noise ordinance approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> calls for people to be cited for any noise from their vehicle that is frequent, repetitive or continuous and is done in conjunction with the starting, operating, repair, rebuilding or testing of any motor vehicle, motorcycle or off-highway vehicle. The noise can't disrupt people living within 50 feet of any dwelling unit. The amended noise ordinance approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has wording borrowed from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The discussion, though, quickly changed directions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>, responding from a question by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> citizen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Stevens</ENAMEX>, wanted to know what the city could do to curb the amplified music being played from mobile carts, such as ice cream vendors.
</P><P ID="8">   "Why can't they have a tinkle bell?," asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city councilman. "Then we would all be happy."
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> said his complaint has nothing to do with the cultural aspect of operating such a business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> said the amplified noise coming from these carts disrupts people in residential and business areas of town.
</P><P ID="10">   "Personally, as a resident, I vote for the tinkle bells," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said he would have to research the city ordinances a bit more to see if there was an exemption for the mobile carts to play amplified music. But, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> immediately said he would like to see amplified music from the mobile carts included in the amended noise ordinance before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> suggested city staff contact each of the mobile cart operators that would be effected by the ordinance. She further suggested publishing the information in Viva, a Spanish newspaper publication. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she was concerned the information wouldn't get out because many of the mobile cart owners don't read or speak English.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said the vendors will be warned several times before being cited by police officers, so felt there was no need to take the steps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> suggested.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> unanimously approved the amended noise ordinance to include amplified music coming from mobile carts.
</P>   






 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




