49 10 47 41 26 42
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  It seems to me that people have vast potential. Most people can do extraordinary things if they have the confidence or take the risks. Yet most people don't. They sit in front of the telly and treat life as if it goes on forever.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Adams</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>