
<P ID="1">How are you going to spoil your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>?
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/12/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Boxes of chocolates, bouquets of flowers and jewelry are all traditional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> gifts. However, there are plenty of other options open to people living in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. Tokens of how much you care can be given in the form of everything from a weekend at a local bed and breakfast to a special dinner cooked right at home.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Beck</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beck</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Co. Jewelry Design Gallery</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, jewelry is a very traditional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> gift. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> said he thinks jewelry is one gift people tend to lean towards when it comes to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> because of the strong connection between jewelry and romance. For example, when marriage is proposed it's jewelry that is used to signify the commitment.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> said in the weeks leading to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> he will sell a lot of heart shaped gemstones, usually either diamonds or rubies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> said people also come into the store looking specifically for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> charms for charm bracelets.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> said the shop also carries a variety of crystal vases, which make for nice flower arrangements. Another new twist on a traditional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> gift is a 24 carat gold rose. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> said the rose is a real flower dipped in 24 carat gold.   Flowers are another traditional <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> gift. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark and Sara Cook</ENAMEX>, owners of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris Floral</ENAMEX>, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> is the shop's biggest day of the year.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year Valentine's Day</TIMEX> was like doing a whole month's worth of business in one day," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cooks</ENAMEX> said the biggest sellers come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14</TIMEX>, are dozen and half-dozen bouquets of red roses.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara</ENAMEX> noted that there are people out there who would prefer to get something with a slightly longer life span than cut flowers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX>. She said she has had women come up to her and request that when their husbands walk through the flower shop's door that they be directed toward the potted plants.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX>, flowers and plants make good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> gifts because it makes whoever is receiving them feel special.   "Flowers make you feel good," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> added that when a person receives a bouquet of flowers they know it was made especially for them. "It brings out happiness in a person," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara</ENAMEX> finished.   Another gift that can evoke happiness in a person is the gift of chocolates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Alexander Auld</ENAMEX>, CEO of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chukar Cherry Company Inc.</ENAMEX>, said she thinks chocolate has remained an integral part of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> because it's sweet.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auld</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chukar Cherries</ENAMEX> uses dried fruit and enrobes them in natural chocolate, leaving their customer with a premium chocolate gift for the coming holiday.   "It's just really complementary," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auld</ENAMEX> said of the combination of dried fruits and chocolate.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auld</ENAMEX> said some popular gift items <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Valentine's Day</TIMEX> have included the company's cabernet chocolate cherries, which feature a red tart cherry covered in semi-sweet chocolate; black forest chocolate cherries, which are bing cherries covered in semi-sweet chocolate and dusted with cocoa powder; and chocolate honey roasted pecan, which are honey roasted pecans covered in milk chocolate.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Auld</ENAMEX> said, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chukar Cherries</ENAMEX> also offers some <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>'s gift ideas to satisfy a dieter's sweet tooth. She said the company offers everything from naturally dried <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rainier</ENAMEX> cherries to a cherry pistachio mix.   Another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX>'s idea that combines chocolate with the tastes of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> is the ninth annual An Intimate Red Wine and Chocolate Affair, which benefits <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hospice</ENAMEX>.   Lyla Wandling of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hospice</ENAMEX> said the event, set to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 13</TIMEX>, will give those in attendance a chance to taste different red wines offered by local wineries, as well as different chocolate confections, which will make up the ultimate chocolate judgment. The judgment is a contest featuring chocolate desserts made by area chefs.   Wandling said the event will also include music from an area jazz band, as well a small silent auction.   The Intimate Red Wine and Chocolate Affair also serves as the kick-off for the annual Yakima Valley Red Wine and Chocolate weekend, which brings wine tasters from all over the state to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> to taste different red wines, alongside chocolate treats.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Tucker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tucker Cellars</ENAMEX> said the association of red wine and chocolate seems to be increasing in popularity, and he thinks a lot of has to do with the romance associated with both items.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Cellars</ENAMEX> offers 13 different wine varieties, and is planning on releasing a new port, a sweet red wine, for the coming event. He said the winery will also be serving chocolate truffles.   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said wine can make an excellent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> gift in and of itself, adding that he typically sees a lot of sweet white wines purchased this time of year, although he noted that he also sees a good number of dry red wines being sold.   "People have a lot of different palates," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said, noting that there is no telling exactly which wines will be popular as gifts. "No two palates are the same," he said.   Another local winery gearing up for the Red Wine and Chocolate weekend is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tefft Cellars</ENAMEX> in Outlook. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tefft Cellars</ENAMEX> offers visitors a different way to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX>. Located near the winery is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Inn</ENAMEX>, a bed and breakfast featuring three bedrooms, a working kitchen and a living room space. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian McKee</ENAMEX>, general manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tefft Cellars</ENAMEX>, said the bed and breakfast features a wine theme and is only rented out to one party at a time. This means that regardless of whether you use one bedroom or all three, you will have the entire bed and breakfast to yourself.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKee</ENAMEX> said the house was remodeled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last winter</TIMEX>, with each of the three bedrooms now featuring its own bathroom.   "It's a home away from home," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKee</ENAMEX> said. He noted that the deck extending out from the house can serve as a romantic place to share a bottle of wine and watch the sunset over the neighboring vineyard.   For those people who are interested in spending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> weekend a little farther from home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dottie Cervantes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Travel Connection</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> said there are plenty of places a couple can visit together.   "Because it falls on the weekend a lot of people want to do a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Coast</ENAMEX> package," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said, which can include traveling anywhere from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rocky Mountains</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific</ENAMEX> coastline.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said when planning a romantic getaway for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> the most important thing is making sure you're spending the time with someone special, where you go comes second.   "For some parents just getting away from the kids is good," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said.   Those people who don't necessarily want to find a baby-sitter for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> can bring the romance of the holiday home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori Charvet</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Countryside Catering</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> said creating a special dinner at home can be as easy as cooking your sweetheart's favorite dish and serving it on your best china. She said adding stemware and good silver can also help lend a more romantic feel to any meal.   For those who want to create a special meal without taking gourmet cooking classes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> suggested starting with dessert. She said dessert can be as easy as baking a chocolate cake, then serving it topped with pie cherries, whipped cream and chocolate syrup.   For those who feel more comfortable in the kitchen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> suggested cooking a pork tenderloin served with an apple chutney.   However, just because dinner is served at home doesn't mean people can come to the table dressed casually. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said it can be nice to dress up for dinner at home. She also added that serving dinner at home also means that things can go at your own pace. There can be time to linger over dessert and share appetizers before the main course.   "Make it a two-hour meal," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Beach</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> offers a variety of ways to make your <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX> feel special, from full body massages to pedicures and tanning, the local business offers a bit of everything.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Dalrymple</ENAMEX>, manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Beach</ENAMEX>, said the shop houses a massage therapist, tanning beds, an exercise room, a gift shop and a full service salon, as well as espresso. She said gift certificates can be purchased for just about any service the shop offers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cathy Hunsaker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scissor City</ENAMEX>, the salon housed at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Electric Beach</ENAMEX>, said receiving a gift certificate for a pedicure or a haircut can make anyone feel special.   "It makes that special person feel wonderful," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunsaker</ENAMEX> said.   Those people looking for more traditional ways to show their <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX> how much they care can find everything from candles to picture frames at the Funny Farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX>, owner of the Funny Farm, said the shop offers a little of everything. She said in the past few days women have been coming into the shop picking up little gifts for their husbands, including everything from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valentine</ENAMEX> coupon books to gift packs of quality liquor.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said men coming into the shop have been looking at everything from boxes of chocolates to candles.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said one of the most important things she offers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> is a wide variety of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> cards.   "A card is an important thing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

