
<P ID="1">Zillah resident newest addition to farm network
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/28/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University Farm Family Support Network</ENAMEX> has been helping farm families throughout the state, acting as an impartial third party and helping families tackle different issues that come down the pike.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Rodionoff</ENAMEX>, coordinator of the Farm Family Support Network based out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX>, said the organization helps farm families work through business stresses, meet their business goals and helps them understand both their financial and family situation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodionoff</ENAMEX> said although the Farm Family Support Network is based out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX>, the 10 consultants that work for the organization are located throughout the state. He said in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> the Network has worked to help a local farm family create a cash flow estimate for fruit crop production that they could then take to a bank to help them get approved for a loan. He said the Network also helped a local farmer by simply offering a third party opinion on his farming operation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodionoff</ENAMEX> said sometimes all that is needed is for an impartial third party to come in and look at a farm operation, noting that sometimes it can be better than simply relying on neighbors and relatives' opinions.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodionoff</ENAMEX> said the 10 consultants that work for the Farm Family Support Network work on a part-time, on-call basis, with each of the consultants working out of their homes. He noted that when consultants meet with farmers they typically meet at the farm they will be analyzing.   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, the organization recently hired <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Hurlburt</ENAMEX> to work as a consultant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodionoff</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX>, who lives on his family farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>, has an extensive financial background, having worked previously as an accountant, and experience working with farm families. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX> said he is currently a full-time apple farmer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodionoff</ENAMEX> said one of the reasons <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX> was hired to work as a consultant for the Farm Family Support Network is because the organization needed a consultant who could be stationed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX> said one of the reasons he decided to apply for the consulting position is because being a farmer himself and having worked as an accountant, he felt it would be a good match for his skills. He said it's also nice to be able to lend a helping hand to families in stress. He said as a consultant he is able to help connect farm families with different resources that can help them get through tough situations. In essence, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX> said, it's like problem solving.   "We help give them the tools to fix it themselves," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX> said.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodionoff</ENAMEX>, when farm families in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> contact the organization, the organization in turn will contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX> about the family. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hurlburt</ENAMEX> will then contact the family and set up a time to meet with them.   Each of the consultants working through the Farm Family Support Network undergo training by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> extension office, helping them understand different aspects of the changing agricultural industry. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodionoff</ENAMEX>, consultants also work to familiarize themselves with different organizations and services that could benefit local farm families.   Farm Family Support Network is an organization that is funded through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture Risk Management Agency</ENAMEX>. The organization offers its services at no cost to farm families and the program is confidential. For more information about the Farm Family Support Network call 1-800-469-2981.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

