


<P ID="1">Blanket primary eliminated in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/24/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> declined to review a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Circuit Court</ENAMEX> decision that declared <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state's blanket primary unconstitutional.
</P><P ID="4">   Because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ninth Circuit Court</ENAMEX> decision wasn't over-ruled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state must now change the primary election process it has used for nearly 70 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> voters have been allowed to vote for whichever candidate they wanted, regardless of political affiliation or political seat sought by a candidate.
</P><P ID="5">   The appeal to the blanket primary ruling had been filed by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX>, a firm believer in the long standing blanket primary that allows voters to cast their ballots according to conscience and belief, rather than tradition or political history. Because <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX>'s petition was denied by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>, the state legislature must now come up with an alternative to the blanket primary.
</P><P ID="6">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>'s decision to not review the case pleased the state's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> leadership. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Republican Party</ENAMEX> Chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Vance</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> will continue to work with Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> and the legislature to craft an open primary law "...that respects the civil rights of the members of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s political parties and encourages maximum voter participation in the nomination of our candidates."
</P><P ID="7">   But not all parties in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state were pleased that the appeal to the ruling striking down the state's blanket primary wasn't considered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Grange</ENAMEX> members, who along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX> and other groups started the blanket primary back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> with a proposed initiative to the state legislature, voiced its displeasure.
</P><P ID="8">   "We feel that the appellate courts have overlooked significant differences between the primary statutes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and those in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">State Grange</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Hunt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "But we're not unprepared," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>. "We've also been talking with legislators and letting them know that they don't have to give the political parties control over the primary in this state."
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> explained that the legislature can adopt a "qualifying primary," in which the top two candidates, regardless of party, move to the general election. He said candidates for state office and the legislature could still have their party preferences designated on the ballot. Voters would be able to vote for any candidate for each office, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>, as they have for 70 years under the blanket primary.
</P><P ID="11">   "We believe this will hold up to any constitutional attacks the political parties try to hit us with through the courts," explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "We're not about to turn over control of the election process to the (political) parties. If the legislature, for any reason, is unable to come to a consensus about changing the primary, we're prepared to move forward with our initiative," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunt</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   The "People's Choice" initiative (I-872) was filed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Grange</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, and would implement a "top two" primary in which voters would not be required to declare party affiliation at any stage in the election process.
</P><P ID="14">   In learning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX> had decided not to hear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed</ENAMEX>'s appeal, the Washington State Senate Republican caucus announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> it will work quickly to restore the state's primary election system.
</P><P ID="15">   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, we are at an historical crossroad as the legislature looks for an alternative to the blanket primary," said Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Roach</ENAMEX> (R-Auburn), chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> Government Operations and Elections Committee</ENAMEX>. "Legislators are uniquely positioned for this upcoming debate. We know what the people want and we know what the court demands."
</P>   






 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




