
<P ID="1">Burglars strike in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">GRANDVIEW - Two <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> businesses were busy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> repairing broken windows and doors after would-be thieves attempted burglaries in two different parts of town.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> police officers investigated a burglary at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dave's Recycling Center</ENAMEX>, located in the 800 block of Dykstra Lane, where they found a door had been kicked in to gain entrance into the center's office. The burglary was discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> weekend.   According to the police report, nothing was discovered missing.   Meantime across town, burglars broke a window to gain entry into Highway Tire Store in the 100 block of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>.   Taken was an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> in change, according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> police report.   Although there were a number of tools visible at the tire shop, only the money was taken, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

