
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> awarded <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> grant for wastewater treatment plant upgrades
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> grant for improving the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> wastewater treatment plant has been adopted as a part of the Omnibus Appropriations funding measure.   Republicans and Democrats joined to break a filibuster and approve the final appropriations measure for the fiscal year, which began almost <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four months ago</TIMEX>. The measure has since been signed by President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> was among the lawmakers that voted in favor of the measure.   "Like many, I had serious reservations about several provisions in the omnibus appropriations bill. The fight to overturn the attack on overtime and other issues is not over. But I know what's at stake here and it is time to move on," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, a senior member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Appropriations Committee</ENAMEX>. "I voted to fund our federal responsibility to education, health care, job training and veterans. And I vote to help our state as it seeks to move forward with job creation and economic development."   The funds that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will be receiving is the largest amount going to a single <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> community. The funds were sought by former city manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>.   "It will be used for the wastewater treatment plant upgrade," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Engineer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bridges</ENAMEX>. "It determines the amount we need to borrow."   Currently, the project is estimated to cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12.3 million</NUMEX>, which will pay for the complete project from design through construction.   The project is expected to be completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2007</TIMEX>.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX>, the grant, which is money that doesn't have to be paid back, will assist in lowering the amount of money the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will have to borrow in the form of a loan.   Borrowing less money will help moderate rate increases for low-income wastewater users, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>.   The money will be used to bring the wastewater treatment plant up to compliance with federal water quality standards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said it will include the addition of an activated sludge basin, upgrades to the primary clarifiers and adding a redundancy system, which would make it so the city wouldn't be out of compliance if there is a problem with the wastewater treatment plant.   The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12 million</NUMEX> will also pay for upgrades to miscellaneous equipment, such as pumps.   Currently, the city's waiting on approval of an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX> loan though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Works Trust Fund</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX>. The city is also applying for a loan from the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> of Ecology revolving fund. The loan is for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> of the project.   "We don't have to accept either loan," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX>, adding that the city can also continue to seek other grants though the wastewater renovation process.   With the loans, the earliest the money would be available is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said he hopes the federal grant funding will be available sooner.   The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> could accelerate the project and a consultant could be hired sooner than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> with the money.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said the city will have to hire a consultant to complete the design work for the project.   "I'm already in the process of completing the environmental documents for the federal funding," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX>, a requirement for the funding.   Other projects funded under the Omnibus Appropriations bill are the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter Clore Wine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culinary Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, which received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX>. Also, funds (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX>) were provided to renovate a home for pregnant teens in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tri Cities</ENAMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> was set aside for the state methamphetamine program.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

