


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> Grizzlies beat <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> to reclaim Apple Bowl trophy
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - The questions flew back and forth. The buzzer rang under the hot studio lights as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Grizzlies</ENAMEX> confidently set out to reclaim the coveted Apple Bowl trophy for the fourth time in Apple Bowl history this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The five-member academic team, led by high school advisor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Thomas</ENAMEX>, beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley Apple Bowl</ENAMEX> team with a score of 295-215 in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> championship finals.
</P><P ID="6">   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> KYVE Apple Bowl finals were televised <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 22</TIMEX>, from the television studios on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX> campus.
</P><P ID="7">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> team handily beat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s defending champions, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley Rams</ENAMEX>, in the 24th finals of the popular high school quiz competition, which is produced by KYVE television in collaboration with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Team members <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Barr</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Kilian</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> all took turns fielding questions about science, English, history and math and a variety of miscellaneous topics. The all-senior Grizzly team earned the right to advance to the championships by beating out teams from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">La Salle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> high schools early in the season, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   As their reward, the team brought home the Apple Bowl trophy, which will be on display in the high school business office for several days before taking up a prominent spot in the school trophy case.
</P><P ID="10">   In addition, the team will split a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> savings bond five ways, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, who is in his second year of coaching the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> team. They also received medals to keep and t-shirts for taking part in the competition.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>, who previously coached the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School Apple Bowl</ENAMEX> team, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> group knows a lot about a variety of topics.
</P><P ID="12">   "They are a sharp group," he added.
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




