
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> approves purchase of portable classroom
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - In an effort to gain space for extra classrooms, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School Board</ENAMEX> approved the purchase of a portable unit during this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>'s board meeting.   The new unit will add two classrooms to the campus at the Mabton Jr.-Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> building, giving math teachers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Fleming</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Durham</ENAMEX> regular classrooms, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Morris</ENAMEX>, high school principal. He said both teachers are currently using non-classroom facilities within the district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fleming</ENAMEX>'s makeshift classroom is located within a room near the district bus garage and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Durham</ENAMEX> is now utilizing the district board room as a classroom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> said the addition of staff and additional enrollment led to the need for extra classroom space. He said the new portable classroom will be used for junior high and high school math class instruction.   The addition of the two classrooms will cost the district an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>. She said the cost also includes such things as setting the unit upon a new foundation, and electrical and water needs.   The unit will be situated at the south end of the high school parking lot and should be ready for use 10 weeks after the unit is ordered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said.   In other action taken at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 25</TIMEX> meeting, the board approved a safe school/healthy students agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Services District</ENAMEX> 105. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said the agreement will provide case management services to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>. The case manager will be housed in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> and will work full time with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> students.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

