
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RUBY BELLE MURPHY
RUBY BELLE MURPHY
Ruby Belle Murphy</ENAMEX>, 93, long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> resident, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 10, 2004</TIMEX>, at Prosser Memorial Nursing Home.  
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 4</TIMEX>, 1911in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Effie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ackerman</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur VanWye</ENAMEX>. She received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and graduated with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX>.  Following her education she went to work for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> newspaper and later for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Fruit</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.  On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12, 1942</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson Murphy</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. They lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, and later moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, where she worked as a welder in the shipyards.  She returned to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> and made her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> in the early 1980’s, where she made her home until the time of her death.  
She is survived by one daughter, Mary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; step-daughter, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> Dettbarn of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; three grandchildren; three step-children; and five great-grandchildren.
She was preceded in death by her parents; her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson Murphy</ENAMEX>; one brother; and two sisters.
 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial</ENAMEX> services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, May 14, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Church</ENAMEX> of the Nazarene.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PATTY CLARICE MORROW
Patty Clarice Morrow</ENAMEX>, 90, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>, beloved wife, mother and grandmother, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, May 6, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> Terrace in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 16, 1913</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bloomfield</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jefferson and Hallie Hutchings</ENAMEX>. She graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930</TIMEX> after advancing a grade.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 19, 1936</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty C. Hutchings</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul O. Morrow</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. They celebrated their 67th wedding anniversary in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2003</TIMEX>. She was a homemaker for much of her married life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> worked along side her husband helping operate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Tent & Awning, then on Yakima Valley Highway, from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1959</TIMEX> until they sold the business and retired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> enjoyed the family camping and fishing trips, especially those that included the three grandsons. Her sense of humor sparked those family gatherings, where she was among the first to laugh and enjoy stories and games. She was an avid gardener, and the resulting roses and other flowers were a familiar sight for 22 years at the Morrow’s home along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Crescent</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> was a busy time in the kitchen, where she preserved what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> grew in the vegetable garden. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> was an accomplished seamstress. She spent years of leisure time crocheting afghans for family members. Every time we snuggle under one of your creations, Mother and Grandma, we will feel the love that went into it. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> were both enthusiastic supporters of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> athletics and rarely missed a football or basketball game.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat</ENAMEX> was a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>, where she played an active roll in the United Methodist Women and on church committees. She served as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UMW</ENAMEX> treasurer and as a church financial secretary for 30 years.
</P><P ID="5">  She is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Galbraith</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Thompson</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Rosa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> Also surviving are her sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daisy Dent</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mesa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ariz.</ENAMEX>; three grandsons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Thompson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Windsor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sean Thompson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Forest Hills</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.Y</ENAMEX>. and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Galbraith</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
She was preceded in death by her parents, and two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleo Hutchings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clara Groenig</ENAMEX>.
Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, May 14, 2004</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, followed by a memorial service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor Pat’s memory may contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Memorial Home Care Services</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospice</ENAMEX>). Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

