
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> focuses on how a national news story can affect a small town
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: 
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23, 2003</TIMEX> is a date that will always carry a certain amount of significance for the residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, many of whom earn their living in the dairy and cattle industries.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, representatives from the local media, along with several members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> community, gathered at the Silver Dollar restaurant in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> to talk about how the discovery of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>), or mad cow disease, at a dairy farm near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> affected the community and those members of the media who regularly cover the area. The forum, titled "Mad Cow: Not a Black and White Issue," was presented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William O. Douglas</ENAMEX> chapter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Professional Journalists</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPJ</ENAMEX>).   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Isaacs</ENAMEX>, president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William O. Douglas</ENAMEX> chapter of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SPJ</ENAMEX>, told the 22 people in attendance, which included a mix of area reporters, community members and representatives from the local dairy and cattle industries, that the focus of the forum was to discuss how a world-side story affects a local community after the satellite trucks have left town.   Panel members for the forum included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Jenkins</ENAMEX>, editor of the Yakima Herald; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Darigol</ENAMEX>, news director for KNDO television, an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NBC</ENAMEX> affiliate based in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Silver Dollar</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Chester</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaDon Linde</ENAMEX>, vice president of the Washington State Dairy Federation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darigol</ENAMEX> both said the announcement that a suspected case of mad cow disease had been found in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> came at a time when news is traditionally slow, and when many people in the industry take time off to be with family for the holidays. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said as soon as the announcement was made everyone at the newspaper knew they had a challenge in front of them.   "We just knew it was going to be a tough story to cover," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darigol</ENAMEX> said the same thoughts rippled through his newsroom.   "We realized immediately that this was a huge story and an important story," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darigol</ENAMEX> said.   But, before reporters could be sent out to gather information, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darigol</ENAMEX> explained that there were some tough decisions that would have to be made.   "We tried to give to the viewer what we thought would be most important to them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darigol</ENAMEX> said. "We wanted to present the facts as fast as we could find them."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said the Yakima Herald staff knew that the barrage of media coverage on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> would be part of the story they told, but they also knew that it meant they would be competing with a variety of other news sources on the story. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said the newspaper knew it would have to keep its stories as local as possible.   "This was not a story about cows, it was a story about people," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said.   She said for 11 days following the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX> announcement the Yakima Herald ran locally written stories about the mad cow issue on the front page, then on day 12 the paper switched over to running a mix of locally written stories and stories written by members of the national media. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said the mad cow issue stayed on the front page for 26 days.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX>, a local dairyman, the announcement that a suspected case of mad cow disease had been found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> brought with it an entirely different experience. He said he remembers getting a phone call from his brother in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> telling him about the discovery and what had been on the news. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said it wasn't more than an hour later that he began receiving calls from members of the media looking for comments on the discovery.   However, reporters weren't the only people calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX>. He said other dairy and cattle farmers were calling, asking what they should do about the reporters and satellite trucks that were beginning to gather outside their farms.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said one of the largest concerns the industry felt, was what all of the media coverage would mean for the cattle and dairy markets. In the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> said he feels that it's a tribute to how the media handled the issue and how the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> worked to get information out that the discovery didn't become a disaster for the industry.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said when the announcement was made and the media began to descend on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, many residents in the community turned to city hall and the mayor for information about what was happening.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said looking back on the events following the discovery, there was a definite difference between the national media attention and the way the local media covered the story.   "The local media focused on the effects of the national media," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester</ENAMEX>, manager of the Silver Dollar, also dealt with the media in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. However, she dealt with them on a different level. She explained that the community restaurant ended up serving as a place for reporters to hang out between press conferences and national announcements.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester</ENAMEX> said when she heard news about the discovery of mad cow disease, she didn't think much of it. It wasn't until she was heading to work the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">next morning</TIMEX> to start making breakfast at the restaurant that she figured out just what the announcement meant. She said as she turned the corner to go to the restaurant she was bombarded by a wall of light, even though it was still dark outside. The light was from the cameras of the different news trucks that had rolled in over night.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester</ENAMEX> said that first day her customers were made up mostly of members of the media. The dairymen who usually come in for breakfast were suspiciously missing, she added.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester</ENAMEX> explained that serving as the hub for members of the media meant that she got to know the men and women behind the questions in a different way.   "I got to make a connection with the media, a different connection," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester</ENAMEX> said. "I got to know them."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chester</ENAMEX> said in the months since the discovery things in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and at the Silver Dollar have slowly returned to normal.   Despite the national media having left <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darigol</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenkins</ENAMEX> said it's important for the local media to continue to follow the story.   "We do want to keep following it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darigol</ENAMEX> said.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

