
<P ID="1">Grandview campus to host fall job fair
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> will host a job fair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 10</TIMEX>, for students interested in applying for work in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   The event will be held in the campus student lounge from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>   Students should bring resumes and all the information they may need to fill out an employment application.   Local Wal-Mart and Safeway stores will have representatives on site to answer questions and help students seeking employment find opportunities for work within their community.   Wal-Mart is looking to hire as many as 200 new employees by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>, according to Grandview YVCC Campus Dean Claude Dotson.   "This is a great opportunity for our students," he said.   For more information about this event, contact the YVCC Grandview campus at 882-7000.      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library plans <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> storytime, party   Plan your pumpkin carving now, urges <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Public Librarian Kay Saunders</ENAMEX>. "But save the actual carving to coincide with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Library's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> jack-o'lantern carving contest," she said.   The contest, which will offer prizes for the best carvings, will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 29</TIMEX>, at the library, 621 Grant Ave., from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX>   In addition to pumpkin carving, a special story time will be held and a magician is scheduled make an appearance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX> said.         
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

