


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> should be able to use new fire truck by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of April</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Fire Chief Jim Stanton reported to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on the status of the city's new fire truck.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> reported that the city should have access to the fire truck purchased in partnership with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of April</TIMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="7">Police department earns accolades
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> extended words of congratulations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the police department had received a letter from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Bureau of Investigations</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> was instrumental in capturing a subject who has eluded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="10">King holiday to be on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX> agenda
</P>

<P ID="11">At the request of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Councilwoman Jennie Angel, a discussion concerning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> holiday will be on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX> agenda.
</P>

<P ID="12">The city doesn't currently recognized <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Martin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Luther King Jr. Day</TIMEX> as a paid holiday for city staff. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> wants to have the discussion to have the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> holiday recognized by the city.
</P>

 


<P ID="13">City staff to check on annual spring clean-up event
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> requested at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting to have city staff look into whether there will be the annual spring clean-up day.
</P>

<P ID="15">The annual spring clean-up day is held in conjunction with Yakima Waste Systems. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents are able to dispose of waste and other materials free of charge.
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said he would get in contact with Yakima Waste Systems about the status of the event and come back with a report to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="17">Seeger in charge of 'Spirit' awards
</P>

<P ID="18">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> placed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> in charge of organizing the annual Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> awards.
</P>

<P ID="19">The Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> awards are handed out during the community's annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> celebration.
</P>

<P ID="20"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said the awards recognize past, living and youth pioneers in the community. He was hoping to have nominations submitted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




