
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/20/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> offers driver’s edclasses in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> will offer driver's ed training classes, beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>.
Sign-ups are ongoing now, by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> at 894-4951. The cost to enroll is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> for students living within the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$275</NUMEX> for those who reside outside the district boundaries.
The driver's ed classes will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from June 1 through the end of July</TIMEX>, on Tuesdays, Thursdays and Saturdays. The classes will be held from 5:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> the first week, with classroom hours switching to 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 10</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4">After-school soccer campon tap <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1-4</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> is offering an after-school soccer camp <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1-4</TIMEX> for kids in kindergarten through sixth grade.
Open to both boys and girls, the camp will be held from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX> each of the four days at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> soccer fields.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Camp</ENAMEX> directors will be <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> soccer coaches <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Pineda</ENAMEX>, Artemio Rodriguez and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Jolliff</ENAMEX>.
Registration forms are currently available at the local parks and rec office. There is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> fee to attend the four-day camp.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

