
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">Obits.0721
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">IGNACIO CISNEROS
Ignacio Cisneros</ENAMEX>, 54, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 15, 2004</TIMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 11, 1950</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio and Maria Elena (Cervantes) Cisneros</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, and later made his home in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio</ENAMEX> worked for various farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> and for Independence Foods.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio</ENAMEX> enjoyed fishing, playing pool, listening to music and most of all spending time with his grandsons.
He attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ignacio</ENAMEX> is survived by eight children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Criscelia Valenzuela</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reynaldo</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Cisneros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esmerelda Cisneros</ENAMEX>, Elizet Rodriguez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Cisneros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selena Cisneros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Cisneros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremiah Cisneros</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; five grandchildren; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fidel Ortega</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; and two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esperanza Cisneros</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juana Godinez</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his parents; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwardo Cisneros</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia Ortega</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Ortega</ENAMEX>.
Recitation of the Holy Rosary will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 22, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 23, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BARBARA A. MILLER
Barbara</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobbie</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. Miller</ENAMEX>, 78, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 18, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 30, 1925</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ind.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harold</ENAMEX> and Teckla Swanson.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20, 1948</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert A. Miller</ENAMEX> in Seattle.
She was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corp League</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redeemer Lutheran Church</ENAMEX>.
She is survived by her sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Miller</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheryl</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Miller</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sandpoint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Miller</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Tegner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Anderson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Manzanita</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; four grandchildren; and numerous nieces and nephews.
She was preceded in death by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September, 2000</TIMEX>.
A memorial service was held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, July 21, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Redeemer Lutheran Church</ENAMEX>, 3606 S. Schafer Rd., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>. Memorial contributions may be made to Toys for Tots.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RONNIE SHIFFLETT
Ronnie Shifflett</ENAMEX>, 54, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 16, 2004</TIMEX>, due to injuries sustained in an accident.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 22, 1949</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sweetwater</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dessie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wyatt</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shifflett</ENAMEX>. He never completed school and instead started working in the fields as a child. He always talked about going back to school to further his life. He was an evangelist for many years, traveling with his uncles. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> he renewed his minister’s license after stepping away for many years. He traveled to many places in his earlier years, singing at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake</ENAMEX> of the Ozarks with various famous singers and musicians, holding tent revivals and working to help his family.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14, 1980</TIMEX> he and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Lipe</ENAMEX> were married in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Peoria</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ariz.</ENAMEX> They met while tying onions in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>. They moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>, where they chose to make their home. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie</ENAMEX> always joked he didn’t like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, he liked the people but didn’t care for the town. He was always kidding that the Lord had brought him to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as a punishment. He did enjoy each moment spent with people though.
He was a kind person who talked to everyone near him. He didn’t know a stranger. He enjoyed kids and flagging at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>. Just a few months ago he received a Golden Apple Award from the school district and a bike was donated to him by the school and Wal-Mart. He was grateful and loved showing off his Golden Apple Award and the bike was a joy in his life every day he had the opportunity to ride it. He also loved playing his guitar and ministering to the lost. He was a great father and husband, who can never be replaced.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronnie</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Shifflett</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; his first wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva Miller</ENAMEX>; three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tessie Hubbard</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Missouri</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shifflett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn Shifflett</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shifflett</ENAMEX>, Jr. and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Violet</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Yeatman</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clint</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>; many uncles, aunts, nieces and nephews; and one grandchild, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonas Hubbard</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Shifflett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dessie</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Odell Baird</ENAMEX>; one aunt; and one uncle.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 23, 2004</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Hills Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 26, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornerstone Assembly</ENAMEX>, 400 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Ave.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens.
Memorials are suggested to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cornerstone Assembly</ENAMEX> for the Shifflett Family, P.O. Box  149, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98944.
Roses are red, violets are blue, the sky is grey, dark and we can’t believe it’s true. Everyone is grieving we <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> you so much, Dad, we wish you could tell us what to do. We need your advice and guidance. You were taken away too soon. So many emotions are running through all bottled up inside. We need you and know we didn’t say it enough, but we love you. We wish this was just a bad dream and you would come and comfort us soon, but this nightmare is reality even though we don’t want to believe it's true. So if you’re looking down touch our shoulders, tell us you’re OK. We <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> you so much Dad. God be with us and you. What should we do? We feel like we let you down. Put your arms around us and tell us it isn’t true. We feel your presence and know you’re here. Tell God we still love Him even though he took you. We <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> you so much Dad, we’ll always love you.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> and CJ
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ROBERTA F. WARREN
Roberta F. Warren</ENAMEX>, 82, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 19, 2004</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Life Care Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 30, 1921</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bessie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McDaniels</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Barker</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta</ENAMEX> received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben F. Warren</ENAMEX> in Seattle. Following their marriage they made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberta</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Salvation Army</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebekah Lodge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
She is survived by two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Warren</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemarie</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Richland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Warren</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MaryEllen</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>; three grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bobby Warren</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Bartell</ENAMEX> of Auburn; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Barker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Barker</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; numerous nieces and nephews; and numerous extended family.
She was preceded in death by her parents; her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ben F. Warren</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 22, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> until time of the funeral service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Burial will be at Grandview Cemetery, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

