
<P ID="1">Dollar Tree open, sales are booming
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Since opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> shoppers have flocked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Dollar Tree on Yakima Valley Highway.   To say the shoppers' response to the new store has been "great" would be an understatement, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Switzer</ENAMEX>, who is overseeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> store's opening.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Switzer</ENAMEX> said opening sales exceeded the company's expectations. "We're very excited about that," he said.   "We've been very busy," he said.   The store, which is located in the former Staples building on Yakima Valley Highway, features name brand products for the entire family, all priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>. It also offers a variety of familiar items for the family car and the family pet. Everything from dog food to party goods are also priced at just a buck, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Switzer</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> store will celebrate its official grand opening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 12</TIMEX> through 14, with many special sales, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Switzer</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Switzer</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Speights</ENAMEX> will be the store's manager once he completes training. The store employees 40 people and is open seven days a week.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Dollar Tree is the national chain's fourth store in the region, with similar stores located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>. The Dollar Tree company boasts 2,500 stores across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

