
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Harvest Dancefor senior citizens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 3</TIMEX>
Floor stomping country music, to be performed by local musician <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Holden</ENAMEX> and his friends, will entertain those who attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s Harvest Dance.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>, in conjunction with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School VICA Club</ENAMEX>, will host the fourth annual Harvest Dance on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 3</TIMEX>. The 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 p.m.</TIMEX> social event will again be staged at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> gym.
There is no cost to those 50 years of age and older who attend, plus free refreshments and beverages will be provided.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Pfeifers in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YAKIMA - One</ENAMEX> of Gospel music's most popular artists, The Pfeifers, will be featured in concert at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima's Stone Church</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 16</TIMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
Since organizing more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a decade ago</TIMEX>, The Pfeifers have enjoyed much success nationally and internationally. Their performance venues have included such locations as Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jerry Falwell's Thomas Road Baptist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynchburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Va.</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mickey Gilley Theatre</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Branson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX> The group also currently has a "Top 20" release with its song, "Father's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>."
The musical group has also enjoyed appearances on the Nashville Network's "Primetime Country" and Trinity Broadcasting Network's "Praise the Lord" programs. In addition, the band's weekly television program, "The Pfeifers - Lifting Jesus," is delivered into homes across the country via 20 TV stations and two satellite feeds.
Promoters say the group's unique ability to combine exceptional vocal harmonies with brass instrumentation, along with complete lighting and video presentations, creates musical excitement that is appealing to all ages.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fair</ENAMEX> entries can be turned in as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - You've canned and quilted your fingers to the bone, and now you'd like to be recognized for all your hard work. Why not enter your quilt or preserved food items into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fair</ENAMEX> officials begin accepting all quilt and food preservation entries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 10</TIMEX>. Entries can also be submitted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 11</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> These entries include both the youth and open class divisions.
Exhibitors wanting to enter their quilts or food preservation items can enter the fairgrounds through gate 3.
Entries into the sewing, crafts and ceramics divisions will be taken on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Sept. 17</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, and again on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> Entry to the fairgrounds will be possible through gates 3 or 15 on both days.
Photography, fine arts and woodcarving entries are scheduled to be received on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 18-19</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>
Baked goods entries will be received <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Sept. 20</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> Exhibitors who enter the baked goods division or food preservation category will have the chance to win the coveted title of "Queen/King of the Kitchen," a new contest sponsored by Bon Macy's. The contest is for exhibitors who enter at least 10 food classes. Judges will give points for first, second and third places, and the person with the most points will win the title and an Artesian mixer from Kitchenaid.
Fruits and vegetables and other field crop entries will be taken <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 22</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> and on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
Flowers may be entered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>, between 4 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> All floral entries should be taken to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> building through gate 10.
For more information on entering an item into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fair go on-line to the web site: www.fairfun.com. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s fair opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 24</TIMEX> and runs through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6">‘Wine Country Polo’ event set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18-19</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WHITE SWAN</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents are being invited to catch the excitement when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>'s wineries combine with the heart-stopping action of galloping polo ponies. Promoters promise a festive weekend for both long-time polo enthusiasts and those experiencing the thrill of polo for the first time.
The weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18-19</TIMEX>, some of the best players from throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> will face off for "Wine Country Polo." The two-day tournament will be held at the polo field near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Swan</ENAMEX> (2280 Barkes Rd.). The event is expected to attract between 300 and 500 people.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, patrons will have the opportunity to enjoy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> wines as they cheer their favorite teams to victory.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s tournament, though, isn't just about polo and wines. It is an important fund-raising event, benefiting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Partners Habitat</ENAMEX> for Humanity. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Habitat</ENAMEX> for Humanity group is preparing to build its 100th home in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.
The cost to attend both days of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18-19</TIMEX> event is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> per person, which includes lunch by Classic Events Catering. One-day attendance is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45</NUMEX>. Event wine glasses will be available for tasting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> wines, and bottles will be available for purchase, as well.
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

