
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/29/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Car washfund-raiserset for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 8</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> student <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Elerding</ENAMEX> will hold a fund-raising car wash <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 8</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Wal-Mart store from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
Monies raised from donations will be used to fund his trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Australia</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sports Tours USA</ENAMEX> team to play soccer. Elerding's overseas trip is planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July of this year</TIMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

