
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> commissionersto meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port District</ENAMEX> commissioners will hold a specially called meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 21</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
The commissioners are scheduled to meet in executive session to discuss the possible sale and purchase of real estate. They estimate they'll be in executive session, which is closed to the public, for about an hour. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s meeting will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Port</ENAMEX> administration</ENAMEX> office on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Seventh Street</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX> team leader
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">PULLMAN - Amanda Martinez</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> graduate, has been appointed to the position of team leader for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX>'s Cougar Connector program.
A junior, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> is studying hospitality and business management at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pullman</ENAMEX> university.
The Cougar Connectors are an elite group of student ambassadors chosen for their positions because of their ability to communicate effectively with prospective students during campus tours.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

