
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jazz teacher scores high at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX> dance contest
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A 17-hour cross country road trip with three small boys would have been enough exertion for most young mothers, but not for energetic <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristine Gimlin</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. She not only made the trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>, she donned dance shoes to compete against more than 500 hip hop dancers.   Like her fellow dancers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlim</ENAMEX> was competing for Monster of Hip Hop dance scholarships and other honors at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> contest, held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 24-25</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlim</ENAMEX>, who teaches jazz classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin School of Dance</ENAMEX>, earned the right to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denver</ENAMEX> contest while competing in a national hip hop contest in Seattle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>.   The petite dancer not only competed, she placed among the top 20 dancers performing at the contest. The ranking earned her an invitation to advance to yet another national contest, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin School of Dance</ENAMEX> owner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Martin</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX>'s employer and mentor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> has been invited to audition at the Monster Hip Hop contest to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orlando</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fla.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 14-15</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> was spotted by national talent scouts while dancing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Westlake Dance Center</ENAMEX> in Seattle, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denver</ENAMEX> contest was really rough.   "I thought the Seattle Monster contest was tough, but it was nothing like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX>," she said.   "There were a lot of really talented people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX> and I was really nervous," she said.   "But I didn't give up," said the petite, young woman, who claimed she make it into the top 20 "by the skin of my teeth."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlin</ENAMEX> auditioned with more than 500 other dancers from around the nation at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> event. She said the top six dancers received scholarships to study dance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Broadway Dance Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York City</ENAMEX>. Another six dancers earned free air fare and tuition to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Orlando</ENAMEX> dance competition. "The rest of us were invited to try again, she explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gimlim</ENAMEX> said her ranking in the top 20 dancers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denver</ENAMEX> event gave her a lot of personal satisfaction.   "It means I will be able to attend future contests as a teacher. I'll be able to take my students to the hip hop contests, opening new doors for them," she explained.   "We have a lot of talented dancers here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and I want to help them go to the next level," she said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

