
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX> will let his record speak for itself in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> campaign
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/14/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">4th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> has no qualms on how he will be judged by voters come <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>) hasn't yet formally announced his candidacy for re-election, but did reveal <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> that he has every intention of seeking a sixth term to the U.S. Congress.   "I'll be running on my record of service," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, who stopped off for a short visit in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> enroute to making an appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, where he and fellow Republicans turned out to announce the formation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Farm</ENAMEX> and Ranch Leadership Team.   In confirming that he will once again be a candidate to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> voters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> campaign has already swung into high gear. Money has already been raised, he said, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>' camp is organized in all 10 counties he represents.   Why should <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> voters return <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> to the nation's capital?   Simply put-Hastings said his record of service shows he has the best interest of local residents in mind. He points with pride to his representation of the ag industry.   Most recently, he was instrumental in securing federal funding for the Black Rock Reservoir feasibility study.   "And we'll be prepared to act when the feasibility study is done," he promised.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> also was one of the key players <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> in convincing the USDA to purchase asparagus from local growers. American asparagus growers have fallen on tough times recently, because of the federal government's decision to open the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> marketplace to South American grown asparagus.   He, too, helped bail out ailing apple growers several years ago when they couldn't find a market for their crops, by convincing his fellow legislators to offer financial assistance.   Another feather was added to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>' cap when he worked successfully to get the allocation of federal funds for the market access program doubled to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200 million</NUMEX>. That program is set up to help American farmers market their crops overseas.   Agriculture isn't the only area of interest <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> has.   In terms of the clean-up at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford Nuclear Reservation</ENAMEX>, he has worked to do away with the funding spikes of the past. "I feel we've secured stable funding for the clean-up that is needed there, and in the process that has accelerated the clean-up," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> isn't shy in bringing up the citizenship bill he recently sponsored, that was eventually adopted by lawmakers and signed into law by President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>. In essence, the legislation cuts the waiting period to become an American citizen from five years to one for those who have served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> military.   "Anybody willing to put their life on the line for this country deserves to have the process speeded up to become a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> citizen," he said. "I'm very proud this bill was signed into law."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>' time in trying to get himself re-elected <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> may be limited, as he is currently serving as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state vice chairman of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> re-election campaign. He said a concentrated effort is underway to "...carry <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>." In the last Presidential election, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s electoral votes were cast for Democrat Al Gore.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>' stop-off in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> came on the heels of his recent trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. He relayed one of the messages many of the troops returning from the Mideast bring with them, that it is unfortunate the media doesn't cover the positive aspects of what the American military is doing in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Things like rebuilding schools, returning the government to the people, themselves, and opening up the worldwide information highway to the Iraqi people are all positive things that get little attention, he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said he saw for himself that the Iraqi people are craving information from the outside world, as now just about every home there sports a satellite dish.   When police stations in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> get bombed by terrorists and entire police forces are wiped out, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said more Iraqis step forward as replacements than positions that are open-another sign that the Iraqi people are in favor of what the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> is attempting to accomplish there.   "I came back with a different impression than we're getting over here," he said. "We're in a war on terrorism."   He cites the recent increase in terrorist attacks in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> to the approaching date of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>'s governing council is scheduled to take power.   Bottom line-Hastings said he stands behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s decision to involve military troops in freeing the Iraqi people from their oppressors.   All in all, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> is proud of what he has accomplished during the five Congressional terms he has served <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX>, and believes the stances he has taken is for the betterment of all.   "I certainly think it's a record I can run on," he said.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

