


<P ID="1">Lights, camera, action...Wal-Mart distribution center celebrates grand opening
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/15/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Like a Hollywood premiere, the stars of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> were out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to celebrate the grand opening of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart Distribution Center</ENAMEX> 7021. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX>, Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Byam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fourth District</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Development Association</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David McFadden</ENAMEX> were just a few of the local officials who took part in the glitzy grand opening ceremony.
</P><P ID="5">   Balloons lined the hallway, spotlights flooded the presentation stage and employees of the distribution center added to the energy that sparked through the standing room only crowd.
</P><P ID="6">   The ceremony held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> served to commemorate the opening of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> distribution center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. The grocery distribution center currently employs more than 400 people, and is designed to ship 200,000 cases on an average day. The building itself, which is large enough to house 20 football fields, is situated on 115 acres of property just off of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodall Road</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Gray</ENAMEX>, general coach of the new distribution center, helped welcome the crowd to the ceremony. He also took that time to explain one of the ideas behind <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>'s inviting work environment. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> told those in attendance that he likes to think of the distribution center as a big house and those who work in it as a large family.
</P><P ID="8">   "We're all part of it," he said, pointing to the multitude of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> employees. "It's inclusion, it's diversity. It's what we're all about."
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> noted that the employees of the distribution center are all excellent people. He explained that more than 6,000 applications were received for the more than 400 positions at the center.
</P><P ID="10">   "We were looking for those folks to come in with a good attitude," he said. "What we're looking for are good, quality people."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> noted that the jobs the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> distribution center has brought to the community are key, noting that with new jobs comes enthusiasm. He said if a person is happy and enthusiastic about their job that enthusiasm rubs off on the person's family, on their neighbors and eventually it affects the entire community.
</P><P ID="12">   "We're beginning to see that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said. "We know we're going to see some pretty exciting things."
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> has made <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> its newest home, he has had conversations with developers and business owners who are beginning to think of the community as a place to be.
</P><P ID="14">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> is getting to be known as what's happening now," he said.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Holden</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Community</ENAMEX>, Trade and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Economic Development</ENAMEX> said the distribution center is a good example of what economic development is all about, "a local community having a vision."
</P><P ID="16">   She said when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> was first looking to site a new distribution center, it was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> communities as a whole that worked together to make the vision a reality.
</P><P ID="17">   "The community made <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> feel this was a place they would be at home," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="18">   Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Byam</ENAMEX> said the entire <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> was involved and worked together to bring the distribution center to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   "They say it takes a village to raise a child," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byam</ENAMEX> said. "Well, it also takes a village to site a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Duff</ENAMEX>, division vice president of logistics for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart Stores Inc.</ENAMEX>, said it was that cooperation among the cities of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> that impressed the company.
</P><P ID="21">   "We had never encountered that before," he said.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said even with the distribution center not yet running at full capacity, the surrounding area is already beginning to see the benefits. She noted that every month since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> unemployment rates in the area have dropped by at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fourth District</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> said having the distribution center sited in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> also brings with it another benefit. He said the area's economy is largely agriculture based, and for economic growth diversity is needed.
</P><P ID="24">   "This center gives us that diversity," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="25">   In conjunction with the grand opening ceremony, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> also presented a number of grants to different community organizations, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police and fire departments, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Fair and Rodeo.
</P>





 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




