


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Council</ENAMEX> begins tackling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> city budget
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Facing a budget shortfall of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$190,000</NUMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members rolled up their sleeves and got to work on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget.
</P><P ID="5">   Council members took the time <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to wade their way through the budget figures for several city departments, including the fire, police, animal control, library and parks and recreation departments. Each department head talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> about the numbers in their budget and where costs have shifted from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget year.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to explain to them why the police department's budget is looking at an increase of about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">9.6 percent</NUMEX> over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget. The total budget for the department for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is sitting at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,758,700</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> noted that most of the increase is accounted for with the rising cost of health care and increases in salaries.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said for the past several years he has been asked to create the police department's budget without making any increases. When looking forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said he simply took the actual cost of things so far <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, averaged it out over 12 months and plugged those numbers into his budget, adding in the expected increases for salaries and health care costs.
</P><P ID="8">   "That's where I came up with the figures I have now," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   He added that he also included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$52,900</NUMEX> in his budget for capital items. Those items include the purchase of five tactical ballistic vests at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX>, three computers at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>, four mobile computers for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX>, a vehicle light bar for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,500</NUMEX>, three portable radios for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,400</NUMEX>, the remodeling of the dispatch counter for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,500</NUMEX>, four tasers for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,500</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> for the replacement of the office carpet.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that if the county's criminal justice tax is passed by voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> it would mean an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$162,000</NUMEX> a year in revenue to be used for the police department.
</P><P ID="11">   "It's revenue that can be spent on new programs," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> discussed whether or not those funds could be used to cover the costs of some of the capital improvements <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> included in his budget.
</P><P ID="13">   There were also several places in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>'s budget where costs are expected to go down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. For example, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> budgeted <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> for communications. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, that number drops to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>, that was a place he might have overestimated costs for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, noting that he simply took actual costs from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to come up with numbers for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Treasurer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Myers</ENAMEX> noted that another place dollar amounts are less is in the area of vehicles. He noted that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> there were a number of vehicles that fully depreciated. He noted that this does mean that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> those numbers will likely go back up when new vehicles are purchased.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Rick McLean</ENAMEX> pointed to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX>'s estimate when in it comes to overtime costs at the police department, noting that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> included <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$79,000</NUMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget for overtime. He asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> what the average salary of an officer is, and if it would be more cost effective to hire another officer instead of paying the overtime costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said despite the addition of another officer the department would likely still have high overtime costs because of the time necessary to take care of things like writing out reports and doing all of the paperwork that needs to be completed.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> then talked about the animal control budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, which stands at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$47,400</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> said the budget is about the same as it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. He explained that the city's animal control officer spends about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of his time taking care of his animal control duties and the rest of his time working for the police department. This means only half of his salary comes out of the animal control budget.
</P><P ID="17">   When it comes to the fire department's budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Fire Chief Charles Damron</ENAMEX> did some shuffling of dollars to make the most of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> funds the city receives on an annual basis.
</P><P ID="18">   The shuffling of figures is what led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> to actually lowering the fire suppression budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$112,240</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$103,520</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. On the other hand, the city's budget for emergency medical services went up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$76,700</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$105,520</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> explained the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> funds he will be using are currently sitting in reserve and can only be used for emergency medical services.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> added that he made the changes in the budget, shifting more funds to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> side of the budget because of the ratio of calls the department has been receiving. He noted that an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">75 percent</NUMEX> of the calls the department responds to are medical calls, with the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> of calls being fire related.
</P><P ID="20">   "It makes sense to move the money to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> from fire suppression," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> explained to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   One cost council was concerned about was in the cost of insuring the fire department vehicles. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Clerk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Posse</ENAMEX> noted that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, the large jump in insurance costs is due to the addition of the new pumper truck. She noted that is costs an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,800</NUMEX> a year to insure the vehicle. She also explained that the city's deductibles are already sitting at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> per vehicle, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> just several years ago.
</P><P ID="22">   Another area <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> about was in the category of uniforms and clothing, noting that under <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> the city budget no funds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damron</ENAMEX> explained that this was one of the categories where he took the expenses out of the fire suppression category and placed them into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> budget. He pointed out that he did the same thing when it came to small tools and equipment, adding another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that the shift of funds reflects the city's shift from a fire department to an emergency response department.
</P><P ID="24">   The library is another area where the budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is seeing an increase over the budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, the estimated budget is sitting at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$203,430</NUMEX>, compared to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$185,490</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   What is accounting for that increase is the additional costs the library has budgeted for capital improvements. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Little</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Mariotti</ENAMEX>, representing the library, noted that the increased capital expenditures come from a recommendation from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to begin setting money aside to take care of the big ticket improvements that need to be made at the facility. Included in the budget is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to be set aside for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next five years</TIMEX> for new carpeting, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> to be set aside for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next five years</TIMEX> for the replacement of the heating and air conditioning system, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750</NUMEX> to be set aside for the replacement of computers. The remaining <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17,010</NUMEX> in capital improvements is earmarked for the acquisition of books and other media.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little</ENAMEX> explained that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750</NUMEX> for the replacement of computers is something the city has to do in accordance with funds it receives through a Gates grant for the original purchase of the computer equipment. He noted that the grant required the city to replace the computers in five years.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariotti</ENAMEX> mentioned that the library board is already scared to death that the building's heating and air conditioning system could go at any moment. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Little</ENAMEX> noted that the library has to start somewhere as far as putting money away to make the repairs.
</P><P ID="28">   It was while looking at the expensive capital repairs that need to be made at the library that Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> asked what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members would think about taking the voter approved <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">one and a half percent</NUMEX> utility tax back to the voters. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> could ask voters to extend the utility tax one more year, using those funds to make all of the necessary capital improvements, including new carpet in the library and ballistic vests for the police department.
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Pam Horner</ENAMEX> noted that improvements paid for with the extension of the utility tax would be improvements that would last for years.
</P><P ID="30">   "We're taking big hits and I have to look at cutting programs and cutting people," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said. "But we have these capital expenses."
</P><P ID="31">   Then the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> turned its attention of the parks and recreation department budget, which is currently sitting at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$490,830</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, not including the cost of the senior center or the museum. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that the parks and recreation budget is up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="32">   Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX> noted that he also has several capital improvements that needed to be looked at, but that he didn't include them in his budget because of the situation he knew the city would be in.
</P><P ID="33">   He noted that those improvements include resurfacing the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX> pathway at an estimated cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$18,000</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17,000</NUMEX> for the resurfacing of the tennis courts and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> for the completion of the comprehensive six-year parks and recreation plan, which is required for many grant applications.
</P><P ID="34">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> will meet to work on the budget again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 8</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> in the city council chambers. After looking at budgets prepared by the different department heads, the city will begin looking at ways to balance the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget.
</P>





 










<P ID="35">Webmaster
</P><P ID="36">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




