
<P ID="1">State-of-the art music hall opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 3</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - Launching a new era of music education and music performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> will open the doors to its new, state-of-the-art music education building on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 3</TIMEX>.   "This magnificent structure has been in the planning stages for many years," says <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerilyn S. McIntyre</ENAMEX>. "Now, it is a dream come true for all of us and a fitting home for our outstanding music program."   The $29-million facility measures approximately 70,000 square feet and features a 600-seat concert hall, 150-seat recital hall, 30 practice rooms, four rehearsal rooms and several classrooms and faculty studios.   Among its most impressive features are a main entry with high ceilings and tall windows for natural light, and a main performance hall with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> boxes. In addition, walls and ceilings of rehearsal rooms are tailored to particular music groups. For instance, the choir room is shaped and outfitted differently than the orchestra room.   "This building means a tremendous step for the department of music and the community," Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Aspaas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> director of choral activity, explains. "Guest artists will now be lured to the region in part due to the quality of performing spaces. For an institution of higher learning, this kind of facility is almost unheard of."   Design of the two-phase facility began in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>. Studio Meng Strazzara served as the project architect-engineer. With Lydig Construction filling the role of project contractor, construction of Phase 1, including the concert and recital halls, started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October 2002</TIMEX>. Phase 2, involving the classrooms, practice facilities and faculty studios, began the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following year</TIMEX>.   "We thank our legislative delegation and other friends of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central</ENAMEX> in the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, who worked long and hard to provide the funding we needed to achieve our goal for all the people of the state," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McIntyre</ENAMEX> added.   Hertz Hall, constructed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX> for a music department of 150 students, has been the most recent home for the music department, which now comprises 260 music majors. It's projected to grow to 326 majors by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2010</TIMEX>.   "On a scale of one to 10, Hertz Hall was about a four and the new music building is a nine," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Larry Gookin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWU</ENAMEX> director of bands, claims. "That's how big a difference the new building will make in music education and performance."   The first performance in the new building, featuring students and faculty, will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 3</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 13</TIMEX>, the Seattle Symphony will also perform there as part of a year-long series of "Inaugural Season Showcase Performances."
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

