


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> conservation district position open
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">One elected supervisor position with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Yakima Conservation District</ENAMEX> is open. Those interested in serving as a volunteer supervisor from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area are asked to contact district officials at 1116 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Hwy. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, or by calling 837-7911.
</P><P ID="4">   The district supervisor represents landowners and the general public while directing natural resource conservation programs.
</P><P ID="5">   To be eligible to hold a supervisor's position, a candidate must occupy land within the conservation district boundaries, or be in possession of land within the district as an owner, lessee, renter or tenant. A candidate must also be a qualified county elector and a registered voter.
</P>   
<P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Indelook Club</ENAMEX> to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 14</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley Eshelman</ENAMEX> will host the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jr. Indelook Club</ENAMEX> meeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Jan. 14</TIMEX>, at her home, weather permitting. Co-hostess for the evening activities will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Brown</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> program will include a presentation by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eshelman</ENAMEX> on her trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thailand</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> retains commerce, trade committee chair
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>) remains chairman of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Senate Commerce & Trade Committee</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following yesterday</TIMEX>'s announcement on the first day of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> legislative session that some assignments had been changed.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> also retains his seat on the Natural Resources, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy & Water Committee</ENAMEX>, as well as his seat on two other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">committees-the Rules Committee</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ways & Means Committee</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> snowmobilers found unharmed
</P><P ID="13">   AHTANUM MEADOWS - A group of four Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> snowmobilers, reported as lost in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Darlan Mountain</ENAMEX> area, were discovered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> unharmed and safe.
</P><P ID="14">   Shortly after <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Sheriff's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> received a report that four snowmobilers hadn't made their way out of the Ahtanum area near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Darlan Mountain</ENAMEX> as planned. A search and rescue team found the subjects' vehicles and snowmobile trailers parked at the Ahtanum Meadows snow park, and set up a command post. At about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m. Monday morning</TIMEX> the four <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> snowmobilers were located on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Fork</ENAMEX> of the Ahtanum.
</P><P ID="15">   All four were in excellent condition, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s deputies.
</P><P ID="16">   Search and rescue team members report that the four outdoor recreationists-three men and a woman-had ridden into the area known as Blue Slide, north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Darlan Mountain</ENAMEX>. Due to darkness the four felt it safer to remain until daylight before trying to get out of the area. The four snowmobilers were well equipped with shovels, extra food and fluids, as well as fire starter and emergency blankets. The four reported they built a fire and settled in for the night.
</P><P ID="17">   The identity of the four snowmobilers is not being released per their request.
</P>   
<P ID="18">   County auditor's office closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Auditor</ENAMEX>'s office will be closed the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Jan. 15</TIMEX>, so that staff members can attend a retreat.
</P><P ID="20">   "It is extremely important that our staff have this opportunity as we begin a new year in service to the public of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Auditor Corky Mattingly</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   The office will resume regular business at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> that day.
</P>   
<P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> meeting canceled
</P><P ID="23">   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> has been canceled to due to weather conditions, according to a club spokesperson.
</P><P ID="24">   The group was to have met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Jan. 15</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood's Fairway Restaurant</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   "Inclement weather has forced the group to postpone its meeting until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Carlyle</ENAMEX>, a club spokesperson.
</P><P ID="26">   She said a representative of the Yakima Regional Library System will be the club's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> guest speaker, discussing a proposed annexation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Library into the regional library system's taxing district. The annexation issue will come before the voters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late spring</TIMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearl Hughes Guild</ENAMEX> meets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearl Hughes Guild</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Center of Seattle</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 16</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunny Spot Restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Highway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Cater</ENAMEX> will be in charge of the hostess project.
</P><P ID="30">   The local guild as a part of its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> program will be joining other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Center</ENAMEX> guilds to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> to establish an endowment to support pediatric infectious diseases research.
</P>   






 










<P ID="31">Webmaster
</P><P ID="32">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




