
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> brothers return from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The home of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva Martinez</ENAMEX> was festive this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> as she welcomed her sons home from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>.   A tearful homecoming with family began about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> when her sons arrived at her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> home.   It had been a year since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> saw her oldest son, Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael Ramirez</ENAMEX>, 25, and six months since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Specialist Job Ramirez</ENAMEX>, 24, had visited home, according to the brothers' sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socorro Ramirez</ENAMEX>.   The brothers signed up for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> two weeks apart.   "I kind of always wanted to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Job Ramirez</ENAMEX>, who was first to enlist. "I was going to Eastern and after I stopped going to school I came home."   A short time later he decided to sign up for a military tour. Scheduled to be released this coming spring, he recently re-enlisted.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX> was attending law school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Willamette University</ENAMEX> when he decided to enlist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>. "I realized I didn't want to be a lawyer," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> graduate.   "You play with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GI Joe</ENAMEX>'s when you're little and you want to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX>. I also needed a way to pay off student loans."   Both men are stationed out of Ft. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and recently returned from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Job</ENAMEX> has been in the states about a week and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX> about four days.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> brothers each received a four-day weekend and decided to visit their mother and other family in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. They will be taking block leave in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, which will give them a month off.   The two brothers are in the same <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Striker Brigade</ENAMEX> combination team, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">3rd Brigade</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Infantry Division</ENAMEX>.   Both work in supply and were actually at the same camp in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> for a while before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX> was promoted and moved about 50 kilometers away.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> is colder and rainier than everybody thinks it is," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX>, who added that they had two days of snow before he left <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>.   Stationed in the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mosul</ENAMEX>, which is a huge sprawling city, he said that although they are trained to work in supply, they, like other military personnel, had duties that aren't typical of supply officers. They often go on convoys into the city.   "All the cooks are guarding gates," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX>.   Being in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mosul</ENAMEX> for a year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX> has seen differences made in the services to the military personnel, as well as the citizens of the city.   He said the first three months they were there it was difficult without some of the amenities now offered, such as Internet cafes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ismael</ENAMEX> has also seen improvements in city sanitation and sewage treatment because of work don