
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> scraps <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> from funding list
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">A playground and a new education center, both in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, are the big winners in the divvying up of a pocket of federal funds being administered by the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> of Directors.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board began accepting proposals in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> to disperse <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> in remaining funds it has left out of an initial <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 million</NUMEX> federal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> grant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>'s proposal for a new grape and wine education center at the Grandview YVCC campus received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38,500</NUMEX> of the remaining <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>'s treasury.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX>'s playground proposal for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX> also received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX>.   Also receiving <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horizon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Project Upskills, which is a program to help people learn technology for career advancement, in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> health care career seminar program received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,500</NUMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> received <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX> to purchase equipment for a youth activities program.   Noticeably absent from the list of awardees was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s request for funds for the construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView</ENAMEX> skate park. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> created a bit of controversy when it made a request to have all of the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> project, even though the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board had planned to distribute the funds among a number of community based projects.   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> was disappointed to find out the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board of directors didn't allocate any funding for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> proposal.   Part of the city's request for funding <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> was to provide dollars to help <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX> build a skate park he has been trying to see come to fruition for years.   "It is an extremely worthwhile opportunity," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> was even more curious as to why <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> didn't receive any kind of funding from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>, since the project received unanimous approval from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Don Stiles</ENAMEX> attended a meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board after it received the requests for proposals in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board went through a process where it awarded points to projects to narrow down the list for funding consideration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> project was the top consideration of the board at the time and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> was curious as to how it could completely fall off the radar. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board had provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> for his skateboard park a while back, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.   "It is beyond me as to why it fell out of the group," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> was more than displeased with the decision of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said it has come to his attention that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> proposal was taken out of consideration for funding before <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> made its official presentation on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 10</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said during the initial go-around in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> project and the proposal from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horizon Inc.</ENAMEX> were the only ones to receive <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> board approval to move to the next step.   "Based on that, we thought we had a good chance of getting this done," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX>. "This in my opinion was the wrong decision. We should have been looking at something for the kids."   In the final analysis, majority vote ruled, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>.   "I'm very disappointed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, who also serves on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> had been instructed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to champion the park, a task she said she took seriously.   "I kept the park discussion open for over an hour trying to get the board members to vote for it," she said.   "I did my best, " she said.   But in the end, sustainability, longevity and the agency's ability to leverage <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds into other money were the criteria the board used in determining which projects to fund, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Souders</ENAMEX>, chair of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board.   "I believe we did the best job we could to expend the money offers to help the most people in the areas," Souders said.   She said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board voted to fund the wine and food education center based on its sustainability and future potential for jobs in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board met in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early January</TIMEX> to decide which proposals the members felt would make best use of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>'s grant funds, said Souders.   Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX> is elated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board's decision to fund his city's playground project.   "We are thankful they saw the merit in our project," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> has an ambitious plan to build a large playground for youths ages 5 to 12 at the west end of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX> near Euclid Avenue. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX> is the largest park in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, covering 28 acres.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said the playground equipment meeting the needs of community youths is lacking in the city's park system, which he is hoping to remedy with this project.   There are many benefits to having the playground area at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>, believes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>. The park is located near three mobile home parks and two apartment complexes. One of the mobile home areas is strictly for senior citizens. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> is hoping that with the playground area he will be able to bring together the senior citizens and the youth who frequent the park.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> added the city's playground committee, which consists of himself, assistant parks director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gretchen Chronis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Charvet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Jimenez</ENAMEX>, are excited to move forward with the project. The group will soon be visiting the schools and speaking with youngsters to find out what kind of equipment they would like to have at the park.   "We are putting together a plan to go into the schools to get some vital feedback from the kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>. "So we have a true representation."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said the support of the community was one of the areas he felt was strong on the city's application for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> has already received financial and labor donations to put the playground in.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> is expecting to spend slightly more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> on the playground. The project also benefited from an anonymous donation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.   The playground project, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> is hoping, will be completed before the end of the school year.   The recipients learned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> via written notification that they had been awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds.         . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

