
<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds race past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OTHELLO</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> out ran the Huskies <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, racing past the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> team to claim victory in a three-game match.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team defeated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> by scores of 25-15, 25-8 and 25-12.   "It was a pretty good team effort," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX>. "We did a good job of doing the things we had to do."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> added that the game came at a tough time for the Lady 'Hounds, noting that it's Homecoming week and many students are staying up late.   He added that the long bus ride to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> was also tough on the team.   "Riding to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX>, then having to play - that's kind of tough," he said.   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said he was happy with his team's performance against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX>.   "They did a good job and played really well," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.   Helping add a bit of spunk to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s game was senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> explained that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornejo</ENAMEX> has been working on a new serving style, which she tried out against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX>.   "She had a long string of serves that really dominated the game," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.   He said that the serve <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornejo</ENAMEX> is using is something she picked up while playing against some larger 4A schools.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornejo</ENAMEX> had a good night overall with 6 aces, 16 service points, 3 kills and 4 assists. Also helping out the Lady 'Hounds were Chante Bottineau with 8 digs and 18 assists, Kealey Johnston with 10 service points, 3 kills and 11 digs, Danelle Cowan with 9 kills and 2 blocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> with 2 kills and 7 digs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> with 10 kills and 3 service aces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX> with 8 service points, and Tonhya Wysong with 1 kill and 14 digs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said the game with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX> marks one of the last few matches the team will be forced to play on the road.   "They are going to come to our place to play us now," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.   Before the Lady 'Hounds (5-0, 6-1)return to their home court they will be taking part in the Wenatchee tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

