


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> takes another run at '<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX>'
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Mason</ENAMEX> is ready for round two with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S. Fourth District</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>, a Democrat, held a press conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to announce his bid to unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, a Republican. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> is looking to build on the nominal success he had the first time around in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> joined the political fray late in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> election and ended up as the Democratic challenger against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, managing to grab nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of all votes cast in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election.
</P><P ID="7">   "(I ran) to try and hold him accountable for things that had gone wrong," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> had a laundry list of political wrongs that he accuses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> of being involved in, including not taking necessary precautions to battle corporate corruption, such as Enron, and backing President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s stance about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "We are now in a war destroying our international reputation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> implied that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> is a tool of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> presidency and that is one of the reasons he has been able to accumulate the power he has gained in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. circles.
</P><P ID="11">   "He is an automatic vote for them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> also tackled the always controversial subject of Social Security. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> said contrary to what Republicans are saying, Social Security will be viable with a few adjustments until the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year 2052</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> said it is important to ensure the long-term success of Social Security because that is the retirement fund for more than half of Americans.
</P><P ID="13">   Veterans benefits are another area <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> has ignored. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> said it is important for past and present veterans to know they will be supported.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> also wants to be involved with promoting economic development in the Tri-Cities area and work on the Hanford clean-up plan. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> has long ignored the complaints of the Hanford workers.
</P><P ID="15">   In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> wants to develop ways to promote agriculture while brining in new manufacturing businesses to the area. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> has a plan similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> in the promoting the agriculture industry, but he also wants to expand educational opportunities, such as the expansion of the Grandview <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Community College</ENAMEX> campus.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> was also livid about the need to promote high wage jobs, which he feels will provide people with financial security, pensions and quality health care.
</P><P ID="17">   "The government's job is to partner with business and labor," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX> said he plans to campaign on the differences he has with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   "I have a vision for why I am running," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mason</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> hasn't done his job for the district."
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




