
<P ID="1">Local youngsters invited to take part in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley Band</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cheer Day</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Learning what it takes to make the most of a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">march</TIMEX> down a parade route is something band members from throughout the area will be doing as part of the first ever <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley Band</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cheer Day</TIMEX>, which is scheduled to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 12</TIMEX>, during the Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   The event will pair members of area marching bands and cheerleading squads with staff members from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. Among those who will be helping lead the event is Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad McDonald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> marching band director.   The one-day camp will bring the students together in sectionals to work on performance techniques and later marching techniques, while members of local cheerleading squads come together with the university squad to learn some new moves.   Registration for the camp begins at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 a.m.</TIMEX> in the main lobby of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX>, where students will spend the day working together until the community parade that evening. The students will have a chance to showcase what they learned during the day as they <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">march</TIMEX> down the parade route as one large musical group. Following the parade the students will gain free admission into the fair, where they will put together a large college-style pep rally.   The cost to take part in the event is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> per person, which includes a t-shirt, lunch, snacks and admission into the fair. Those individuals interested in taking part can contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX> at 882-4085.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

