


<P ID="1">G'view sweeps Ki-Be Bears
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BENTON CITY</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> managed to pull out a win against a tough Ki-Be team, sweeping past <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX> in a three-game match.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team pushed past Ki-Be, winning by scores of 25-17, 25-12 and 25-23.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said he figured going into the match that whichever team won would most likely end being co-leader in the league.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team played pretty well against the Ki-Be team, which was the 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> champions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "We dug up the ball and ran up the middle," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said. "And they weren't able to stop that."
</P><P ID="9">   Despite playing strong volleyball during the first two games of the match, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team seemed to relax a little in the third game. Ki-Be was able to take advantage of that lull, and brought the score uncomfortably close to the Lady 'Hounds.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said Ki-Be is a good team, adding that they are good at everything from serving to hitting.
</P><P ID="11">   "They really try to let you make your own mistakes," he said.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said there were several players who did a good job for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, including sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">setter Chante Bottineau</ENAMEX>, who had 24 assists, 2 kills and 10 service points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said the two kills were a "big deal," adding that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bottineau</ENAMEX> had a good night.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> was another player <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said played well against the Ki-Be team.
</P><P ID="14">   "She played really tough," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> had 14 kills, 3 aces and 8 blocks for the night.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> also played tough against the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornejo</ENAMEX> had 4 kills, 2 setting assists and 8 service points.
</P><P ID="17">   Danelle Cowan also had a good night with 10 kills and 4 blocks.
</P><P ID="18">   On the defensive side of things, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said freshman Kealey Johnston and junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonhya Wysong</ENAMEX>, who had 18 and 16 digs respectively, played well against the Ki-Be Bears.
</P><P ID="19">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team (3-0, 4-1) will take to the court again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> during a tournament in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Monroe</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said there his team will face off against several 4A teams.
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




