
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> sets world record-again
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Outlook's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Luther</ENAMEX> once again made his mark on the weightlifting world on perhaps the brightest stage in the world-Las Vegas.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> was one of 722 lifters from 39 states and 13 different countries to take part in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Twinlab World Bench Press</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deadlift Championship</ENAMEX>. The world lifting meeting was held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9-14</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Riviera Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>. The meet featured more than 80 hours of competition, which will be aired on ESPN in the near future.   "It was a pretty good meet," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>. "It was enormous."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> set a world record in the junior men (165 lbs.) division, bench pressing 458.3 lbs. on his third attempt, besting his previous world record mark by 1-1/2 lbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> weighed in at 160 lbs. for the world meet.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> has come a long way from the first time he competed at the world event when he was 19 years old. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> benched 419 lbs. his first time at the world meet.   "To be honest," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>. "I didn't think I was going to lift anything worthwhile this time."   The Outlook strongman qualified for the world competition during a meet held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> marks the first time in three years that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> has competed at the world meet. This is the largest meet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> has ever competed at. In the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said, he has competed at meets where lifters haven't been tested for steroids. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said he wanted to see how he fared at a meet against lifters that tested steroid and drug free.   "I wanted to see how I could compete," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>.   Compete is just what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> did, even after struggling early on. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> failed to make his first lift, nearly dropping 429-1/2 lbs.   "My form was off," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>. "My head wasn't into it."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> got back to form for his second lift, having an easy time with 451-3/4 lbs.   "I felt better with this lift," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> then hit his world record making lift on his third attempt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> had set his previous world bench press record, one of many he has owned over the years, during a meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">eight months ago</TIMEX> in the Tri-Cities.   In the junior men's division, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> was clearly the dominating lifter out of a field of eight participants. The lifter who took runner-up honors to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> was a distant second, clearing only 348 lbs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>'s lifts were good enough to win the open men's division, as well. The competition was a bit stiffer in the open men's division. The second place lifter in the open men's division was from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Norway</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Norway</ENAMEX> lifter cleared 436 lbs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said because of the number of lifters at the meet, it took a long time to finish the competition. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> was one of the first participants to do his lifts, competing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of the world event. After competing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> had to wait until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> to find out how he fared.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>'s performance in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> was perhaps even more notable because of an injury he sustained two months before the world meet. While working out a couple of months before worlds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> pulled a pectoral muscle in his chest. While preparing for worlds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said he was scared to lift heavy weights out of fear of further injuring his chest muscle and having to pull out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas</ENAMEX> meet.   Besides the size of the meet, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said he was surprised at the variety of competitors.   "Everybody seemed real nice," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>. "The guys are so huge. They are polite."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> was also amazed at the level of performance by some of the participants. In particular, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> was impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Seahawks</ENAMEX> football team strength coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Gillespie</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gillespie</ENAMEX> competed in two divisions and on his opening day missed all three of his lifts at 661 lbs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gillespie</ENAMEX> came charging back his second day of competition and cleared 661, 668 and 706 lbs.   "I couldn't believe it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>. "I had never seen anyone <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> all of his lifts on the first day and come back like that."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gillespie</ENAMEX>'s mark was a world record in the 308-lb. weight class.   "He was pretty impressive," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>.   Competing at worlds like he did showed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> a few things about himself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said that many of the weightlifters live the profession too much. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said that many of the lifters own gyms or have jobs revolving around their career. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> said he was glad to see he could compete with lifters who take the profession that seriously, since he is only able to dedicate a part of his time because of other commitments.   "It makes me feel good that I can do construction (for a living) and go to a world competition and actually place first in open men and junior men," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> is awaiting his invitation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Classic</ENAMEX> competition in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>.   "That is supposed to be huge," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Classic</ENAMEX> is a massive body building meet that actor and current <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> Governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold Schwarzenegger</ENAMEX> holds every year.   "It is supposed to be unreal," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

