


<P ID="1">County Democrats show support for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/27/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Surprisingly, many <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Democrats are still in favor of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Dean</ENAMEX> facing off against President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX> this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Democratic Convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s Carpenter Hall, which drew a jam packed crowd of about 250 people, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Dean</ENAMEX> supporters showed surprising strength by electing 17 delegates to attend the state convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early June</TIMEX>. Supporters of the nation's front runner to take on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>, elected 22 delegates to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The turnout for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Saturday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Democratic Convention was one of the best-attended county conventions in a decade.
</P><P ID="6">   Of the many issues considered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> for inclusion in the Democratic party platform, the debate on the issue of same-gender couples ensued. Delegates weighed in on a motion to change the phrase "civil marriage" to "civil union," and to drop another reference to marriage in the platform plank. But, the motion was rejected.
</P><P ID="7">   A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> city controversy-the construction of a new Wal-Mart store in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">west Yakima-was</ENAMEX> injected into the floor debate, as delegates considered a resolution opposing the expansion of the North American Free Trade Agreement. Supporters of the resolution said the agreement has a devastating impact on American jobs. Speakers at the county convention urged attendees to support local businesses as a way to protect jobs and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> economy from competition from national box stores.
</P><P ID="8">   In passing the anti-NAFTA motion on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the delegates also expressed opposition to the Free Trade of the Americas and the Central American Free Trade Agreement as pacts that threaten American jobs.
</P><P ID="9">   Democratic delegates voted down a motion to strike "universal gun registration and licensing" from the platform, and resoundingly expressed their opposition to a proposal in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to replace the image of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Franklin Delano Roosevelt</ENAMEX> on the dime coin with that of Ronald Reagan.
</P><P ID="10">   Also <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, overwhelming support for the proposed Black Rock Reservoir was voiced, along with a resolution urging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> not to close the Walla Walla veterans hospital as a budget saving measure. Convention attendees also voted to ask <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to pass the DREAM Act to help to make higher education more affordable for undocumented students and to enable them to attain full citizenship. Also approved was a resolution for incorporating <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> Indian tribal histories into existing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state history and social studies classes.
</P>   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




