
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> enters into agreement for animal control services
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">At this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> entered into an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society of Central Washington</ENAMEX> to provide animal control services in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.   "We have enjoyed the positive relationship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> and hope to continue that relationship in the future," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society of Central Washington</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Director Alan Landvoy</ENAMEX> wrote in a report presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> asked for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s fee for services in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. The amount the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to approve, which it did, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,815</NUMEX> per month, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$21,786</NUMEX> per year.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> shelter housed more than 11,000 animals, 504 of which came from within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city limits. Dogs accounted for the largest number of animals housed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> catered to 290 dogs from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area, 132 of which were euthenized. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area cats were also a frequent visitor to the Humane Shelter. There were 178 cats from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area taken to the Yakima shelter in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, 125 of which were euthenized.   Of the 504 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area animals taken to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> shelter, 259 of them were killed. The shelter did manage to find homes for 108 of the animals, 98 of which were dogs.   Under the terms of the agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> agrees to provide at least 20 hours of service within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city limits. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> also agrees to pick up all injured or dead animals as part of the contract.   The city will be pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> per day for any dogs housed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> that are needed in criminal investigation cases.   In the event of extra patrol needed, the city will pay the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humane Society</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per hour.   The contract also states the city will keep all of the money from fines.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

