
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> parkwill explodewith activitiesthis <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4th of July</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> city park will be full of activities for the entire family <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 4</TIMEX>.
Headlining the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4th of July</TIMEX> activities is a day-long car show and shine. Also, numerous service organizations will have booths set up and will be prepared to tempt the tastebuds of those in attendance with specialty foods.
The day's activities will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> with a kiddie parade through the downtown streets of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
The fun then shifts to the city park. Besides the car show and shine and the many food booths, there will be bingo games offered by the Knights of Columbus  from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> Numerous game and activity booths will be operating during the same time period.
From <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> the city park stage will be the site where several entertainers will perform. The Dirty <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Blues Band</ENAMEX> is set to perform from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tara & Trina</ENAMEX> from 1:15 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 p.m.</TIMEX> and The Shades from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
Following the fun in the park event, a fireworks display is scheduled at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Art Fiker Stadium</ENAMEX>, at approximately <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Senior actorsto present ‘Mame’  in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October, 2004</TIMEX>
Over The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill Theatricals</ENAMEX> has announced it will present the timeless musical, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mame</ENAMEX>," as its fall production.
The over age 45 amateur acting group will present the play in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-October</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium. Tryouts will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2</TIMEX> and 3, from 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Hazzard</ENAMEX>, who will direct the popular play
"We encourage men and women, ages 45 and older, to join us in presenting this entertaining play about a bigger than life woman and her adventures," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazzard</ENAMEX>.
The play will be produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Sartin</ENAMEX>.
For more information about the tryouts or Over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> membership, call 837-3157, 882-2919 or 786-3990.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima Folklife Festival</ENAMEX> bigger, better than ever
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - More than 100 music and dance performances at 13 venues highlights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima Folklife Festival</ENAMEX>.
The three-day extravaganza is set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and Sunday—July 9-11.
The main thrust of activities will once again take place at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Franklin Park</ENAMEX>. Besides dance and music, there will be plenty of kids activities, a medieval faire, crafts and food booths.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 10</TIMEX>, park entertainment kicks off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> Between the nearby museum and the park, six stages will be set up, all featuring folklife musicians. Non-stop entertainment will be presented until about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> that evening.
For those who want to continue the fun, a contradance will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway Grange Hall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and 11th avenues) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, from 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> Organizers say there will be line and square dancing to a live string band, and instruction will be provided for beginners.
The fun starts all over again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 11</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Franklin Park</ENAMEX>, with more musical groups performing from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
For those who want to get an early start at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s festival, six <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> eateries and pubs will host live music <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9</TIMEX>. The sites include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>'s Brewpub, The Depot, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keg & Cork</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Barrel House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greystone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Essencia Bakery</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourmet BBQ Extravaganza</ENAMEX> set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 9</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Like barbecue? Then plan on camping out all day under the flag pole at the Yakima County Courthouse on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 9</TIMEX>.
The Yakima County Sheriff's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> will host its eighth annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gourmet BBQ Extravaganza</ENAMEX> that day. Breakfast will be served from 6:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>, and lunch and dinner from 11 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, the Sheriff's agency raised more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,000</NUMEX> for Special Olympics. Some of that money came from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s barbecue fund-raiser. The proceeds from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s event will also benefit Special Olympics.
"Our agency led all other law enforcement agencies in the state, earning us the number one position in the Circle of Honor for the fifth year in a row," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> spokesman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacee Brooks</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 9</TIMEX>, breakfast menu includes eggs, ham, sausage, pancakes, juice, coffee and hot chocolate. The lunch and dinner menu offers gourmet burgers, foot-long dogs, chips, fruit and drinks.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> offers free concert series
MOSES <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LAKE</ENAMEX> - Centennial Theatre, located on the lakefront in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>, will again be home to that city's free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert series.
Organizers say they have booked another exceptional season with a variety of talent and genres.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s line-up includes the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Moyer Orchestra</ENAMEX> with guest vocalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisha Mitchell</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 4</TIMEX>; The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills Brothers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 17</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rangers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell Gunter</ENAMEX>'s Coasters on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 31</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Misty River</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 7</TIMEX>; Lavay Wells & Her Red Hot Skillet Lickers on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 14</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Stewart</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 28</TIMEX>; and BeatleMania Live on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 4</TIMEX>.
Admission to all the concerts is free. The venue features casual grass bowl seating at an award winning amphitheater. Entrance to the theater will be on a first-come, first-serve basis.
The kick-off event this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 4</TIMEX>, features <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Moyer</ENAMEX>, a dedicated woodwind instrumentalist, vocalist and arranger. His orchestra is a collection of some of the finest musicians in the Inland Northwest. Accompanying the musical group to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> will be Gospel recording vocalist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elisha Mitchell</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> native is described as having a heavenly voice and a name to match, as her name in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hebrew</ENAMEX> means "God of salvation."
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenix Festival</ENAMEX> returns <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TROUT LAKE</ENAMEX> - After a one-year hiatus, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenix Festival</ENAMEX> returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trout Lake</ENAMEX>, better than ever.
Following in the revolutionary spirit of festivals such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burning Man</ENAMEX>, Tribal Gathering and Earthdance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenix Festival</ENAMEX> is an autonomous music and arts festival happening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Independence Day</TIMEX> weekend, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1-5</TIMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> festival will feature performances on multiple stages by globally renowned musicians, actors, lyricists and visual artists.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s entertainers will include Blackalicious, The Coup, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saul Williams</ENAMEX>, Jello Biafra, Tipper, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dara</ENAMEX>, Hive, Shakta, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Tripwire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lusine</ENAMEX>, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Projectile</ENAMEX>, Consolidated & the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Free Music Society Orchestra</ENAMEX>, Supersoul & The Grand Inquisitor, and DJ Realm.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trout Lake</ENAMEX> organizers are adding a new dynamic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenix Festival</ENAMEX>, with a first ever live thematic performance stage, formally named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Culture Jam</ENAMEX>. The stage will showcase regionally, nationally and internationally recognized musical artists specializing in electronic, intelligent dance music, dub, hip-hop and culturally eclectic sounds.
The four other stages will focus on an eclectic mix of electronic music genres, workshops and visual art. Additionally, there will be several interactive theme camps and art projects that will provide a snapshot of the festival's cultural community.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris West</ENAMEX>, who is helping to promote the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1-5</TIMEX> event, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenix Festival</ENAMEX> is a fun environment for thousands of participants to freely express themselves. He said it is the largest outdoor, non-commercial and community-based underground music and arts festival in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX>.
Tickets range in price from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65</NUMEX></NUMEX>, and are available on the internet at the website: www.brownpaperticket.com.
For more information about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phoenix Festival</ENAMEX>, go to the site: www.phoenixfest.com.
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

