


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jody Davis</ENAMEX> new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Beads were thrown, masks were worn and in the end a new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> court was decided. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, after a Mardi Gras themed program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jody Davis</ENAMEX> was named <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>, along with co-finalists <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tara Collins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jae Mains</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The three members of the new court were selected from a group of 12 girls who spent the evening putting their best foot forward for the judges. Throughout the program the girls were judged in five different categories, including interview, scholastics, talent, fitness and poise. The interview and scholastics categories were judged before the program began on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The 12 girls taking part in the program <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Liz Razo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Barrera</ENAMEX>, Kesha Cruz, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lita Cervantes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Segovia</ENAMEX>, Cheyanne Trevino and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Varner</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mains</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The program started with an opening number to "When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Saints</ENAMEX> Come Marching In," which featured the 12 contestants running through crowd, tossing beads and setting a festive tone for the rest of the night.
</P><P ID="8">   After running in and introducing themselves to the crowd filled with friends, relatives and community members, the girls went directly into their fitness routine, which was choreographed to a medley of Mardi Gras-themed songs, including "Carnival" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bo Diddley</ENAMEX>, "I Want to Do It All" by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teri Clark</ENAMEX> and "Mardi Gras" by Queen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ida</ENAMEX>. During the routine, the girls showed off their coordination and stamina doing push ups, kicks and stretches, all while smiling and showing the judges that they were having a good time.
</P><P ID="9">   Also getting into the act was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linsley Grow</ENAMEX>, who performed a tap routine with her younger sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allison Grow</ENAMEX>. The two sisters took to the stage and entertained the crowd with their fancy footwork.
</P><P ID="10">   Following the performance, Mistress of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ceremonies Gretchen Chronis</ENAMEX> introduced the five judges for the evening, which included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa ETorchon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, who works at Cascade Natural Gas; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Goetz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coulee City</ENAMEX>, who works for Goetz Wheat Ranches; homemaker <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jennifer Goetz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coulee City</ENAMEX>; homemaker and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Maljaars</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Highland School District</ENAMEX> employee and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> Princess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina McDaniels</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tieton</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   During the talent portion of the night, each of the 12 contestants took to the stage for 90 seconds to show the judges what they do best, be it singing, dancing or giving a dramatic performance.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> started the talent portion off with an a cappella vocal solo to "Amazing Grace," followed by a hip hop dance routine performed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mains</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Razo</ENAMEX> took to the stage dressed in a bright pink top and white pants to sing "When You Say Nothing at All." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barrera</ENAMEX> danced to "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Que Ricmo</ENAMEX> No Pare," while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cruz</ENAMEX> did a funk dance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madrigal</ENAMEX>, dressed all in black, gave a dramatic performance entitled "Hard to Say Goodbye," during which she mourns the loss of her best friend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornejo</ENAMEX> showed off her dance skills through a spirit dance, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> performed a soliloquy titled "Empty." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Segovia</ENAMEX> took center stage in a poodle skirt, saddle shoes and a pink sweater to perform a dance to the song "Lollipop." <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trevino</ENAMEX>, wearing a mint green dress, signed to the song "My Immortal," followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> who played "A Whole New World," on the piano. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Varner</ENAMEX> concluded the talent portion of the evening, dressed in a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yankees</ENAMEX> baseball shirt, singing "I Want to Do It All."
</P><P ID="13">   During poise, each of the 12 girls had a chance to choose their own evening gown as they prepared to perform a short group dance routine, complete with masquerade masks, before being asked an impromptu question by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX>. The girls answered questions ranging from which television character they would most like to trade places with to what they worry about.
</P><P ID="14">   After a brief intermission, it was time to begin presenting awards. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> Chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cookie Shannon</ENAMEX> presented the Friend of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> award to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> for all of their help when it comes to using school facilities throughout the year for different <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> activities.
</P><P ID="15">   The Be Your Best Self award, whose recipient is chosen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Committee</ENAMEX> based on a girl's reliability, helpfulness and promptness during the period leading up the program, was presented to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>. The Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junior</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> award, which is voted on by the contestants, was presented to both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mains</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   The category awards went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Collins</ENAMEX> for talent, interview and poise; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> for scholastics and fitness.
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




