


<P ID="1">27th animal imported into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow found
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/26/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">USDA</ENAMEX> has announced that yet another cow that was imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> (bovine spongiform encephalopathy) infected cow that started the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> mad cow disease scare just days before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> has been located.
</P><P ID="4">   The animal was located at a facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>. The operation is now under a state hold order, prohibiting the movement of specific cows believed to be associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow. Once it is determined that an animal is not potentially infected the hold order is removed from that specific animal.
</P><P ID="5">   A total of 27 cows of the 80 animals imported along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow have been located. A total of 170 animals from the Mabton and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> dairies, where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cows were milked, and a Mattawa dairy finishing facility have been destroyed and tested for mad cow disease. Test results have been negative.
</P><P ID="6">   A total of 10 cows at the Mabton dairy were imported with the infected cow. Three cows at the Mattawa facility have been traced to the Canadian herd that was imported with the infected cow. Others in the Canadian herd that were imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> have been discoverd-one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quincy</ENAMEX>, one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>, three in Burley, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and three in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tenino</ENAMEX>. Six cows from the original 81 have also been located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Connell</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Another 17 cows with ties to the infected cow are also being sought. One of the animals was located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
   
   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




