
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helicopter</ENAMEX> pilot uninjured in crash
PROSSER - 56-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George P. LeLoup</ENAMEX> avoided injury when his helicopter crashed in a cherry orchard near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>.
According to Benton County Sheriff's Captain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Kissler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeLoup</ENAMEX> was drying a cherry crop with his helicopter near North Hinzerling and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McReadie</ENAMEX> roads at about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:40 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissler</ENAMEX> said the helicopter's rotor struck a power line.
"The pilot was able to land the craft in the orchard," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissler</ENAMEX>.
The power line that the helicopter's rotor struck was knocked down, though. Several trees and the helicopter, itself, were also heavily damaged.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kissler</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FAA</ENAMEX> has been contacted and the federal agency will be conducting a formal investigation.
The helicopter piloted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX> man is owned by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Monson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> volunteers for Girls Nation event in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Dobson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will serve as a volunteer during the 58th annual session of Girls Nation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. the week of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24-31</TIMEX>.
Girls Nation is a hands-on government education program that brings together some of the top female high school seniors in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>. A total of 96 girls from 48 states participate in the week-long citizenship program.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dobson</ENAMEX> will be part of the government staff at Girls Nation.
The American Legion Auxiliary traditionally sponsors the Girls Nation event.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Rail painting party set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents are being invited to leave their mark on the community two Saturdays from now, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX>.
Behind the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, a rail painting party will be held that day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said all community residents are urged to take part in the beautification effort.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> explained that in an effort to continue adding color and beauty to the city, the guardrail near the railroad tracks at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> will be painted with handprints of all the participants.
Local citizens, young and old alike, are asked to take part. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX> event is set for 9 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">Tickets available for annual Hospice benefit auction
Tickets are on sale for the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice benefit auction, which is scheduled to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 9</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navarro's Community Center</ENAMEX>, 548 S. Sixth St. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
The "Circle of Life"-themed event will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> with a silent auction. The live auction will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> and doors will close at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> Heavy hors d'oeuvres will be served and those in attendance will have a chance to bid on items ranging from different wine packages to a play/dollhouse being built by the Boys Scouts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>.
Tickets for the auction are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per person or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> per couple, and are available through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice. For more information call 837-1676.
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

