
<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For more than 20 years <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Roberson</ENAMEX> has been providing electrolysis services to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents seeking permanent hair removal.   Most of her career, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX> has practiced out of a beauty shop on Seventh Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, but about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">four years ago</TIMEX> when New Image moved to Edison Avenue, so did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX> and her sister, who lives in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, are both certified electrologists.   "In our family we have people who have a lot of hair and you can't work on yourself, so when the opportunity came up we both took the classes," said the Mabton resident.   "It's a rewarding field," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>, who finds a lot of satisfaction in helping women who are uncomfortable with facial hair or other problem areas.   "There are three times in life when women grow hair, puberty, pregnancy and menopause," she said.   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>'s services are not only sought by women. Men wanting their hands or backs hairless also visit her, as do high school aged boys and girls and college students home on vacation.   "As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, electrolysis is the only method of permanent hair removal that is recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>. She said plucking, tweezing, creams, waxes and other methods of hair removal don't kill the follicle and instead draw more blood to the area where hair is removed, causing it to grow back thicker and darker.   Although some people think that electrolysis is similar to a medical procedure, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX> is quick to let all know that they are not medical persons, but she added it is not the "back door business" people used to think it was.   "We are not medical people ourselves, but we have a lot of medical people talk to us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>.   She recently returned from an electrolysis conference in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, where she heard from medical professionals on different things to look for on client's skin and was updated on new technologies.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX> said she often sees or notices changes in moles that a client may not know about.   Without diagnosing a skin problem, she may suggest that a client see their doctor about the condition. On a few occasions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>'s suggestion to go to the doctor has proven to benefit her clients, who were found to have cancerous spots on their faces.   Electrolysis by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda</ENAMEX> is a second job for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>, who does quality control for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stadelman Fruit Company</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>. Her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> office hours are in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late afternoon</TIMEX> and evening by appointment.   "I give a free consultation to anyone interested," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>. "This is not like getting a shot," she tells her clients. "I go along the hair follicle and use a high frequency heat machine to cook the hair from the inside out."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX> said her clients keep her interested in continuing electrolysis.   "When I see my clients on the street walking with their head high, it makes me feel good," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberson</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

