
<P ID="1">Mayor pro-tem suggests regaining control of library
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s joint meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> offered a suggestion concerning the local library.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> wants to enter into discussions with the school district to find a way to take back operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Public Library from the Yakima Valley Regional Library System.   "We should look at some kind of joint venture between the city and the school district," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> opted during budget discussions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to put before local voters the issue of whether or not to support an additional 50¢ per thousand assessed property value tax to keep the library open under the operation of the Yakima Valley Regional Library. Voters approved that tax <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members then relinquished control of the library to the county-wide system.   The regional library system is set to take control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of 2005</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> suggested the partnership with the local school district because he said he feels city residents will be shortchanged by the regional library system. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said the financial figures regional library officials are releasing show that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents are paying more into the system than they are getting.   "I think we can take that same 50¢ and do just as good or better," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>, who is involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library Board</ENAMEX>, said regional library officials do have a plan in place to improve the local facility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she would like to see them given the opportunity to improve the facility before any talks of taking back the library happen.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> didn't rule out such a discussion between the district and the city. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> did caution there would have to be some changes made in the materials offered at the library if the district managed the facility because of the youths who would use it.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

