
<P ID="1">Spring Fling evolving into a 10-day festival
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - Spring Barrel tasting may be more than six months away, but area chambers of commerce are already starting to look ahead to the annual event as they makes plans for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Spring</TIMEX> Fling festival.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> Director of Promotions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tourism Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX> talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> event and the work that is already going into it.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said Spring Fling is an event that has brought together chambers of commerce from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX>. She explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> chambers are working together to organize a 10-day festival that will attract those who are visiting the area for Spring Barrel tasting to stay and enjoy what the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> has to offer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said since the inception of Spring Barrel tasting, the event has grown to such a magnitude that area wineries are beginning to expand, what was once a one weekend event, into a two weekend affair. She said wineries found that as Spring Barrel tasting grew they weren't able to spend the one-on-one time with their customers. Now, wineries are beginning to invite their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VIP</ENAMEX> customers to attend a pre-barrel tasting event the weekend before.   And it's that expansion of Spring Barrel tasting that the local chambers are trying to build on.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> explained that local businessman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denlea</ENAMEX>, who recently opened the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Best Western Grapevine Inn</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, brought the idea of a Valley-wide festival to the forefront after observing the Tulip Festival that takes place every year in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skagit Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denlea</ENAMEX> noted that the communities in that area worked together to fill the 13 days of the Tulip Festival with a variety of activities.   "So when people are in town for the Tulip Festival, they have something to do that isn't necessary tulip [related]," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said. She added that as a result of the combined efforts the festival brings <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16 million</NUMEX> in tourism revenue into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skagit Valley</ENAMEX>.   She said the Spring Fling festival can serve as a way for the communities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> to take advantage of the many visitors who come into the area for Spring Barrel tasting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> admitted that when planning for the festival first started, the different communities involved were a little territorial. However, as time has gone by the communities have realized that working together is what is important when it comes to making the festival a success.   "It has been a great process," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said.   At this point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corliss</ENAMEX> said the group of chambers involved in coordinating the Spring Fling festival are working on preparing the calendar of events. She encouraged any organization interested in putting together an event to come forward.   "We're excited about it," she said, noting that the event is already starting to see growth.   Other business that took place during the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> included the presentation of a check to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Aquatics Committee</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Kresse</ENAMEX> presented a check for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> to the committee, challenging 10 other people to donate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> each, which two members did. To date, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Aquatics Committee</ENAMEX> has raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,860</NUMEX> toward a new pool facility for the community.   To help raise additional funds, the committee is hosting a yard sale at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> building at 109 E. A St. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 23</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> Donations for the yard sale are being accepted at the site from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>).
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

