


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/17/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Library vote appreciated
</P>

<P ID="5">WARNING! The 673 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> registered voters who said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> on the library annexation are in danger of being hugged with "wild abandon" by me and every other dedicated library user who lives in the county. With no voice in the matter, we just crossed our fingers and hoped. Actually, we said a few prayers, too.
</P>

<P ID="6">While we're busy appreciating the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> voters, we'll include the voters who didn't go to the polls or use the absentee ballots to vote NO. Not voting in this case can be viewed as a willingness to support all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents who do use the library, whether they're among that group or not.
</P>

<P ID="7">Just in case I haven't made the intention of this letter clear: thank you, thank you, thank you! Maybe it's a good thing that county residents don't know any of the yes voters or abstainees. There would be a whole lot of hugging going on!
</P>

<P ID="8">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daphne Stewart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="9">Veteran plaques
</P>

<P ID="10">I am a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Memorial Committee</ENAMEX>, of which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Schlieve</ENAMEX> is the chairman. The second phase of the construction of this memorial is coming to an end. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg</ENAMEX> is presently selling bronze plaques that can be purchased for any veteran who has ever served directly in an American war or conflict.
</P>

<P ID="11">The veteran paid a great price by willingly putting his life in harm's way so that the world would be free of tyrants, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>. And many gave up their lives for this great cause.
</P>

<P ID="12">Because of them millions of people now live in freedom around the world. And those millions are now closing in on being over a billion in just the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 100 years</TIMEX>. Thus, the value of what the veteran has done for humanity cannot be measured.
</P>

<P ID="13">But for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> they can be remembered. Yes, for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> you can memorialize the veteran on one of the finest veterans memorials in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. It's right here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. But time is running out. When these plaques are sold, then the opportunity to remember our war veterans will have passed, and will probably never return to us again during our lifetimes.
</P>

<P ID="14">And all it costs is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX>, which is a very small price to pay when you consider how much they have already paid for your freedom, and the freedom of millions and millions people around the world.
</P>

<P ID="15">I urge you to contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Schlieve</ENAMEX> and purchase a bronze plaque before this opportunity is gone forever. You'll never regret it.
</P>

<P ID="16">/s/ Major <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delbert Pease</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




