
<P ID="1">'<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hounds</ENAMEX> race past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, 42-12
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> football team picked up its third CWAC South victory of the season <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> via a dominating 42-12 win over the Toppenish Wildcats.   With the exception of one defensive breakdown, the Greyhounds kept <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> in check for most of the night.   "We had everyone up blitzing on that one breakdown," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Justin Lamb</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> running back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Garza</ENAMEX>, who led all rushers in the game with just over 160 yards, squirted past the oncoming blitzers and raced 77 yards for a TD.   The Wildcats added their only other score of the night just before halftime. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomas Suarez</ENAMEX> capped off the scoring drive with a 3-yard plunge into the end zone.   But by the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suarez</ENAMEX> found pay dirt, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> already had a commanding 28-6 lead on the 'Cats.   The '<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hounds</ENAMEX>, who went into the locker room at intermission up 28-12, added two touchdowns after the break to account for the 42-12 drubbing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said his defensive unit did a solid job of shutting down <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> in the second half.   "Especially the two goal line stands we had in the second half, when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> still had their first unit in there. We had a mixture of first and second unit players on the field, and our kids held when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> had the ball deep on our end of the field," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> coach went on to single out senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Dill</ENAMEX>, who played well, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>, from his cornerback spot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dill</ENAMEX> basically killed one <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> scoring opportunity when he intercepted a pass in the end zone. He returned the ball about 30 yards to give the '<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hounds</ENAMEX> good field position.   Scoring-wise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX> rushed for three touchdowns on the night. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quarterback Brandon Artz</ENAMEX>, a junior, had two TD throws, both to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX>.   "It was our third straight week of having a rusher over 120 yards," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>, speaking of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX>'s performance. "Our offensive line is finally getting it done."   In assessing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX>'s play, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said his quarterback was "...really solid. With a good running game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> is finding some time back there to throw the ball," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s win over the Wildcats upped <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s CWAC South record to 3-2, 3-4 overall. The '<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hounds</ENAMEX> close out regular season play this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> at home against league leading <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> (4-0, 7-0).   "Oh yeah, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> is going to provide us a challenge," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said. "They're as efficient and disciplined as any team I've seen.   "We're just going to try to improve on what we're already doing well," he added.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

