
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roach</ENAMEX> begins new term as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> president
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Even though she has been the president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> for the past several years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lu Ann Roach</ENAMEX> has not lost her enthusiasm for the leadership role.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roach</ENAMEX>, along with officers who have served with her in the past, reaffirmed their commitment to the service-oriented group.   Serving with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roach</ENAMEX> will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LouAnne Stiltner</ENAMEX>, first vice president, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Carlyle</ENAMEX>, second vice president; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith Higgins</ENAMEX>, third vice president; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Serrano</ENAMEX>, treasurer; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elsie Bell</ENAMEX> as recording secretary.   Also installed as officers were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nita Coleman</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Miller</ENAMEX> as the editors of the club's newsletter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deborah Clark</ENAMEX> will handle publicity, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Yockey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Jacobson</ENAMEX> sharing hostess duties.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> has been one of the staunch supporters of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Pathway and recently contributed funds for the establishment of a new shady shelter on the pathway. The structure will be dedicated to the memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Blunk</ENAMEX>, husband of long-time club member and pathway promoter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Blunk</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blunk</ENAMEX> reported that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> has agreed to match the club's pledge for the shelter project, as have the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> commissioners.   "We are hoping to hear soon if the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> will also support the project," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blunk</ENAMEX>, who along with her late husband worked most of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 20 years</TIMEX> to establish the pathway.   In addition to supporting beautification projects, such as the pathway, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nouvella Club</ENAMEX> presents scholarships to local high school students, supports literacy programs, and engages in presenting programs of general interest to the members.   More than 30 women are currently members of the 46-year-old club, which meets once a month.   The club doesn't meet in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, but will host a style show and membership drive when it resumes meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roach</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

