


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/30/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ABEL BARAJAS</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ABEL BARAJAS</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Barajas</ENAMEX>, 18, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 26, 2004</TIMEX>, due to injuries sustained in an automobile accident.
</P>

<P ID="6">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 23, 1985</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose M.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elva (Bravo) Barajas</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX>, graduating with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">He is survived by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose and Elva Barajas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>; three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balanca</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carina Barajas</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mattawa</ENAMEX>; and his grandparents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador and Elva Bravo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonor Barajas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beverly</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by a large number of aunts, uncles, nephews, nieces and cousins.
</P>

<P ID="8">He was preceded in death by his grandfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Barajas</ENAMEX>.
</P>  


<P ID="9">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 1, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be recited at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 2, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MOISES S. Martinez SR.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moises S. Martinez Sr.</ENAMEX>, 74, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29, 1930</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Monterrey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria De Los Angeles</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silva</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cresencio Martinez</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">He is survived by four daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Trevino Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Alaniz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Alicia Vidales</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rita Trevino Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; and three sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moises Martinez Jr.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Angel Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

 


<P ID="14">HAZEL <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M. HANNAMAN</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel M. Hannaman</ENAMEX>, 89, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 26, 2004</TIMEX>, at her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 29, 1914</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jayton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Frances (Luman) Rasberry</ENAMEX>. She received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1, 1933</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chester</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. Following their marriage they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> before settling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. She later married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn O. “Bill” Hannaman</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 1964</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coeur</ENAMEX> d’Alene, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>. She was manager of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview VFW</ENAMEX> for many years.
</P>

<P ID="17">She is survived by her two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Turner</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Paducah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent</ENAMEX>. and
</P>  
<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Bratta</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Caesar</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>; 12 grandchildren and 21 great-grandchildren; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alene Nelson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buddy Edwards Jr.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>; and a daughter-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Chester</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="19">She was preceded in death by her parents; two husbands, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Chester</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn O. “Bill” Hannaman</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnie Lee Chester</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>; and two granddaughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Lee Turner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ready Ann Mitra</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="20">Private memorial funeral services were held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABEL V. GABBERT</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabel V. Gabbert</ENAMEX>, 96, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 28, 2004</TIMEX>, surrounded by her loving family.
</P>

<P ID="23">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12, 1908</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles W.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olive</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bates</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Barlow</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="24">Mabel’s love for gardening, roses and iris’ were evident at her retirement home.
</P>

<P ID="25"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabel</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Deer Park Seventh-day Adventist Church</ENAMEX> and was deeply devoted to her family and religion. She was known for always wearing hats with gloves and scarves on special occasions.
</P>

<P ID="26"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabel</ENAMEX> is survived by her children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Johnston</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Springdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Tipton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>) Knutson of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Springdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Johnston</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cooley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costa</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Diego</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>; 20 grandchildren; 37 great-grandchildren and nine great-great-grandchildren.
</P>

<P ID="27">Visitation will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 2, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at Hennessey Jones Funeral Home Chapel, 2203 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">N. Division St.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 3, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at Hennessey Jones Funeral Home Chapel. To honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabel</ENAMEX>, her family members and friends will be wearing hats to the service. Committal services will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Oct. 5, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> and will take place at Mabton City Cemetery, 881 Vance Rd., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>. Memorial contributions are suggested to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spokane Junior Academy</ENAMEX>, 1505 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">W. Cleveland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 99205. Arrangements have been entrusted to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hennessey Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="28">Webmaster
</P><P ID="29">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




