


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> says no to housing project
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Citing uneasy economic times, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> voted to not pursue a Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) for a housing rehabilitation program.
</P><P ID="5">   Council members had been looking for the past few months at pursuing another CDBG to implement a housing rehabilitation program. The city is currently in the final stages of its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing rehabilitation program, which is being funded through a CDBG.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> expects the grant monies for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! program to be expended by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Conference of Governments (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX>) representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Weinmann</ENAMEX> informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that any application for new housing rehabilitation funds would most likely be submitted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-November</TIMEX> with monies being made available in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early spring</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> brought up some concerns for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to look at before opting on whether or not to enter into the agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX>. He said the city would have to come up with slightly more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,100</NUMEX> to apply for the grant with the assistance of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the city is incurring some problems with expenses for the current CDBG program. The expenditures for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing rehabilitation program are coming out of the planning department's budget. But because of some other financial commitments the city is involved with and other budget issues, the planning department's budget will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$91,000</NUMEX> in the red by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX>. That figure would rise by the additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,100</NUMEX> due to costs associated with applying for the grant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> also wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to know the city would be committed to matching the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> made reference to during the meeting as part of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s match for the CDBG funds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> said the city wouldn't need to come up with the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> match for two years.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, however, was concerned with the city making any financial commitment in uncertain economic times. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> he is already expecting next budget year to be a tight one for the city.
</P><P ID="10">   The suggestion <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> had for the city was to wait a year and look for options to ensure it would have those match funds available for the grant. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it would be better for the city to take this stance than end up refusing a grant from the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> suggested that if the city does move forward with another housing rehabilitation program that a separate fund is set up to account for any loan payments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said right now all repayments go directly into the general fund and are difficult to trace.
</P><P ID="11">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>'s recommendation of waiting a year. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said the city needs to ensure it has adequate funds for such priority areas as law enforcement and fire services before forging ahead with a housing rehabilitation program.
</P><P ID="12">   "We had a tough budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> was also concerned about the budget and committing money the city doesn't know if it will have to such a project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said he didn't want to commit the money for the housing rehabilitation program and then find out the city doesn't have the dollars down the road and people have to be fired.
</P><P ID="14">   Councilman John Torch also agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, saying that the city's expenditures are exceeding revenue streams. Torch suggested the city wait one year.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> went a different avenue, saying he was in favor of pursuing the program because he thought it was good for the city.
</P><P ID="16">   "Even if we spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> it is not like we are throwing money away," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said once the money from the paybacks on the loans for the housing projects comes back the city should start receiving a steady stream of money. He added that the programs should become self-sufficient, actually generating revenue for the city. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he would be willing though to go with the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the issue.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> unanimously decided not to pursue funds from the state to start a new housing rehabilitation program.
</P><P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




