3 20 0 23 38 33
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Many that live deserve death. And some die that deserve life. Can you give it to them? Then be not too eager to deal out death in the name of justice, fearing for your own safety. Even the wise cannot see all ends.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. R. R. Tolkien</ENAMEX> (1892 - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>), The Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Of</ENAMEX> the Rings, Book Four, Chapter One
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>