
<P ID="1">Congressman tours <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, meets with American troops
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/25/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">IRAQ</ENAMEX> - While on a five-day trip to see first-hand how American troops are faring in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> came face-to-face with a young man whom he had aided in becoming an officer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> had the opportunity to chat with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Ayre</ENAMEX>, formerly of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Finley</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> had given an appointment to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Air Force Academy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>.   "He didn't know who he was to be transporting, but he recognized me and took time to re-introduce himself to me," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.   "It just goes to prove that we are living in a small world," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to visit with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> troops, tour military operations and to see for himself how the Iraqi rebuilding effort is progressing.   The 4th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> lawmaker said he had the opportunity to meet and share meals with the troops, many of whom have been stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>.   "We arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bagdad</ENAMEX> in time to mark the first anniversary of start of the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.   "What impressed me most was the high morale of the troops," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, who was among those who voted to fight the war on terrorism, said he felt a personal obligation to see first-hand how the troops were doing.   "I wanted to get a pulse on the situation," he said, saying he was pleased with the American troops' attitudes. He said their positive morale has renewed his commitment to provide the troops with whatever they need while stationed overseas.   He also met with the commanders of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Combined Joint Task Force</ENAMEX> and other senior level <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> officials regarding the current military operations.   "We also met with members of the provisional Iraqi government, who are preparing for a constitutional election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.   He said the Iraqi leaders seemed optimistic they will be able to to govern themselves.   "It's a difficult task they have ahead of them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> noted.   "Even though they have lived under a brutal dictatorship for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past quarter</TIMEX> of a century, they are optimistic they can make a new government work," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said the new Iraqi government has a great potential for making a healthy comeback.   "We noticed an extensive system of canals in the region. I believe if the new government allows its farmers to produce, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> could become the bread basket of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Middle East</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, who was part of a six-person Congressional delegation to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, also visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jordan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kuwait City</ENAMEX> and the military hospital in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ramstein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX>, where injured American troops are being treated.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

