44 36 7 25 14 25
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  I must study politics and war that my sons may have liberty to study mathematics and philosophy. My sons ought to study mathematics and philosophy, geography, natural history, naval architecture, navigation, commerce, and agriculture, in order to give their children a right to study painting, poetry, music, architecture, statuary, tapestry, and porcelain.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> (1735 - 1826)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>