


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall Doak</ENAMEX> to leave post
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> Executive <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Director Marshall Doak</ENAMEX> has announced he will be leaving the economic development agency to go into private business.
</P><P ID="5">   At the same time, he announced that the agency he has worked for during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX> will be undergoing an identity change.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said he departs the agency as it is undergoing a name change.
</P><P ID="7">   "We have dropped the incorporated title and have changed our identity to better express what we are about," he said.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> economic board of directors voted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> to change its name to "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Development Association</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="9">   "We even have a new logo, created by DeLeesa Sarducci, which expresses the board's dedication to diversity, the community and growth," he explained.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX>'s resignation is effective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 31</TIMEX>. However, he said he will continue to make himself available to the board as the transition to a new director is made.
</P><P ID="11">   He said the search for a new director is expected to begin within the next several weeks.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX>, who took on the task of leading the community-based business development agency in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2002</TIMEX>, said he plans to remain in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "I plan to stay in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and open my own investment broker office," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="14">   "I've always believed in entrepreneurship and staying in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> offers me a lot of positives for my own business opportunities," he said.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX>, who said he is proud of the work he has done for the community business climate, said often the general public has not been privy to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> work.
</P><P ID="16">   "The nature of this business is confidentiality. But we are always interfacing with developers on some level," he said.
</P><P ID="17">   "This has been a fun and exciting job and I find it continues to be an exciting time to live in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," he said.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past week</TIMEX> he has been in talks with a number of commercial developers who are in the pre-development stages of their plans.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said as he leaves the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Economic Development Association</ENAMEX>, he is working with several groups on commercial and residential developments, who are actively seeking to develop properties in the community.
</P><P ID="20">   "Some of these are past the interest stage and are moving into the pre-development stage," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> said, adding he expects to be making some announcements in the next few weeks.
</P><P ID="21">   "I expect we'll be making some announcements about new developments in the coming weeks, perhaps days," he said.
</P><P ID="22">   During his two years as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> economic development front man, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doak</ENAMEX> has worked on such projects as the development of businesses surrounding I-82 exit 69, including the siting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Best Western Motel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




