
<P ID="1">Everson girl spends holiday shadowing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ER</ENAMEX> nurses
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Unlike most young people her age, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX> didn't spend her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Year</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> holiday skiing or doing other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> time activities. The serious-minded, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Everson</ENAMEX> woman was found shadowing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> emergency room nurses during the days leading up to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> nights, the first year nursing student tagged along with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ER</ENAMEX> nurses <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristi Cramblit-Powers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Schell</ENAMEX>, in order to get a first-hand feel for working the emergency room. She also had the opportunity to visit the medical floor during her two-day job shadow experience.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> over the holidays visiting her uncle, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX>, who had put her in contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX>'s mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX>, worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years ago</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ER</ENAMEX> desk, so young <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX> was familiar with the community.   "I just wanted to see where she had worked," said the 18-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Pacific University</ENAMEX> student.   "Uncle Ed helped me make arrangements to spend time in the hospital emergency room over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Year</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX> added. She said she has always wanted to be a nurse. Even though working as an emergency room nurse may not be her future nursing career choice.   "I do hope one day to work in the area of pediatric nursing," she explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX> said she appreciated the opportunity for the first-hand experience. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice and Kristi</ENAMEX>, who is one of my mom's friends, were very nice and helpful," she added.   "We were happy to have <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsey</ENAMEX> join us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schell</ENAMEX>. "We hope she had a good experience," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlotfeldt</ENAMEX>'s request to shadow professional nurses is welcomed by the hospital administration.   "We try to work with individuals who are interested in seeing first-hand the world of nursing," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lathen</ENAMEX>, the hospital's director of community relations and physician recruitment.   He said job shadows and on-site tours are one way for the hospital to encourage young people to look up-close at careers in the medical field.   "We have scholarships and other incentives available for health careers students and we want to make them available to those interested," he said.   Persons interested in nursing careers or lab technician careers are encouraged to contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Garner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SCH</ENAMEX>'s director of nursing, or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Gray</ENAMEX> in human resources for more information.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

