
<P ID="1">Berry farmer presents fund-raising opportunity
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mike</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Youngquist</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Vernon</ENAMEX> have been farming berries, cauliflower and cucumbers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skagit Valley</ENAMEX> for move than 35 years. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean</ENAMEX> spoke to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX> about the possibility of selling berries as a local fund-raiser.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX> said her family first got started in farming in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1800s</TIMEX>, growing oats, which were shipped to the greater-Seattle area and used to fuel the city's horse drawn carts. As her family continued to farm, the industry began to change and the family moved into growing crops like the ones they grow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, the Youngquists, who form the company <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike & Jean</ENAMEX>'s, grow strawberries, raspberries, blueberries, cucumbers and cauliflower.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX> said the crops the family grows aren't the only thing that has changed in the industry. Processors started to move out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skagit Valley</ENAMEX> area, leaving the farm with little choice but to take its operation to a new level. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike & Jean</ENAMEX>'s went to direct marketing.   "It's really risky," she said, noting that they had to build a new facility and start dealing with different grocery stores.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike & Jean</ENAMEX>'s grows, processes, packs and promotes all of the produce they specialize in. She added that cauliflower is their largest crop. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX>, the farm hires about 200 seasonal workers a year.   In regards to the company's fund-raising opportunities, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX> explained that since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mike & Jean</ENAMEX>'s does do direct marketing they can offer organizations, like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Daybreak Rotary, a good price on berries. She said the club can then turn around and sell the berries as a fund-raiser, offering consumers a good price while still making a profit.   "The consumer gets a price they can't beat," she said.   When it comes to fund-raisers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX> said groups have their choice of selling fresh washed and sliced strawberries, raspberries and blueberries, as well as individually quick frozen raspberries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Youngquist</ENAMEX> said the strawberries should be available <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX> through 20, raspberries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5</TIMEX> through 20 and blueberries <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5 through Aug. 14</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

