



<P ID="1">Mayoral candidate squares off on arts funding
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s leading challenger to Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>'s re-election bid told a group of interested citizens that the city's struggling arts-and-culture sector needs support and money.
</P>
<P ID="5">"Arts and culture will never be marginalized when I'm mayor," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX> vowed during a speech on arts and culture held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Swiss Park</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. More than 50 people attended, including local artists, musicians, and authors.
</P>
<P ID="6">Earlier in the day, Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> released an eight-point plan to bolster the city's arts, culture and heritage sectors. The plan includes making municipal buildings available to artists to use and generating money by taking a portion of a hotel tax his administration would levy, as well as a portion of the amusement tax already being levied on tickets over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX>. 
</P>
<P ID="7">Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> also wants to build on the city's "cultural revival" through improved marketing of small- and medium-sized artists and groups. "We have many people hidden away. We need to bring them out and give them places to perform and help them build audience," Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said at his news conference, which featured a performance by two dancers from the Sage and Thistle Contemporary Dance Theatre.
</P>
<P ID="8">The mayoral candidate noted this particular issue has lacked strong leadership at City Hall, and some made indirect jabs at Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>. "Leadership on this needs to come out of the mayor's office, and that hasn't happened in many years," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX></P>