
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> told unsolicited publications, salesmen a problem
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Outhet</ENAMEX> just wants to be left alone and he wants the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> to do something to meet his needs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holding</ENAMEX> a copy of the Yakima Herald-Republic's The Scoop, which is a weekly publication filled with inserts that is delivered to local residents' homes each week, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members to do something about the unwanted material that is thrown on people's front doors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX> not only pointed out the Herald-Republic's publication, but said other unsolicited materials, such as phone books, cause a problem as well.   "I didn't order it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX>. "I don't want it."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX> pleaded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to do something to curb the problem. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX> said unsolicited materials left on a door step of a vacationing person can be a sign to a burglar that no one is home.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX> also asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to do something about the door-to-door salesmen who pester local businessmen.   As far as unwanted materials being left on people's doorsteps, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said he believes the city's litter code covers this problem, but said he will look more into the matter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> further explained that with the door-to-door salesmen issue, there is nothing on the city books that stops them from frequenting retail businesses. Under the city code, door-to-door salesmen can't solicit items in residential neighbors, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> said he was in favor of looking into the matter of stopping unsolicited materials from being left on a person's door step.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX>, saying he too is irritated with the situation surrounding the door-to-door salesmen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said salesmen frequent his business, but they come in with such items as fruit or other materials meant for his employees to purchase. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said there is usually nothing the salesmen have that would benefit his business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> also said the city is doing a disservice to local businesses who purchase business licenses by allowing the salesmen free reign of the city.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> urged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to take caution in implementing any ordinance addressing this situation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the city doesn't want to deter groups such as high school students or Girl Scouts from performing fund-raisers.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> directed city staff to look further into the matter.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

