


<P ID="1">Local Republicans hear from three judicial candidates
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">What should a person look for when it comes to choosing a candidate to fill an open position in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX>? <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>), three candidates for the position talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX>, noting what they feel are important things voters should keep in mind when selecting a candidate.
</P><P ID="5">   The three candidates for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX> judge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Bruns</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine Gibson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Tait</ENAMEX>, each took time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to tell local Republicans a little bit about themselves and why they hope to be elected to the judge position.
</P><P ID="6">   The first candidate to speak was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruns</ENAMEX>, who announced his candidacy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last April</TIMEX>. He said the reason he decided to run for the position was because he felt in order to make a change, a person needs to be involved.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruns</ENAMEX> said since announcing his candidacy he has spent time talking to judges in the area, trying to find out what it takes to be a good judge. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruns</ENAMEX> said in talking to different judges he found that there seems to be two kinds of judges in the system, activist judges and judges who treat both the lawyers and the litigant with respect.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruns</ENAMEX> said it's those judges who respect both the lawyers and the litigant in a case that make the litigant feel as though they have had a chance to be heard.
</P><P ID="9">   "They are the good judges...they believe in the system," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruns</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruns</ENAMEX> went on to talk about case loads, noting that Judge <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heather Van Nuys</ENAMEX>, whose position all three candidates are seeking, has had so many affidavits of protest filed against her that she has been rendered "almost useless." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruns</ENAMEX> said he feels that simply getting someone into the system to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Nuys</ENAMEX> will help alleviate case loads.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> then took his turn speaking to members of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX>, who was born and raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, said he has 27 years of legal experience under his belt.
</P><P ID="12">   Despite having so many years of service <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> said a lot of stock should not be put on how many cases a candidate for the position has tried during the course of their career. He explained that a person can try 30, 40 or 50 automobile accident cases, but they won't learn any more than if they had tried five auto accident cases.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> said over time he has tried a wide variety of cases and is now to the point in his career that he knows, as an attorney, how to handle complex legal matters.
</P><P ID="14">   "A judge needs to know how to sort all that out," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="15">   He added that his experience has also given him the ability to negotiate, which he feels is an important quality for a judge to possess.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> then told local Republicans that if they are not sure who they are going to vote for in the race for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> judge, one good way to figure it out is to talk to local lawyers. He noted that talking to lawyers is a good way to figure out who would make a good judge.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> then pointed to a recent poll conducted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Bar Association</ENAMEX>, in which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> was selected as the best qualified to serve as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> judge.
</P><P ID="18">   The poll took into account candidate evaluations done by 124 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> lawyers, who judged the three candidates on legal ability, judicial temperament, integrity and relevant legal experience. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> came out ahead in each of the categories.
</P><P ID="19">   The final candidate for the position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX>, then took his turn talking to members of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX>. He noted that although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> was selected as the best qualified in the local poll, only 1/3 of lawyers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Bar Association</ENAMEX> took part in the survey.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX>, 55, said he has been in private practice since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1975</TIMEX>. He said he was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, but moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> at the age of six. He also told members of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> that he worked his way through college and law school. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX> said he worked as a garbage man in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pullman</ENAMEX> while attending college, but also held jobs as a construction worker and a farm laborer.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX> said after law school he decided to come back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to start his own practice.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX> said his legal experience has included a wide range of cases, everything from adoption cases to probate. He added that he has appeared in courtrooms in at least 30 of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s 39 counties.
</P><P ID="23">   "A lot of my practice has been in criminal and family law," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tait</ENAMEX> added that his experience would come in handy, since most of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>'s backlog of cases has to do with criminal cases.
</P><P ID="25">   Although there are currently three candidates for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX> Judge position, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX> that field will be narrowed down to two after the primary election. The primary election is set to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 14</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




