


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds place sixth at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> 
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> volleyball team started strong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> at the 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament, but a loss <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> kept the 'Hounds out of the running for the title.
</P><P ID="5">   The Lady 'Hounds finished their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> run with a sixth place finish, winning two of four matches.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> won both of its matches <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. The team made short work of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steilacoom</ENAMEX>, winning by scores of 25-5, 25-17, 25-6. The Lady 'Hounds also dispatched Rochester by scores of 25-18, 25-10, 25-12.
</P><P ID="7">   However, when the Lady 'Hounds took to the court against Meridian this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>, things didn't turn out exactly how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> had hoped. The team lost to the eventual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> titlists 19-25, 15-25, 25-13, 18-25.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said Meridian had one excellent player, who was adept with her spikes and overall net coverage.
</P><P ID="9">   "She was the best player at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of the Meridian team member.
</P><P ID="10">   Following the loss to Meridian, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s first loss to a 2A team all year, the Lady 'Hounds weren't able to recover their composure.
</P><P ID="11">   "They were pretty disappointed because they lost their goal [of taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> title]," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="12">   He noted that when it came time to play the last match of the tournament his team didn't have its heart in it.
</P><P ID="13">   "Some of them were still a little disappointed," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="14">   And it's that disappointment that led the Lady 'Hounds to lose their second match of the day against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>. In the trophy round match that decided third and sixth place honors at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> was upended 25-20, 23-25, 25-15, 21-25, 11-15.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said he was a little disappointed with his team's performance against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kings</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>, but added that he understood that this team had just seen their aspirations disappear.
</P><P ID="16">   "They had high aspirations and when that didn't happen, that one goal, they didn't refocus," he said.
</P><P ID="17">   Overall at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tourney, staged in the Yakima SunDome, freshman Kealey Johnston had 21 kills, 7 aces, 53 service points and 113 digs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Johnston</ENAMEX> did an outstanding job at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   "She was probably the best all around player on the team," he said.
</P><P ID="19">   Also helping the 'Hounds were senior Danelle Cowan with 57 kills, 12 blocks, 5 aces and 34 service points, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> with 50 kills, 9 aces, 34 service points and 14 blocks, senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> with 12 kills, 6 blocks and 5 assists, junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> with 5 kills and 64 digs, setter Chante Bottineau with 121 assists, 39 digs, 3 kills and 3 aces, Tonhya Wysong with 147 digs and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX> with 4 service points and 3 digs.
</P><P ID="20">   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said he was happy with his team's performance, noting that this marks the fifth time in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last seven years</TIMEX> that the volleyball team has brought a trophy back from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament.
</P><P ID="21">   Looking back at the season, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team did well and he is looking forward to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. He said he expects the Lady 'Hounds to be a highly competitive team in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




