


<P ID="1">Few problems on election day
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">While federal election observers watched <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters file into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lincoln School</ENAMEX> gym all day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, election volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hazzard</ENAMEX> greeted voters with a quick lesson in electronic ballot casting.
</P><P ID="5">   The federal monitors, who declined to answer questions about their role in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> election, were in town to mare sure all voting regulations were followed. In particular they were watching to see that bilingual election workers were available to help out those voters who needed that service.
</P><P ID="6">   Meanwhile, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazzard</ENAMEX> handled brief tutorials in the use of the e-slate electronic voting system which is new in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "It's really simple if you follow the instructions," he said. "Most people haven't had any trouble with it in our area," he added.
</P><P ID="8">   While election workers heard a few grumblings about the state's new party preference ruling, most people simply stepped into the booths to make their choices.
</P><P ID="9">   "We have more people turning out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," noted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Kirk</ENAMEX>, a long-time election worker.
</P><P ID="10">   "I can remember years when we only had 17 voters by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>," she said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirk</ENAMEX> said as of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> more than 88 voters had passed by her station at Lincoln gym. "We should be getting a few more after 5 when people get off work," she added.
</P><P ID="11">   According to post-election survey results issued by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX>, only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> of the state's voters support the new primary system, while <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">79 percent</NUMEX> oppose the system. However, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">84 percent</NUMEX> of the voters appeared to be confident their votes were being accurately recorded.
</P><P ID="12">   Early <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> returns showed that of the 17,812 voters who cast ballots in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s primary election, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.9 percent</NUMEX> voted Republican.
</P><P ID="13">   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1.3 percent</NUMEX> of the votes were cast by people who voted for the Libertarian candidates on the ballot.
</P>





 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




