


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> school levy failing
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s bond and special levy measures, which achieved an easy 60-plus percent approval on election night, gained more "yes votes during the count of late arriving absentee ballots <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s four-year <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> maintenance and operation levy gained 208 more "yes" votes, upping the approval rating to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65 percent</NUMEX>. The levy issue received 1,252 "yes" votes and only 662 "no" votes on election night.
</P><P ID="6">   The district's <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> bond measure gained an additional 186 "yes" votes when absentee ballots were counted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>. The measure now has 1,376 "yes" votes to 817 "no" votes.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>'s <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$195,000</NUMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M&O</ENAMEX> levy also gained support <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. The measure, which received a healthy <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> approval on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, gained 20 more "yes" votes during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s count.
</P><P ID="8">   The Mabton measure received 221 "yes" votes and only 53 "no" votes on election night.
</P><P ID="9">   While the voters in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger School District</ENAMEX> seemed bent on approving their <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$515,793</NUMEX> special levy, it has failed to gain the necessary votes for a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> super majority.
</P><P ID="10">   As of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger M&O</ENAMEX> measure only had a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">59.09 percent</NUMEX> approval.
</P><P ID="11">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Election Department</ENAMEX>'s count of absentee ballots was delayed somewhat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, when the department's computer system failed. The election department was back on line by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> issuing the most current levy results.
</P><P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="13">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




