


<P ID="1">Council censure ok'd
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/20/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Public embarrassment? Well, that is not quite what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> says he is promoting with a new resolution he presented <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to publicly censure <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members who are more than 60 days delinquent with any tax or fee owed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   In a narrow 4-3 vote, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s censure resolution. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> voted against the measure.
</P><P ID="6">   Under the resolution, any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member delinquent to the city or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> with a bill will be subject to a vote of censure within two regular meetings. The resolution of censure will include all known information on the delinquent bill. The censure will also become an item on every regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agenda until the delinquent bill is paid. If the delinquent bill is owed to the city, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member's stipend, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> per meeting, will be withheld until the bill is brought current.
</P><P ID="7">   It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> who presented a strong case for approving the censure resolution. In a prepared statement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> advocated for the passage of the resolution.
</P><P ID="8">   "The issue before this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is one that will set a precedent for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and will provide a model, which will influence other governing bodies," read <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX>. "Through the implementation of this rule, we are sending an important message to the citizens of this community that your <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members are not above the law."
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> said the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> already requires elected officials and those running for office to disclose financial information to the public.
</P><P ID="10">   "The idea being that the public's right to know far outweighs any right that these matters remain secret and private," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX>. "The new rule will serve a higher purpose for the community, holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members to their promise of enforcing and supporting the laws of the land, by preventing abject defiance of these same laws."
</P><P ID="11">   "I think it is an accountability issue," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> explained that the censure doesn't affect a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member's right to vote on matters.
</P><P ID="13">   "It is basically the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> policing ourselves," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> elaborated by saying the community expects firefighters and policemen to be fit. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> needs to be economically fit. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said it is an ethical matter for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members in regards to paying their bills.
</P><P ID="15">   "If they can't balance a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22,000</NUMEX> per year income, than what makes us think they can balance a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$22 million</NUMEX> budget," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members need to be held to the highest standards, but had some issues with the proposal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> was concerned that city staff would end up having to monitor the financial records of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>, though, explained the censure vote would only come to a head when a delinquent issue was brought before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> also saw the censure motion as a platform for any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member who had an issue with a tax or fee. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>, though, countered by saying he would invite any <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member to use it as a platform to voice their opinion.
</P><P ID="17">   "We need some people who think taxes are unfair to have a forum," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> wasn't of the same opinion.
</P><P ID="19">   "When I ran for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> I didn't know I was going to be policing my peers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she doesn't think the censure motion is needed. She said there are a variety of reasons why someone could be in financial trouble. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> added that because someone is in financial trouble it doesn't mean they are not capable of making a good decision on the budget.
</P><P ID="21">   "I don't feel it is necessary," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>. "I don't believe it benefits the community in any way."
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Firefighter Bob Johnson</ENAMEX>, in attendance at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting, said he is against making the private issues of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member's public. He did suggest the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> adopt a code of conduct.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> agreed with the need to hold the members accountable.
</P><P ID="24">   "I don't know if this is the way to go about it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>. "I think this is a little too harsh."
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> added he has had family members with financial problems, but it wasn't necessarily their fault. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> added he wouldn't want to read about the financial problems of a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman</ENAMEX> on the front page of the newspaper.
</P><P ID="26">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="27">Webmaster
</P><P ID="28">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




