
<P ID="1">Festival of Trees kicks off the holidays
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">What has long been viewed as a gala to kick off the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> holiday season, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital Auxiliary</ENAMEX>'s ninth annual Festival of Trees will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 19</TIMEX>.   The organizers of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s event are again planning to offer Alderwoodrs an opportunity to break out their holiday party clothes and enjoy an evening viewing beautifully decorated Christmas-themed trees designed especially for the occasion.   Held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mini Mall, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s event begins at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> The three-hour social allows party-goers to support medical scholarships, while gathering festive holiday decorating ideas.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, 15 ornate festooned trees will fill the Mini Mall hallways, while party-goers socialize and enjoy hor'd oeuvres and wine.   The cost for the evening is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> per person and tickets are available at the door, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Maling</ENAMEX>, president of the hospital auxiliary.   She said proceeds from the event, which will include a holiday raffle, will benefit the auxiliary's medical scholarship program and hospital's equipment fund.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> we are inviting local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Hat Society</ENAMEX> members to include us in their schedule of holiday activities," said Maling.   The trees will be on display for several days at the Mini Mall before being removed for display at area businesses and homes during the holiday season.   "We invite everyone to join us in the unveiling of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s Festival of Trees," said Maling.   For more information about the event, call Maling at 837-1620 or co-president <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yolle Widdows-Guizar</ENAMEX> at 837-1601.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

