


<P ID="1">Voters being asked to maintain <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s quality of life
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A library is an important piece of any community. It serves as a place to gather information, peruse different magazines and newspapers, offers a wide selection of reading materials and can also be a site from which to search for your favorite musical group on the internet. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valley Regional Library Director Monica Weyhe</ENAMEX>, libraries play such an important role in a community that realtors often include information on libraries, alongside information on public schools when talking to perspective home buyers.
</P><P ID="5">   "It brings a quality of life to the community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="6">   That quality of life in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is currently being threatened. Voters are being asked to approve a ballot measure on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX> that if approved, will annex the local library into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> system. A yes vote, in effect, will keep the doors to the local library open.
</P><P ID="7">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Public Library</ENAMEX> currently contracts with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> for library services and materials. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> owns the library building. But, it is the regional library system that provides staff members, computers and other materials, such as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> reading program, for the local site.
</P><P ID="8">   The city currently pays <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> annually to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> for its services. If the annexation proposal passes it will go into effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2005</TIMEX>, and the regional library will reduce the annual fee for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX>, which is the amount set aside for the library in the city's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget.
</P><P ID="9">   However, it costs more than the annual fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> a year to operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> officials, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> it will cost approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$369,825</NUMEX> to operate the local library, which includes the cost of staff members, supplies and children's services. Besides the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> paid by the city, much of the money to operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Public Library</ENAMEX> is collected from people living in the unincorporated areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, whose residents pay 49.6¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value.
</P><P ID="10">   Other local communities that have annexed into and are now part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rural Library District</ENAMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moxee</ENAMEX>. The communities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Buena</ENAMEX>, Nile, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Terrace Heights</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Swan</ENAMEX> are part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rural Library District</ENAMEX> because they are located in the unincorporated areas of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> explained that just outside the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city limits county residents are already paying the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rural Library District</ENAMEX> rate of 49.6¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value. This is the rate <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city residents will pay if voters approve the annexation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Public Library</ENAMEX> into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> system on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "Your neighbors are already paying at the library levy rate," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   She said the annexation will give the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library a more stable source of funding, as well as provide for some improvements to the local facility. She said upon the annexation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library, there will likely be more funds available to put into things such as the library's infrastructure, books and other services the local facility offers.
</P><P ID="14">   Currently, the library serves 2,437 people who have been issued library cards, and offers services ranging from internet access to research assistance. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> facility offers a vast collection of fiction and non-fiction books for the entire family, as well as large print and Spanish language selections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay Saunders</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> librarian, said the local facility also offers a variety of services, including internet classes in English and Spanish, story time for small children, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> reading program for all ages, books on tape and CD, as well as musical cassettes and CDs and movies, both fiction and non-fiction for all ages.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX> said the local library also offers those who visit a chance to glance through an array of newspapers and magazines, as well as a chance to seek help from five library staff members.
</P><P ID="16">   "They are a rich source of local information," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saunders</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="17">   For local resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Kezele</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library</ENAMEX> chairman, having access to a library facility like the one offered in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is important. She said libraries are public places that are used by everyone, no matter their age.
</P><P ID="18">   "The public library is for all ages," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Public Library</ENAMEX> was founded in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1911</TIMEX> with a Carnegie Grant. She said the reason <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Carnegie</ENAMEX> set up the grants was because he felt libraries were the "people's university."
</P><P ID="20">   "I have always felt it was a community building," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettie Siliano</ENAMEX> during a recent meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Friends</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Library Committee</ENAMEX>. "Can you imagine the community without the library?" asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettie</ENAMEX>'s husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Siliano</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrice and Jose A. Villanueva</ENAMEX>, who live next door to the library, having the facility in such close proximity was a perk while they raised their children.
</P><P ID="22">   "It was nice for them to go over and do their homework at the library," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatrice</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="23">   The Villanuevas, Silianos and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezele</ENAMEX> make up a group of approximately 35 committee members who are working to distribute information about the upcoming annexation election.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said in order for the annexation measure to pass it must be approved by voters with a simple majority, which means <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> plus one person.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezele</ENAMEX> explained that if the ballot measure does not pass, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents will lose access to library services.
</P><P ID="26">   "People in the city will not be able to get a regional card," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezele</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said if voters do not approve the annexation there will not be enough tax base to continue operation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library. She said at a cost of 49.6¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value, a person with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> home will pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$49.60</NUMEX> a year to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rural Library District</ENAMEX>. She said if the ballot measure passes that equals out to roughly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> a month.
</P><P ID="28">   "I hope that they will see the value in that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="29">   She said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library is considered the regional library center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   "It's really an important center," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said. "It's hard to think about such a busy regional center closing."
</P><P ID="31">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents will have a chance to voice their opinion on the library annexation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 9</TIMEX>, in the special election. Those residents voting absentee must mail in their ballot between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 18</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="32">Webmaster
</P><P ID="33">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




