
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> seeks support for fireworks display 
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> needs your help to promote freedom's birthday   In order to finance one of the best <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> Fireworks displays in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> is collecting spare change.   Thanks to the help of community volunteer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, patriotically decorated donation jars have been set out at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> businesses to collect much needed funds for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fireworks display, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> president.   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> has generously allocated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> display," she said. But more cash is needed.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s gala cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> and we are a bit short," she explained. "We have mailed out letters seeking financial support to a number of community groups. We have already received several commitments for funds and several other groups have indicated they will be making donations," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smart</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fireworks display will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 4</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clem Senn Football Field</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   In addition to the fireworks display, a barbecue and 21-gun salute will precede the festive light show, she said.   On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 3</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> will host the much anticipated Come Back to the Country Soapbox Derby on Grant Avenue, with games and food to be featured in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>. The weekend celebration will also include the annual "Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>" Awards ceremony prior to the derby races.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions</ENAMEX>, in cooperation with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> veterans groups and other service organizations ask that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents consider sending a generous donation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions</ENAMEX>, P.O Box 1103, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>. 98944.   For more information about the fireworks campaign, call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Smart</ENAMEX> at 837-3898 or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Schlieve</ENAMEX>, 882-4498.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

