
<P ID="1">Annual Prosser Wine and Food Fair offers new attractions 
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - Want to sample some Singing Toad Late Harvest or Risky Business Ice wine?   Then visit the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maison de Padgett Winery</ENAMEX> tent at the 23rd annual Prosser Wine and Food Fair, to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 14</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Art Fiker Stadium</ENAMEX>.   New to the annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> wine and food festival, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maison de Padgett Winery</ENAMEX> will be joined by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Baker Vineyards</ENAMEX>, which will be serving its Voignier and Late Harvest Viognier wines.   The two wineries will be among 32 wineries featured at the "grandfather" of all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> outdoor wine events, according to wine and food fair organizers.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, wine enthusiasts can look forward to sampling the wines from several other new wineries, as well. Also new to the annual fair will be Alexandria Nicole, which will feature a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> Syrah and a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> Viognier. Making a first time appearance at the fair will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave B Estate Winery</ENAMEX>, which will be serving up its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cave B Chardonnay</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX>'s Merlot. Another newcomer to the fair will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Quixote Wines</ENAMEX> with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> Riesling and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> Gerwurztraminer.   These wines along with many others, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cabernet Sauvignon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">River Mist</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Drop Dead Red</ENAMEX> and Blue Franc Lemberger, can be enjoyed and paired with a variety of foods available on the grounds that day. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> there will be 17 food vendors to share the stage with the wineries. Fair-goers can expect to find everything from German Sausage to Raspberry Sorbet. Catering by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cathleen</ENAMEX> is among the new vendors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, and will be featuring a Tuscan creme cheese spread on a baguette and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> spinach dip with black baguette. For something a little more unusual, try the lamb burger salad served by Alexandria Nicole.   Once again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, the Yakima Valley Dairy Women will tempt fair-goers with their mini cheesecakes, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennewick Lions Club</ENAMEX> will offer shrimp cocktails and deep fried mushrooms.   For 23 years, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Wine and Food Fair Board</ENAMEX> of Directors has given every winery in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> a chance to participate in the popular fair, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Webber</ENAMEX>, board president.   "We send out invitations to all the wineries in the state and the first 32 wineries to respond are the wineries we see at the event," she explained.   "This event is very advantageous for the new wineries in the state. It serves as a venue to have thousands of people sample and purchase their wine, then spread the news about their wine," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webber</ENAMEX> explained.   The wine and food fair board's goal has always been to promote the wineries in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX>, she explained. "We have succeeded in doing that over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 23 years</TIMEX>," she said.   Tickets are now on sale at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>, which includes script and a souvenir glass. To purchase tickets call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> at (509)786-4545 or 1-800-408-1517. Tickets are also available at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Cellars</ENAMEX> on Yakima Valley Highway in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

