


<P ID="1">Casino/restaurant opening planned
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob and Sue Rice</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, as well as a handful of investors, are gambling that opening a casino in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> will be a sure bet with local residents.
</P><P ID="5">   The site of the new casino will be the former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elks</ENAMEX> lodge, located right next door to Black Rock Creek Golf Course. The lodge was sold several years back and reopened as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairway Restaurant</ENAMEX>. The restaurant was closed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. The monstrous building is now in the hands of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s, who are the general partners and majority owners of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RS Kids LLC</ENAMEX>, made up of a small group of investors intent on offering adult entertainment in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> couple is quick to point out that its new venture, to be called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RC</ENAMEX>'s, is much more than just a casino. A restaurant offering formal dining, as well as a sports bar and banquet rooms, will hopefully draw a wide array of people into the new establishment, they say.
</P><P ID="7">   The restaurant and sports bar are tentatively scheduled to be opened on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 16</TIMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s are planning for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX> opening of their casino.
</P><P ID="8">   The site being developed for the new business, along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, lies in an unincorporated area of the county. As such, all gaming taxes generated at RC's will go into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> coffers. There is a potential for the county to net a quarter of a million dollars annually from the gambling taxes.
</P><P ID="9">   A more realistic figure, says Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>, (perhaps conservative depending on who you talk to), is that <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180,000</NUMEX> will be generated in gaming taxes each year. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> bases his estimate on how similar sized mini-casinos have fared in other communities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, at the request of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s, lowered the gaming tax rate from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> to 10 percent-the same rate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Yakima</ENAMEX> assesses card room and mini-casino owners doing business in that municipality. RC's will be the first casino from which the county will draw taxes.
</P><P ID="11">   Ironically, the approximate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200,000</NUMEX> expected to be netted in gaming taxes each year at RC's could have gone into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s bank account. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2002</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s sought permission from the city to expand their bowling center, to include a mini-casino. Their business, Valley Lanes, is located in the heart of the city, directly across from the high school on Edison Avenue.
</P><P ID="12">   But when the couple began making inquiries at city hall in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late May 2002</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> quickly enacted an emergency moratorium on accepting license applications for house-banked card rooms. Later that year, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, despite the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Planning Commisson's recommendation to allow mini-casinos in the city, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> vote unanimously to prohibit any such gambling activities within the city limits.
</P><P ID="13">   "Our first choice was to do business in our own town," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>, a native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> who has operated several businesses in the city, including the bowling center he now operates and several mini-marts.
</P><P ID="14">   "Being forced out of the city to do business, we've had to spend more money than we wanted to," he continued. "The plan had been to offer an all-in-one package at the bowl, although the casino would have been separate from the bowling end of it."
</P><P ID="15">   What has <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> lost?
</P><P ID="16">   "Obviously, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$180,000</NUMEX> in taxes each year," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>. "Who couldn't use that kind of money?
</P><P ID="17">   "Our original plan was to have an all-inclusive entertainment center at the bowl. It was something we wanted in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, something that could appeal to families.
</P><P ID="18">   "The fear might have been that a card room would bring in trouble," he continued. "But card playing doesn't bring in the trouble. It's the alcohol that can cause problems.
</P><P ID="19">   "But we were already serving alcohol at the bowl. We didn't have trouble with that, and we still don't.
</P><P ID="20">   "There's not a lot of entertainment options in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. We wanted to add something to the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>, a professional bowler who still takes time to compete at several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PBA</ENAMEX> events each year despite his hectic business schedule.
</P><P ID="21">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s have not had to deal with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> on their current endeavor. Their new casino doesn't fall under the jurisdiction of the local municipality. The processing of the paperwork and permits has been through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Gambling Commission</ENAMEX> and with the county. Final approval from the state is expected within weeks, if not days.
</P><P ID="22">   Although the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> won't directly benefit from taxes generated at RC's, there will be an economical benefit via the creation of between 50 and 70 new jobs at the casino and restaurant. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s are currently advertising the job openings, which include everything from managers and floor supervisors, waitresses, dealers, security and surveillance personnel to cooks, cashiers and dish washers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> said the salaries should range from an average of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> a month for management to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13</NUMEX></NUMEX> an hour for the other staff members.
</P><P ID="23">   The casino end of the business at RC's will offer gaming enthusiasts several options of play. Already in place are two poker tables, which will afford card players both open play and tournament style action. Seven other gaming tables will also be operated on a daily basis, featuring such games as Blackjack, Pai Gow, Spanish 21, 3-Card Poker and Texas Shootout.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> said the casino tables will be opened to customers in the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late afternoon</TIMEX>, with a closing time at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 a.m.</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="25">   With the way the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s have configured the upstairs hall of their new building, the dining areas will be closed off from the casino.
</P><P ID="26">   "We want it so families who aren't interested in the casino can still come out and have dinner in just a restaurant setting," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="27">   The formal dining establishment will offer a full dinner menu, "...but there will be a flare for Italian food and steaks," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chef Rick Grindrod</ENAMEX>, who specializes in Italian food and desserts and has such stops as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snipes Mountain Restaurant</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barn Restaurant</ENAMEX> on his resume, has already been secured to oversee the operation of the kitchen.
</P><P ID="28">   RC's will also offer its patrons two sports bars, one of which will be a no-smoking section. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> said numerous television screens, featuring a varied sports package, will be operating around the clock for the enjoyment of all sports enthusiasts.
</P><P ID="29">   Also being made available to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents are two banquet rooms. Additional banquet seating may be added in the ground level of the building at a later time if the need arises.
</P><P ID="30">   At the outset, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s plan to expand the current parking area to mirror that of their neighbor-Black Rock Creek Golf Course. Down the road, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>, lighting and landscaping improvements are planned.
</P><P ID="31">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Black Rock Creek PGA</ENAMEX> head <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">pro Jeff Bender</ENAMEX> welcomes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> and the casino next door to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> golf course. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> said based on what he has seen first-hand at the bowling center operated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>'s, he's expecting a well operated, well maintained business that will complement the entertainment the golf course provides.
</P><P ID="32">   "My vision is that golfers will come here for tournaments, we'll give them a couple of drink coupons and eat lunch here, and then after the awards ceremony we'll give the golfers <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> in casino chips and go have dinner next door," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="33">   Such an arrangement suits <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX>, as well.
</P><P ID="34">   "We're going to be competitive in terms of specials for our customers," he said.
</P><P ID="35">   "The bottom line is we want a relaxed and enjoyable atmosphere here. We want people to come out for dinner, whether they're gamblers or not.
</P><P ID="36">   "It's a big investment. But it all came down to numbers, based on the area's population. We felt there is enough people here to warrant putting in something like this," he continued.
</P><P ID="37">   "But I'll be honest, it would have been difficult to do this without the relationship we have with some other casino owners we know. They have made it possible. They've been a very valuable asset to us.
</P><P ID="38">   "Our dream was to offer the people here a true entertainment center," he added. "Unfortunately, the only thing that will be missing out here is the bowling center."
</P>





 










<P ID="39">Webmaster
</P><P ID="40">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




