
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantwell</ENAMEX> bill would makeB Reactoran historical site
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Cantwell</ENAMEX>'s proposal to protect <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s historic B Reactor cleared the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Senate Energy & Natural Resources Committee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantwell</ENAMEX>'s bill directs the Secretary of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interior</ENAMEX> to conduct a study on the potential for developing the B Reactor and other key facilities as historical sites.
"The contributions to science and country made by former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> workers should not be forgotten," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantwell</ENAMEX> (D-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>.). "We need to preserve the B Reactor so that future generations will better understand the work of our nuclear veterans, their dedication to our country and the difficult issues our country faced during the nuclear arms race era."
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fourth District</ENAMEX> Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>) has introduced similar legislation in the U.S. House.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Medicare’s new prescription drug cards available
As of this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>, senior citizens were able to start signing up for Medicare's new prescription drug discount cards. The new cards are expected to offer seniors discounts on their prescription drugs of up to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX>.
Participation in the prescription drug discount card program is voluntary. Annual fees for the cards range from free to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> government will pay the enrollment fees for qualifying low-income senior citizens. Seniors who choose to enroll will be able to begin using the discount cards starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> withdraws from county commissioner race
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary George</ENAMEX>, who just a short time ago announced his candidacy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> County Commissioner Tim <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>' seat, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> he was withdrawing from the race.
A Yakima area businessman and community volunteer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> said the decision was in the best interest of his family and their future plans.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Puget Sound strawberriesready for harvest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>
It's been a sunny spring and that means Puget Sound fresh strawberries will be ripe and ready for market a little <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early this year</TIMEX>.
Puget Sound farmers are reporting early crops, with harvesting beginning as early as this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.
Those interested in traveling to the Puget Sound area to purchase the fresh berries can find sites that have the strawberries available at: www.pugetsoundfresh.org.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Chinook Pass opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>
At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6</TIMEX>), state highway crews opened Chinook Pass to motorists.
This is the earliest Chinook Pass has been opened for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> season since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>.
A combination of more efficient methods of snow removal, unseasonably warmer temperatures and below normal snowpack were what the road crews needed to complete the plowing, snow blowing and avalanche control work.
Chinook Pass is designated as a National Scenic Byway, and provides an entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Rainier National Park</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McClure</ENAMEX> school dedication ceremony planned
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McClure Elementary School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> will hold a building dedication and 25th anniversary celebration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 25</TIMEX>. Numerous activities are planned for the ceremony, which will boast a theme of "Our Children, Our School...Our Future."
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McClure</ENAMEX> students and their parents are invited to a barbecue that day at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>, on the playground side of the school. At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>, there will be a dedication program in the gym for all families and community members, featuring a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power Point</ENAMEX> presentation, a review of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McClure</ENAMEX>'s history and speeches by Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> Superintendent of Public Instruction Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Bergeson</ENAMEX>. Those responsible for the upgraded building, the architects and contractors, will also be sharing with the audience.
In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McClure</ENAMEX>'s "Ring of Honor" (retired staff members) will be present, and there will be a special memorial for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McClure</ENAMEX> faculty members who have died.
</P> 
<P ID="9">Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?
Employees at more than 30 county establishments that serve adult beverages will soon be asking, "Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?"
In this case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> is the designated driver.
Under the direction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Traffic Safety Task Force</ENAMEX>, the "Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?" campaign kicks off this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. Patrons at the participating establishments who identify themselves as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bob</ENAMEX>, and are with two or more customers who purchase adult beverages, will be served soda free of charge.
The participating establishments will have "Who is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>?" posters in their windows. Of the 34 businesses that have signed up to participate in the designated driver program, several are in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blue Moon Bar & Grill</ENAMEX>, Snipes Mountain Brewery, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fairway Restaurant</ENAMEX>, the Silver Dollar, Chompi's Sports Bar, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Pheasant Lounge</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mt. Adams Country Club</ENAMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

