


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Council</ENAMEX> takes first look at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> city budget
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> got its first look at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget. Although it's only <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>, council members are getting ready to pull up their sleeves and get to work on ensuring that the budget is drafted in a way that looks beyond <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, helping to ensure that the city continues to be in fair financial shape in the future.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> explained to council that over the years the city has felt the impact of several voter passed initiatives, noting that the city saw an initial reduction of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700,000</NUMEX> a year after those initiatives passed.
</P><P ID="6">   "How do we recover that revenue or make up that shortfall," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> asked council. He then explained that the city has made up the difference over the years through the additional taxes coming in from the new Wal-Mart distribution center, changes in operation and reductions the city has made over the years. And the city is expecting to make up the rest during the growing period that is currently being experienced. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said new construction, new homes acity make up the rest of the revenue lost due to the passage of those initiatives.
</P><P ID="7">   "There's a lag time between any significant event and something that will pull you out of it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said. "I think that lag time is now."
</P><P ID="8">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>, the city is looking at having an increase in its operating budget of more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$118,000</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. The total operating expenses for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> are estimated at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.5 million</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that the increase will be absorbed by the city through its current expense fund balance. He noted that council recently decided to try and keep the fund balance above <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400,000</NUMEX>, instead of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> it had been aiming for in the past.
</P><P ID="9">   "[That] will help us through the lag time," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> added that the preliminary budget includes the city continuing to provide services at the same level that is currently offered.
</P><P ID="11">   According to the preliminary budget, there are small increases in the operating budgets of several department funds. There is a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3 percent</NUMEX> increase estimated in the street fund's operating budget, although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the level of service is expected to remain the same. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said in the cemetery fund the operating budget is actually a little less than it was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, noting that over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> the revenue stream at the cemetery hasn't been has high as was expected.
</P><P ID="12">   "It could be pretty tight if revenue doesn't increase," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said of the cemetery fund.
</P><P ID="13">   The water and sewer fund could see a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.9 percent</NUMEX> increase over <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s budget, bringing its operating budget to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,972,840</NUMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX>, a rate study is already underway with the engineer expected to talk to council about any necessary rate adjustments in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   There is an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8 percent</NUMEX> increase in the irrigation fund's operating expenses, bringing the total preliminary budget to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$241,813</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> told council this increase comes from the increased cost of irrigation rates.
</P><P ID="15">   When it comes to the garbage fund there is also an increase in the operating budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36,010</NUMEX> increase will cover the cost of the community clean-up program, which the city implemented <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   The equipment rental fund could see a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23,420</NUMEX> increase in its operating budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the reason for this increase is the increased cost of fuel. He told council that half of the increase had to do with rising fuel costs.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> will take a closer look at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget in the coming weeks. The first budget session when council will begin working with the document is expected to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 1</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




