
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> teen looks ahead to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> Presidential inaugural
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - While most young people are eagerly awaiting the start of the new school year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Presidential Classroom Scholar Ashley Lara</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> is eagerly watching the presidential campaign between President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> and Democratic presidential candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>.   Even though she isn't yet old enough to vote, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> has an intense interest in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s presidential race.   "No matter who wins, I have plans to attend the Presidential inauguration," said the enthusiastic teenager.   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> junior, toured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. as a participant in the Presidential Classroom Scholars Program. The program introduces American teens to the inner workings of the federal government, allowing them to examine how current issues affect public policy, she explained.   As a Presidential Classroom Scholar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> had an opportunity to meet national leaders and to learn about careers in public service.   "I had a wonderful time in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C.</ENAMEX>," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> spent seven days in the nation's capital, where she not only experienced the hustle of life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District of Columbia</ENAMEX>, she also had an opportunity to tour a number of national monuments, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Memorial</ENAMEX>.   "We had an extremely busy schedule, attending lots of seminars and meeting lots of people, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Nader</ENAMEX>," she said.   "We also had the chance to sit in on a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> hearing, tour the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> and to attend a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> briefing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> added.   As a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. experience, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> met with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state representatives. and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> floor where the inaugurations are held.   No trip to the nation's capital would be complete without a tour of the Capitol Building, the Library of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ford Theater</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lincoln Memorial</ENAMEX>, all sites the Grandview teenager visited during her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> visit to the city.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> said one of the highlights of the trip was celebrating the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> at Fort McNair overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Potomac River</ENAMEX>. She also watched the changing of the guard and the laying of a wreath on the tomb of the Unknown Soldier at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arlington National Cemetery</ENAMEX>.   "We did so many things and I am very grateful to all the people and different organizations that sponsored my <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. trip," she said. "Overall, it was everything I expected, and so much more," she said.   "I made a lot of close friends from across the nation and hope to see some of them again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> when I return to witness the swearing in of our next president," she added.   "I'm very excited about the inauguration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>," she said, noting she is now working to raise money for her travel expenses.   Saying she admires President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>, she will support whoever wins the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election.   "Personally, I prefer the Bush-Cheney ticket," she said. "I admire <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. I believe he has stayed true to is beliefs and has a strong moral character," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> was also highlighted by her selection to star in a series of educational videos, which will be used by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction as a part of its "Student Engagement Project."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX>'s father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sabio Lara</ENAMEX>, said the videos are directed at high school students and their parents, explaining the importance of standardized testing, senior cumulative projects and other issues facing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>'s students.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley</ENAMEX> was chosen for the video as a result of a presentation she made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> as a nominee to be a junior representative to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Board of Education</ENAMEX>," he explained.   While she was one of five finalists for the spot, she didn't land the state board position.   "She was later contacted and asked if she would be interested in working on the video project," he added.   "It was very interesting working on the video and I met a lot of great people," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> said the video will be distributed to schools throughout the state this school year.   "It's been a fun year," said the poised, young woman. "I'm looking forward to what <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this next year</TIMEX> will bring," she smiled.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

