


<P ID="1">Synthetic Prion Causes Neurological Disease In Mice
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="4">Scientists at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton Laboratories</ENAMEX> have produced a prion protein that can trigger the development of a neurological disorder in mice that is similar to "mad cow" disease, according to a new study announced by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> institute. The findings demonstrate that prions, an unusual class of infectious proteins, can make copies of themselves without the presence of viral DNA or RNA, damage brain tissue, and cause neurological diseases.
</P>
<P ID="5">The breakthrough by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Boynton</ENAMEX>, and colleagues Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">A. VonRyker</ENAMEX> and Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Sanderson</ENAMEX>, was announced by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX> spokesperson <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurel Sulfate</ENAMEX> and is scheduled to be published in an first-tier publication.
</P>
<P ID="6">For the study, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX> and his colleagues produced prion protein fragments in bacteria, folded them into larger protein structures called amyloid fibrils, and then injected them into the brains of susceptible mice. The mice began exhibiting symptoms of disease in their central nervous systems.
</P>
<P ID="7">The amyloid form of the prion protein, which is thought to cause prion disease, was also found in the brains of the diseased mice. The researchers then administered brain extracts from these animals to another group of mice, which subsequently developed similar symptoms 90 to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">150 days later</TIMEX>. The disorder seems to be distinct from that caused by other known strains of prions, suggesting that the synthetic prion didn't merely activate a pre-existing prion in these mice and that the synthesized prion protein itself is sufficient to make infectious and disease-causing prions.
</P>







<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, </P>