
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> woman injured in one-car accident
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea M. Gonzales</ENAMEX>, 21, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was injured in a one-car accident that took place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> on State Route 241, 15 miles north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
According to the Washington State Patrol, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX> was traveling northbound on State Route 241 around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> when she failed to negotiate her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chrysler New Yorker</ENAMEX> around a left curve. She then overcorrected and rolled her car, which landed on its side.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX> was wearing a seatbelt, but was injured in the accident. She was transported by ambulance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
 
<P ID="4">Loophole closed to shore up <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DUI</ENAMEX> convictions
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> signed House Bill 3055 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, closing a loophole in the law allowing drunk drivers to avoid punishment for their crimes. HB 3055, which was sponsored by Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenea Holmquist</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>), protects the admissibility of breathalyzer tests as evidence in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DUI</ENAMEX> cases.
"Prosecutors from throughout the state and law enforcement community were frustrated by the letter of the law that made it difficult for breathalyzer results to be used in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DUI</ENAMEX> cases," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX> said. "The evidence was being thrown out based on the most trivial defense arguments, something as minor as the punctuation in the notice given to suspects when the tests were administered. This bill cleans up the statute so field sobriety tests can be administered and used as reliable evidence."
According to the Washington State Patrol, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of the more than 40,000 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DUI</ENAMEX> arrests in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> each year involve breath-alcohol tests. The bill clarifies the requirement of law enforcement officers to notify <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DUI</ENAMEX> offenders of their rights and obligations to consent to a breath test. Following the procedures spelled out in the bill, the breathalyzer test results will be admissible.
"Defendants can still raise questions about the significance of the breathalyzer test results, but they can't prevent the results from being introduced as evidence," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holmquist</ENAMEX> said. "This is a reasonable approve to justice that protects the rights of the defendant while ensuring that those who drink and drive are punished for this serious offense."
HB 3055 takes effect 90 days from the end of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> session, which adjourned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11</TIMEX>.
</P> 
 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merit Resource Services</ENAMEX> offers scholarship opportunities
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merit Resource Services</ENAMEX>, a state-approved chemical dependency treatment agency, is offering two <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> scholarships to area students. The Howard Kelleher Lifetime Achievement Award scholarships are named after Kelleher to honor his dedication to helping individuals and families in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> find recovery from drug and alcohol addictions.
The scholarship will be awarded based on a written essay. The title of the essay contest is "Are alcohol and drugs a problem in my school, how does it affect me and what help is available?"
The deadline to apply for the scholarship is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>. For more information about the scholarship contact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Merit Resource Services</ENAMEX> at 837-7700.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

