
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE</ENAMEX> teacher earns state accolades
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kylee Sonnabend-Liberty</ENAMEX> was so busy worrying about a fellow teacher, she didn't hear her name called as the winner of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WALA</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Association for Learning Alternatives</ENAMEX>) Educator of the Year award.   "I was shocked when my dinner companions told me they were calling my name," said the reserved <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> English teacher. She received her award during the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WALA</ENAMEX> spring conference held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ocean Shores</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonnabend-Liberty</ENAMEX>, who has taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>, said she didn't know she was even nominated for the state award given to teachers of alternative education.   "She goes far beyond what's expected of her as a teacher," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Babcock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> administrator   "She is critical of the needs of her students and re-evaluating how to best get the information to them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babcock</ENAMEX> said.   In the nominating letter to the state association, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babcock</ENAMEX> described <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonnabend-Liberty</ENAMEX> as a self-disciplined person who demands of best of herself and her students.   "Under her guidance, students grow not only in skills but in self-confidence and assurance of their abilities," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babcock</ENAMEX> wrote.   "She is a person who overworks," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babcock</ENAMEX>.   "It's just part of her make-up. She doesn't think of her efforts as going the extra mile. She considers it part of the job," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonnabend-Liberty</ENAMEX>, who has spent much of her career doing long-term substitution work, holds a Master's in education from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>. She began teaching full time when her career as a karate teacher came to an end as a result of a hip injury.   "I do tend to over analyze my job a lot," she admitted." I try to think of ways to do it better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonnabend-Liberty</ENAMEX> not only teaches English at PRIDE High, she works with students on their learning experience plans and with seniors working on their senior portfolios. She serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX>'s coordinator for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> (Measures of Academic Progress) testing and works to monitor students' reading progress.   She is also an active participant in the school improvement plan and the district teaching and learning committees.   "She is a role model not only for her students but for all educators, who truly want to make a difference and impact students' lives in a positive manner," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Babcock</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

