15 8 22 49 32 3
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Any ordinary favor we do for someone or any compassionate reaching out may seem to be going nowhere at first, but may be planting a seed we can't see right now. Sometimes we need to just do the best we can and then trust in an unfolding we can't design or ordain.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Salzberg</ENAMEX>, O Magazine, The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> of Intention, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2004</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>