
<P ID="1">Penalties costly, but Vikes victorious
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Nearly 200 yards in penalties stifled a strong start by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> football team this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyle</ENAMEX>.   But, the Vikes put up all the offense they would need in the first quarter on their way to a 9-0 non-league victory over the Cougars.   "There are a lot of new guys on offense," Mabton Coach D.J. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said of his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> crew.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said he has only three returning starters on offense and the rest are new faces.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Zepeda</ENAMEX> recorded the first points of the season for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> when he booted a 25-yard field goal. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s second score came when senior quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Harris</ENAMEX> hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zepeda</ENAMEX> on a 39-yard bomb. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> couldn't convert on the extra point.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> finished his passing night 3-of-10 for 82 yards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> racked up more than 200 yards on the ground. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Elizondo</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> with 65 yards on 10 touches. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eli Perez</ENAMEX> added 52 yards on eight carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> picked up 48 off eight carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Castillo</ENAMEX> rushed for 46 yards on 10 carries while Jovani Ochoa had three carries for 21 yards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said the 16 penalties <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> picked up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, which led to almost 200 lost yards, countered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s offensive output. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said that it seemed like any time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> would get a drive started, the Vikes would pick up a penalty that would set them back.   Defensively, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> was more than impressed with his team, especially since it was the first game of the year.   "They recognized a lot of things," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said he was impressed with how his players moved so quickly to where the ball was.   "No one had to make a tackle by themselves," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said the Cougars simply couldn't move the ball against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s defense, which proved to be the difference in the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s defense held the Cougars to just 95 yards rushing and 54 yards passing.   "We are more physical on defense than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "No one is afraid to make a hit."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said offensively <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> will run more option plays <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and it is going to take his younger players more time to figure things out.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> (0-0, 1-0) is going to have its hands full this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at home in its league opener against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX> has won the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> title for the past several seasons. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said he feels his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> are a more physical team than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX>. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Waterville</ENAMEX> brings to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> some experience, especially in the backfield.   "They have a couple of good running backs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "If we play our assignments like we know we can, we should be good."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

