
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/30/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> passes transportation inspection
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District Transportation Supervisor David Taylor</ENAMEX> talked to the school board about the recent transportation inspection. He explained that the district's fleet of vehicles in inspected by the Washington State Patrol twice a year. He said there is one surprise inspection in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> and a more thorough inspection done just before school starts.
Taylor said during the most recent inspection 38 buses were looked at and only a couple of issues came up. Taylor said there were seven lights out among the buses, but considering that each bus has 42 to 50 lights the ratio isn't too bad.
Taylor said two buses were pulled out of service, one was a mini bus and another was a bus the district plans on using for parts.
"Both of those buses were from the early '80s," Taylor said.
Overall, Taylor said the district fared well in the inspection.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Board works to set up sex education committee
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members came together to find a way to appoint a Health, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Family Life and Sex Education Ad Hoc Committee</ENAMEX>. The formation of the committee comes after parents voiced concerns about the sex education curriculum taught in the district.
Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> explained that more than 20 people had shown interest in serving on the committee, meaning the only task left was deciding how many members the committee would be made up of and who would serve on it.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> board member Bill Wells suggested the board be made up of three community members, one student, one teacher, one administrator and a chairman.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> expressed concern that one teacher wouldn't be able to represent the concerns of all teachers in the district when it comes to the subject of sex education.
Ultimately, the board decided the committee would be comprised of three parents, two teachers, one student and one administrator, with the group coming together to select a chair.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> approves discipline handbooks
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> members voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to approve the discipline handbooks for the 2004-05 school year.
Administrators from each of the schools in the district presented the board with a copy of their handbook, which was presented to students at the beginning of the school year.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEA</ENAMEX> contract changes approved
Changes to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEA</ENAMEX>) contracts were approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> pointed out that some of the changes included in the contract were provisions for elementary planning time and changes in leave language. For example, he noted that maternity and adoption leaves are now both called family leave.
Overall, board chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanne Kilian</ENAMEX> said the bargaining process went well <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
"It was a very good process," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said.
According to the board, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SEA</ENAMEX> ratified the contract changes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7">First day of school draws 4,684 youths
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Business Dave Plesha</ENAMEX> talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> about enrollment numbers.
Plesha said the first day of school, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 25</TIMEX>, there were 4,684 students in the district, which does not include kindergarten students, who didn't start classes until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 27</TIMEX>.
Plesha told board members that the number of students registered in the district increased by 265 students on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 26</TIMEX>.
He noted that the official count is set to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Sept. 7</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Early Learning Center</ENAMEX> has 20 students attending
Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Community Resources Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX> told members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> there are currently 20 students enrolled in the district's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Early Learning Center</ENAMEX>.
He added that the number of infants enrolled in the center is at capacity and there is already a waiting list for those wanting to attend classes at the facility.
</P> 
<P ID="9">WASL scores release date announced
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, Executive Director of Instruction and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Learning Gary Vegar</ENAMEX>, announced that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction is set to release <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) scores <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 1</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="10">First day of school runs smoothly district wide
Administrators representing schools from throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> reported to members of the school board that the first day of school ran smoothly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
"It went really well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School Principal Janie Hernandez</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Birr</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> said despite a few glitches, everything went fairly well the first day.
"The teachers were great," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX> said. "Everyone was upbeat."
</P> 
 


 




<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

