


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> grants variance for farm animals
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/1/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> granted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric and Georgia Porter</ENAMEX> permission <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to house livestock on pasture located at 626 W. Edison Avenue.
</P><P ID="4">   The conditional use permit was granted for the property, which is located within an R-2, medium density residential zone.
</P><P ID="5">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>, livestock are allowed as a conditional use in an R-2 zone.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said livestock have been allowed to graze the acre parcel in the past on a short-term basis, but the new decision will allow animals to graze there full-time. Property surrounding the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porter</ENAMEX>'s land is currently pasture.
</P><P ID="7">   The field is piped with water from a well, so water will be available for the animals, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Porter</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porters</ENAMEX> applied for the conditional use permit so they can keep their children's horses, cows and small farm animals they show in livestock shows and fairs close to home.
</P><P ID="9">   In their application, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Porters</ENAMEX> said they plan to bring in hay and grain for the care and upkeep of the animals when necessary.
</P><P ID="10">   The conditional use permit was approved on a permanent basis as long as the applicant is living at the address.
</P>   
<P ID="11">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




