
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> harriers finish up conference match-ups
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - Let the fun begin!   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> cross country team concluded what most will admit is a meaningless conference schedule. On the horizon is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> meet, the first step for those attempting to qualify for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> cross country meet.   Competing at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> boys and girls squads were upended by the host Bulldogs, as well as by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>. The Grizzly boys team concluded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> play with a 1-5 record. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzly</ENAMEX> harriers were 0-6 in league play this season.   In the boys race, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenden Scott</ENAMEX> again proved he will be a force when the postseason races roll around. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> garnered a second place individual finish in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, coming in just six seconds back of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">winner-Joe Darda</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darda</ENAMEX>'s first place finish, coupled with a fourth place individual finish by teammate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isak Bergman</ENAMEX> and a seventh place showing by the Bulldogs' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Jorgensen</ENAMEX>, powered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> to a 21-39 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley-Ellensburg</ENAMEX> boys match-up, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> prevailed by a 26-33 score.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>'s top finisher was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richie Williams</ENAMEX>, third overall in a time of 18:00. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> was well back of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darda and Scott</ENAMEX>, who clocked times of 17:19 and 17:25, respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rams</ENAMEX>, though, had superior team depth to knock off both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s match-ups. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> claimed the fifth and sixth place individual finishes to go along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>' third place showing, and also grabbed the eighth through 12th place individual finishes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cipriano Meraz</ENAMEX> had the second fastest time for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> course, clocking a 19:26 to earn a 13th place finish. Also competing for the Grizzly boys were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sterling Scott</ENAMEX>, 22nd in a time of 20:11; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Gaspar</ENAMEX>, 25th in 20:28; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Burbidge</ENAMEX>, 39th in 22:02; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dane Schmick</ENAMEX>, 57th in 25:34; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Warner</ENAMEX>, 62nd in 26:20; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Lick</ENAMEX>, 63rd in 27:47.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s girls race, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> were beaten 20-43 by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> and 21-39 by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. The overall individual winner was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Schubert</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>, who recorded a time of 20:25. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rams</ENAMEX> claimed the top seven individual finishes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercedes Martinez</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s top finisher. She clocked a 24:22 to earn an 11th place finish. Also competing for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Fuller</ENAMEX>, 23rd in 30:48; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelina Fernandez</ENAMEX>, 24th in 30:59; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Benitez</ENAMEX>, 27th in 31:23; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Mora</ENAMEX>, 30th in 35:25.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> meet will be staged on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>'s hilly three-mile course, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 23</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garry Lorance</ENAMEX> appears to be the runner to beat on the boys side. Regional action is slated to be held the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Saturday, Oct. 30</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> at a site yet to be named. The class 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> meet is again scheduled to take place at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> Willows Golf Course in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 6</TIMEX>).
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

