


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opts to leave damaged intersection as four-way stop
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> voted to leave the damaged intersection at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandridge Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Second Street</ENAMEX> as a four-way stop, for now.
</P>

<P ID="6">The intersection was damaged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX> when a semi-truck hit one of the overhead wires and a fire hydrant, bringing down several service poles and the stop lights they supported.
</P>

<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opted to leave the intersection as a four-way stop while the city pursues emergency funding through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Improvement Board</ENAMEX>. The funding would make it possible for the city to upgrade the intersection to include a steel pole signal system with mast arms, pedestrian signals and a new turn radius that would make it easier for semi-trucks to make it through the intersection. The estimated cost of the upgrade is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$262,000</NUMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves final plat for phase three of new subdivision
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> approved the final plat for Vista Villas phase three. The new subdivision is located off of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Highland Road</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">The approval of the final plat means that developer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Johnson</ENAMEX> will be able to begin selling lots.
</P>

 


<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves minimizing fence permit fee
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to minimize the fee to obtain a building permit for a fence.
</P>

<P ID="13">Previously the total fee included a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> permit issuance fee, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38</NUMEX> permit fee and a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.50</NUMEX> state fee, making the total fee for a fence permit <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62.50</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voted to eliminate the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> issuance fee, therefore bringing down the total to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$42.50</NUMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="14">Council sets first budget hearing
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> will take its first look at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this month</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members set <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX> as the date for their first budget meeting. The meeting will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> and take the place of the regular study session.
</P>

 


<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> approves annexation request
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> voted to approve an annexation and rezone request made by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Adamson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Adamson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck and Kim Stegeman</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="19">All of the property involved in the annexation is located on Pleasant Avenue in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, just outside the current city limits.
</P>

<P ID="20">The group petitioning for annexation is also asking that their property, which is all zoned residential through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, be rezoned single family residential by the city.
</P>

<P ID="21">The annexation request will now go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Planning Commission</ENAMEX> for a public hearing.
</P>

 


 






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




