
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> family first to participate in innovative conservation program
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SPOKANE</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Eight years ago</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill and Dean McLean</ENAMEX> switched from their traditional farming methods to a conservation-based approach, they believed their investment would pay off - someday.   Through the years, it has. They've seen erosion rates on their dry land farm reduced, soil quality improved, and their entire operation become more consistent and sustainable - even through prolonged periods of drought.   Recently, that investment in conservation paid off again.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McLeans</ENAMEX>, who farm near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coulee City</ENAMEX>, were recognized at a ceremonial signing event held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s first agricultural producers to participate in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Conservation Security Program</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSP</ENAMEX>).   Authorized in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farm Bill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSP</ENAMEX> is a voluntary program that provides financial and technical assistance to promote the conservation and improvement of soil, water, air, energy, plant and animal life, and other conservation purposes on Tribal and private working lands. The program supports ongoing stewardship of private agricultural lands by providing payments for maintaining and enhancing natural resources.   "While conservation incentive programs and technical assistance from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> date back to the Dust Bowl days of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1930s</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Natural Resources Conservation Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NRCS</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">State Conservationist Gus Hughbanks</ENAMEX>, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSP</ENAMEX> represents the first time agricultural producers are being paid for ongoing stewardship." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX>' agency administers the program, which is expected to be available to farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McLeans</ENAMEX> farm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses Coulee Watershed</ENAMEX>, which was one of only 18 watersheds nationwide - and the only watershed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> - to be included in the program's debut-year. Of the 83 applications in the watershed, 43 met the minimum requirements for water quality and soil quality, according to the NRCS. Of the 43 qualifying applications, 13 were approved for Tier I; 26 for Tier II; and four for Tier III, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said.   "Those applicants who met the minimum requirements will be participating in three different tiers reflecting both their documented historical conservation management, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said.   He said farmers who sign the agreement also agree to implement additional practices to further enhance the environment.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said that producers would receive annual payments between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$550</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,135</NUMEX></NUMEX> for Tier I contracts; <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$380</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,625</NUMEX></NUMEX> for Tier II contracts; and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,366</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,300</NUMEX></NUMEX> for Tier III contracts. The payments are for a broad range of conservation work that protect and enhances natural resources, including water quality, soil quality and wildlife habitat.   All successful applicants have achieved high technical standards for protecting soil and water quality," he said.   "Farmers, such as the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McLean</ENAMEX> family, are model conservationists who we can point to as our first line of defense in managing ecosystems like the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moses Coulee Watershed</ENAMEX> with both productivity and careful stewardship as twin goals," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said.   Nationally, the 2,188 farmers and ranchers who were awarded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSP</ENAMEX> contracts currently represent 1.88 million acres. Work done by the producers in the 18 selected watersheds will eventually benefit both their own watersheds and the people and resources downstream.   Announcements regarding which <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> watersheds will be selected for the program next are expected later in the year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said.   "Producers can look at the conservation activities of these successful <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSP</ENAMEX> applicants now," he said, "so they can ready their farms and ranches for the time when their watershed is selected."   The NRCS offers technical assistance and a "portfolio" of other conservation programs to help producers implement conservation activities that can help them qualify for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CSP</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said. "The key," he said, "is to begin early."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McLeans</ENAMEX> represent the best of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s conservation community.   "They, like hundreds of other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> producers, are doing what no single program or agency is capable of doing - they are protecting the natural resources upon which all future generations of Americans depend," he said.   "This is an historic time for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s agricultural producers, and it's a new day for conservation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hughbanks</ENAMEX> said.      photo courtesy of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s Conservation Security Program   Eastern Washington dry land farmers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill and Dean McLean</ENAMEX>, who have spent the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past eight years</TIMEX> investing in conservation-based farming methods, were recently honored as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s first agricultural producers to participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX>'s Conservation Security Program.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

