


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> voters approve school levy
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/28/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - After seeing a levy request fail by just six votes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger School District</ENAMEX> is celebrating in the aftermath of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s levy election.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> voters passed a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> maintenance and operations levy by a healthy margin of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">62.7 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "It's a happy day in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Dunn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "We were anxiously waiting for the final tabulation of the votes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> at the courthouse and started celebrating, when the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> polling places closed, revealing we had the necessary votes," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   The 345 "yes" votes for the M& O levy means the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> district will see nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.1 million</NUMEX> flowing into the school coffers during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="9">   He said the levy approval will be matched by state equalization funds for the tiny school district.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dunn</ENAMEX> said the levy funds will be used to add a new multipurpose/cafeteria to the middle school, purchase a new school bus and will provide funding for additional educational and sports materials.
</P>   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




