


<P ID="1">Still no decision on killing cattle
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A week into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> mad cow disease scare that started in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and officials still haven't decided the fate of the 4,000 cows on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dairy or the additional 400 bull calves that are in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> feeding operation.
</P><P ID="5">   Both the dairy and the calf feeding operation were quarantined <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> after the first case of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>) was found.
</P><P ID="6">   The dairy was home to the infected cow and the bull calf feeding operation is where her recently born calf was sent shortly after birth.
</P><P ID="7">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Cherry</ENAMEX>, spokesperson for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</ENAMEX>, a part of the USDA, investigators are still looking at options at both sites and talking with owners of the operations.
</P><P ID="8">   "If they can't identify the specific calf, which is what I understand is the issue, they may have to depopulate the herd, but there has been no decision made at this time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherry</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   She said investigators want to make sure all options are exhausted before cattle are destroyed.
</P><P ID="10">   The investigation continues into the origin of the infected cow. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron DeHaven</ENAMEX>, chief veterinary officer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, announced that additional records obtained by the infected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX>'s owner showed the cow as an older cow than originally thought. The cow is now believed to be 6-1/2 years old, born in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April of 1997</TIMEX>, just months before the feed ban went into effect in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> added that the chief line of investigation they are following maintains the cow came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>. DNA testing will confirm if the infected cow really was one of the 74 that came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August of 2001</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said they are also seeking out the 73 other cows that are believed to have been imported from the same farm into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "While reviewing records we have also determined that an additional eight animals from the same herd in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> were also shipped to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, so now we are tracing the location of all 81 animals," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   Even though only one of the cows was found positive for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said because of precautionary measures, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> remains at very low risk. He said there is nothing to indicate the other cows were infected with the disease.
</P><P ID="14">   "We can't pinpoint the exact time at which the animal may have consumed contaminated feed," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephen Sundlof</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>. "Feed is purchased from a number of different outlets, and even those outlets receive their materials from various different places."
</P><P ID="15">   With a case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, he added that it is only prudent to re-evaluate the precautionary steps being taken to screen slaughtered cows for the brain-wasting disease that occurs in ruminant, or animals such as cows, sheep and goats, that chew their cud.
</P><P ID="16">   The ban on feeding ground up cattle parts to other cattle for protein is believed to help stave off the outbreak of the disease in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sundlof</ENAMEX> said research has shown that as little as half a gram of infected brain fed to cattle, especially calves, can result in the disease in those animals.
</P><P ID="18">   "Half a gram is a very small amount, so that if it were to get into the cattle feed there is potential for that even very small dose to result in the disease," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sundlof</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   He added that although it only requires a very small amount of raw central nervous system tissue to infect cows, the tissues are sent through a rendering process.
</P><P ID="20">   "This reduces the infectivity by a factor of at least 10, so it would take 10 times that much," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sundlof</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sundlof</ENAMEX> said that cattle are more susceptible to the disease than humans.
</P><P ID="22">   "We don't know what the dose obviously is in humans, but it would be much greater than the dose in cattle," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sundlof</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="23">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




