
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
‘Liberty Quartet’in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 7</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WEST VALLEY</ENAMEX> - The "Liberty Quartet" will appear in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Nov. 7</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Valley Church</ENAMEX> of the Nazarene.
Described as an outstanding <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southern Gospel</ENAMEX> group, the quartet will perform at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> in the church sanctuary, located at 72nd and Nob Hill Boulevard.
A love offering will be collected during the concert, which is open to the public.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Frisbee</ENAMEX> tourneyon tap <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 30-31</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PASCO</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Frisbee</ENAMEX> enthusiasts are being urged to watch the action at the fifth annual "Hanford Howl Ultimate Frisbee Tournament."
The two-day event will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Youth Soccer Association</ENAMEX> fields, near the TRAC facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>. It is being sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Visitor and Convention Bureau</ENAMEX>, Desert Lorax and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Ultimate Frisbee Club</ENAMEX>.
Competition will take place between <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 30</TIMEX>, and from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Oct. 31</TIMEX>. Generally, four games take place simultaneously. The final championship tournament will be staged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
For extra flavor, competing teams will don <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Halloween</TIMEX> costumes in keeping with the theme, "Hanford Howl."
The two-day tournament will involve teams from across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX>. At least 300 people are expected to compete.
"Events such as these are not only fun, they benefit the community since proceeds from this tournament are donated to charity," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kris Watkins</ENAMEX>, president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Visitor and Convention Bureau</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sally McFarlane</ENAMEX>, the tournament's publicity coordinator, is encouraging the public to attend, at no charge, and learn more about the sport of Ultimate Frisbee.
"It's a fast paced team sport that combines the elements of soccer, football and basketball. Players try to pass the Frisbee down the field into an end zone to score goals," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFarlane</ENAMEX>.
"Generally, there are seven players on each coed team, four men and three women," she continued. "A very unique aspect of the Ultimate Frisbee sport is the fact that the game is played without referees or officials. It requires the players to call their own fouls and relies on what is called the 'spirit of the game," a concept that promotes competitive play but not at the expense of sportsmanship."
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

