
<P ID="1">Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> seeded fourth for Regionals
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">WHAT HAPPENED? This is probably the question of the hour for fans of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> girls basketball team.   After putting on one of their most beautiful displays of basketball skills this season <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">loser-out District</ENAMEX> tournament game, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> failed to show up <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was blown out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> 59-19 and then just couldn't hang <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, losing 60-34.   The pair of weekend losses put the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> as the No. 4 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> seed and gave them a first-round Regional loser-out, match-up at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.   Friday night</TIMEX>'s game against the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> was basically over in the first half. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> jumped out to a 30-13 lead. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> put their stamp on the game with a 29-6 second half showing.   "We took so many shots," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Leo Gomez</ENAMEX>. "We came out and couldn't hit a basket."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> was ready to play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, as the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> were geared up for a run at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> title on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> wasn't helped any by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiffanie Ulmer</ENAMEX>, who had her way against the less experienced post players of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> had a game-high 18 points.   "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>) were just ready to play," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "The game got to the point where we couldn't do anything right."   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> was much the same story for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> was simply ready for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s consolation pairing.   "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>) were a much different team (then when we beat them in the last game of the regular season)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "They put the pressure on and they never took it off. We shied away."   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mustangs</ENAMEX> flexed their muscles in the first half, outscoring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 35-13. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> played a much better second half, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said it was too late by then.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> are having trouble generating any offense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said he would like to see the same <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> team that took the floor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> come out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Tuesday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   "We just haven't showed up after <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s game and played how we can," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "Hopefully, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> we step it up and come ready to play.   1 2 3 4 T   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 5 8 2 4 19   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> 18 12 17 12 59   Scoring: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwood-Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 8, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 4, Bobi Haringa 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniella Rivera</ENAMEX> 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kacee Jo Bootsma</ENAMEX> 1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg-Tiffanie Ulmer</ENAMEX> 18.   Rebounds: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 7, Bobi Haringa 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 5, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanna Pangle</ENAMEX> 5, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 4.      1 2 3 4 T   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 9 4 15 8 34   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> 18 17 16 9 60   Scoring: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwood-Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 11, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 7, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatima Ruelas</ENAMEX> 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Alvarez</ENAMEX> 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 4, Bobi Haringa 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanna Pangle</ENAMEX> 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Caballero</ENAMEX> 2.   Prosser-Alex Lulp 14.   Rebounds: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 7, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 7, Bobi Haringa 6.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

