


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> presentation scheduled to come before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">A report from engineering firm <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gray & Osborne</ENAMEX> will be one of the highlights on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 14</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> agenda.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gray & Osborne</ENAMEX> will provide <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with a report on information gathered from a recent public meeting involving community input for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> road improvement project.
</P>

<P ID="7">Also coming before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX> will be a report on the city's water comprehensive plan, including information concerning cross connections. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will also hear a report on the new International Building Code that has to be adopted by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> will provide a report on an issue surrounding a law enforcement tax <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Sheriff Ken Irwin wants to put before voters. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will also consider a street closure request along Fifth Street on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 3</TIMEX>, which is being done as part of the community's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> celebration.
</P>

 


<P ID="8">Hand print project to done <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 19</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX> will finally see a long-standing community project she has been wanting to undertake come to fruition.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with a report on her hand print project along the guardrail just outside of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said the guardrail is scheduled to be scrapped and pressure washed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this week</TIMEX>. The guardrail will then be painted white this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">The actual hand print event will take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 19</TIMEX>, from 9 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> At that time, members from the community are encouraged to come and place their hand print on the guardrail as a symbol of community unity.
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




