
<P ID="1">Grizzlies capture first-ever Regional
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CHENEY</ENAMEX> - At the beginning of the season <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> boys soccer coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Pineda</ENAMEX>, who was recently named the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> coach of the year, said his Grizzlies planned on being one of the four best teams in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies are now just two games away from accomplishing their goal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, which entered the postseason as the No. 3 seed out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>, took care of business this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> and in the process captured the program's first-ever Regional championship.   The Grizzlies defeated a determined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> team, the top seed out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greater Spokane League</ENAMEX>, 2-1 on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> to win the Regional crown and a top seed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will host <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> in an opening round 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Tuesday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> The game will be played at the Grizzly football field. The Grizzlies beat the Falcons <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Tuesday</TIMEX> 2-1 in a shootout to gain an automatic berth to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>. The Grizzlies have owned <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> the past two seasons, losing only once in five games.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> had a very hard style to play against.   "They are a good team," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> runs a lot of overlaps. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> also has a style that has four defenders, which allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Blackhawks</ENAMEX> to attack or play defense with five players because of the set-up on the field.   "The boys were able to destroy that," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "It took a while."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> strung out his forwards, forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Blackhawks</ENAMEX>' defense to come up. With <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cheney</ENAMEX> coming out of its grouping, the Grizzlies were able to attack offensively up the middle, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s first goal came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior Martinez</ENAMEX>, who was recently named the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> player of the year for the second consecutive season. The Grizzly junior scored at the 15th minute off an assist from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Jimenez</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies' second goal was off an indirect kick taken by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> at the 26th minute. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> flicked the ball to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Galvan</ENAMEX>, who sent a header to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silvano Ramos</ENAMEX>, who sent the ball past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>'s goalie in the one-on-one.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> until the 68th minute, when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blackhawk Devin Merrill</ENAMEX> scored. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said the goal came off a corner kick that curved past keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Hernandez</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies outshot <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> 11 to 8 on goal. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> finished with four saves and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Hooley</ENAMEX> had seven saves.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said he was very pleased with his defense in the first half.   "Our defense played really well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "We stopped a lot of their runs."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> credited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> with making adjustments in the second half. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Blackhawks</ENAMEX> dominated much of the play in the second half.   "In the final 20 minutes, we had a lot of attacks on our side," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> broke down <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s defense by using a lot of long kicks to penetrate deep into Grizzly territory.   What worked well for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> overall, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>, was that the Grizzlies didn't try to reinvent the wheel.   "We were consistent," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "Nobody got out of their usual style of play. We were very disciplined about marking other players."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> did say he would liked to have seen his team play stronger in the second half. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said the Grizzlies need to realize teams are going to make runs if they are behind and especially at this level <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> needs to be ready an entire game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said it feels good to have won a Regional championship.   "I am really happy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "It is a reflection of every member of our program."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> expects <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s home game with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> to be an exciting one. The Falcons this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> ended <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley-Yakima</ENAMEX>'s string of a decade-plus of appearances in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament with a 2-0 victory to capture the No. 3 seed into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.   "I think they have had a lot of time to make adjustments," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "I think it will be another exciting game."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

