
<P ID="1">Red wine, chocolate fest scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - Like red wine? Chocolate?   If so, plan on attending the ninth annual "An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intimate Red Wine & Chocolate Affair</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 13</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Community Center</ENAMEX>.   The 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> event will feature red wine sampling, as well as indulging in a cornucopia of white, milk, dark and bittersweet chocolate. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> event is the kick-off to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Winery Association</ENAMEX>'s three-day "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Wine</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chocolate</ENAMEX> Weekend," where participating wineries will feature samplings of red wine and chocolates.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX> event is again being sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice organization. Event organizers say the fourth annual "Ultimate Chocolate Judgment" contest will be held that night, as well. The chocolate entrees will be judged by a panel of chocolate connoisseurs, with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150</NUMEX> cash prize to be presented to the "Judges Award" winner. For entry information and rules call 837-1676.   Tickets to the red wine and chocolate evening's activities, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> for singles and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> for couples, are available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice office on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Outlook Road</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.      Talent contest needs performers   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - Cash prizes ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX></NUMEX> will be awarded during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s amateur talent contest at the Fraternal Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> lodge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 24</TIMEX>, show is open at no cost to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> members and their guests.   For show time information and to sign up to compete contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> lodge at (509) 865-2229.      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Swing</ENAMEX> band to perform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 8</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Swing</ENAMEX> band of Smiley Davis will perform at the Fraternal Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> lodge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 8</TIMEX>.   The 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> dance is open to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> members and their guests. The day's activities will also include a one-hour open microphone session, as well as a potluck dinner.      Farming, ranching equipment to be displayed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PORTLAND</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - An estimated <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> worth of farming and ranching equipment will be on display at the 35th annual <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Agricultural Show</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Expo Center</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27-29</TIMEX>.   Equipment and tool manufacturers, as well as providers of services for the agricultural community, will be on hand. Antique and restored farm equipment will be a featured attraction at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s show.   Also, in conjunction with the ag show the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Horticultural Society</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nut Growers Society of Oregon</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Association of Nurseries</ENAMEX> will hold business meetings and educational seminars those three days.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Show</ENAMEX> hours will be from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 27</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28</TIMEX> and from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 29</TIMEX>. Admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for adults. Children under 12 will be admitted free.      <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floridis</ENAMEX>   in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The Yakima Folklife Concert Series will present <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenn Adams</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Floridis</ENAMEX> on stage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Great Hall</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 6</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolling Stone</ENAMEX> describes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adams</ENAMEX> as "...a genuine talent," describing the guitarist as having a clear voice and creating poetic music.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Floridis</ENAMEX>, according to The Missoulian, is a "...consummate guitarist/songwriter with a sensitivity and control that is truly mind-boggling."   Both artists will be performing with a back-up band.   Tickets for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> performance will be available at the door of the museum that night, and are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for children.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

