
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> blanks Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>, 3-0
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevie Fischer</ENAMEX>'s blistering attack from the service line carried the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellensburg High School</ENAMEX> girls volleyball team to a 3-0 sweep over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   The Bulldogs improved to 2-2 in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> play with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s night victory, while the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> slipped to 0-2. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will attempt to nab its first conference win <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> will play their third consecutive home league match this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>.   With the exception of the middle game of the three-set match <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> gave the visiting 'Dogs all they could handle.   In the opener, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> forged an 8-4 lead. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>' jumped out to the early advantage, thanks mostly to the back-to-back kills slammed by junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy Linde</ENAMEX> and a service ace ripped by senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> rallied, though, and down the stretch the two clubs stayed within a point or two of each other. In the end, it was the Bulldogs pulling away for a 25-21 decision. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> had four of her five kills <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> in the opening game.   Unable to get any kind of a run going when serving the ball, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was quickly dispatched in the second contest, coming up on the short end of a 25-10 score.   "We got all of our points on sideouts," lamented <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Angel Carrizales</ENAMEX>. "We never once served a run."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX> was a dynamo for the 'Dogs in the second game, coming through with nine consecutive service points.   "A lot of that had to do with our serve-receive errors," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrizales</ENAMEX> said. She explained that her Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> will be working on returning serves in upcoming practices.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> swung out to an 8-4 lead in the third set, "...but we hung in there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrizales</ENAMEX>. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> eventually knotted the score at 14-all. During that game tying rally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX> collected five straight service points, which included notching one ace from the service line. After <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> rallied to forge a 19-18 lead, the Bulldogs closed out the action with six consecutive service points from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fischer</ENAMEX> to end the game at 25-18.   Despite sustaining the loss <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrizales</ENAMEX> said there were positives that came out of the match. "One of our goals was to keep our service errors to just six. We only missed four serves, so that was a very good thing," she said.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>' top server was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linde</ENAMEX>. A jump-server, she blasted all 13 of her attempts successfully over the net.   On the negative side, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s girls showed they need to improve on their serve-receive efforts.   Individually for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Talia Spini</ENAMEX> turned in the best performances at the net against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. They each had five kills and two blocks. The team's primary setter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kacee Jo Bootsma</ENAMEX>, was credited with 14 assists, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> teammate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devina Martinez</ENAMEX> collected 24 digs.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

