
<P ID="1">Briefly in Entertainment
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Teens invitedto Granger dance
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - Teens 14 to 18 years of age are invited to a dance in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 9</TIMEX>.
Music will be provided by Mid-Columbia Dance Productions. The 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX> dance will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger Lions Club</ENAMEX> building (109 East 'A' Street). Admission costs are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per person and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for couples.
All funds raised at the event will be used to benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>'s National Night Out Against Crime city-wide celebration in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.
Organizers encourage the teens to "leave their attitudes and colors behind" when attending the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9</TIMEX> dance.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sportsman's Day</TIMEX> ‘show and shine’ set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 12</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NACHES</ENAMEX> - With proceeds benefiting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Make-A-Wish Foundation</ENAMEX>, organizers of the annual <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sportsman's Day</TIMEX> celebration in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> will hold a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Show & Shine</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
The hot rod and motorcycle show will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 12</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naches Middle School</ENAMEX>. Registration will be from 9 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> that day.
The show is open to owners of motorcycles and automobiles of all makes and models. Door prizes, raffles, a poker walk, rides, vendors, bingo and concessions are all offered.
The judging of the entries will be held from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>
Participants can pre-register, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>, by contacting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Todd Slagle</ENAMEX> (509-673-3235). Same day registration will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Car showfund-raiserto benefitcancer survivor
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ZILLAH</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lil Gibby</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fund</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> Car Show will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stewart Park</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>.
Proceeds raised from the event will help a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> family that has incurred medical expenses for one of its youngsters that has been diagnosed with cancer.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24</TIMEX> car show will feature three classes of competition—lowriders, imports and an open class. There is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> registration fee to compete.
Trophies will be awarded for first and second place finishers in each class, as well as for the best of show winner.
Organizers say live entertainment will be provided at the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> show, as well as door prizes, concessions and a raffle.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> gallery features new show
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - "The Spirit of Exploration: Celebrating <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>" is the title of a new exhibit at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Association Art Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX>.
The juror of the show is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Poppenga</ENAMEX>, an artist living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Milton-Freewater</ENAMEX> and working at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitman College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Walla Walla</ENAMEX>. She has a wide range of art, life and work experience that coincidentally includes wildlife painting and artifact drawing for archeological projects.
The works of the artists that were chosen for the special exhibit were selected on the basis of aesthetic merit, as well as reference to the theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>.
The exhibit opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 29</TIMEX>, and runs through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 13</TIMEX>. The gallery is located at the entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Howard Amon Park</ENAMEX>, 89 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Blvd.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Enumclaw hosts Highland games
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ENUMCLAW</ENAMEX> - Competitive Highland dancing, individual piping and drumming, pipe bands, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX> athletic events, traditional Scottish foods—you will see and experience it all at the annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Scottish Highland Games & Clan Gathering</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s event will be held at the King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Fairgrounds</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Enumclaw</ENAMEX>, the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> 31-Aug. 1.
Organizers invite everyone to thrill to the bourdon of the bagpipes and the cadence of the drums as they witness first-hand a fine array of talented pipers and drummers competing before judges of worldwide renown.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Enumclaw</ENAMEX>'s Highland games are the sixth oldest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> and the largest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 31</TIMEX>, schedule of events include an opening ceremony, the massing of the pipes and drums and parade of the clans, and a traditional <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Scottish</ENAMEX> party that is open to all.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Aug. 1</TIMEX>, a church service will be held, as well as a piobaireachd competition, a parade of the clans and a closing ceremony.
Admission costs each day are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> for children and senior citizens.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Hop Rod Brew Fest returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> area
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Puterbaugh Farms, located between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>, will again be the site of the Hop Rod Brew Festival.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s fest, as tradition dictates, will again feature beer and wine sampling, a hot rod show and shine, and hot food grilled by the Knights of Columbus. Children's activities will also be set up so families can attend.
A special treat at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fest, scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 10</TIMEX>, from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX>, will be the guitar and vocal talents of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Fortier</ENAMEX>.
Admission costs will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for everyone under 21 years of age. All proceeds will benefit the Knights of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbus Scholarship Fund</ENAMEX>.
Puterbaugh Farms is located on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley Road</ENAMEX>, just off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midvale Road</ENAMEX> that runs south from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Rawls</ENAMEX> to perform in Seattle in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-July</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lou Rawls</ENAMEX> will take the stage five times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8-11</TIMEX> at Dimitriou's Jazz Alley in Seattle.
With a voice as distinctive and instantly rcognizable as any in music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> will perform an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> set on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 8</TIMEX>, a pair of 8 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:15 p.m.</TIMEX> sets on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9-10</TIMEX>, and two more 6:30 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:45 p.m.</TIMEX> sets on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rawls</ENAMEX> is currently touring to support his latest release, "Rawls Sings Sinatra."
Tickets, priced at about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>, are available by calling Dimitriou's Jazz Alley at (206) 441-9729.
</P> 
<P ID="10">‘Roar in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Core’Labor Day</TIMEX> weekend
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">COEUR D'ALENE</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">IDAHO</ENAMEX> - Motorcycle enthusiasts and rock-n-roll fans need to pencil in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> weekend on their calendars.
"The Roar in Core" will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 3-6</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kootenai County Fairgrounds</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coeur d'Alene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>. The event will entail all aspects of the cycling lifestyle, including bike displays from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, interactive exhibits, vendors row, tattoo artists, custom bikes, poker runs and charity rides.
Organizers also promise top notch musical entertainment for rock-n-roll fans. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 4</TIMEX>, on stage will be Shades of Purple, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jude Bowerman</ENAMEX> and The Fabulous Thunderbirds. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 5</TIMEX>, No Quarter and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Frampton</ENAMEX> will entertain what is sure to be a capacity crowd.
The four-day event also offers on-site camping, a saloon and NASCAR simulators. The Roar in Core will be held the same weekend as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Coeur d'Alene</ENAMEX>'s Balloon Fest.
Tickets for The Roar in Core are available at any Tickets West location.
</P> 
<P ID="11">Hop industry highlighted at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> museum
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The traveling exhibit, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brewer</ENAMEX>'s Gold: a history of the hop industry in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">British Columbia</ENAMEX>," is set up for viewing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX>, 2105 Tieton Drive in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
The exhibit explores the multi-faceted and often overlooked story of the hop industry. Using artifacts and photographs, the exhibit explores the industry's development, the principal growers, the "hop craze" of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1890s</TIMEX> and the diverse cultural and ethnic work force that included First Nations, Japanese and Mennonites, each with their own story to tell.
The exhibit officially opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 2</TIMEX>, and will remain at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 1</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="12">Maryhill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert series gets underway <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MARYHILL</ENAMEX> - The Maryhill Winery and Amphitheater, in conjunction with  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Blues Concerts, announces the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert series. Scheduled to kick off the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert season at the Amphitheater overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX>, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, will be the Temptations, Hootie and the Blowfish, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Henley</ENAMEX>.
Tickets go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> Additional acts will be announced later.
The fabulous Temptations will be in concert at the winery  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
Performing for more than 40 years timeless hits and backed by a screaming band, the Temptations show is nothing less than a walk through American music history. Thanks to their fine-tuned choreography – and even finer harmonies – The Temptations became one of Motown’s most elastic acts. They handled both lushly-orchestrated pop and politically-charged funk with equal flair on such timeless hits as My Girl, Papa Was A Rolling Stone, Since I Lost My Baby, Ain’t Too Proud To <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beg</ENAMEX> and Just My Imagination.
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31.50</NUMEX> general admission, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46.50</NUMEX> reserved, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> dinner rail plus applicable service charges.
Coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 30</TIMEX>, will be Hootie and the Blowfish, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
Hootie and the Blowfish's mainstream pop variation of blues-rock brought the band to the top of the charts. Cracked Rear View, the group’s first album, was released in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 1994</TIMEX> and a single, Hold My Hand, worked its way into the Top Ten. Its success propelled the album to Number One, as well as launching a second hit, Let Her Cry, which was quickly followed by Only Wanna Be With You. Cracked Rear View became a full-blown music biz phenomenon—selling 13 million copies.
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> general admission, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45</NUMEX> reserved, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> dinner rail plus applicable service charges.
Out of all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Henley</ENAMEX>, who will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 6</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, has had the most successful solo career. The End of the Innocence was his most ambitious and commercially successful album, selling over three million copies and staying on the charts for nearly three years, launching the hit singles The End of the Innocence, Heart of the Matter, New York Minute, How Bad Do You Want It?, and The Last Worthless Evening.”
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59.50</NUMEX> general admission, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$79.50</NUMEX> reserved, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> dinner rail plus applicable service charges.
Tickets for these shows go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at all Ticketmaster outlets and on-line at ticketmaster.com.
For more information contact www.maryhillwinery.com or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gilbert</ENAMEX> at (425) 990-0222.
</P> 
<P ID="13">Train showchugs intoSeattle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9-11</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - The 15th annual National Train Show, the world's largest model train show, will be staged at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle's Seahawks Exhibition Center</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9-11</TIMEX>.
The illustrious event is held in a different city and state each year.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> extravaganza will showcase all aspects of model railroading, including the industry's newest and most unique products and services from national manufacturers and retailers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> and around the world. The event will cover more than 165,000 square feet of space, including 35,000 square feet featuring extraordinary operating model train displays.
Show hours will be from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 9</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10</TIMEX> and from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 11</TIMEX>. Admission prices are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX> for senior citizens and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for children 6 to 12 years of age. Children 5 and younger will be admitted free of charge.
</P> 
<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fireworks</ENAMEX> festival and concert setto be held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SPOKANE</ENAMEX> - The popular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Royal Fireworks Festival & Concert</ENAMEX> returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Riverfront Park</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.
The festival will again include classical baroque music, theatre, dance and pageantry.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>, the evening headline event will be a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1749</TIMEX> revival of Shakespeare's The Tempest, capped off with fireworks. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 25</TIMEX>, the grand finale will be the Royal Fireworks Concert, as Allegro's Royal Band will take the stage and provide <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18th century</TIMEX> outdoor wind band music, concluding with dazzling fireworks choreographed to the music.
A crowd of more than 30,000 is expected for the festival performances.
Additional weekend performances are being scheduled and will be posted on Allegro's web site in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> at: www.allegrobaroque.org.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24-25</TIMEX> weekend festival is free to visitors.
</P> 
<P ID="15">‘Mame’ auditions set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2</TIMEX>, 3
Over The Hill Theatricals will hold tryouts for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mame</ENAMEX>" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Aug. 2</TIMEX> and 3, from 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church
Tryouts</ENAMEX> for the musical are open to over age 45 amateur actors, who will present the play in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-October</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Hazzard</ENAMEX>, who will direct the popular play
"We encourage men and women, ages 45 and older, to join us in presenting this entertaining play about a bigger than life woman and her adventures," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazzard</ENAMEX>.
The play will be produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Sartin</ENAMEX>.
For more information about the tryouts or Over the Hill membership, call 837-3157, 882-2919 or 786-3990.
</P> 
<P ID="16">Yakima Folklife Festival bigger, better than ever
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - More than 100 music and dance performances at 13 venues highlights <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s Yakima Folklife Festival.
The three-day extravaganza is set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and Sunday—July 9-11.
The main thrust of activities will once again take place at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Franklin Park</ENAMEX>. Besides dance and music, there will be plenty of kids activities, a medieval faire, crafts and food booths.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 10</TIMEX>, park entertainment kicks off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> Between the nearby museum and the park, six stages will be set up, all featuring folklife musicians. Non-stop entertainment will be presented until about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> that evening.
For those who want to continue the fun, a contradance will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broadway Grange Hall</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and 11th avenues) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, from 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> Organizers say there will be line and square dancing to a live string band, and instruction will be provided for beginners.
The fun starts all over again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, July 11</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Franklin Park</ENAMEX>, with more musical groups performing from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
For those who want to get an early start at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s festival, six <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> eateries and pubs will host live music <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 9</TIMEX>. The sites include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant</ENAMEX>'s Brewpub, The Depot, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bob</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Keg & Cork</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Barrel House</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Greystone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Essencia Bakery</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> offers free concert series
MOSES <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LAKE</ENAMEX> - Centennial Theatre, located on the lakefront in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>, will again be home to that city's free <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert series.
Organizers say they have booked another exceptional season with a variety of talent and genres.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s line-up includes The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mills Brothers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 17</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rangers</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornell Gunter</ENAMEX>'s Coasters on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 31</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Misty River</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 7</TIMEX>; Lavay Wells & Her Red Hot Skillet Lickers on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 14</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Stewart</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 28</TIMEX>; and BeatleMania Live on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 4</TIMEX>.
Admission to all the concerts is free. The venue features casual grass bowl seating at an award winning amphitheater. Entrance to the theater will be on a first-come, first-serve basis.
</P> 
 


 




<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

