
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> grads tops in national automotive technology testing
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> graduates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Hazzard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Johnson</ENAMEX> have earned scholarships while attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Universal Technical Institute</ENAMEX> to study automotive technology.   The young men scored in the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> on a national placement test to attend their choice of the nationwide network of technical schools, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brett Schutte</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTI</ENAMEX> educational representative.   "They are representative of the quality students we've come to expect from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> not only to make the announcement about the two young men's good fortune, but to also honor long-time auto shop instructor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Paulakis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulakis</ENAMEX>, who has taught auto mechanics at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 22 years</TIMEX>, received a pin set, in the form of a gear shift, as well as a plaque from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTI</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick</ENAMEX> continues to turn out the kind of students who are making the choice for careers in the automotive industry, from technicians to detailing an auto design," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> visited <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to make the announcement about the graduates' good fortune while giving a recruiting speech to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulakis</ENAMEX>' current group of auto shop students.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazzard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> are both attending technology training programs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX> campus," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> said. When they complete their training, which may take as long as 12 to 20 months, they will be able to go to work pulling down salaries of up to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$24</NUMEX> a hour, he told the students.   Technicians with factory training can command salaries even higher, he added   "As long as there is a need to fix cars, truck, boats and motorcycles, there will be a need for highly trained technicians," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulakis</ENAMEX>' students to work on maintaining good grades, not just in auto shop, but in all their classes, to maintain a good attendance record and to keep their driving record spotless.   "Employers look at all of those areas in addition to your training when it comes to hiring the best person for their business," he said.   "As an employee in a highly competitive field you'll need every edge you can get to get the job," he told the students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazzard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> are among more than 18 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> students in recent years who have gone to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UTI</ENAMEX> and into careers in the automotive industry, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> said.   "They are among the thousands of young people who are learning that the days of the shade tree mechanic are a thing of the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutte</ENAMEX> told the current crop of gear heads. "You can't get the same on the job training you could get in your father's day," he said. The training available in technical schools is a fast way to become employable, he added, encouraging the students to carefully consider their career plans.   "Make sure you can get a job in the area you choose," he said.   There is a lot of money to be made in the automotive technology, he said.   "And a long as people drive cars, there will be a need for highly skilled technicians," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

