
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> resigns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> named interim city manager
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">While he still has a couple of days left of work, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> formally accepted the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> of work as city manager will be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Jan. 8</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> will be leaving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to become chief administrator for the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX>, population of roughly 3,500 residents.   "He has done an incredible job," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fonfara</ENAMEX>. "He has been wonderful."   "This city is a far better place because you have been here," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>. "You are going to be missed."   Following an executive session <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> formally approved the appointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> as the interim city manager. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also approved a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> pay increase for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> as interim city manager. Without the <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> pay increase, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>'s current salary as assistant city manager/city attorney is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,388</NUMEX> per month. This is the third time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> has been appointed as the interim city manager. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> filled in at the position following the resignations of former city managers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Fancey</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hahnfeldt</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fancey</ENAMEX> was forced out of his job in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX> after nearly 18 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hahnfeldt</ENAMEX> was hired to replace <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fancey</ENAMEX> and resigned six months after being hired.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> was hired by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Chelan</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Dec. 18</TIMEX>. He will begin his position in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 12</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> heads to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX> after 23 years of service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> was the city's first parks and recreation director, taking the position in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>. After six years as parks director, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> took the position as the director for the economic development agency, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX>, which he held for 12 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> was hired as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city manager in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> held discussion on the process for hiring a new city manager <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s executive session. Before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> could dive into the discussion, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan White</ENAMEX> stepped forward. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> thanked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> for his 23 years of service to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents.   "He will be missed tremendously," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>. "There is some benefit. I might have a chance of winning fantasy football now."   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> initially set the salary range for the new city manager between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,489</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$84,276</NUMEX> per year, as it currently stands in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> suggested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> change the posting to read the salary range read between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80-90,000</NUMEX> per year, depending on qualifications.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> disagreed with the direction <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wants to take with the salary for the new city manager.   "I think you are under paying this position," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> said he has always felt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> hasn't paid the city manager enough. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> said he felt the city manager should be paid in comparison with what <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> is making, which is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$113,000</NUMEX>.   "We need somebody to come into this community and do what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> did," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>. "(Paying) <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80-90,000</NUMEX> is not going to get that done. You aren't going to attract somebody at that salary level to do this job."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he didn't disagree with what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> was saying, but said it boiled down to financial resources. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> needs to stay in line with what is budgeted for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX> countered by saying the significantly smaller community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX> managed to nearly match <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>'s current salary in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. As city manager, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> was making <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,023</NUMEX> per month.   "If you get the right person in here, he will make it back for you 10 times," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">White</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fireman Bob Johnson</ENAMEX> cautioned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at dishing out any significant amounts of money for a new city manager. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> could be hearing back from the different bargaining units about what their respective department employees are being paid.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> answered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>'s concerns by saying that it is relatively easy to find firefighters, saying the city has applicants lining up "around the block" for the position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said the city has a hard time finding a city manager or police officers and he wasn't sure why.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> said he and Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> were going to take an active lead developing the posting for the city manager position.   "We are going to get rolling on this and get that posting out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> also wished <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> good-bye at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.   "It has been good <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>. "I wish you well."   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

