


<P ID="1">Elerding grabs two top six finishes at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Zone</ENAMEX> swim meet
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">We already knew his older brother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick</ENAMEX> can swim, but now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey Elerding</ENAMEX> is making a name for himself as well.
</P><P ID="5">   Elerding, 14, returned <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Zone</ENAMEX> swim meet in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Redding</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> The meet features the best swimmers by age group from 13 western states, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Elerding nabbed a top five finish in the 1,500-meter freestyle event. He was fifth in the mile-long event with a clocking of 17:24.89. The top time in the 1,500 was 17:05.46.
</P><P ID="7">   In the 800-meter freestyle, Elerding placed sixth in a competitive field with a time of 9:07.92. The winning time in the 800 was a clocking of 9:00.07.
</P><P ID="8">   "I should have had two top five finishes," said Elerding.
</P><P ID="9">   Elerding has been swimming since he was 6 years old. He is a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tri-Cities Channel Cats</ENAMEX>. The Channel Cats are affiliated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Swimming Association</ENAMEX> and compete in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> year around.
</P><P ID="10">   During the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>, Elerding dedicates four hours per day, except for Wednesdays and Fridays, to swimming. During the school year, Elerding swims for two hours each day, but puts in some extra time during the weekend.
</P><P ID="11">   Elerding will join his brother at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>, where he will be a freshman.
</P><P ID="12">   Elerding said through his association with the Tri-Cities swim team he has been able to travel extensively. He has competed in swim meets year-around in Seattle, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Federal Way</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pendleton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore</ENAMEX> to name just a few spots.
</P><P ID="13">   One of the reasons Elerding stays involved with swimming is because he enjoys competing, bettering himself and being involved.
</P><P ID="14">   "I have been doing it for so long it would be a waste of time to quit now," said Elerding.
</P><P ID="15">   The 800 freestyle is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elerding</ENAMEX>'s favorite event.
</P><P ID="16">   "It is the right distance," said Elerding. "It is not too long. It is not too short."
</P><P ID="17">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> marks the third time that Elerding has competed at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Zone</ENAMEX> swim meet. Elerding also swam at the meet when he was 10 and 12 years old.
</P><P ID="18">   By finishing in the top six in both freestyle events, Elerding qualified for the Senior Sectional Championship <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next spring</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   "The youngest people are usually like 14 years old," said Elerding of the competition at the Senior Sectionals. "That is what I was aiming for."
</P><P ID="20">   The Senior Sectionals provide a unique opportunity for swimmers, who can post qualifying times for such prestigious events as the U.S. Open and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Olympic</ENAMEX> trials.
</P><P ID="21">   A notable point about Elerding's outing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western Zone</ENAMEX> swim meet is that he hasn't swam either the 800 or 1,500 freestyle races that many times. This was only the third time that Elerding swam the 800. Elerding said there is only one meet during the year that he competes in the 800 freestyle race.
</P><P ID="22">   Elerding said he is happy to have qualified for the Senior Sectional Championships. Elerding added that he enjoys competing in swimming and doesn't really have any ultimate goal in regards to where he would like the sport to take him.
</P><P ID="23">   "I usually make-up ones all the time," he smiled.
</P>





 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




