
<P ID="1">Ethics topic of discussion at Daybreak Rotary meeting
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/18/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident and pastor of Our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saviour's Lutheran Church Ron Jetter</ENAMEX> has been spending time serving as part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> as a representative of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministerial Association</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX>, who served as the speaker during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>'s meeting of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX>, said the hardest thing about ethics is defining it.   "Our job is to put it into words," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said of the committee.   He said when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> was first created <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, it was created with the idea that teaching students to read and write isn't enough. Through their education students should also learn what is ethical, moral behavior.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> told Rotarians that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> is an organization made up of eight people. Four people on the committee are school district employees, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Supt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>, as well as representatives from the school district's administration, classified and certified staff. The remaining four members of the committee are made up of community members.   When the group was formed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said one of the first tasks presented to it by the school board was to create a code of ethics for the district.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said the code of ethics is three-fold. He explained first, staff members need to set a good example for the students, setting the bar high for excellence. The next component is the students.   "We want them know they're expected to achieve, and to treat others with respect," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said.   The final part of the three-fold plan involves parents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said the committee had a difficult time deciding whether or not the school district had any right to tell parents what is expected of them. In the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said, the parent component has proven to be one of the most important portions of the code of ethics. He said parents play a vital role in supporting children through school involvement, as well as helping them make ethical decisions.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said since the creation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> the school board had brought several important issues to them, including whether or not armed police officers should be on school campuses.   "We spent a few weeks on that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said, noting that the committee took time to talk to the local police chief, as well as the student resource officer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said the group has also tackled the issue of branding, which is when a school district signs an exclusive contract to market a particular product on school grounds.   The most recent issue the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ethics Committee</ENAMEX> has taken on involves the athletic code. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> explained that there is a portion of the athletic code that deals with the use of alcohol, tobacco and drugs and what happens if a student is found to be using the substances or found in the vicinity of minors who are using the substances.   "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety percent</NUMEX> of the issues that come to us have nothing to do with books and teaching," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jetter</ENAMEX> said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

