


<P ID="1">Neptunes no match for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharks</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Full throttle. That's how the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sharks</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> swim team attacked the visiting Grandview Neptunes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The defending <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swim League</ENAMEX> champions throttled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, 551-278. The victory boosted <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s record to 3-1 on the season.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Sharks</ENAMEX> were firing on all cylinders <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. They won 48 races to just 26 wins garnered by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> also managed to outscore the Neptunes by a 144-84 margin in second place points, collecting 36 runner-up finishes in the individual races to only 21 second place finishes by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s girls were especially formidable <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. They won 33 of the 37 girls races.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Knee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Castillo</ENAMEX> made the biggest splashes for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Sharks</ENAMEX>. Knee won all five of the girls 14&U individual races. She also was on both girls 14&U winning relay teams. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> pulled the same trick in the girls 10&U events.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Dolan</ENAMEX> turned in a super effort, as well. She won four of the five girls 12&U individual races, and sparked her club to two relay victories, too. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preventing Dolan</ENAMEX> from getting the sweep was <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinzi Poteet</ENAMEX>, who claimed top honors in the 50-meter breaststroke. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Poteet</ENAMEX> edged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolan</ENAMEX> by 19 one-hundredth's of a second.
</P><P ID="10">   Girls 8&U swimmers Sydnee Hernandez and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Broersma</ENAMEX> collected all the first place points for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in that age division. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hernandez</ENAMEX> was a three-time winner, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Broersma</ENAMEX> taking the 50-meter breaststroke.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Sharks</ENAMEX>' girls 18&U competitors also didn't allow <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to pick up a single win. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Matson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Razey</ENAMEX> each nabbed two individual victories, with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> teammate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Kresse</ENAMEX> grabbing the other. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> also won both of the relay events in that age division.
</P><P ID="12">   The only age grouping on the girls side that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> dominated was at 16&U. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allison Grow</ENAMEX> was a three-time winner for the Neptunes. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachelle Durfey</ENAMEX> got the two other individual wins.
</P><P ID="13">   As much as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Sharks</ENAMEX> dominated <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> didn't let the evening go by without showing it had several quality swimmers of its own.
</P><P ID="14">   The Neptunes' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jared Churchill</ENAMEX> was a one-man wrecking crew at 10&U. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> won all five individual races. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristian Vargas</ENAMEX> provided <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Churchill</ENAMEX> with the biggest challenge, finishing second in four of the five events.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> also won four of the five boys 12&U individual events. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Contreras</ENAMEX> was victorious twice, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> teammates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Mottice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Michener</ENAMEX> each nailed down one victory. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Preventing</ENAMEX> the Neptunes from a sweep was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Sharks</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Hollander</ENAMEX>, who won the 200-meter individual medley.
</P><P ID="16">   The Neptunes also dominated the boys 14&U and 16&U age divisions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jase Michener</ENAMEX> picked up three wins for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, and teammate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Concienne</ENAMEX> got the other two 14&U victories. At 16&U, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Robillard</ENAMEX> was a four-time winner for the Neptunes. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Knee</ENAMEX> gained the other 16&U win.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad Tyhuis</ENAMEX> cleaned up in the boys 8&U events. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> dynamo won all four races.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, too, looked strong in the boys 18&U races. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasey Hursh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Howat</ENAMEX> each won twice, and fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shark Kaleb Hursh</ENAMEX> was a one-time winner.
</P>   
<P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at
</P><P ID="20">   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him
</P><P ID="21">   at bstory@hawkpress.com
</P><P ID="22">   First place finishers
</P><P ID="23">   Girls 8&U (S) Sydnee Hernandez-3, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Broersma-1</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="24">   Girls 10&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Castillo-7</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordain Saenz-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marisa Broersma-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tara Van</ENAMEX> Corbach-2;
</P><P ID="25">   Girls 12&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alissa Martin-2</ENAMEX>, (S) Josslyn Ahumada-1, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Dolan-6</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Siller-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Schlenker-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinzi</ENAMEX> Poteet-1;
</P><P ID="26">   Girls 14&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Knee-7</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Mendoza-1</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaitlyn Broersma-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Anderson-1</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="27">   Girls 16&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachelle Durfey-3</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allison Grow-3</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="28">   Girls 18&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Matson-4</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Razey-4</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Kresse-3</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Henry-1</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="29">   Boys 8&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tad Tyhuis-4</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="30">   Boys 10&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristian Vargas-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni Rodriguez-2</ENAMEX>, (S) Darick Anderson-1, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Garza-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grant Stutesman-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jared Churchill-5</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="31">   Boys 12&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Hollander-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trent Mattice-3</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Contreras-4</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Michener-3</ENAMEX>, (G) Christian Salinas-1, (G) J. Churchill-1;
</P><P ID="32">   Boys 14&U (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Concienne-4</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Charvet-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jase Michener-5</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Womach-2</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="33">   Boys 16&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Knee-3</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Kresse-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Robillard-4</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="34">   Boys 18&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasey Hursh-4</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Howat-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaleb Hursh-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Morris-1</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="35">   Second place finishers
</P><P ID="36">   Girls 8&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany Broersma-2</ENAMEX>, (S) Lyndsee Anderson-1, (S) Sydnee Hernandez-1;
</P><P ID="37">   Girls 10&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marisa Broersma-3</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jordain Saenz-2</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="38">   Girls 12&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Dolan-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kinzi</ENAMEX> Poteet-4;
</P><P ID="39">   Girls 14&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sidney Mottice-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cheyenne</ENAMEX> Bank-1;
</P><P ID="40">   Girls 16&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachelle Durfey-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allison Grow-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Britney Sanchez-1</ENAMEX>, (G) Larell Michener-1;
</P><P ID="41">   Girls 18&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Kresse-2</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Matson-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Cowan-1</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="42">   Boys 8&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Garza-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bryce Carpenter-3</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="43">   Boys 10&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristian Vargas-4</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Giovanni Rodriguez-1</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="44">   Boys 12&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Luff-1</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Hollander-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Contreras-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Michener-1</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="45">   Boys 14&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexander Henry-1</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Concienne-2</ENAMEX>, (G) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jase Michener-2</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="46">   Boys 16&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Kresse-3</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Knee-2</ENAMEX>;
</P><P ID="47">   Boys 18&U (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Morris-1</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kasey Hursh-1</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Howat-1</ENAMEX>, (S) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kaleb Hursh-1</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="48">Webmaster
</P><P ID="49">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




