


<P ID="1">Construction of jail at county fairgrounds to begin in next few weeks
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/25/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - In the next couple of weeks people living near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fairgrounds</ENAMEX> could see some movement as far as construction of the new county jail is concerned.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Jundt</ENAMEX>, jail project manager, said stage one of the jail project is already under contract, permits are in place and construction should be starting soon.
</P><P ID="6">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners voted to set a bid opening date for bid package two for the first phase of stage one of the jail project. The bid opening was set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 16</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jundt</ENAMEX> explained that phase one of the project includes two stages that will ultimately lead to two 288-bed housing facilities being built, as well as an administration building. The first stage of the project involves the construction of the first 288-bed facility, with the second phase including the second 288-bed facility and the administration building. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jundt</ENAMEX> said plans are still being compiled for stage two.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jundt</ENAMEX> said at this point phase one of the project includes all of the current plans for the jail site, located near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fairgrounds</ENAMEX>. He said phase two of the project will be looked at in the future, when more housing capacity is needed.
</P><P ID="9">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jundt</ENAMEX>, bid package one for the first stage of phase one of the project was the contract to transfer the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pierce County</ENAMEX> facility from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pierce County</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> jail site, as well as the work to transform the temporary facility into a permanent structure.
</P><P ID="10">   He said bid package two includes some site work, as well as some work to the building's interior. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jundt</ENAMEX> said the site work includes work on curbs, gutters and sidewalks, while the interior work includes some structural construction, including stud walls, ceilings and floors.
</P><P ID="11">   Although work is scheduled to begin soon, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jundt</ENAMEX> said paperwork has been filed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX> for an injunction on the project. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Superior Court</ENAMEX> officials, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert DeAtley</ENAMEX> filed a petition for review for an injunction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>. If an injunction is granted, it could potentially stop work on the site. A hearing date has been set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2</TIMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




