
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CLEVELAND LEE MITCHELL
CLEVELAND LEE MITCHELL
Cleveland Lee “Cleve” Mitchell</ENAMEX>, 73, long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> resident, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 5, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parkside Care Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 22, 1930</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lubbock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sadie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cates</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Mitchell</ENAMEX>. He worked in the oil fields and was a beekeeper, pig farmer, carpenter and owner of a dairy farm, and managed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> Rise Resort in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Copalis Beach</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod Mitchell</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Shelton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Hatch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McMinnville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Mitchell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Mason</ENAMEX> (Loffer) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cornelius</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; 13 grandchildren; 10 great-grandchildren; five siblings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanie Dalrymple</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Riggins</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Parker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jean Alexander</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Philip</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gil</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Wells</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>; and one uncle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Cates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baja</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>
He was preceded in death by his parents; his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelda</ENAMEX>; and one grandson, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Differding</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 8, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 9, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ANTONIO URRUTIA
Antonio “Tony” Urrutia</ENAMEX>, 68, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 5, 2004</TIMEX>, at his home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13, 1936</TIMEX> to Macedonio and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benita</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, graduating with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2, 1957</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Padilla</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Following their marriage they moved to Seattle, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX> for one year. Later moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> worked construction on various dams on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX> and he worked for a short time at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>. He also worked for Mountain States Construction for several years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> owned a cherry orchard on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Heffron Road</ENAMEX> and a 20-acre farm on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snipes Pump Road</ENAMEX>, where he farmed various produce over the years and Concord grapes.
He was a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Carpenters Local Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church Advisory Board</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hospital Board</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cemetery Board</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> cherished spending time with his family, camping and going to the beach, watching them participate in various school activities, supporting them in all their endeavors, especially basketball. He also took special pride watching his son and son-in-law coach basketball and football. His latest joy was seeing his granddaughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie</ENAMEX>, coach at the college level.
He is survived by his wife of 47 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Urrutia</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Urrutia</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora Urrutia</ENAMEX> of Outlook and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MaryAnn Potter</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; six grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Urrutia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenna Urrutia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerri Urrutia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Potter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Potter</ENAMEX>; and twin great-grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Wells</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Wells II</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by four brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Urrutia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art Urrutia</ENAMEX>, both of Seattle, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Urrutia</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bence Urrutia</ENAMEX> of Auburn; and five sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Maltos</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Cruz</ENAMEX>, Lupe Gutierrez and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eva Martinez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his parents; and one infant sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isabel</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 8, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 9, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Cemetery, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. In lieu of flowers, those wishing to honor Tony’s memory may contribute to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

