


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Consent items OK’d by council
</P>

<P ID="5">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved the consent items on <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s agenda.
</P>

<P ID="6">The approval of the consent items included the minutes of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 13</TIMEX> meeting, as well as a list of vouchers for payment that totaled <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$494,335</NUMEX>. Also approved by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harley and Nancy Riel</ENAMEX>'s request for a renewal of their liquor license at The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pub</ENAMEX>, located at 432 S. Sixth St.
</P>

 


<P ID="7">Resolution
adopted for
land acquisition procedures
</P>

<P ID="8">A resolution adopted by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> paves the way for the completion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> improvement project.
</P>

<P ID="9">Because federal funds are being used for the upgrade, the project falls under the jurisdiction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Highway Administration</ENAMEX>. One of the components of compliance with the federal agency is adopting a "Right of Way Procedures," which is applicable to acquisitions of rights-of-way that are necessary to complete the project. Because the city personnel that were designated for such acquisitions have changed since the last street improvement project in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, a resolution was adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> that provides an updated procedure.
</P>

<P ID="10">In essence, new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> is now designated to handle all administrative settlements relating to land acquisitions, including executing right of way procedures on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The resolution also calls for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Engineer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bridges</ENAMEX> to serve as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> project acquisition officer.
</P>

 


<P ID="11">Bicycles declared surplus items
</P>

<P ID="12">More than 70 bicycles the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> has recovered or found since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> will be disposed of through either sealed bid, auction or donated to a charitable organization.
</P>

<P ID="13">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> adopted a resolution that declares the bicycles as surplus items.
</P>

<P ID="14">Under state law, the local police department had to attempt to locate the owners of the bicycles before they could be declared as surplus.
</P>

 


<P ID="15">Deal struck
to house prisoners from westside
</P>

<P ID="16">An interlocal jail agreement between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountlake Terrace</ENAMEX> was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17">The agreement calls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> to accept prisoners from the Seattle area community at a rate of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> per day. The obligation to accept <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountlake Terrace</ENAMEX> prisoners is on a "space available" basis.
</P>

<P ID="18">Terms of the agreement include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> providing transportation, if available, to pick up the Mountlake Terrace prisoners, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> accepting bail, fines or other money for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mountlake Terrace</ENAMEX> for those prisoners held in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail.
</P>

 


<P ID="19">Council’s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX> meeting canceled
</P>

<P ID="20">Because of a lack of agenda items, the regularly scheduled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting has been canceled.
</P>

<P ID="21">In voting <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to cancel the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> left the door slightly ajar, as the stipulation was made that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX> meeting would be held if an agenda item surfaces between now and then.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




