
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Quintero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galvan</ENAMEX> pull all A's at Mabton High
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/24/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">MABTON - Two students, freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis E. Quintero</ENAMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Galvan</ENAMEX>, earned perfect 4.00 grade point averages for the final quarter of the 2003-04 academic year at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   The two teens were among the 26 students named to the "Highest Honors" list. To be eligible for that distinction, students had to maintain a minimum <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> of 3.50.   "Highest Honors" achievers included seniors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Alvarado</ENAMEX> (3.90), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Aviles</ENAMEX> (3.81), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Brambila</ENAMEX> (3.68), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandro Gutierrez</ENAMEX> (3.65), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Cervantes</ENAMEX> (3.62), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Torres</ENAMEX> (3.58) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanca Diaz</ENAMEX> (3.58);   junior Sirena Mireles (3.50);   sophomores <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alida Mendoza</ENAMEX> (3.95), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Beeman</ENAMEX> (3.90), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Arevalo</ENAMEX> (3.83), Guadalupe Gomez (3.81), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Vijil</ENAMEX> (3.75), Yadira Calzada (3.65), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayra Diaz</ENAMEX> (3.62) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Sanchez</ENAMEX> (3.54);   and freshmen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniela Angel</ENAMEX> (3.87), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Rojas</ENAMEX> (3.85), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Nunez</ENAMEX> (3.81), Talisa Sotelo (3.77), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Valle</ENAMEX> (3.70), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moises Gutierrez</ENAMEX> (3.62), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shari Williams</ENAMEX> (3.61) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe Rosas</ENAMEX> (3.51).   A total of 48 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> students were named to the final quarter regular honor roll, for maintaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>'s between 3.00 and 3.49. They included eighth grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecelia Sanchez</ENAMEX>;   freshmen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Marquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Tellez</ENAMEX>, Vicente Tovar, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josie Chase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique Huecias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Irby</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Carrasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriana Navarro</ENAMEX> and Zuleyma Orellana;   sophomores <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celida Diaz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorena Leon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurelia Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomas Martinez</ENAMEX>, Jesica Orozco, Vicente Solis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Berta Torrres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert Uribe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orlando Cervantes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Melendez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Regina Palomarez</ENAMEX>;   juniors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafaela Quintero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sophia Beltran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Harris</ENAMEX>, Rosario Ortega, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Rios</ENAMEX>, Claro Calzada, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Magana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Reyna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Alaniz</ENAMEX>;   and seniors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Galvan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Powell</ENAMEX>, Maximiano Ramirez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betsy Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oswald Fonseca</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Tellez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra Geertsma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodolfo Carreon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalo Navarrete</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Alvarado</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Palacios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Vijil</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Diaz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Lorenzana</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

