


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> closes last chapter of 10-year book
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A decade of hard work and dedication came to a close <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>), as members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lower</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) gathered for their final report to the community.
</P><P ID="5">   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 10 years</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has helped create jobs, improve area infrastructure and provide housing opportunities for low income families. The group has been involved with a number of projects in the communities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, through either directly contributing funds or helping to leverage funds through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> designation.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> is part of a nation-wide federal project that was started more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10 years ago</TIMEX> to help empower low income, rural communities. When <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> first received their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> designation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board was presented with <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 million</NUMEX> that was supposed to help leverage more funds to help the two communities. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Tully</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, as of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board had designated all of its funding with the exception of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,600</NUMEX> that will be used to cover closing costs and the final audit.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geri Horvath</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> noted that over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 10 years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board has been able to turn that original <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.9 million</NUMEX> into <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$83.6 million</NUMEX>, helping to leverage money for a variety of projects in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   But despite the financial success the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board has seen over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decade</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said she doesn't feel that it marks the largest contribution the organization has made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   "It's the impact on the community that really stands out in my mind," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   She noted that instead of numbers she started looking at the different services and projects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has brought to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   She pointed to the jobs that have been created thanks to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> designation, highlighting infrastructure improvements <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> helped make possible at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> wastewater treatment plant. The improvements helped keep industry alive and well in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, therefore preserving nearly 600 jobs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said the local job market isn't the only area the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> can be felt. She noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> was involved with the needs study that was done in regards to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "There was some forethought in that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said, noting that the first spark for that project started with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has also helped people realize the dream of home ownership. She said through the Self Help Housing program, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> was involved in, there are 28 families who are living in their own homes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 10 years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has helped create 150 new housing units for low to moderate income families in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. In terms of housing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> also played an integral part in the creation of the Bienstar transitional center.
</P><P ID="14">   "That's a direct result of the work of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>," she said.
</P><P ID="15">   Very recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Horvath</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> designation helped the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> purchase a new pumper truck for the fire department.
</P><P ID="16">   "It's really a better place to live, a better quality of life, for the people in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> [thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>]," she said.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC Board</ENAMEX> Chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Souders</ENAMEX>, who has been involved with the group for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past eight years</TIMEX>, also opted to look beyond the numbers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. She said for her, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has been about people and helping to make life better in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> area. She also added that although <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> was marking the end of its 10-year existence <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, she feels the effect of the organization will continue to be felt in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley</ENAMEX> for years to come.
</P><P ID="18">   She told a story of a 17-year-old boy who had a brush with the law several years ago and was assigned to take part in the Kids First program, which was created with help from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>. Souders said the young man rode his bike to Kids First every day, making no qualms when asked by the younger children why he didn't drive. She said he pointed out that he had gotten his driver's license taken away because he had been drinking and driving.
</P><P ID="19">   "His story was much louder than anything an adult could say," she said.
</P><P ID="20">   She added that now that young man is a father of two, working at the Wal-Mart distribution center, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> helped contribute funds toward, where he is earning a living wage.
</P><P ID="21">   "The work of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has changed lives and the impact of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> will go on," she said.
</P><P ID="22">   During the slide show presentation, master of ceremonies <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo Ruelas</ENAMEX> touched on other projects <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> has been involved in over the years. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> helped fund a new playground in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>, helped leverage funds for the creation of a daycare facility at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> campus of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Community College</ENAMEX>, and helped get many youth programs started in the area, such as the Youth Coalition. He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> helped provide funds for the construction of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Commons</ENAMEX>, a housing complex in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, provided a mini-grant to Horizons, which helped them build a new facility in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and helped leverage funds for the construction of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> also helped fund a feasibility study for the SunnyView skate park and helped provide infrastructure improvements to Grandview Port property.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> used <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> as an opportunity to thank <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> for everything they have helped make possible in the local community.
</P><P ID="24">   "In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> we have some projects that are <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funded that I think will be around for awhile," he said.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>, a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board and a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member, agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>, noting that she feels the effect of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> will live on.
</P><P ID="26">   She also commended all of the people who have been involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> over the years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said it has been nice to see people come together to change the lives of people in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Cohen</ENAMEX> with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Community Trade and Economic Development</ENAMEX> also took time to thank the people who have worked on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> initiative over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past decade</TIMEX>. She added that although the formal <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> group was coming to a close, the work of the initiative is something that will continue.
</P><P ID="28">   "I know in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 10 years</TIMEX> we'll still be talking about the successes of the whole community," she said.
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX>, who was a part of the group that helped bring the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> designation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, said one of the best things that ever happened through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> was the bringing together of people on the board. He noted that it brought the communities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> together.
</P><P ID="30">   "We were no longer looking at it as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> or as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, we were thinking of it as a community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="31">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hill</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> said it has been exciting to work with the board itself over the past several years. He added that without the board <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> wouldn't be where it is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="32">   "I'm only sorry that we are coming to the end of the initiative," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hill</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="33">   And to mark the end of the initiative, Souders rapped her gavel one last time. Although it was technically the last meeting of the board, Souders noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> will live on.
</P>





 










<P ID="34">Webmaster
</P><P ID="35">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




