

<P ID="1">A campaign could end with champagne
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="4">Buoyed by staff energy and a growing pot of money, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> is succeeding to be a viable contender for mayor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as supporters are encouraged by the beat of his candidacy.
</P>
<P ID="5">The former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> farmer entered the race <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX> with notable advantages, including a solid base of support among established <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> citizens and a face familiar to voters citywide.
</P>
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> has entrusted much of his campaign to family members and friends. He has succeeded in raising money, and all of his professional campaign advisors speak glowingly of his chances.
</P>
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> understands he must start ramping up for the final push to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election, and he has a hard fight against the popular incumbent Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P>
<P ID="8">"It's an exciting campaign," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Teacher</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> family friend who works on the effort. "My excitement speaks for a lot of people, because a lot of people would like to see the campaign succeed."
</P>



 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




