
<P ID="1">Obituaries for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday May 7, 2004</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">AVIS B
AVIS B. CRANFORD
Avis B. Cranford</ENAMEX>, 77, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 4, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7, 1926</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rockham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S.D</ENAMEX>. to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> (Root) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>. She received her early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Dakota</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX> she with her family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She attended <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> and graduated with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1947</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Cranford</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where they together made their home.
She is survived by her mother, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Cranford</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat McMeans</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; two grandsons; one granddaughter;
She was preceded in death by her father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Irwin</ENAMEX>; and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Cranford</ENAMEX>.
A memorial service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 10, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. In lieu of flowers, those wishing to honor Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cranford’s</ENAMEX> memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JAMES DOUGLAS ETHRIDGE
James Douglas Ethridge</ENAMEX>, 57, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, May 5, 2004</TIMEX>, at his home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderale</ENAMEX>.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 26, 1946</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vernon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Violet (Hatrick) Ethridge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Roslyn</ENAMEX>. He received his education in the Alderdale, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> schools. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1965</TIMEX> he enlisted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> serving during the Vietnam War until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1967</TIMEX>.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 12, 1984</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Thompson</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Together they made their home on the family farm. He worked for two and half years at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWI Security</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
 He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juanita Ethridge</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Peterson</ENAMEX>; five daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Borrough</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perry</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boardman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Wilkenson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Violet Armstrong</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellingham</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam Kly</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>; 13 grandchildren; six brothers; and one sister.
He was preceded in death by his adopted parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert and Pearl Peterson</ENAMEX>; one sister; and two brothers.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 11, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, May 12, 2004</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ROBERT FRANCIS BAUERLE
Robert Francis “Bob” Bauerle</ENAMEX>, 79, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident and businessman, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 4, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fountain Hill</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariz.
Bob</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Corder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dessie</ENAMEX> (Westerfield) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francis Bauerle</ENAMEX>.  He graduated from the eighth grade in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Summit</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX> and later completed his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GED</ENAMEX> and a two-year college equivalency.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> joined the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Marine Corps</ENAMEX> during World War II at the age of 16 and was involved in combat operations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific Theater</ENAMEX> including the invasion of Pelieu.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1, 1945</TIMEX>, he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene H. Knowlton</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, where he was a service manager at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ross Lynch Motors</ENAMEX>.  In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where they founded Bob’s Auto Clinic and Red Barn Antiques of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> the Bauerles began their realestate career and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> received their realestate brokers’ license and founded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Bauerle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates Realtors</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> completed his career as a realtor at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Investment Company</ENAMEX>. His wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 7, 1994</TIMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> later met and married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leone</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21, 1997</TIMEX>. They made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chandler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ariz.</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last seven years</TIMEX>.
He was co-founder of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daybreak Rotary</ENAMEX>, president of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Garage Owners Association of America</ENAMEX>, board member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rotary</ENAMEX> and a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Harris Fellow</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Home Security Bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc</ENAMEX>, Yakima Valley Economic Development; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Visitors and Convention Bureau</ENAMEX>, director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Port Authority</ENAMEX>; He was a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Farm Land Management</ENAMEX>; member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Eagle; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Elks Lodge #2112; Kiwanis and “acclaimed” <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fantasy Football Association</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leone Bauerle</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert L. Bauerle</ENAMEX>; daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Bauerle Hughes</ENAMEX>; and grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corley Bauer Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Lauren Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Andrew Bauerle</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timothy John Bauerle</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his wife of 47 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Bauerle</ENAMEX>; half-brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Buck Willard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Willard</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, May 10, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at Wells Funeral Home. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, May 11, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  Burial will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens, under the direction of Wells Funeral Home. Those wishing to honor Bob’s memory may contribute to the Veteran of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign Wars Memorial Fund</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

