


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> proposes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> liquor sales
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/26/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Traditionally, liquor stores throughout the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> have been a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday through Saturday</TIMEX> affair. However, House Bill 2131 is threatening to change that tradition, allowing liquor stores to open their doors for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales.
</P><P ID="5">   Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Chandler</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>) explained that the bill, which was passed by the Washington State House of Representatives <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> and is currently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>, would create a pilot program that would allow 20 state-run liquor stores to open for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales.
</P><P ID="6">   According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Distilled Spirits Council</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, there are currently 27 states that allow <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> liquor sales, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa Hawkins</ENAMEX>, a spokesperson for the council, said many states see <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales as a way to help generate more state tax revenue.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said he is not convinced that over time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales would help raise more money. He said studies done in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> have found that although people are making purchases on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> sales have fallen. He explained that people who would regularly purchase liquor on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> are now simply waiting to make the purchase on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "It was a wash," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said the pilot program would allow stores in the largest markets in the state to remain open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. He noted that after a set amount of time the state would go back and evaluate those stores to see if <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales are proving to be successful.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, who voted against the bill in the house, said he believes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales will mean an increase in the cost of operations for many stores, noting that stores are going to have to pay employees to man the stores an extra day each week.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX>, owner of the Funny Farm, which serves as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> liquor store, explained that if the bill passes she won't necessarily be directly affected. She said the bill would give her the option, as the owner of a contract liquor store, to stay open on Sundays, but it's not an option she feels she would ever take advantage of.
</P><P ID="12">   The Funny Farm, like Spirits Etc. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, is one of 155 contract liquor stores in the state. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Liquor Control Board</ENAMEX>, contract stores operate under contract with the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> explained that as a private business owner she is still responsible for everything from paying the rent to labor costs. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> run liquor stores are operated by the state with state employees. According to the liquor control board, state run stores service more populated areas in the state.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said the nearest state run liquor stores are located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and the Tri-Cities.
</P><P ID="14">   As a contract store, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said she would be given the option to open for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales.
</P><P ID="15">   "Personally, I object to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   She said she feels <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> should be a day of rest for everyone. She also pointed out that being open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> would mean an increase in her labor and overhead costs, but not necessarily an increase in her sales.
</P><P ID="17">   "I think they could learn from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> without changing our liquor laws," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Tucker</ENAMEX>, owner of Spirits Etc. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, echoed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX>'s sentiments, noting that if the bill passes and she is given the opportunity to stay open on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, she most likely wouldn't do it.
</P><P ID="19">   "It's the one day I get to not think about this stuff," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said of Sundays.
</P><P ID="20">   She said as a business owner with a family, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> is her day to get things done for her household, including the weekly shopping.
</P><P ID="21">   "I just don't think it's a good idea," she said.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX>, who originally supported the bill, said he did so because it had a companion bill that would have given a share of the revenue from liquor sales to rural counties. He said when the companion bill was killed, HB 2131 lost his support.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chandler</ENAMEX> said the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> sales bill is currently in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate Ways and Means Committee</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   "It has a ways to go," he said.
</P><P ID="25">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




