


<P ID="1">Citizen compliments Cinco de Mayo event
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/14/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Brandvold</ENAMEX> complimented the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> and the city at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandvold</ENAMEX> said the jail trustees and chamber officials did a nice job of maintaining the downtown area where the Cinco de Mayo event was held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> also extended his congratulations to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> chamber for what he viewed as a successful Cinco de Mayo event.
</P>   






 










<P ID="6">Webmaster
</P><P ID="7">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




