


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Not a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> supporter
</P>

<P ID="5">After 9/11 it was obvious to all Americans that fighting terrorism was a number one priority. So what did President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bushdo</ENAMEX>?
</P>

<P ID="6">Did he build upon the upswell of support from other nations after the attack? No—in the rush into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> he alienated numerous long term allies of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="7">Did he commit more resources to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> to flush out the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Quida</ENAMEX> leadership? No—he started a major disaster in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>
</P>  
<P ID="8">instead. How many terroristshave been created by this nightmare? How many of our brave American soldiers have been killed or severely wounded? How many more will be put in harm's way when the draft that the government is quietly trying to introduce passes?
</P>

<P ID="9">Did <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> continue the talks with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Korea</ENAMEX> to contain their nuclear abilities? No—he stopped the talks initiated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> administration</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">Didhe at least protect targets at home, such as power plants, chemical plants, bridges? No—he started thejob by initiating a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> of Homeland Security, then failed to fully fund it. Meanwhile, police resources are stretched thin and nearly two-third's of firehouses are understaffed.
</P>

<P ID="11">Will John Kerry do better? Millions of Americans think he will. This election is the most important one in my lifetime. Please vote.
</P>

<P ID="12">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Meister</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> deserves your vote
</P>

<P ID="14">A few months ago, my nephew was injured during a night mission delivering fuel to an army base in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. He has recovered, is back on mission, and was recently awarded a Purple Heart.
</P>

<P ID="15">I became concerned about his (and his unit's) future safety when I learned that his unit lacked the appropriate number of Night Vision Goggles to safely perform their night-time missions. I was so concerned that I wrote to both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX></ENAMEX> and two members of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> to request their help.
</P>

<P ID="16">Why am I telling you this? I want you to know that the only response I received (four e-mails and three phone calls) was from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Simmons</ENAMEX> at Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s office. Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s office subsequently initiated a "Congressional inquiry" into the situation, and I have recently received confirmation from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, that within days of this inquiry, the unit received 34 additional Night Vision Goggles for use in their convoys. This may be a coincidence, I'll never know. What I do know is the unit got what they needed to improve their safety.
</P>

<P ID="17">While I don't live in Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s congressional district, and neither does my nephew, he took action. Virtually every other congressional office responds only to constituents that actually live in their "specific" congressional district. The congressman from my "actual" district, and both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX>, never responded to my inquiry. That doesn't mean they didn't (or did) act on my request. It just means they never responded.
</P>

<P ID="18">I have never before solicited support from friends and family for a political race. I am <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> is running for senator <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this November</TIMEX>. Please, consider my endorsement of him when you cast your vote. Please vote!
</P>

<P ID="19">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Hallett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hallett Cinemas, LLC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="20">TV ad absurd
</P>

<P ID="21">Why doesn't Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> spend money on issues that matter?
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s new TV ad accusing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> of moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX> is absurd. Instead of talking about issues that really matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> is taking the easy way out and painting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> as a liar and abandoner of his district, when he is anything but that.
</P>

<P ID="23">There are serious issues that face our state—issues like tax reform, health care and medical liability reform. And <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> is hiding from her poor voting record, and instead promoting campaign rhetoric. She is shying away from debates and refuses to come clean on the issues.
</P>

<P ID="24">I hope voters can see past the rhetoric <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> puts out there and are able to make a conscious decision about who they want to elect to represent us.
</P>

<P ID="25">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Fisher</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>
</P>

 






 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




