
<P ID="1">Selah blanks the Grizzlies
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SELAH</ENAMEX> - It was a long night for the faithful of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football team this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies were thumped by their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> rivals 35-0, as a fired up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> team took care of business, said Grizzly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Mark Marro</ENAMEX>.   "They wanted it more," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s loss marks the second week in a row that the Grizzlies have been shut out. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> lost 20-0 at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> the previous week.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> (2-4, 4-5) will be looking to end the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> season on a bright note <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, as the Grizzlies host 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s game against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> wasn't played as badly as the final score might indicate. Going into the second half, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> had a mere a 14-0 lead following a late second quarter touchdown.   In the second half, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> used a strong ground game to rack up three touchdowns to account for the final score. The last touchdown by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> came on a 72-yard burst by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rowan Ringer</ENAMEX> late in the game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> offered few excuses for his team's performance on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   "We just didn't get off the ball," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>) controlled the line of scrimmage."   The Grizzlies did manage to threaten inside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>'s 20-yard line a few times, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>, but the drives ended up self destructing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said in the second half <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> simply was overpowering.   "They physically got after it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "We came out flat. They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>) just took it to us."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had several players who put forth a strong individual effort, but the team chemistry wasn't flowing enough to keep up with how <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> was playing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX> nearly had a 100-yard rushing night, gaining 95 yards on 21 carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammate Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX> had 25 yards on eight totes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> did most of their damage on the ground, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ringer</ENAMEX> ran for 132 yards on just 10 carries.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> is looking to end the season strong <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at home against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>. The Grizzlies will have an opportunity to finish .500 for the season with a win over <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX>.   "They are a good team," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "We are going to have to get after it."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

