
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> trips up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> grid team, 14-7
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Mark Marro</ENAMEX> isn't one to lambaste an official for a call that many would say cost his team a victory. But when asked if the pass interference penalty that was assessed his club <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late in Saturday night</TIMEX>'s game was a horrible call, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> couldn't offer up much support for the referee in question.   Simply put, the Grizzly football team got homered this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> on the field of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX>. A very questionable pass interference call with about two minutes remaining allowed the home team to keep alive its game winning drive. Shortly after, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Roberts</ENAMEX> hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Butler</ENAMEX> on a 50-yard TD pass that gave the Seattle area team a 14-7 victory.   "It was a tough way to have it end," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> forged a 6-0 lead on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Schwartz</ENAMEX> bulled his way into the end zone from eight yards out. The TD run came in the opening quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX>'s successful extra point kick upped the Grizzlies' lead to 7-0.   To <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX>'s credit, they kept the Grizzlies off the scoreboard the remainder of the contest. But that isn't to say <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't have its way <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Playing in a steady downpour, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> opted to make the run the featured attack, and boy, did it work.   Using the one-two punch of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX>, the Grizzlies rolled up nearly 215 yards on the ground.   "The two runners complement each other well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>, explaining that the 6'1", 220-lb. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> is a power runner, while the 150-lb. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> is more of a scatback type back.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX>) is rarely taken down by the first hit, and often the second hit doesn't do it, either," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> in accounting for the 120 yards <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> gained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.   In contrast, the much smaller but speedier <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> picks and weaves his way between defenders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> scooted in and out and around <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX>'s defensive squad well enough to pick up 93 yards on the ground. The contrasting running styles kept <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> off-balance all night long.   Much of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schwartz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX>'s success toting the ball <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> has to be credited, though, to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s offensive line-especially the left side. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the trio of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Garza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucas Ramos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Escobar</ENAMEX> did an exceptional job of opening up holes for the two runners.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> did note, however, that some of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s younger offensive linemen need to make rapid improvement. "Our line play has to get better," he said of the underclassmen.   To keep the home team on its toes even more, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> called enough passing plays so that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX>'s defensive backs couldn't crowd the line to help stop the run. Surprisingly, considering the heavy rain quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cantu</ENAMEX> had to contend with, the Grizzly QB connected on 10 of his 17 attempts, tallying 72 yards through the air. And, he didn't serve up any interceptions.   Unfortunately, the one <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">miscue Cantu</ENAMEX> committed came at a most inopportune time-on the Grizzlies' last drive of the night. With <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> trying to tie the game with under a minute to play, advancing the ball all the way to inside <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX>'s 30-yard line, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> fumbled away a snap that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> pounced on.   What is surprising is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> fumbled the ball only once all night long. With the heavy rains, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said it became increasingly difficult to grip the pigskin.   To those who might point to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> for ending the potential game tying drive, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said there never is just one play that wins or loses a ballgame.   "We were in the position we were in because of how we played as a team," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> didn't get its first score of the game until after the fourth quarter got underway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corey Williams</ENAMEX> got the home team on the board when they connected on a 34-yard touchdown pass. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> failed to square the contest at 7-all, though, as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Guevara</ENAMEX> raced in to block the extra point attempt.   The Seattle private school team grabbed the lead from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with just under two minutes to play, on the 50-yard bomb <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> delivered to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> following the controversial pass interference call. A two-point conversion pass, from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberts</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX>, accounted for the final 14-7 score.   With the exception of the two final period touchdown receptions, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> held <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastside Catholic</ENAMEX> to just 62 yards passing. The Grizzly defensive unit also only allowed 54 rushing yards.   "Except for those two big plays late in the fourth quarter, we controlled the whole game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   He is particularly proud of the job his defense did against the Seattle team.   "It was a phenomenal effort," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>, mentioning the defensive line play of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Cruz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Garza</ENAMEX>, as well as the outstanding jobs that linebackers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Hazzard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Guevara</ENAMEX> turned in. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>, too, said he was pleased with the play of defensive backs <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe Zamarron</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX>.   The seven-point loss <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> sustained <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> was its first defeat of the season. The Grizzlies (0-0, 2-1) must now prepare for six consecutive <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> games, including its conference opener at home this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against the perennially tough Prosser Mustangs.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> always gives you its best," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   "Both us and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> have had a rugged non-league schedule, with most of the games on the road.   "When they come into town <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, we're going to do what we do well. It will be business as usual, no surprises to speak of," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

