


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DAVID EARL HILEMAN</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DAVID EARL HILEMAN</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Earl Hileman</ENAMEX>, 59, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 7, 2004</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28, 1944</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erma (Hoskinson) Hileman</ENAMEX>. At 17, he joined the U.S. Navy. He served five cruises on the nuclear powered submarine USS Alexander Hamilton. He was honorably discharged in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>. He moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> and became an electrician.
</P>

<P ID="7">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1972</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Lorraine Shottenkirk</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8">He is survived by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Hileman</ENAMEX>; and daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Herion</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cain</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tonia</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Poulsbo</ENAMEX>; and a sister, Kathy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">He was preceded in death by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erma (Hoskinson) Hileman</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">A memorial service for Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hileman</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 14, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at 68703 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Ferry Rd. PR NW</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Prosser</ENAMEX>. Jones Funeral Home will conduct funeral arrangements.
</P>

 


<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GUADALUPE Angel</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe Angel</ENAMEX>, 78, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 6, 2004</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 12, 1925</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rosebud</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josephine (Cantu) Angel</ENAMEX>. As a youth, he worked as a bell boy. He served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX>. He moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> in the 1940’s, working for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hanford and Northwest Glass Co.</ENAMEX> While at the glass company, Lupe invented an automated mold cleaner. He had an inventive mind that kept him busy.
</P>

<P ID="14">Survivors include his wife of 20 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by his ex-wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Rocha Angel</ENAMEX>; and their children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lilly Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Renton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Jose</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nellie</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kent</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Angel</ENAMEX> of Seattle and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everett</ENAMEX>; five brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felix</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louise</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert (Holanda) Carranza</ENAMEX> of Auburn, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Ann</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carranza</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simon</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>; four sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josephine Rodriguez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Minnie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alvarado</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Max</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gamboa</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virginia Molina</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by five step-sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marge</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galaviz Jr.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Galaviz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeAnn</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galaviz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marie</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galaviz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentino</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Galaviz</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Burien</ENAMEX>; five step-daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Castanada</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sara Galaviz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicky</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Garza</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lily</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurelio</ENAMEX>) Bermudez of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; 20 grandchildren; 30 great-grandchildren, 31 step-grandchildren and 34 step-great-grandchildren; and 80 nieces and nephews.
</P>

<P ID="15">He was preceded in death by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josephine Cantu Carranza</ENAMEX>; his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX>; his step-father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Carranza</ENAMEX>; an infant daughter; an infant sister; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Angel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Carranza</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16">Viewing was held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Aug. 9, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Hills Funeral Home Chapel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Recitation of the Rosary was held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Hills Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services were held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Aug. 10, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX>. Burial was held at Mabton City Cemetery.
</P>

 


<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ALICE L. KNIGHT</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice L. Knight</ENAMEX>, 84, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> went to be in the loving arms of her heavenly Father <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 7, 2004</TIMEX>, from her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 30, 1919</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bertha</ENAMEX> (Haye) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allen Grant</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, who were pioneer homesteaders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 21, 1943</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie Knight</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Church</ENAMEX> of God. Following their marriage they made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>, before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1968</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="20"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> cherished time spent with her family. She enjoyed music, baking, sewing, crocheting, writing poetry and picking cherries. After retirement <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie</ENAMEX> delighted in taking several trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> was a life-time and active member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of God, where she played the organ for more than 30 years.
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice</ENAMEX> is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlie Knight</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; five children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arleta Langdon</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grassvalley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry Allen Knight</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virlene</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">La Rae Ross</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeRoy</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Knight</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Georgeana</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Knight</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; 12 grandchildren; three great-grandchildren; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Naomi Wagner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="23">She was preceded in death by her parents; three brothers; and three sisters.
</P>

<P ID="24">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Aug. 11, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. A celebration of life service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 12, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of God. Burial will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Hills Memorial Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 12, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>, under the direction of Jones Funeral Home. Those wishing to honor her memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of God elevator fund or to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice. Memorials may be left at Jones Funeral Home or at the church at the time of service.
</P>





 










<P ID="25">Webmaster
</P><P ID="26">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




