


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> contends he has no problem with DSN
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">"The animosity is between me and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> managing editor)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> used that statement <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>) to clarify what he said is a misconception that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> councilman has issues with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "The reporters that are there at the newspaper, I have a lot of respect for," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>. "I think that Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> is let run amuck with his editorials."
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said that he doesn't have a problem with the local newspaper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he has always been treated fairly by the reporting staff. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said for a long time he has had problems with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> and former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Daily News Publisher Tom Lanctot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said based on the "frustrating" personal history he has with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> and Lanctot, it has led to the animosity he feels towards them <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   In regards to a line in an email that was read aloud at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> not printing the truth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> replied that he bases that remark on his own research.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> in his editorials lets his vendettas be known. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said as an individual he has the right to let known his personal gripes.
</P><P ID="10">   "I can have my personal feelings," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> can speak for the community in his editorials then why can't he speak for the community from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> seat.
</P><P ID="12">   As far as letting his personal feelings factor into the controversy surrounding the rejection of the newspaper's bid to publish legal notices, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he wants to make sure the city is spending its money appropriately. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he is only one vote and the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will side as they see accordingly.
</P><P ID="13">   "The city gains by a fair bidding process," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>. "It (the legal bids) will prove out one way or another."
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




