


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/8/2002</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">1-6 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GV Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">New mayor pro tem appointed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> a new mayor pro tem was appointed with Norm Childress taking over the position from Councilman Bill Flory.
</P>

<P ID="7">"I appreciate your serving for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>," Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flory</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P>

 


<P ID="8">Treatment plant project accepted as complete
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to approve the influent force main replacement project at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> wastewater treatment plant as complete, therefore releasing the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,051</NUMEX> retainage.
</P>

<P ID="10">Work on the replacement project was completed by R & G <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Excavating, Inc.</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="11">Annexation request goes on
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Following a closed record public hearing during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> meeting dealing with the petition of annexation and rezone from the den <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hoed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grow</ENAMEX> families, the petition will move on in the county's annexation process.
</P>

<P ID="13">The annexation request deals with approximately 91 acres of property located north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interstate</ENAMEX> 82, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">abutting Olmstead</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County Line</ENAMEX> roads in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




