
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> building projects in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$353,781</NUMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/27/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">In just a little less than two months, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gayle Hays</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beauty Academy</ENAMEX> is hoping to be able to move her beauty school from the four-room building she is currently renting to a new 2,520 square foot facility being finished at 440 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnard Blvd.</ENAMEX>, in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horizons Inc.</ENAMEX> building owned by the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX> said she is expecting to move her school from its current <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Edison Avenue</ENAMEX> location to its new home on Port property in roughly 45 days.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis Jansen</ENAMEX>, Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> project administrator, said the 2,520 square foot space in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horizons Inc.</ENAMEX> building has been available for lease since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last January</TIMEX>. He noted that when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Horizons Inc.</ENAMEX> portion of the building was completed two additional spaces were left unfinished. He said the Port left them unfinished so the sections of the building could be finished to suit whoever the leasee ended up being.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jansen</ENAMEX> said the Port is paying to have the portion of the building finished, noting that it hopes to recoup its costs by leasing the location.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX> alone, the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> applied for four building permits from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> building division for the project, including permits for plumbing, mechanical and a water meter.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX> said once the space is finished she will have five sinks, 20 student stylist stations on the main floor, a basic classroom and a facial room. She said the floor plan also calls for a storage room, an office and a student lounge.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX> said the classroom will have the capability of handling anywhere from 10 to 20 people and the facial room will house two facial tables, which are tables a person can lie down on while receiving a facial treatment.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX>, in the new building she will be able to handle approximately 30 students through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beauty Academy</ENAMEX>, which was started in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 2003</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX> said she chose the Port property because of its close proximity to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> and the Mid-Valley Mall, as well as the fact that the building features good parking, lighting and is handicap accessible.   "Everything was good about it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hays</ENAMEX> said of the Port property.   Another project that has been ongoing since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of December</TIMEX>, has been the expansion of Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randall Schuler</ENAMEX>'s office at 1725 E. Lincoln Ave.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5</TIMEX>, DeVos Builders applied for a building permit with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> building division for work on the office.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eileen Timmermans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuler</ENAMEX>'s office manager, said the expansion includes an office, a new lab and additional storage space. She said the lab will be used to make retainers and plaster casts of teeth. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timmermans</ENAMEX> said both services are currently offered at the facility, however the expansion of the office will allow more space for the work to be done.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timmermans</ENAMEX> said work on the office expansion should be completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.   The building permits issued for work on the new beauty academy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuler</ENAMEX>'s office are five of 41 permits issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. All told, the total valuation of the 41 projects is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$353,781</NUMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> building division also conducted 376 inspections during the month of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>.   More than half of the 41 permits issued <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> were building permits, with 21 being issued by the city. Eight of the permits were for mechanical work and six were for plumbing projects. The remaining permits were issued for everything from two water connections to a public works street excavation.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

