
<P ID="1">Teaching nun goes from private to public schools
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia Hinojosa</ENAMEX> first felt the call to a life of ministry as a fifth grader growing up in the small <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Taft</ENAMEX>.   A nun with the Missionary Daughters of the Most Pure Virgin Mary, which has a convent at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood's St. Joseph Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. This is her fourth round in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the first was in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX>.   "They usually let us stay three to five years before they transfer us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>. Transfers are based on where the needs are for different skills.   She has been to three of the five convents in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> currently operated by her order. The order, which is focused on education, also has three convents in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Peru</ENAMEX> and 45 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.   Before she was transferred back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, she was at a convent in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Jersey</ENAMEX>, where she taught kindergarten students.   Moving back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where the private Catholic school had been closed, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said she and the four other nuns at the local convent have been focusing on other aspects of education at the church.   "This is my first year in just pastoral ministry," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>, who will be celebrating 44 years as a nun in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.   She has been teaching <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCD</ENAMEX> religious classes and been speaking to adults and children alike at the church.   She said the local nuns participate in the church's food bank, a jail ministry, small church groups and they make visitations to shut-ins.   "We also help with retreats," she added.   "It's another ministry," she said. "I had always been in the classroom."   Out of the classroom for the first time since she became a nun, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said she and some of her fellow nuns have found ways to keep in touch with kids.   "When I first learned I wasn't going to be teaching, I thought, man, I'm going to miss those kids, but God provided. He sent me to public school," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>.   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX> she has been an elementary school substitute teacher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>.   Although dressed in "street clothes," she said youngsters from the school recognize her.   "They stop me in the hallway and say, 'you're the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CCD</ENAMEX> lady'," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> remembers, as a youngster, playing school with neighborhood children in the garage of her family's home. She said the neighborhood children would gather and she would always be the teacher. It was most likely something she and her sisters learned from their mother, who would teach the neighborhood children how to read.   "I love to teach," she said. "I think I was a born teacher."   The seventh of 16 children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said seven of the nine girls in her family are teachers.   At age 17, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> decided to become a nun. Moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, where the order is headquartered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> completed religious training before finishing her high school degree through correspondence. She went on to earn her Bachelor's degree in education from Texas A&M. She also holds a Master's degree.   During the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> months she takes continuing religious education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>   Sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucia Hinojosa</ENAMEX> has been a nun for nearly 44 years. A member of a teaching order, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said she feels she is a natural teacher. Since the private Catholic school has closed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, she has been substituting in the public school district, as well as teaching religious education and supporting various church ministries.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

