


<P ID="1">G'view kids helping choose park toys
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - When it comes to making decisions for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX>, the local city council usually takes the reigns. However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> a different approach was taken to decision making in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX>, along with Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recreation</ENAMEX> Deputy Director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gretchen Chronis</ENAMEX> and other members of the local playground committee, split up and took the decision making process to the schools.
</P><P ID="6">   "We need your help," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX> told a group of third grade students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> is looking to the children of the community to help decide which of three different playground structures should be built at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s 28-acre <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Funding for the construction of the playground structure is coming from a variety of sources, including donations from several different service clubs and private groups. The bulk of the funding for the project came in the form of a grant from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX>, which awarded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> for the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> was donated to the project from an anonymous donor.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX> explained the entire process to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Charvet</ENAMEX>'s third grade class at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Arthur H. Jones Elementary School</ENAMEX> by telling the 8 and 9-year olds that the city had received a large amount of money and wanted to do something wonderful with it.
</P><P ID="10">   "Here's where we need your help," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX> told them.
</P><P ID="11">   As <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> handed the students voting ballots, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX> took time to talk to them about the three options the city is looking at for the playground structure.
</P><P ID="12">   Reading off descriptions that included monster slides, rock climbers, play storefronts, talking tubes, suspension bridges, spiral slides and climbing poles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX> instantly grabbed the attention of every student.
</P><P ID="13">   After talking to them about each structure, she asked the students to close their eyes and try to imagine what each one would look like.
</P><P ID="14">   "They are all wonderful," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX> told the students, explaining that when it came time to cast their vote for a playground structure they should be thinking about what activities they like to do and which structure they thought would be the most enjoyable.
</P><P ID="15">   Then each student was allowed to cast their vote for their favorite structure.
</P><P ID="16">   "We can assure you that one of these is going to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chronis</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said the playground structure that proves to be most popular is scheduled to be installed in the park <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX>, before schools let out for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   Voting on the three structures will continue through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 27</TIMEX>. Anyone interested in taking a closer look at the three playground options or voting on their favorite can do so at Grandview City Hall or the Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation</ENAMEX> office, where descriptions and diagrams of the three structures are on display.
</P><P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




