


<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Every family needs a father figure and the father figure for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> boys basketball program is head coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Parrish</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>, 36, will be the first to tell you none of the successes he has had as head coach of one of the most successful basketball programs in the state would be possible without those surrounding him.
</P><P ID="6">   The one reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> might take such a pride with his family of players and the way they represent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> is he understands what it is to be a Greyhound.
</P><P ID="7">   A native of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> played basketball for the Greyhounds, a three-year player on varsity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX>, going on to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bend Community College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> to play two years of basketball. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX> with a Bachelor's degree in education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> now teaches a variety of social science classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX>, in addition to a weight training course.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> returned home from college and became engaged to his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy</ENAMEX>, who is the daughter of long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Durado</ENAMEX>. A job opened up at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Middle School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, where he stayed for three years before heading to the high school. At the same time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>'s wife was hired in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser School District</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> and his wife have three children-two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Payton</ENAMEX>, 9, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teagan</ENAMEX>, 6, and one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Treyton</ENAMEX>, 2.
</P><P ID="10">   One of the reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> became a teacher was his father-in-law, who motivated him to get into teaching.
</P><P ID="11">   "It is something I always wanted to do," he added. "I have never really had any other aspirations."
</P><P ID="12">   But perhaps the most guiding factor as to why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> wanted to become a teacher is that he wanted to be a coach.
</P><P ID="13">   "I knew I wanted to get into coaching. I just wanted to stay around the game," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>. "I have kind of a passion for the game of basketball."
</P><P ID="14">   This is the sixth year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> has been the head coach of the Greyhound boys hoop program. Prior to taking over the head coaching job, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> spent two years as the junior varsity coach. In his six years as head coach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> has amassed an impressive record of 119 wins and 25 losses. In his first four years as head coach, the Greyhounds were in the 2A ranks, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> ended up with a record of 95 wins and 13 losses. In his first year as head coach, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> went 20-7, placing fifth at the 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> basketball tournament. The Greyhounds followed up with fourth and third place finishes at the 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> basketball tournaments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>'s shining moment as a coach came three seasons ago when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> made a remarkable 27-0 run, defeating <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chelan</ENAMEX> for the 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> title at the Yakima SunDome. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said that was a rewarding moment as a coach because it was the fourth year he had spent with a core of players who were finishing their prep careers under him.
</P><P ID="15">   The following season the Greyhounds were bumped up to the 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>, where he accumulated a respectable 16-9 record before losing in the playoffs. Of those nine losses last season, one was in overtime to 2A Kiona-Benton. Another two losses were to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> and the Greyhounds ended up dropping three games apiece to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the Greyhounds have an 8-3 overall record.
</P><P ID="16">   Arguably, one of the big reasons for the Greyhounds' success on the basketball court could be the attitude <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> and his coaching staff instills in their players.
</P><P ID="17">   "We want to obviously be a good basketball team," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>. "I am really big on getting kids to put forth a good effort. I want them to do it the best they can."
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said his mother always taught him if you are to do something, do it right the first time, which is what he tries to instill in his players.
</P><P ID="19">   One thing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> and his staff always tells their players is whether on or off the court they are representing their school, families, friends and the community, so always do their best.
</P><P ID="20">   Another reason the Greyhounds could be doing so well is the players have bought into his staff's stressing of being one and never putting individual statistics before the team.
</P><P ID="21">   "We are real big on getting the kids to understand what their role is," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>. "We have kids that are not selfish. It is just a team effort."
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said the players also understand what it takes to be successful. Each day, he post the team's plans for the day at different spots at the high school. There is also a thought of the day read at the start of each day of school that players need to have memorized by the time practice comes around. If the players don't know the thought of the day, they end up running.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said he wouldn't be able to do what he does as head coach without his staff, which includes junior varsity coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Brownlee</ENAMEX>, C-squad coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Martinez</ENAMEX> and freshman coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zane Wells</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   While one of his most trusted advisors is his assistant coach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brownlee</ENAMEX>, it is something former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Greyhound</ENAMEX> head coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Schuette</ENAMEX>, who coached the Greyhounds to two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> titles, told him when he was first hired that sticks with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   "He said, your first year you work as hard as you can and it will take them at least 10 years to get rid of you," he laughed. "I at least have four more years."
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> takes a special pride in being a Greyhound, something he hopes his players will always carry with them.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> also added it is special to put on the uniform of a Greyhound basketball player.
</P><P ID="28">   "I wore the uniform when I was coming through," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>. "I tell (my) players, take a lot of pride in (being a Greyhound), especially when they put that jersey on."
</P><P ID="29">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="30">Webmaster
</P><P ID="31">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




