
<P ID="1">Two 4A teams beat <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girls
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> girls fastpitch softball team had its hands full this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> spring openers, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> were clipped by a pair of strong Class 4A schools.   The Enumclaw Hornets, which advanced to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last spring</TIMEX>, edged the Class 3A Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> 7-3 in the first of three games played in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX> swept the afternoon doubleheader from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, winning 5-0 and 28-15.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Kris Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said despite sustaining the three losses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, she remains optimistic the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> will fare well this season.   "We're young, we only have one senior on the varsity. Considering who we played <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, I thought the girls performed well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>.   "Especially on offense," she continued. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> at this time of the season, we were only coming up with one or two hits a game. But we had three hits against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enumclaw</ENAMEX>, then five hits and nine hits in the two late games against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said.   The last of the three games played <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, won 28-15 by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX>, there was a total of 26 hits.   "I think fatigue kicked in," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>," explaining the two clubs committed a total of 15 errors. Between the tiring arms of the opposing pitchers and the fielding miscues, the final tally more resembled a football score.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s top guns at the plate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX> nightcap were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Soto</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Serl</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soto</ENAMEX> had a double in the second inning and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBI</ENAMEX> single in the third enroute to posting a 3-for-3 effort at the plate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serl</ENAMEX> added a 2-for-2 offensive performance for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX>'s top hitter in the twin bill finale was its pitcher, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilgore</ENAMEX>, who went 4-for-5 by slapping four singles.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilgore</ENAMEX> had a 2-for-3 performance in the opener against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, which included socking a solo home run in the top of the seventh.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serl</ENAMEX> was 1-for-3 in the 5-0 loss to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said none of her Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> advanced past second base in the opening game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX>.   "We came through with five hits against them, but we left them all stranded," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. "We made some base running errors."   In the day's first game against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enumclaw</ENAMEX>, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> scratched out three runs in the bottom of the third, and were ahead 3-1 heading into the top of the fifth frame. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Hornets</ENAMEX> exploded for five runs in the fifth, though, blanking <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> through the final four innings enroute to scoring their come-from-behind 7-3 victory.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s three-run third began with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacey Yanez</ENAMEX> drawing a walk. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanez</ENAMEX> ended up scoring on her own, as she stole second and advanced two more bases on two passed balls. Following a strikeout, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Cruz</ENAMEX> drew another walk for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>, moving to second on yet another passed ball. Following the second strikeout of the inning, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenny Wells</ENAMEX> clutched up and drove in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> with a single. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serl</ENAMEX> closed out the scoring for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> by lashing an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">RBI</ENAMEX> double to plate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.   Pitching-wise for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erika Martinez</ENAMEX> went the distance in the opener against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enumclaw</ENAMEX>. She scattered 10 hits in the 7-3 loss, giving up five walks along the way while fanning one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> (0-2) also took the loss in the nightcap against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX>, pitching the first three innings. She departed the pitching rubber with her club trailing by a 23-12 count. Viri Pasillas pitched all of the opening game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX>, limiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s 4A opponent to just five hits. She walked only three. Pasillas (0-1) was touched for five runs in the last two innings she pitched against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spanaway Lake</ENAMEX> in the second game of the twin bill.   In looking ahead to the remainder of the season, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said she has everyone back off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s squad with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonya Ramos</ENAMEX>.   "Those will be some difficult shoes to fill," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said of her shortstop's departure, "But we're a year older and a year more experienced.   "I think we're going to be alright," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serl</ENAMEX> will be replacing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramos</ENAMEX> at short, and based on how she played this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serl</ENAMEX> should fill in nicely there.   The one other change the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> must make <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> is at third. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Wells</ENAMEX> had been penciled in to play the hot corner, but she suffered a broken ankle in practice and most likely will miss the rest of the season. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> brought up <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eleanor Martinez</ENAMEX> from the JV this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>, and she filled in there as well as could have been expected. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> was a second baseman on the JV, so will need some time to make the adjustment at third.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s varsity is scheduled to take on visiting Kiona-Benton in a single game this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

