


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves mutual aid agreement
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> approved a mutual aid agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Office of Emergency Management</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">The agreement brings all of the cities, fire districts and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> together under one mutual aid agreement that is coordinated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Office of Emergency Management</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> receives update on cable TV upgrade
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> talked to members of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> about the cable television upgrades being made by Charter Communications.
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> reported that upgrades were originally scheduled to be completed by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX>, and at this point Charter has all of the underground work complete and is working on hanging cable from PP&L power poles throughout the community.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said the company is hoping to begin phasing in upgraded connections as early as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves fencing ordinance
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - People living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> will now have to apply for a building permit before they can install a fence.
</P>

<P ID="13"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> approved a new fencing ordinance that sets in place a variety of regulations when it comes to the installation of a new fence. The regulations include that the fence can not be more than six feet tall unless a special use permit is granted and outlines material that can not be used to construct a fence, such as barbed wire, plywood, pallets, cardboard and used tires.
</P>

<P ID="14">The new ordinance will go into effect <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="15">Council outlaws parking area near middle school
</P>

<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> voted to eliminate parking on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Second Street</ENAMEX> in front of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Middle School</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17">Parking will be eliminated for 60 feet along the south side of Second Street, from the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hillcrest</ENAMEX> west, and 116 feet of parking will be eliminated on the north side of the street from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hillcrest</ENAMEX> west.
</P>

 


<P ID="18">County auditor explains new voting system
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Auditor Corky Mattingly talked to members of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> about the new electronic voting system that will be used in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>'s general election.
</P>

<P ID="20">She showed one of the electronic voting mechanisms to members of the council, showing them how the system will work. She pointed out the system does not use a touch screen, instead people will use a rotary dial to cast their vote.
</P>

 


<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Council</ENAMEX> approves rezone application
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> approved the rezone of nearly five acres of property located off of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Fifth Street</ENAMEX>. The request for re-zoning was made by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Boboth</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="23"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Boboth</ENAMEX> requested the property be rezoned from AF1 agriculture to R-1 single family residential.
</P>

 


 






 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




