
<P ID="1">13 ladies vying for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> crown
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">After years of seeing a sparse turnout, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> organizers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> are gleaming with pride because of the number of young ladies competing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s crown.   More than a dozen young women from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> will take to the stage at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 23</TIMEX>, for the right to wear the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> crown.   The pageant will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Rubio</ENAMEX>, and her princess, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corina Cortez</ENAMEX>, will be relinquishing their crowns at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23</TIMEX> pageant.   "We are excited about the pageant <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo Program Coordinator Carlos Maya</ENAMEX>. "The pageant has grown so much."   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> program has seen sparse participation, with five girls competing for the crown each year.   "We are excited to have the largest crowd (of girls) come out yet," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX>.   The 13 young ladies competing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> crown <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Rangel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Ortiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maribel Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yesenia Jalifi</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie Moran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iris Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Macias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anabel Diaz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janet Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Cervantes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Casillas</ENAMEX> and Kathya Quijano.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rangel</ENAMEX> is a 17-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident. She will be performing a singing routine in the talent portion of the program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> is a 17-year-old student at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, where she is involved with the Grizzliettes drill team.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ortiz</ENAMEX>, 18, is also from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and she plans on performing a dance routine as her talent at the pageant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>, 16, is a student at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. She will be performing a dance number as her talent routine.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jalifi</ENAMEX>, 16, will also be performing a dance routine at the pageant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moran</ENAMEX>, 17, is a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzliettes</ENAMEX> dance team at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, where she also serves as the senior class and dance team treasurer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruiz</ENAMEX> is a 17-year-old Outlook resident. One of the club's the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> student is involved in is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor Society</ENAMEX>. She is also active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Explorers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macias</ENAMEX>, 18, is also from Outlook. She plans to perform a dance routine as part of her performance in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23</TIMEX> pageant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX>, 15, is from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> is heavily involved with church activities and loves to play the piano.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, 17, will be representing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. At <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> she is involved with the dance/drill team. She will be performing a dance routine during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 23</TIMEX> pageant.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> is one of two young ladies from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> signed up to participate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX>, 17, is involved with cheerleading at her school. After high school she plans to attend college to study fashion designing.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casillas</ENAMEX> is an 18-year-old student at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School</ENAMEX>. After high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casillas</ENAMEX> is interested in going to college to study interior design.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX> said he is excited about the coming pageant. He said many of the young ladies competing can relate to the rich heritage associated with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> holiday.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fifth of May</TIMEX>, marks an important date in the Mexican and Mexican American communities. The day marks the victory of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexican Army</ENAMEX> over the French at the Battle of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Puebla</ENAMEX>. The victory holds significance because it stands as a symbol of Mexican unity and patriotism.   Several of the young ladies competing have their own reasons for entering the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> pageant.   "I've always wanted to ride on a float," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said she usually doesn't participate in many activities such as this and she thought it would help her meet new people and experience different things.   "Running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> is like a dream come true for me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX>. "It is a great opportunity."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diaz</ENAMEX> said she has always looked up to such people as past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> royalty and wanted an opportunity to represent her community in the same role.   "I am very excited," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cervantes</ENAMEX> said she felt like running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> would give her an opportunity to represent her culture.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casillas</ENAMEX> shared many of the same reasons for running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Casillas</ENAMEX> said she feels it is an opportunity to represent her culture in a positive light.   The outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubio</ENAMEX>, said the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> has been a great experience for her and that she may want to participate in other pageants now.   Her princess, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corina Cortez</ENAMEX>, has also enjoyed the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   Both of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> court members said they feel the program has grown a lot in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubio</ENAMEX> said the court is now viewed on a level field as the other courts throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX> has kept both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubio</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cortez</ENAMEX> busy. They have completed various community service projects, such as staging a rally to support <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> troops in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, as well as putting together holiday care packages.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubio</ENAMEX> said she will miss being <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX>, but said she is looking forward to turning over her crown.   "I like helping the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubio</ENAMEX>. "But I want someone else to feel the same experiences."   The new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> will receive a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500</NUMEX> scholarship and her royalty will receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> scholarships. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX> said there will also be opportunities to pursue other scholarships.   During the next few weeks, each of the participants will be selling raffle tickets and gathering business sponsors to help pay for the expenses of the pageant and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> float.   At the pageant, each participant will be judged in the area of individual talent, evening gown wear and grade point average. Judges will also look for the responses of contestants during a spontaneous question period.   "Our pageants have been very exciting in the past," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX>. "Everything is really upbeat. We invite everybody to come out."   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

