
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The parents, athletes and coaches of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> would like to thank the following individuals for supporting the opportunity for the youth of our community to participate in school activities.   On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 17</TIMEX> the following physicians voluntarily provided sports physicals to 215 student/athletes: Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Loffer</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Bingham</ENAMEX>, Dr. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Biggs</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Couturier</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Kim</ENAMEX> and Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anne Nealen</ENAMEX>.   The following individuals also volunteered invaluable support: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Garner</ENAMEX>, RN; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Robinson</ENAMEX>, RN; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penny Ross</ENAMEX>, RN; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Loffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haile Loffer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lathen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Lathen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Linde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzi Carpino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melodie Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Stamschror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alice Aguirre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Wells</ENAMEX>, Capri Miles and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> rally squad.   Thank you again for the continued support of the activity programs within the schools and the youth of our community.   /s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Daley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletic</ENAMEX> Director, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

