


<P ID="1">Fake checks costly to G'view businesses
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - To date, the counterfeit check scandal believed to be operating in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> has bilked more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> from unsuspecting business owners.
</P><P ID="4">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX> has received multiple reports that checks have been cashed at local businesses and later found to be counterfeit.
</P><P ID="5">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> detectives, what appear to be legitimate payroll checks have been cashed. The majority of them were cashed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late last week</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "We have identified over 50 bad checks so far," said the police. "We have identified 40-plus names that are used on these checks."
</P><P ID="7">   It is unknown how many suspects are involved since different identifications may have been used by the same suspect more than once. Identifications being used by the suspects is also counterfeit. Currently, there aren't any suspects in custody.
</P><P ID="8">   The business being used on the counterfeit checks is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evans Fruit Company Inc.</ENAMEX> with an address in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowiche</ENAMEX>. A company representative said that payroll checks from the business beginning with number 295 should be considered suspicious.
</P><P ID="9">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> police, there are some good payroll checks from the company, but any checks that begin with the numbers 295 should be confirmed with the company before being cashed.
</P><P ID="10">   The Grandview police suggest that all identification be carefully examined before a check is cashed. Detectives also suggest that a thumbprint be placed on cashed checks, which can be helpful to investigators.
</P>   
   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




