
<P ID="1">Seniors dominate 4.00 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> list at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Of the 38 students named to the 4.00 grade point average honor roll for the first semester of the 2003-04 academic year at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, nearly half are seniors.   The 18 seniors who scored perfect grades for the first semester include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Anderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tasha Axmaker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Barr</ENAMEX>, Nehemias Chalma, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Derek Dolan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX>, Alaina Hull, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Kilian</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Kresse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maira Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebecca Razey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Sambrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Taylor</ENAMEX>, Deann Trautman and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Van Wingerden</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> junior class has eight students named to the 4.00 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> honor roll. They straight-A students are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Alanis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Bingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizeth Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea Durfey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Juarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marika McNerney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenden Scott</ENAMEX>.   Six sophomores are listed on the all-A's honor roll. They include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Alquicira</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Linde</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Plesha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra Romero</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Van Wingerden</ENAMEX>.   The straight-A freshman group for the first semester is comprised of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachelle Durfey</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Estrada</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jillian Jetter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Nevarez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sterling Scott</ENAMEX>.   Numerous other <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> students have been named to the regular honor roll for the first semester. To qualify for that distinction, students had to maintain at least a 3.00 grade point average.   The regular honor roll students from the freshman class include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Aguiar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Amaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Arola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlyn Avalos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reginald Avalos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Ballesteros</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Bravo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leticia Camacho-Reyes</ENAMEX>, Heather Cant, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Carpenter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anayelli Casas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe Ciriano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Cisneros</ENAMEX>, Carly Dahlstrom, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natasha Daniel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Engel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Espindola</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amelia Esquivel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebekah Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Fluaitte</ENAMEX>, Sadrac Franco, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felicia Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherran Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariel Garza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Hale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Renee Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jarred Huenefeld</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Huerta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Jimenez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Kennedy</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Kim</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Knee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Knee</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Kresse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anayeli Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Magana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marlene Magana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Mandrell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Martin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marina Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianna Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Meza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Moore</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Morfin</ENAMEX>, Anestacia Olivarez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Omlin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Paulakis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elayne Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Picazo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Polo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Ramos</ENAMEX>, Nayeli Rodriguez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mallory Saldana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Salinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Sambrano</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Freddy Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Sartin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Scherer</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dane Schmick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Solis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica Tlatelpa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ana Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerri Urrutia</ENAMEX>, Santa Valdivia, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audra Vasquez</ENAMEX>, Corrin Veiga, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Vidales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Wavrin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levi Wiersma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Wise</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Yanez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eduardo Zaragosa</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> sophomore class is represented on the regular honor roll by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Aguirre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grecia Alanis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Albrecht</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica Almeida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josue Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Bardell</ENAMEX>, Sunny Barnes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crystal Barraza</ENAMEX>, Bones Boboth, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurelio Bueno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yanet Candido</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Casas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Austin Copenhaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacqueline DeRuyter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bianca Diaz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Diaz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Downing</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyson Driesen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Espinoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Galvan-Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel Galvan-Velez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Gomez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel Graham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meghan Grubenhoff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gudino</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Guillen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celia Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, Bobi Haringa, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zachary Hathaway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Hazzard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darren Huenefeld</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Ibarra</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariana Jimenez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Jolliff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Juarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Lara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Loma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joaquin Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leticia Lujan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ariana Macias</ENAMEX>, Jerika Maratinez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucero Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Mendoza</ENAMEX>, Capri Miles, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey Morris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perla Ortega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Ortiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eron Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Rand</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Markus Rollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Roman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alma Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fatima Ruelas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Salinas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvaro Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victor Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Sanderson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo Serna</ENAMEX>, Derrick Simmons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Solis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Stamschror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Tobin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Tyler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Valles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Vasquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griselda Villalobos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lance Warner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lacey Yanez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Zakahi</ENAMEX> and Jordan Zavala.   Juniors qualifying for regular honor roll accolades include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candelario Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Alvarez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Amaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Baldovinos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Barr</ENAMEX>, Geneveve Barrios, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan Beals</ENAMEX>, Kacee Bootsma, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Brito</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lionel Candido</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cantu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Cornelius</ENAMEX>, Maria Corona, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marina Cruz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Cullen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeramie Drollinger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sonia Flores</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocio Galvez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mirian Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Garibaldo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skyllar Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Griffin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cris Guevara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Guillen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jared Holman</ENAMEX>, Yesenia Jalifi, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Jetter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Travis Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Lick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sofia Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maribel Madrigal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Marin</ENAMEX>, Asuncion Marquez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Martin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devina Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercedes Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodolfo Meza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Morris</ENAMEX>, Miryam Navarro, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christopher Newberry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lanna Pangle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Pasillas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viridiana Pasillas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Plesha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Quinonez</ENAMEX>, Kasi Puente, Magaly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delia Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Rios</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Ross</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandra Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Salazar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teresa Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esmeralda Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Sarmiento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reid Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Schwartz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Stamschror</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Thomas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esteban Trujillo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Uribe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Velasquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Waterman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurora Weaver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evan Wu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe Zamarron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Zamorano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Zepeda</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> senior class members earning regular honor roll status for the first semester are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luz Abundiz</ENAMEX>, Guadalupe Angel, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griselda Arias</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Barcenas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Priscilla Bazaldua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Blanco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Burgard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Call</ENAMEX>, Mayra Carrillo, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Araceli Casas</ENAMEX>, Catalina Castro, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Chiprez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Christensen</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra Coder</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne Cohan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Daire</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo Diaz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Evans</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Fernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roxanne Fernandez</ENAMEX>, Amber Fox, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Galvan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Galvan-Velez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Galvez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizette Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Garza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Gilleland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Isley Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Grimmer</ENAMEX>, Suleime Guzman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erin Hall</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Hazzard</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Henry</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herman Hitchcock-Lain</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicholas Howat</ENAMEX>, Brionna Hughes, Branimit Janjevic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatriz Jimenez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lindsay Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jared Jongsma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Kearney</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Kellogg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Lopez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Lua</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Luke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Maltos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holli Mandrell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humberto Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Matson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Mendez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector Mendoza</ENAMEX>, Tiburcio Mora, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosie Moran</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Morrow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Noriega</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Ochoa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Ortiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Ortiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reece Paulus</ENAMEX>, Kathya Quijano, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janie Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Ramirez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Ramos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Ramos</ENAMEX>, Marisol Reynoso, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cami Richardson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Riojas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Macario Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raymond Romero</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Ruiz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayra Sandoval</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Schiekel</ENAMEX>, Eliazar Sierra, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoffrey Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lester Wells</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Stamschror</ENAMEX>, Steffani Startup, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Taylor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celia Torres</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Valencia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Vargas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pedro Velez</ENAMEX>, Guadalupe Vidaurri, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Webster</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias Wise</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

