


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saul Road</ENAMEX> neighborhood annexation tabled
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">An annexation that would bring four parcels of land in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saul</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill</ENAMEX> road island neighborhood into the city limits has been tabled for further investigation.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> heard a request to annex property along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saul</ENAMEX> roads. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Road</ENAMEX> property belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt and Cynthia Butler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn and Norma Shinn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leon and Daphne Stewart</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saul Road</ENAMEX> property belongs to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose and Blanca Madrigal</ENAMEX>. All four families want their property zoned R-2, medium density. Their property all abut R-2 zoned land already within the city limits.
</P><P ID="6">   The neighborhood, which is just north of I-82, is currently under review by the Boundary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Board</ENAMEX>. It is expected the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> will rule that the neighborhood in question must be annexed into the city limits.
</P><P ID="7">   A nearby neighbor of the four families seeking the R-2 annexation, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manny Ledesma</ENAMEX>, said he is concerned that the owners of neighboring land, not currently being considered for annexation, will seek R-2 zoning in the future as well. The 12-acres, on the southwest portion of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saul Road</ENAMEX>, is not currently being considered for annexation.
</P><P ID="8">   Although the 12-acres is not being annexed at this time, the planning commissioners said it is their intention to eventually recommend zoning the large parcel as mini ranchettes, a zone that was created specifically for the neighborhood. A mini ranchette zone combines the rural lifestyle with the benefits of city living. In general, the mini ranchette zoning would establish one-acre parcels of land.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ledesma</ENAMEX> said he is also concerned that at the time of annexation the residents will have to pay a substantial amount of money to tie into the city's water and sewer system.
</P><P ID="10">   Planning Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Cleghorn</ENAMEX> said the idea that residents would have to pay money to be annexed is a misnomer.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> explained that the land would be "grandfathered" into the city and as long as the present water and sewer systems operate efficiently residents there would be allowed to use the systems already on their property.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Butler</ENAMEX>, who has a rental house on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Road</ENAMEX>, said one of the reasons why the petitioners want the R-2 annexation is that they are close to the city borders and are surrounded by the city, but they still have to call the county for help.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> said the reason they have requested an R-2 zoning is because his parents, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shinn</ENAMEX>'s, have a modular home on the back of their property where his grandfather lived. His grandfather died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   "They would like to keep the trailer, but it's not possible without the R-2 zoning," he said.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ria Van Dyken</ENAMEX>, who lives across the road from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>'s property, told the planning commissioners she is concerned about the petition that was submitted to the city. She pointed out that one of the signees is deceased, one has since moved and one is not a registered voter. Kunker responded, saying being a registered voter is not a requirement to sign a petition.
</P><P ID="16">   The annexation process has been in the works for nearly a year and reflects the residents of the property at the time the petition was signed, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>. He said that it is still a valid petition.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Dyken</ENAMEX> said she would prefer it if the property across the street from hers was zoned mini ranchette. Her concern, along with that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent and Kathy Tramel</ENAMEX>, who live behind <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>'s property, is that a duplex will be built on the property.
</P><P ID="18">   Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tramel</ENAMEX> said he feels the entire area should be zoned mini ranchette.
</P><P ID="19">   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tramel</ENAMEX> said if their property is annexed, they would want to be zoned mini ranchette, even though their property is smaller than an acre.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marv Meyers</ENAMEX>, another nearby neighbor, said that in a meeting held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX> the neighbors of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saul</ENAMEX> roads were promised or guaranteed that when the property was annexed it would be mini ranchettes.
</P><P ID="21">   "I don't think you should go back on your word," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyers</ENAMEX>. "We were promised that was what we were going to get."
</P><P ID="22">   The next door neighbor to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>'s rental on the west side is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norma Guerra</ENAMEX>, who also opposes the R-2 zoning in her neighborhood.
</P><P ID="23">   "The reason Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX> wants a duplex there is to put money in his pocket, not mine," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guerra</ENAMEX>. "We worked very darn hard for what we have.
</P><P ID="24">   "We have a very nice little community there," she said. "The only one who's going to profit here is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>, not us," she added.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Butler</ENAMEX> said that she and her husband are trying to open up future possibilities for their land.
</P><P ID="26">   "Down the road we maybe will put up a duplex," said Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butler</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="27">   In the end, the commissioners asked for more information on what was promised the residents in the neighborhood before making a decision. The issue was tabled until a later meeting.
</P>





 










<P ID="28">Webmaster
</P><P ID="29">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




