43 29 20 41 3 28
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  I define comfort as self-acceptance. When we finally learn that self-care begins and ends with ourselves, we no longer demand sustenance and happiness from others.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Louden</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>