


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s re-election campaign swings into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">"The mom in tennis shoes," who went on to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state in the U.S. Senate, kicks off her re-election campaign <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> is scheduled to travel across the state <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> to meet with voters. Her itinerary includes stops in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> is running for a third term in the U.S. Senate. Her chief rival in the race appears to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The senior campaign officials for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> said she will speak to voters during her swing through the state <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> about the importance of putting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> first. Stumping as a strong, independent voice for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state's needs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> is expected to highlight her shared priorities for job creation, education, protecting Americans' quality of life, improving homeland security and taking care of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> troops and veterans.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> is scheduled to speak at the Tri-Cities Plumbers and Pipefitters Hall in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> (1328 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Road</ENAMEX> 28) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> Her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> stop will be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW Post</ENAMEX> #379 on the corner of Walnut and Fifth avenues.
</P>   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




