
<P ID="1">Governor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">reappoints Matson</ENAMEX> to state economic board
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Port Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Matson</ENAMEX> was recently appointed to a group that has a lot of economic pull within the state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX> the reappointment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> to the state's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Economic Revitalization Board</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CERB</ENAMEX>).   "The legislature funds the board in varying amounts," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX>.   The point of the economic revitalization board is to help economically distressed areas across the state. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said the economic revitalization board is funded to the tune of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX></NUMEX> every biennium. The board lends economic support to such entities as port districts and counties looking for help with funding projects.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> has served two previous terms on the board. His current term will expire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 2, 2007</TIMEX>.   The board currently has 19 people from different fields around the state serving, with one vacancy. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> is also the current vice chair of the group. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Boekholder</ENAMEX> serves as board chair. Miland Walling of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> is a small business representative on the group. Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is one of the state officials serving on the agency board.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> first became involved with the CERB board while attending some meetings representing the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said CERB had helped fund some projects for the local port district.   "I was aware of the value of it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX>. "I pretty much knew it was a good program before I got on board."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said a position opened on CERB to represent the port districts and he grabbed the opportunity.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> opted to seek another term on the board because he enjoys and believes in what the group is doing.   "I enjoy working with the projects and see what is going on," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said it is rewarding to see how the CERB program has helped communities prosper.   The board members meet six times a year with most of the gatherings occurring at Sea-Tac. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said between three and four projects are funded at each meeting.   Over the years, CERB has helped fund many successful economic development projects. But some of the most successful projects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> has been involved with came in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> recognized the need to improve transportation infrastructure to help attract businesses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said many cities across the state took advantage of the opportunity provided by the state to make improvements. The Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Prosser</ENAMEX> received money to make improvements to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midvale Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>, respectively. CERB has also helped the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with funding for improvements to its wastewater treatment plant.   The CERB program is going really well right now, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX>.   "We have a pretty good funding base for the next couple of years," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said locally there are no projects he knows of that will come before CERB in the near future.   But, he added, "It would surprise me if we didn't have any come up."   One part <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> enjoys is the diversity of the group. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said the group is well represented by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> people. However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> said the west vs. east side of the mountain politics never comes into play.   "It is a pretty good group of people," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX>. "It is a good program."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

