


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMSI</ENAMEX> exhibit brings <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Goodall</ENAMEX>'s work to life
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PORTLAND</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - If it walks like a chimp, talks like a chimp and looks like a chimp, is it a chimp? Not necessarily...Sept. 28 the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Museum of Science and Industry</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMSI</ENAMEX>) will open "Discovering Chimpanzees: The Remarkable World of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Goodall</ENAMEX>," which gives visitors a chance to walk like a chimp, climb into a giant chimp nest and learn about primates.
</P><P ID="4">   Through the exhibit visitors will be immersed in the forest environment of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gombe National Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tanzania</ENAMEX>, meeting Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Goodall</ENAMEX>'s now famous chimpanzee subjects, and getting an up close look at them as they fight, hunt, play and communicate with each other. Visitors will see how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX>'s relationship with the chimps evolved from one of strictly scientific interest to one of devotion and a firm commitment to chimpanzee survival.
</P><P ID="5">   "'Discovering Chimpanzees' gives visitors a sense of Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX>'s remarkable story and her global influence, while taking them on an exciting adventure," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Johnson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OMSI</ENAMEX> director of museum and teacher education. "It's an up close and personal encounter with both Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX>, and some very endearing chimpanzee characters."
</P><P ID="6">   The exhibit includes four distinct areas, each one focusing on a different area of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX>'s work.
</P><P ID="7">   The first exhibit, the Chimp Forest, takes visitors into the jungle home of the chimpanzees, giving them a chance to experience what it's like to be a chimp in the lush foliage of the Tanzanian jungle. This area includes instructional videos that teach visitors to walk and talk like a chimp, and also offers them a chance to climb into a chimp nest. The Chimp Forest also has an exhibit that shows people how chimps create tools to fish for termites, it then gives visitors a chance to try it for themselves at the simulated termite mound.
</P><P ID="8">   The Work of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Goodall</ENAMEX> portion of the exhibit brings 40 years of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX>'s research to life through field notes, photographs, video clips and other artifacts. Visitors will be able to sit in a re-creation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX>'s field research tent and watch video accounts of some of her most memorable achievements and milestones during her four decades of research. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gombe</ENAMEX> timeline documents the family history of the chimps, exploring family structure, alpha male dominance and the genealogy of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gombe</ENAMEX> matriarchs.
</P><P ID="9">   Another portion of the exhibit, Primates, is an exploration of the order of primates. Visitors will learn about each of the 12 families of primates, their habitats and threats to their survival. They'll compare their physical characteristics to that of other primates, and join in the primate reunion for a 'family photo.'
</P><P ID="10">   The final portion of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX> exhibit is Reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hope</ENAMEX>. This area of the exhibit is a demonstration of the successful initiatives of individuals who have taken action to deal with environmental and societal issues.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX> has spent more than 40 years in the African tropical forest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gombe National Park</ENAMEX>, studying the lives of chimpanzees in the wild. Her earliest discovery, that chimpanzees create and use tools, something that was originally thought to be a uniquely human ability, forced the scientific community to rethink its distinction between humans and animals. Over the years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Goodall</ENAMEX> discovered several startling similarities between humans and chimps and recent testing has confirmed that chimpanzees share <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">98.6 percent</NUMEX> of the same DNA.
</P><P ID="12">   Discovering Chimpanzees will open at OMSI <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 28</TIMEX> and run through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 2, 2005</TIMEX>. The exhibit is a production of Science North, located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sudbury</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




