


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G'view Council</ENAMEX> votes to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> on lighting upgrades
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The lighting situation at the Grandview library has been a topic of conversation among city officials since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> held a joint meeting with the library board in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voted to allot more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> to help alleviate lighting concerns at both Blehyl Community Library and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> waited several months to approve funding for the improvement project to see if the project would qualify for a state assistance program. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that the project did not qualify for the program, noting that the dollar value to qualify for the program was higher than the cost of both the library and the police department projects combined.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that after receiving word that the lighting improvement project didn't qualify for the state assistance program, he contacted PP&L to see if there was anything the city could do to alleviate the lighting situation in both buildings.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that PP&L was willing to offer the city a rebate if they retrofitted the buildings with more energy-efficient lighting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the total cost of retrofitting the police department and the library would be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,273</NUMEX>, which includes more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> in rebates from PP&L. He added that with the energy efficient fixtures the city should save more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,000</NUMEX> a year lighting the library and more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> a year lighting the police department. He noted that the overall savings means the city will see a return on their investment in 21 months.
</P><P ID="8">   "Then the savings will go on," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said. "The savings will continue."
</P><P ID="9">   In a memorandum to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> outlined that the retro-fitting program will include replacing all of the critical parts of the existing light fixtures, such as sockets, wire and ballasts and replacing them with state-of-the-art equipment. He added that the current 9,000 hour fluorescent bulbs will be replaced with thinner 20,000 hour bulbs.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that the funds to pay for the lighting upgrade will come from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$71,000</NUMEX> in unanticipated revenue that is available for one-time capital expenditures. Since finding out about the revenue in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has voted to spend <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11,000</NUMEX> on improvements to the Dykstra Park Pathway and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,500</NUMEX> for architectural services for the aquatic center proposal.
</P><P ID="11">   The need for lighting improvements at the library was discussed when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> down with members of the library board in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. At that time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Librarian Linda Dunham</ENAMEX> passed around a box that contained a burned ballast, noting that the piece of lighting equipment had started smoking one day and could have caused a fire if it hadn't occurred during regular business hours.
</P><P ID="12">   Work on upgrading lighting at the library and the police department is scheduled to begin sometime <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




