


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds third at 4A tourney
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LAKE STEVENS</ENAMEX> - The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> took their show on the road <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, showing several 4A schools just what the 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team is made of.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, the Lady 'Hounds played in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Stevens</ENAMEX> tournament against 4A teams from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Monroe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Stevens</ENAMEX>. At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the day</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team had played 11 games in five matches, coming home with a third place finish.
</P><P ID="6">   "It was a pretty good day," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> about the Lady 'Hounds performance.
</P><P ID="7">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team managed to push past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monroe</ENAMEX> by scores of 25-20 and 25-13, then split against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jackson</ENAMEX>, winning 24-21, then losing 25-18. The next team the Lady 'Hounds faced was from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port Angeles</ENAMEX>, a team the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls defeated 25-12 and 25-8. The next team on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s list was host <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Stevens</ENAMEX>, a team the Lady 'Hounds beat by scores of 25-22 and 25-19. The final match of the day saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> face off against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX>. The 'Hounds lost in three by scores of 12-25, 25-21 and 13-15.
</P><P ID="8">   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> was going up against a group of 4A teams, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said many of them are teams the Lady 'Hounds have played in the past. This is a tournament his team traditionally takes part in.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said taking part in a 4A tournament like the one held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lake Stevens</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> exposes his team to different styles of play.
</P><P ID="10">   "It's nice to get to see [the other teams] play a little different style of defense," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="11">   He added that it helps prepare his team to adapt to those different styles of play.
</P><P ID="12">   "They get more experience, in case we meet a team from a town that plays like that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said. "We want to get as much experience as possible against different teams."
</P><P ID="13">   He said it's also nice to expose his team to different playing arenas, noting that it gives the team a chance to go to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Everett</ENAMEX> area and see where each of the teams in the tournament are from and where they play.
</P><P ID="14">   Many of the players on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team showed that they can handle the diversity that playing larger schools brings with it. Senior Danelle Cowan racked up 32 kills, 4 aces and 16 blocks for the day, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> had 22 kills, 9 aces and 16 blocks, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> had 12 kills and 8 blocks, Kealey Johnston had 13 kills, 43 digs, 6 aces and 42 service points.
</P><P ID="15">   "She did a really good job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Johnston</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   Also helping out the team was setter Chante Bottineau with 63 assists, 5 aces and 43 service points for the day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> had 3 kills and 20 digs for the Lady 'Hounds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Gonzalez</ENAMEX> had 4 services aces and 5 service points, and Tonhya Wysong had 60 digs.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Penwell</ENAMEX> was brought up to the varsity team during the tournament and got her first four varsity kills during the course of the day.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said playing in the tournament proved to be a good experience for his team.
</P><P ID="19">   It was such a good experience that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team will be facing off against more 4A schools this coming weekend in the Wenatchee tournament. But before the team can head to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wenatchee</ENAMEX> they will play a league match-up against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




