


<P ID="1"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> will bring many changes for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s parks department
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Don Stiles</ENAMEX> made what will almost certainly be his last budget presentation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> during its study session on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   As part of cuts in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget to help make-up for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$393,910</NUMEX> shortfall, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> proposed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to eliminate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX>' position. The position cut will result in a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> savings for the city.
</P><P ID="6">   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> found an ally during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s study session in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Raul Martinez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he would like to comb through the budget to find the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX> to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX>, saying the position was important to the parks department.
</P><P ID="7">   "If we can find the funds as we comb through the budget, I would opt to keep a director," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Prior to discussing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX>' position, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> sifted through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget requests for the parks department. An added expense in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is the unforeseen duty to operate the community center <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   The city will take back control of the community center because the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX>, which is currently managing the facility, terminated its contract. The city assumes control of the community center <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 1</TIMEX>. Plans are to locate the parks and recreation department at the community center, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   Why the city is in such a quandary with the community center, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, is that under the terms of the Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) the city obtained for construction of the community center, officials have to keep the building open to the public.
</P><P ID="11">   "The difficulty we face here is having this thrust upon us when we really don't have the ability to say no," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   The proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget for the parks department totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$530,270</NUMEX>. Operating the community center will add an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$63,180</NUMEX> in expenses. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> and Finance Director Chad Stotz estimate it will cost the city <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$73,180</NUMEX> to operate the community center in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, but the figure was reduced because the city is using <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,000</NUMEX> it already has available in the budget to operate the facility. The city is anticipating <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$53,400</NUMEX> in revenue from the community center in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   Parks and rec salaries in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> will total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$267,160</NUMEX>, down from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$272,630</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. Under the proposed budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> will lose his position as parks director. This will result in the creation of a parks and recreation coordinator. The city will then hire a recreation assistant.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said it was a difficult decision to cut the parks and recreation director position.
</P><P ID="15">   Focusing on the community center, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> explained that to maintain the staffing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> has had at the community center, it will cost the city <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,560</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said the city could help fund some of those positions by continuing catering services at the center. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> is speculating the city could raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> in catering.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> wanted to look at partnering with the school district to possibly hire someone to oversee the community center and the operation of other venues in the community.
</P><P ID="17">   "I feel like all we are going to do at best is keep the doors open at the community center," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said the problem with the city proposal is that the parks and recreation staff will be busy doing their duties and have no time to operate the center.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said one area the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Migrant Council</ENAMEX> was successful in was obtaining volunteers at the community center. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is hoping to establish a strong volunteer base. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> acknowledged that the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> will be a learning experience for operating the community center.
</P><P ID="20">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> wanted to continue to look at partnerships, but suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> move forward with adopting the proposed budget.
</P><P ID="21">   Much like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> was cautious about having the position of recreation coordinator be in charge of parks and recreation duties. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he would like to look through the parks budget for extra revenue funds.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> ended the evening with a few comments for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said he doesn't agree <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">100 percent</NUMEX> with the decision by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> to eliminate his position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> nixed a suggestion that he serves as director of the community center. If <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> does decide to eliminate his position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that after 17 plus years working as parks director it would be hard for him to relinquish the role.
</P><P ID="23">   "It is going to be a challenge, but there are some things I am looking at," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX>. "I appreciate the opportunity to have worked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="24">   There are two other areas that fall within the parks and recreation budget-the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Museum</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Center</ENAMEX>. These two items are reviewed as separate budget areas.
</P><P ID="25">   The city was able to free up some extra money after relinquishing control of the library to the Yakima Regional Library System.
</P><P ID="26">   Maintenance and custodial work for the local library fell under control of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> parks department.
</P><P ID="27">   As a result of giving up operation of the library, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> preliminary budget spread around the duties of the custodian that cleaned the library. This results in a little less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> salary increase for the custodian cleaning the museum.
</P><P ID="28">   The budget for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Center</ENAMEX>, which is also a separate item from the actual parks and recreation budget, will see a minimal increase in its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget because of additional custodial work. The proposed budget for the senior center in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,600</NUMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,810</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="29">Webmaster
</P><P ID="30">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




