
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> makes <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late night</TIMEX> visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> looking for votes
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX> wasn't an ordinary <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> began a whirlwind tour of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, which included an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX> stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, as he tries to become the first senator from the east side of the state in 82 years.   "I am going to be that senator. I have the right values," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> told a large crowd gathered outside of The Outpost convenience store <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. "We are going to bring strong leadership to the United States Senate because you deserve it."   But to become the first senator from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> in more than 80 years, the Spokane Republican will need all the votes he can get on this election day to unseat Democrat incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>.   "We are not quitting until we win this election," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, as he deboarded one of two chartered buses filled with campaign supporters.   "I want everybody in the state to know I want to win this election," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.   Even though <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> is an underdog in his campaign to unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>, it is not the first time the congressman has had his back against the wall.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> pulled off a stunning political upset of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Foley</ENAMEX>, who was speaker of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Representatives at the time, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s fifth congressional district seat. It was the first time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1860</TIMEX> that a sitting speaker of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">house</ENAMEX> had lost a re-election campaign.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, who was heading to his next stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, encouraged the crowd in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to go out and talk with their neighbors about his campaign and what he can bring to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> residents.   "I am not worried about polls. I am not worried about editorials," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>. "I am worried about the people who go out to vote."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> told the crowd that it is time for a change in the United States Senate.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> never comes here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> is a sad incumbent."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> went over some of the issues his campaign is standing on as it looks to garner enough supporters to unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he is in favor of cutting taxes, supporting the troops fighting the war overseas and medical liability reform. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has voted against all those issues while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> ended his stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> by encouraging people to go out and vote for him and other Republican candidates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> also left the crowd in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with one promise if elected to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.   "This won't be the last time you see me in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

