
<P ID="1">School board informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> hoop schedule to be changed next season
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/27/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> high school basketball will have a new look to it <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   That was the message <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Principal Dennis Birr</ENAMEX> and Grizzly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Athletic Director Bill Daley</ENAMEX> brought before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> told board members that at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX> meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> of principals and athletic directors, a new scheduling system for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> games was discussed.   The new scheduling, which will take effect next season, will have boys and girls varsity and junior varsity basketball teams playing all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> games on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> nights. C-squad and freshman league basketball games will be played on Thursdays and Saturdays.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> leaving the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, teams will only have 12 league games. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> did tell the school board that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s varsity teams will still have to play some <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> contests because of its non-league schedule, as other schools that aren't in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> don't fall under this schedule.   Under the scheduling, the varsity girls and junior varsity boys basketball teams would play at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:45 p.m.</TIMEX> on both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> nights for league games. The varsity boys and junior varsity girls would play at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:15 p.m.</TIMEX>   The C-squad and freshman basketball teams will hold the same <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> times for their games. Games times would be different on Saturdays with the C-squad girls and freshman boys playing at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> The C-squad boys and freshman girls would follow at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 p.m.</TIMEX> The school district will not charge patrons to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> games, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said one of the reasons for the change was the extended amount of time students are gone on game nights. Under the old format, all four teams would play on the same night. For away games, students would leave around <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, depending on the game site, and not return until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 p.m.</TIMEX> or later.   "What we will see (under this schedule) is our kids getting home earlier," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>.   There are several benefits to this format, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>. First, the number of workers needed to stage a basketball game will be less. Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said most schools are using nearly 20 people a night to put on a game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said the league will also be able to obtain better officials for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> games. There will also be more gym space available, as games will only be played in two gyms instead of three. Another benefit, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>, is that the varsity coach will have an opportunity to see all squads play.   The negative side to the proposal, pointed out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>, is that not all coaches will be on the bench for each of the games. The C-squad and freshman coaches could conceivably be coaching four nights per week. Non-league scheduling and study time for class assignments could also be limited.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two years</TIMEX>, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> scheduling will be a great benefit for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, as the Grizzlies will have their two byes on that evening.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX> added the new scheduling will also help free up some clogged gym space at the elementary schools. Currently, the basketball programs are interfering with after-school elementary programs such as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st Century</TIMEX> and Latchkey.   "We saw some side benefits coming out of this for our elementary kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Birr</ENAMEX> added that other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> schools are in favor of the new schedule because of a lack of gymnasium space to house all the games simultaneously.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said there is a potential loss of revenue under the new scheduling system, but he is hoping the non-league games will make-up for any loss of monies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> told the board he will be keeping a close eye on the revenue situation.   "It will be a good change and it will be reviewed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

