


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> asked to resign
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> businessman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Sartin</ENAMEX> stood before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> asking for the resignation of one of its members.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> wanted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> to relinquish his seat following remarks he made at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 14</TIMEX> meeting about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960s</TIMEX> civil rights activist Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> being an adulterer.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX> said to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that if he was sitting in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>' chair he would resign after making such remarks about Dr. King. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> rebuffed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sartin</ENAMEX>'s request, saying that his claims about King can be substantiated. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> also added that he didn't leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting after making the remarks, so why would he resign his position.
</P><P ID="6">   "I refuse to," stated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> then put an end to the discussion, which was taking place right at the end of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting, calling for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to adjourn.
</P>   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




