
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/23/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KATHRYN MCDONALD CHARVET
KATHRYN MCDONALD CHARVET
Kathryn</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kay</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDonald Charvet</ENAMEX>, 63, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 21, 2004</TIMEX>, at her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 19, 1940</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Reno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nev.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> (Gibson) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McDonald</ENAMEX>. She attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">San Juaquin Memorial School</ENAMEX> from kindergarten through 10th grade. Her family then moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sacramento</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, where she graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Loretto High School</ENAMEX>. She attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzaga University</ENAMEX>, where she began her studies in engineering, but later majored in English and education.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 15, 1963</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Joseph Charvet</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sacramento</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1965</TIMEX> they settled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to raise their family and begin a career of farming.
She is survived by her husband of 41 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry J. Charvet</ENAMEX>; three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Karen Triplett</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hal Charvet</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kirkland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Skok</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gavin</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Issaquah</ENAMEX>; and eight granddaughters.
A Rosary will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 25, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Church</ENAMEX>. Interment will follow at Mabton Cemetery. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JAKE MAUCH
Jake Mauch</ENAMEX>, 88, long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 21, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 8, 1915</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Robinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.D</ENAMEX>. to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wacker</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mauch</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 22, 1936</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene Haeger</ENAMEX> in Bell Fouche, S.D., later moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> to make their home. He farmed and worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry Weckter</ENAMEX> and the sugar beet factory in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>. They later purchased 80 acres of land, where they farmed and had a small dairy. He also worked various jobs along with his farming, custom hauling, working at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Del Monte</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and cutting meat for Pete Hoyte Market. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> he sold his farm and went to barbering in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, which he enjoyed for many years. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX> he retired and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his wife of 67 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene Mauch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; four daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Brown</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beatty</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlene Poole</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billie Clements</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mona Worrell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reuben Mauch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>; 15 grandchildren; and 17 great-grandchildren.
He was preceded in death by his parents; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Howard Mauch</ENAMEX>; five brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Art</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam and Ben</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvina Moser</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 25, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 26, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elmwood Cemetery</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JOSEFINA PEREZ ALVAREZ
Josefina Perez Alvarez</ENAMEX>, 25, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, June 20, 2004</TIMEX>, due to injuries sustained in an auto accident.
 She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19, 1979</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cueramaro</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olga</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. She received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josefina</ENAMEX> had been currently employed at Pizza Hut in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
 She enjoyed spending time with her children and having a good time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josefina</ENAMEX> also collected angels which she enjoyed very much. She has now passed on to be an angel of God.  She had many friends that knew the loving and kind hearted person that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Josie</ENAMEX> always was. Her particular laugh, look and sense of humor will always be remembered. The love that she had for her daughters can never be replaced for they were her world.
She is survived by her parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olga</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Perez</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexandra Reyna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Giovanni Reyna</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Javier Alvarez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail Alvarez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; her grandmother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonia Salvador</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> and grandparents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorotea Perez</ENAMEX> and Santiago Perez Munoz of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; and numerous aunts, uncles, nieces, nephews, cousins and friends.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 23, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with an evening service at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immaculate Conception Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at Mabton Cemetery. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ENRIQUE GONZALEZ
Enrique Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, 19, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, June 20, 2004</TIMEX>, due to injuries sustained in an auto accident.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 29, 1984</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael and Maria Carmen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reyna</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. He spent his early years in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> with his family until moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>, where he attended school.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique</ENAMEX> enjoyed spending time with his friends and family, and he was a very happy person with many dreams to fulfill.
He is survived by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Carmen Reyna</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard Gonzalez Reyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian Rafael Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joann Jesus Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; his grandparents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe Serrano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Pimintel</ENAMEX>; and many aunts, uncles and cousins.
He was preceded in death by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael Gonzalez</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 24, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be recited at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 25, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immaculate Conception Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at Mabton Cemetery. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.   
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RAFAEL GONZALEZ
Rafael Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, 42, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, June 20, 2004</TIMEX>, due to injuries sustained in an auto accident.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 7, 1962</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serrano</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Carmen Reyna</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. They together made <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> their home until moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael</ENAMEX> worked for various farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rafael</ENAMEX> cherished time spent with his family and enjoyed helping others.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Carmen Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; three sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo Gonzalez Reyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christian Rafael Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joann Jesus Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, brothers and sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sofia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conception Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salvador Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>; and his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guadalupe Serrano</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his father; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 24, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>,  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 25, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immaculate Conception Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at Mabton Cemetery. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JESUS PIMENTEL REYNA
Jesus Pimentel Reyna</ENAMEX>, 26, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, June 20, 2004</TIMEX>, due to injuries sustained in an auto accident.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 4, 1977</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teodoro Reyna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Del Socorro Pimentel</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and was currently attending college at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Basin Community College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> was employed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>, where he worked in construction.
He enjoyed spending time with his family, playing video games with his daughters and fishing with his brothers.
He is survived by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teodoro Reyna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Del Socorro Pimentel Reyna</ENAMEX>; two daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexandra Reyna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Giovanni Reyna</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; and six brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Manuel Reyna</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teodoro Reyna Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Reyna</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Alberto Reyna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel Angel Reyna</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enrique Reyna</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 23, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, June 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immaculate Conception Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at Mabton Cemetery. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

