
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> appoints12 to health, sex education committee
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> created a 12-member committee to review the district's health and sex education curriculum. The members include one administrator, two students, five parents and four staff members. Also included on the list of those planning to participate in the process are four ex officio members.
Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> said he interviewed all of the applicants and narrowed it down to the 12 he was recommending to the board. He said the people on the committee are a very diverse, but a very balanced group.
He added that parents who were appointed to the board all have children who are attending school and are all actively involved in their children's education.
The people who make up the committee include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School Principal Janie Hernandez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> students <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julian Stroh</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mira Mendoza</ENAMEX>, parents <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Bardell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzie Zamarron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marilyn Van Oostrum</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Shuttleworth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Linde</ENAMEX>; staff members <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Griffith</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Alseth</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalia Gonzalez</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Peabody</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. The ex officio members include <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanne Kilian</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan</TIMEX> McDonald with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pregnancy Center</ENAMEX>, Berenise Martinez with Planned Parenthood and Sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Rita Rohde</ENAMEX> with Nuestra Casa.
</P> 


 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

