
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Speed limits changed near distribution center
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted to increase the speed limit around the Wal-Mart distribution center from 25 miles per hour to 35 miles per hour.
The speed limit increase will take effect on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodall Road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Stover Road</ENAMEX> north to the city limits, on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bethany Road</ENAMEX> from the curve north to the city limits, and on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Stover Road</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> east to the city limits.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> takes first step in annexation request
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members accepted a letter of intent for annexation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert and Jacqueline Young</ENAMEX>. The annexation proposal includes just over 18 acres along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stover Road</ENAMEX>.
The parcel being proposed for annexation is designated for residential use in the city's urban growth area future land use designations, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Young</ENAMEX>'s are asking that it be annexed with an R-3 multi-family residential zone.
After being approved by council the annexation proposal will be sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> for a public hearing.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves amendment to recent annexation proposal
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted to approve an annexation proposal from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leroy and Joanna Blankenship</ENAMEX> that included 9.65 acres of property along Wilson Highway. When it was originally approved it was approved with an R-1 single family residential zone.
Since then, the developer requested that the zoning be amended to an R-2 zone that would allow for the building of several duplexes, as well as single family housing.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, council members approved the amendment to the zoning.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

