
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> campus welcomes new dean
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/15/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> students attending <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> courses at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College Grandview</ENAMEX> campus were probably surprised to see this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> a new dean.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Dotson</ENAMEX> began his duties as the new interim dean of the Grandview YVCC campus this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX>, 57, comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Gorge Community College</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, where he was interim associate dean of instruction.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YVCC</ENAMEX> Vice President of Instruction and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Services Anthony Beebe</ENAMEX> said he is excited about the arrival of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beebe</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> has a diverse background that will help make YVCC's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> campus an institution of better learning. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beebe</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> brings strong technical and vocational experience to his position in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "I really do believe he will be a good fit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Beebe</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> is no stranger to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>. His family is from the Tri-Cities, where his father still lives. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> worked for Battelle-Northwest in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> as a technical editor/writer for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Laboratories</ENAMEX> from 1979-80.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> spent a majority of his career in education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Powell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, working at the institute from 1982-99. Some of his other career highlights included being awarded a sabbatical to teach and study management and marketing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boise State University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> in 1992-93. While in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> gained experience as the faculty organization president, an associate professor and a division chair.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> has also worked at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clark College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>., where he was dean of business and technology from 2000-03.   He obtained his Bachelor of Arts degree in English in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> earned a Master's in English from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>. He is currently doing Ph.D course work in American literature at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Wisconsin-Madison</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he is excited about being able to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he was attracted to the position because it was an opportunity to work in a diverse area while serving a large number of students.   "I love rural campuses," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX>. "It seemed a really good fit for me."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he enjoys being involved with students of diverse backgrounds. He said for him it is fun to watch students evolve and grow while obtaining their education.   While the position is on an interim basis, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he does have some goals for the college. One of initial goals is to look at the instructional programs being offered at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> campus and see what can be added or how the programs can be bettered.   "I want to make this place as student-centered as possible," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX>. "That is already being done, but we want to make it better."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> also wants to take a look at the vocational classes being offered at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and stay involved with the technology side to make sure the campus is kept as up-to-date as possible.   "They (YVCC) seem to be doing an excellent job (on the technology side)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX>. "This is as good as you will see."   At the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> campus, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> will oversee a staff of 18 full-time employees and 17 part-time staff members. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he has been very impressed with how obvious it is that the staff wants to do what is best for the students at the college. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said that was one of the first things he saw upon taking the position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said the college staff, from President Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Kaminski</ENAMEX> on down have a deep dedication to making YVCC a better learning institution.   "You can always tell a good college because people are fired up about their jobs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX>. "This is the kind of college you want to be at where they want the students to succeed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he plans to keep an open door to his employees at the college. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he is a big believer in delegating, empowering and recognizing the accomplishments of employees.   "I tend to judge people on their results," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX>. "But I always want them to know there is help if they need it."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> has also been very impressed with how the college is involved with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dotson</ENAMEX> said he enjoyed his meetings with Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> and is looking forward to becoming part of the community. Dotson plans to become involved with the downtown revitalization efforts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

