


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> looks at how best to spend new criminal justice tax
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Although voters just recently passed Proposition #1, which implements an additional 3/10's of a penny sales tax increase in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> to help support the area's criminal justice system, voters are already looking for results.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview City Councilwoman Helen Darr</ENAMEX> noted that she has already received a phone call from a voter asking if they can expect to see more <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> police officers on the streets starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that the county is not going to be able to start collecting the new sales tax until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, with cities not receiving any funding until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Treasurer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Myers</ENAMEX> added that since collection won't begin until several months into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, the city will not receive its full allotment the first year. He said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> the city can expect to receive between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$95,000</NUMEX> from the new criminal justice tax.
</P><P ID="8">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> said since the tax won't be collected until spring, the city should probably wait to hire anyone new. He explained that if the city hires a new police officer in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, the city will end up paying that person's salary. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman Norm Childress</ENAMEX> added that if the city hires a new police officer before the funding arrives, it might be considered that the officer is a regular staff member and not qualify for Proposition #1 funding.
</P><P ID="9">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also voiced concerns about hiring a new police officer, noting that if they have to send the officer to the policy academy it could be a year before citizens actually see the new hire out on the streets.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Robert Morales</ENAMEX> asked why there is such an urgency to begin spending the funds. He noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Police Department</ENAMEX> has <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> with 16 officers for a number of years. Instead, he felt that the city should take some time to figure out where the gap is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX>'s current police service, and where the money really needs to be spent.
</P><P ID="11">   "The urgency I feel is a lot of the time the city only has one officer on duty through the night," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Pam Horner</ENAMEX>. She added that crime continues to grow in the community. "That's my sense of urgency," she said.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that the recommendation to hire another officer came from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Charvet</ENAMEX>. He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has the final decision has to how the funds from the criminal justice tax are spent.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Childress</ENAMEX> also pointed out that he feels its important that the city not look like it's sitting on its hands and not moving forward with something the taxpayers want.
</P><P ID="14">   "People are expecting something quickly," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darr</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="15">   Council members noted that they would like to invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charvet</ENAMEX> to attend a council meeting in order to discuss how the city will spend the funds that will be coming in thanks to Proposition #1.
</P><P ID="16">   "There really are a lot of considerations," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said.
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




