
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> leaders earn national honors
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Saying they face tough choices every day, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> leaders were honored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> by national leaders in the fight against substance abuse in schools. Honored as student heroes for their stand against substance abuse were members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> Leaders in Action group, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club SADD</ENAMEX> (Students Against Destructive Decisions) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TATU</ENAMEX> (Teens Against Tobacco Use).   The group of 50-plus students gathered in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 4</TIMEX>, to be presented the National Outstanding Youth Leadership Award from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Substance Abuse</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mental Health Services Administration</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAMSHA</ENAMEX>). The trophy was presented to the students by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Judy Kosterman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s state former "drug czar."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosterman</ENAMEX>, who now works with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Education</ENAMEX>, praised the teens for their roles in changing the climate at their school and in the community.   "Every day you are called upon to make tough choices and you make them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosterman</ENAMEX> told the teens.   "It's not always easy, but there are people who respect you for what you do and that is what this award is all about," she explained.   The teens leaders, supported by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Promise, were also honored by the national organization during the SAMSHA's <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Faith</ENAMEX> and Community Summit held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 18-23</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> students were applauded for the impact they make on their peers by example and student-driven anti-abuse activities. Among the activities were those which provide alternatives to youths who are tempted to use alcohol, tobacco and drugs, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hughes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District Safety</ENAMEX> Director. The teen leaders represent athletes, club presidents and church youth groups.   "The young leaders have worked among their peers, hosting anti- smoking campaigns, as well as drug prevention programs for middle school-age students," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>.   He said the teens' work during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX> has resulted in several awareness programs now being used in classroom presentations in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools and at church youth group meetings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosterman</ENAMEX> also praised the youths for their courageous stand against drugs and for their dally decisions to be healthy role models to others in the community.   "It is because of your decision to stand for change that you've earned this leadership award," she said.   "It's not just little kids who look up to you," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kosterman</ENAMEX> added. "Adults in your school, your community and in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. look up to you."   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> student leaders were also honored by state leaders <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 5</TIMEX>, when they traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olympia</ENAMEX>, to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> Lt. Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Owen</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

