
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> awards legal bids to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> unanimously approved the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> to serve as the official newspaper for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. This means the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> will publish all legal notices for the city.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voted to reject the then lone bid of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> to serve as the city's official newspaper. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voted to reopen the bid process because some of its members felt that the city had sent out the wrong message a few years ago with the legal publication process.   The hometown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> newspaper has served as the legal newspaper of the city since its inception.   This time around, the city received just two bids to serve as the legal newspaper for the city. One of the bids was from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and the other was from the Yakima Herald-Republic.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> submitted the same bid it did during the initial process in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.70</NUMEX> per column inch. The Yakima Herald-Republic submitted two separate bid amounts. The first amount was for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.48</NUMEX> per column inch for the weekly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> publication Voices. The Herald-Republic also submitted a bid amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.66</NUMEX> per column inch, if published in the regular daily section.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said he did an analysis for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> based on past legal publications.   In his report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> cited the lead time of each publication as a factor to consider. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> offered a lead-time of 24 hours, but has been able to publish notices on a shorter time frame. The Herald-Republic requires legal notices to be in its office by <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> for Voices and three business days prior to publication in the regular section of the newspaper.   In his report, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> noted city staff wouldn't be able to meet the Herald-Republic's deadline for publishing notices of cancelled meetings in the Voices section and would have to pay more money to have them inserted into the daily section.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>'s final analysis showed the city would have paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36</NUMEX> less with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> had it published its legal notices in the Voices publication <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.   "The research <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> has given has allowed us to compare apples to apples," said newly sworn in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rockford</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> touched on how there are benefits for the city to do business with the local paper. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> submitted the lowest bid and has always assisted the city on short notice, so he recommended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> accept the bid.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> also praised city staff for its work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> said while he doesn't always see eye-to-eye with what is written in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>, he wanted to keep the legal publication notices in the community with the local newspaper.   "I for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">one am</TIMEX> glad we have a comparison," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>. "I said I would vote for the lowest bid and I am voting for the lowest bid."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> reminded <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the city will be going through the bid process again in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, as required by state law.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> said she is glad the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> decided to keep the legal publications with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>. She said the local newspaper has always done a good job of promoting events in the community.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> wasn't as cordial about accepting the recommendation of city staff. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has set a precedent for doing business with the local newspaper. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said his biggest area of concern with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> is from the editorial area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said he doesn't agree with many of the editorial comments placed in the newspaper.   "I think we have the low bid and we just have to take it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

