


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approves liquor license renewals
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved a set of liquor license renewal requests at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P><P ID="4">   The liquor license renewals were part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> consent agenda.
</P><P ID="5">   Councilman John Torch was the lone vote against approval of the consent agenda. Torch didn't make his reasons known for his objection.
</P><P ID="6">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> removed a consent agenda item concerning a list of payment vouchers in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$415,747</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> asked the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to remove the item because there was only a partial list of vouchers available to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of the payments actually made. The item will be back before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 5</TIMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="7">   Also on the consent agenda was the minutes of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 15</TIMEX> meeting.
</P><P ID="8">   Liquor license renewals were approved for the following establishments: <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">China Grove</ENAMEX>, 325 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway; Minit Mart and Smoke Shop, 301 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South 13th Street South</ENAMEX>; Park-N-Pak, 905 Lincoln Avenue; Washington Hills Cellars, 111 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Lincoln Avenue</ENAMEX> #B; El Mejor Taquetitos, 544 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Sixth Street</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Chevron, 1805 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




