


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> call for ban on milk products from potentially BSE-infected dairy cows
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/9/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Is milk dangerous?
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Dairy Association</ENAMEX>, of which WestFarm Foods is a subsidiary, say not, but the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Brotherhood of Teamsters</ENAMEX> isn't sure.
</P><P ID="6">   Since the first cases of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>) in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> was found in cows from a Mabton dairy and an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> farm, the USDA has insisted that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> can't be passed through milk. But the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Teamsters</ENAMEX> say there isn't enough information.
</P><P ID="7">   Garnet <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX>, spokesperson for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Brotherhood of Teamsters</ENAMEX>, said the organization hopes a ban on milk and milk products from potentially infected cows will force further investigation into the possibility that milk can pass <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> to humans.
</P><P ID="8">   "Though I have read that tests have shown little evidence that bovine spongiform encephalopathy can be transmitted through a diseased animal's milk, it is believed that prions, the proteins that cause <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, can be carried by white blood cells, which are present in milk," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Brotherhood of Teamsters</ENAMEX> Vice President and Director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Gegare</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   According to the USDA, milk cannot be tested for the disease. USDA sources say the only way mad cow disease can be checked for is post-mortem. Brain tissue is required to test for the disease.
</P><P ID="10">   "We know the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> went to great extent to recall all of the meat that was put out into the system," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   With questions about the possibility of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in milk, he feels products, that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX> said were most likely taken to the WestFarm Foods plant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, should also be recovered.
</P><P ID="12">   "There's not enough research not to do it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   He said milk from cows found with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> was pulled from the shelves.
</P><P ID="14">   "There are still other cows out there (that possibly have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>) that are still being milked," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   Besides calming concerns of citizens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX> said not collecting milk from suspected animals will also ease employees of dairies and dairy processing plants.
</P><P ID="16">   He said when the USDA quarantined the animals there were people in yellow suits and face masks on the dairy, something employees at the plant don't have.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zimmerman</ENAMEX> said the recall of milk is a way of putting consumers at ease, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rae Klein</ENAMEX>, spokesperson for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WestFarm Foods</ENAMEX>, says it's a tactic the union is using to scare consumers and gain leverage in an ongoing union battle.
</P><P ID="18">   Since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring of 2001</TIMEX> employees of WestFarm Foods have been in union negotiations and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last August</TIMEX>, an employee lockout began at the Issaquah and Seattle plants.
</P><P ID="19">   "WestFarm Foods is saddened and disappointed that Teamsters Local 66 is attempting to link its totally unrelated labor dispute with the identification of a case of bovine spongiform encephalopathy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   She said state, federal and international officials, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">World Health Organization</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Agriculture Organization</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Food and Drug Administration</ENAMEX>, have repeatedly confirmed that milk products don't contain or transmit <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   In addition, a non-profit study by TAFS, an international group of scientists and food experts, revealed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2001</TIMEX> that milk and milk products are safe.
</P>   
<P ID="22">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




