
<P ID="1">Wal-Mart distribution center to open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The Wal-Mart distribution center in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will soon be opening its doors.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Gray</ENAMEX>, manager of the new distribution center, which is the length of 15 football fields, was on hand at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> Rotary meeting and said the center will see the first delivery of goods on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> provided <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> Rotarians with some history about himself and the background of Wal-Mart distribution centers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> also touched on some highlights of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> site.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> relocated to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> to manage the area's newest economic attraction. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna</ENAMEX>, have one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zach</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> has worked for Wal-Mart for 19 years.   There are 160 Wal-Mart distribution centers throughout the country, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>. There are plans in the immediate future to build 14 more distribution centers, six of which will be only grocery facilities.   The Wal-Mart distribution center in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is what is referred to as a conventional building, where everything is housed on ground level. Wal-Mart has a couple of revolutionary mechanical buildings, which go as high as 100 feet in the air, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>. Almost all of the items in the mechanical buildings are moved around by crane. One mechanical building is currently in operation in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> and another is set to open in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> around the same time the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> site opens in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> said more mechanical buildings are on the horizon for Wal-Mart because of their increase in productivity.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> site will begin receiving goods on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 1</TIMEX> and start distributing items later in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>.   Once fully operational, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> distribution center will have the capability of moving a half-million cases of products each day. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> said at full capacity there will be 400 trucks going in and out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> site on a daily basis.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> distribution center will provide food goods to 42 super centers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX> territory. A super center is the type of store located in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> said Wal-Mart has plans to build 250 super centers with 50 of those stores being in the coverage area of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> distribution center.   The jobs created by the construction of the Wal-Mart distribution center will be numerous, related <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> to Rotarians. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> site will initially employ 450 full-time employees, with that figure set to expand to 650 within the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next two years</TIMEX>. To help oversee the distribution center in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> executives brought in 30 managers from across the country to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.   "We are very excited to be here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

