
<P ID="1">Greyhounds welcome new coach
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - A large crowd of players welcomed new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> football coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Lamb</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   Somewhere in the neighborhood of 60 players turned out to greet the new head of the Greyhound football program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>, 28, was hired to replace the legendary <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Purdom</ENAMEX>, who retired at the end of last season after three years directing the Greyhound football program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> will be moving down to the very competitive 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX> (CWAC) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> after spending the last couple of years in the 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> comes to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> after a couple of successful coaching stints.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pasco High School</ENAMEX>. The Tri-Cities native played defense for the Bulldogs football team under then defensive coordinator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Graff</ENAMEX>, a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   After graduating from high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> ended up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ilwaco School District</ENAMEX>, where he coached football for three years. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ilwaco</ENAMEX> to the state playoffs. While also in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ilwaco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> guided the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ilwaco High School</ENAMEX> baseball team to its first-ever <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> playoff appearance.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kara</ENAMEX>, moved back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, living in the Tri-Cities where they both are from. The couple wanted to move back closer to their family because they were expecting their first child. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> and his wife have a 10-month-old daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abigail</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said his new daughter has been a delight.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> was going to get out of coaching <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>, but one of his former coaches talked him into taking the job of defensive coordinator at Tri-City Prep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> also ended up coaching the girls varsity basketball program at Tri-City Prep.   "I am a football guy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>. "These other ones just fell in my lap."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> is currently substitute teaching in the Tri-Cities area, where his wife is a first grade teacher.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> is excited about taking over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> football program.   "I have always dreamed of coaching in the area," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School Athletic Director Zane Wells</ENAMEX> is very excited about welcoming <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> to his coaching staff.   "I think he is going to do a great job," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> impressed the interview committee with his enthusiasm and his desire to want to coach in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "He came in with a plan," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.   One of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>'s goals for the program is to create a family atmosphere. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said he has spent years studying the different coaches throughout the state and one coach who has always stuck out in his mind in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Moore</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said he heard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> speak once of the family atmosphere the Mustang football program has and how the coaching staff and players are always there for one another. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said he is hoping to build that type of climate in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "I want to make it a fun experience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>.   Another of his goals is to keep build on the winning success <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> has had in football under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Purdom</ENAMEX> and former Greyhound coach Rock Winters.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> will be busy right off the bat in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Next Tuesday</TIMEX>, the Greyhounds begin spring practice and in a few weeks will be attending a camp at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Oregon University</ENAMEX> before coming back to start preparing for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> season.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said he is looking forward to a long and successful tenure in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "I can see myself staying forever, if they would have me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

