
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ESTHER M
ESTHER M. BOWEN
Esther Martha Bowen</ENAMEX>, 107, of Seattle died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 8, 2004</TIMEX>.
She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 6, 1897</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ky.</ENAMEX> She lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from 1917 to 1945</TIMEX>. She married Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John H. Schutz</ENAMEX>, who died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1970</TIMEX>, she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Bowen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
She is survived by her daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Warmington</ENAMEX> of Seattle; son-in-law, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Warmington</ENAMEX>; and two granddaughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flynn Warmington</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Somerville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maine</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Warmington</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kirkland</ENAMEX>; and many nieces and nephews.
She was preceded in death by her husbands, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John H. Schutz</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Bowen</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1978</TIMEX>; and her seven siblings.
No services are planned. In memory of Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowen</ENAMEX> memorials may be made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX>. Evergreen Washelli is in charge of arrangements, Seattle.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JESUS Martinez
Jesus Martinez</ENAMEX>, 18, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 6, 2004</TIMEX>, due to injuries sustained in an automobile accident.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 1986</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celia</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lujan</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Ignacio Garica</ENAMEX>. He attended grade school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and was currently a senior at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celia and Jose Ignacio Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>; three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica Torres</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patricia Martinez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juana Moreno</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miguel</ENAMEX>; three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Ignacio Martinez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Luis Martinez</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jorge Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>; and grandmother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raquel Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his grandfathers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Martinez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Lujan</ENAMEX>.
Visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 11, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with recitation of the Holy Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 12, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Blessed Sacrament Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Burial will be held at Mabton Cemetery, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GERONIMO H. PINA
Geronimo H. Piña Sr.</ENAMEX>, 70, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Nov. 7, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Regional Hospital</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 6, 1934</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Weslaco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel and Juanita Piña</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 13, 1952</TIMEX> he married Concepcion Mendez in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mercedes</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, making their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Weslaco</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1956</TIMEX>, they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and later to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, where he worked as a foreman for A and B Hops Inc. for 47 years until retiring.
 He is survived by his devoted wife of 52 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concepcion Piña</ENAMEX>; eight sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipa Piña</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geronimo Piña Jr.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar and Sylvia Piña</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Humberto and Felicia Piña</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel and Elissa Piña</ENAMEX>, Josue and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joella Piña</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sherry Piña</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Violeta Piña</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">San Juanita Piña</ENAMEX>; 22 grandchildren; and 16 great-grandchildren; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ciria Tijerina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dominga Garza</ENAMEX>; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio Piña</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Livorio Piña</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Weslaco</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geronimo</ENAMEX> enjoyed baseball (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Mariners</ENAMEX>) and football (The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX>), fishing, playing pool and spending time with family and friends.  He also coached his sons in baseball, and had a baseball team called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">“The Prosser Astros”</ENAMEX> and loved watching them participate in all sports.
 He was preceded in death by his parents; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Manuel Piña Jr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claudio Piña</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margarita Barron</ENAMEX>; and one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel Piña</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 11, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Graveside funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 12, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Prosser Cemetery</ENAMEX>, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

