


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents asked to tax themselves for library costs
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The fate of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Library</ENAMEX> is up to the voters living within the city limits.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> has chosen to let the voters decide what to do with the library.
</P><P ID="6">   A group of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents attended a public forum <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to discuss the upcoming levy, which will ask voters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX> if they want to be annexed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> system.
</P><P ID="7">   In the past the city has contracted with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> system for services. In the agreement the city has paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> annually and has maintain the library building in exchange for services. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> is about one-third the amount it costs to operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Weyhe</ENAMEX>, director of the regional library system. She said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, it cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$370,000</NUMEX> to operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library. The rest of the money to operate the local library comes from unincorporated areas, whose residents pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 cents</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value, as well as from residents paying taxes in other <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> towns. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 cents</NUMEX> assessed by the library is a capped amount that can only be increased with a county-wide polling of the voters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> said at this time she is not in favor of increasing the amount assessed to taxpayers due to the economic situation of the county.
</P><P ID="8">   During the budget sessions in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 2003</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> passed a resolution to have the library issue put up for a vote, according to acting city manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Currently, the city pays for library contract services, which equals to about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 cents</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value. But because of financial reasons the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is asking citizens to take on the responsibility of paying for library services themselves.
</P><P ID="10">   "There is no question that the library is a valuable service to the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>. "The library is one of those services we think is crucial."
</P><P ID="11">   In the past, the library has been paid for through tax monies levied from property owners.
</P><P ID="12">   "We request each year the county adopt a property tax levy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>. "We take those proceeds and we allocate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> for the library."
</P><P ID="13">   The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> currently being paid for the library contract will most likely go back into the current expense fund, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   If the annexation is approved, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> district will give the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX> credit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>. The money would come out of library district reserve funds.
</P><P ID="15">   Rather than waiting to see if the vote passes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> reduced the amount budgeted to the library in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>, when funds started tightening on small towns across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> voters have voted in favor of annexing into the regional library system, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   She said by annexing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> into the regional system, the library district would double the amount of money it receives from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents for library services.
</P><P ID="18">   She said from the library's point-of-view the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$115,000</NUMEX> paid by the city for contract services has not been sufficient for some time.
</P><P ID="19">   "It's been a matter of time before we came to this point," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> added that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> believes that by annexing, the library district will be best served.
</P><P ID="21">   Voting 'yes' for the annexation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Regional Library</ENAMEX> system will increase the number of books, classes, videos and services provided at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>. She added that there are plans to upgrade and enhance the facility, which will be turned over to the library district as a part of the annexation.
</P><P ID="22">   "We think this is the bustling center of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library, which is the second most used library in the system. "We want to sink money into this library."
</P><P ID="23">   A "yes" vote will add a tax to property owners of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 cents</NUMEX> per 1,000 of assessed value. For a home assessed at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$150,000</NUMEX>, the additional tax will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$75</NUMEX> per year.
</P><P ID="24">   If voters choose not to support annexation, then what happens to the library is still unsure.
</P><P ID="25">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library cannot operate on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> the city will pay to the regional system <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="26">   "We couldn't afford to staff that building for that amount of money," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="27">   She said for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,000</NUMEX> a community could possibly have a reading room type library or an interhome exchange.
</P><P ID="28">   Both she and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said there are no contingency plans for a "no" vote.
</P><P ID="29">   "If the vote does not pass we don't know if the city council will step up and pay the other <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weyhe</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   A political action committee was formed after the public forum ended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to begin strategizing on how to support the library services in the community.
</P><P ID="31">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> property owner Bill Flower is heading up the committee, which will begin officially meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="32">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="33">Webmaster
</P><P ID="34">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




