
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Autocross competitionsset for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The fourth annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spring Fling Autocross & Car Show</ENAMEX> will be held at the Yakima SunDome parking lot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Sunday, June 6</TIMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX>
Organizers will close the registration period at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> Timed runs will begin half an hour later. The top three finishers in each class will receive awards. Entry fees are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>.
Also on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, the Yakima County Sheriff's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dept.</ENAMEX> will be raising money for Special Olympics by providing concessions to those attending the one-day event.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Brewfest on tap for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-June</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - Connoisseurs of beer will want to circle the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 18-20</TIMEX> on their calendars.
For the fifth consecutive year, the NWsource.com <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> Brewfest will bring together the best of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> for three days at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Edward State Park</ENAMEX>. The event will offer the opportunity to taste some of the 101 beers that will be served that weekend.
Organizers say the festival provides fun for all ages—with the Rootbeer Garden, Zucchini 500 Races and the Brewers Keg Toss. New <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will be a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> pre-party for adults, featuring some of the Brewfest participating breweries and performances by local bands.
Among the unique products that may catch the attention of those in attendance are <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elliott  Bay</ENAMEX>'s gold medal winning Orange Infusion Ale and Pacific Rim Brewer's Ring of Fire Pepper Ale.
For those who don't care for fermented malt beverages, a variety of ciders will be served at the Cider Garden, including Aspall Dry Cyder, Brut Manoir Du Parc (apple cider) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Poire Mnoir Du Park</ENAMEX> (pear cider).
For more information on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Father's Day</TIMEX> weekend event, go on-line to the web site: washingtonbrewfest.com.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Fort Simcoeto stage Flag Day celebration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12-13</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WHITE SWAN</ENAMEX> - The public is being encouraged to celebrate Flag Day at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Simcoe State Park</ENAMEX> the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 12-13</TIMEX>.
The free living history celebration is scheduled to run both days, as the park will play host to military re-enactment groups from various eras in American military history. The event will include soldier drills and artillery demonstrations. Members of the re-enactment units will camp at the site in period groupings.
The defining moment of the two-day event—a flag raising ceremony—is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Free cake and punch will be served following the ceremony.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Simcoe State Park</ENAMEX> is located about seven miles west of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Swan</ENAMEX>. The park is opened at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX> each day and remains open until dusk. The fort is part of a diverse system of more than 120 parks and programs managed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Parks and Recreation Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Rock-n-rollfund-raiserat YVCC setfor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>
Love that rock-n-rolling music? Radio 88.5 at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Tech</ENAMEX> has just the event for you.
Edge Fest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> will feature 11 live <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> bands <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, June 5</TIMEX>, on the campus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. The music kicks off at high <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>, and won't end until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>. A new band will play each hour of the concert.
The DJs of Radio 88.5 will offer additional activities throughout the concert, such as a halo competition with the winner riding away on a free <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BMX</ENAMEX> bike and a "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> for an Album" event to win free albums.
Admission to the 12-hour rock-n-roll concert is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> per person, or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> per person if they donate at least two cans of food at the gate for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Northwest Harvest</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="7">‘Dino in a Day’ event open to all local families
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANGER</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hisey Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> will again be the site for "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino</ENAMEX> in a Day," to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, June 5</TIMEX>.
Billed as a family event, parents and their children are invited to help apply the cement covering over the dinosaur frame that has already been constructed by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> volunteers. The finished Styracosaurus will be added to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>'s collection of dinosaurs that grace that community.
Work on the dinosaur will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX>
Concessions will be available at the park <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>. There will also be kids activities and music. Also, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hisey Park</ENAMEX> paddle boats and pedal surreys will be available for rental.
The annual <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> event also offers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BBQ</ENAMEX> facilities at the park, a pathway around the park pond for leisurely strolls, ducks to feed, fish to catch and the natural beauty of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima River</ENAMEX> to take in for a day of family fun in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sun.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="8">Maryhill <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert series gets underway <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 24</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MARYHILL</ENAMEX> - The Maryhill Winery and Amphitheater, in conjunction with  the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Blues Concerts, announces the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert series. Scheduled to kick off the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> concert season at the Amphitheater overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX>, near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, will be the Temptations, Hootie and the Blowfish, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Henley</ENAMEX>.
Tickets go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> Additional acts will be announced later.
The fabulous Temptations will be in concert at the winery  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 24</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
Performing for more than 40 years timeless hits and backed by a screaming band, the Temptations show is nothing less than a walk through American music history. Thanks to their fine-tuned choreography – and even finer harmonies – The Temptations became one of Motown’s most elastic acts. They handled both lushly-orchestrated pop and politically-charged funk with equal flair on such timeless hits as My Girl, Papa Was A Rolling Stone, Since I Lost My Baby, Ain’t Too Proud To <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beg</ENAMEX> and Just My Imagination.
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31.50</NUMEX> general admission, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46.50</NUMEX> reserved, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> dinner rail plus applicable service charges.
Coming to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 30</TIMEX>, will be Hootie and the Blowfish, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
Hootie and the Blowfish's mainstream pop variation of blues-rock brought the band to the top of the cSmarts. Cracked Rear View, the group’s first album, was released in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 1994</TIMEX> and a single, Hold My Hand, worked its way into the Top Ten. Its success propelled the album to Number One, as well as launching a second hit, Let Her Cry, which was quickly followed by Only Wanna Be With You. Cracked Rear View became a full-blown music biz phenomenon—selling 13 million copies.
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> general admission, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45</NUMEX> reserved, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> dinner rail plus applicable service charges.
Out of all of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Henley</ENAMEX>, who will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 6</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, has had the most successful solo career. The End of the Innocence was his most ambitious and commercially successful album, selling over three million copies and staying on the cSmarts for nearly three years, launching the hit singles The End of the Innocence, Heart of the Matter, New York Minute, How Bad Do You Want It?, and The Last Worthless Evening.”
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$59.50</NUMEX> general admission, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$79.50</NUMEX> reserved, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$125</NUMEX> dinner rail plus applicable service charges.
Tickets for these shows go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at all Ticketmaster outlets and on-line at ticketmaster.com.
For more information contact www.maryhillwinery.com or <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Gilbert</ENAMEX> at (425) 990-0222
</P> 
<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTH</ENAMEX> theatricals  to announce      fall production
 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX>  - The Over the Hill Theatricals will host a special night out, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 15</TIMEX>, at Country Side Catering, 810 W. Second Street, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
The announcement of the senior actors' fall project will be made following dinner, according to a theater spokesperson. The evening will begin with a social at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>, followed by dinner at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
Dinner is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> per person for a dinner of Swiss steak and trimmings. Entertainment will be provided by the group's perusal committee.
To RSVP, call 837-3157 or  786-3990 by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 9</TIMEX>. 
A second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OTH</ENAMEX> group outing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 22</TIMEX>, at Cohu's Hollow Way Meadows, 1017 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S. Euclid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> is also planned.
Members are asked to bring their own  meat to barbecue and a salad or dessert, plus table service. Beverages will be provided. Production staff will be announced and try-outs discussed at this meeting.
Try-out dates for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX> production are scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2</TIMEX> and 3, at a location to be announced later.
</P> 


 




<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

