
<P ID="1">Smart Beat
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/2/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">If I were able to bestow sainthood onto people who go above and beyond the call of duty I'd save the biggest crowns for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Schlieve</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Oh yes, and for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Corliss</ENAMEX>, my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> members and my co-workers at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>. Why? Because without their encouragement and support, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s "Back to the Country" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> fireworks display, set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Clem Senn</ENAMEX> football field, might not be happening.   I'd also save stars in heaven for those people who demonstrated their support by generously dropping their spare change in the numerous "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Community Fireworks Display" donation glass jars which have been located on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> business counters during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two months</TIMEX>.   From the more than 24 jars sitting on counters at restaurants, city hall, banks, local taverns and even at the local schools, more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$700</NUMEX> was collected to be used toward providing the community with an awesome fireworks display.   In addition to those funds, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fireworks fund received a major contribution of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> to jump start the fund-raising campaign.   But I believe it was through the weekly visits from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> that the money in the jars continued to increase and for that I thank her so much. I know we wouldn't have even come close to collecting the that much money without her timely and gentle nudges.   In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlieve</ENAMEX> and I and my fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX> members encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX>, AmVets and their respective auxiliaries to join forces to host a seafood dinner which netted another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$613</NUMEX> for the fund.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schlieve</ENAMEX>, who has become something of an expert at writing convincing letters for fund-raisers, encouraged <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> volunteer firemen, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pioneers, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> American Legion, Kiwanis and Soroptimists groups to donate an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,320</NUMEX> to the patriotic cause. By <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-June</TIMEX> we realized we were going to raise more than the extra <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX> we needed to put on the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> community <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> pyrotechnic display.   What I didn't expect was the wholehearted support my co-workers brought to the fund-raising effort. Led by the newspaper's production manager, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Taylor Morris</ENAMEX>, and reporter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>, our DSN crew pooled their talents to bake, sew, paint and cook items for two very successful "Red White and Blue" crafts and bake sales. That effort alone, with an extra donation by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Daily News Publisher Tim Graff, added more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$270</NUMEX> to the cause.   Then came the last minute, but equally appreciated donation to the community fireworks fund by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s two <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Hat Society</ENAMEX> chapters, bringing the total fireworks campaign to well over <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>.   I can't begin to explain how excited I am to be able to tell <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> readers that we now have a nice little nest egg to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s fireworks campaign.   Thank you, one and all for all of your support and to my committee for its encouragement and support.   I encourage each of you to enjoy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">all of this weekend</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> activities, from the Come Back to the Country Soapbox Derby races and family fun scheduled in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, scheduled from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>'s pyrotechnic display. Come inside the football field for the best seats at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club-hosted</ENAMEX> patriotic program, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Take time to enjoy pre-show music and ice cream at a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> social being hosted across the street at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Reformed Church</ENAMEX>, which will be followed by fireworks at dusk.   Have a great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> - I certainly plan to, thanks to all of you.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

