


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> expresses concerns with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> held the first of its annual budget study sessions <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, but someone forgot to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> about the get-together.
</P><P ID="5">   The chamber was scheduled to make its annual presentation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> for funding in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. The city allocates funding to the chamber out of tourism tax dollars.
</P><P ID="6">   In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget draft, the city has <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> allocated for the local chamber <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of</ENAMEX> commerce. The money in the tourism fund is raised through a hotel/motel tax and is specifically earmarked to promote tourism.
</P><P ID="7">   But due to a communication snafu on the city's part, the chamber was not present at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> said he would try to schedule the chamber during one of the coming budget sessions.
</P><P ID="8">   Despite chamber officials not being present, several <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members didn't let the moment pass and voiced some concerns they have with the chamber and its activities.
</P><P ID="9">   The main thrust of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s conversation dealt with Sunshine Days, which the chamber significantly downsized <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> said he would like to find a way to help Sunshine Days with tourism dollars. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> said he believes Sunshine Days is an important part of the community that should be promoted.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> replied by saying <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and the chamber need to discuss that situation more in-depth.
</P><P ID="12">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> wanted to look at the agreement with the chamber in two different areas. The mayor said first there was the budget portion of the contract <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> needs to look at, and then the actual agreement.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said based on what happened with the chamber and community events in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, he wanted to see a list of activities the chamber had planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>'s request.
</P><P ID="14">   "I think the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was really caught off guard when the chamber decided to not have Sunshine Days," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> noted some personal concerns he has with the local chamber. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he doesn't see much, if any, business at his downtown bed and breakfast inn from community events sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> chamber. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> went on to say that his inn is full from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> events and even some Grandview community activities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said as the owner of an inn, he should be seeing more return from the local chamber. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he and other hotel/motel owners agreed to charge an additional tax to generate the tourism funds that go towards funding the chamber.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s point. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> said that many <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Valley</ENAMEX> events promote tourism and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> should be looking at ways to attract those same tourists to the community.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> said he wanted to see the chamber promote use of the Centennial Square more and work with downtown businesses as chamber officials had promised.
</P><P ID="18">   "We have got some questions to ask (of the chamber)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he will be talking with chamber officials about <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> concerns.
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




