
<P ID="1">City leaders conservatively ete new housing rehab program
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/12/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Citing financial concerns, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> decided to proceed slowly before entering a new, more extensive housing rehabilitation project to benefit local residents.   The idea to enter a new housing rehabilitation program came from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gene Weinmann</ENAMEX> of the Yakima Valley Conference of Governments (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX> is currently overseeing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing rehabilitation program for the city.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> was providing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with an update of recent activities involving the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the last housing rehabilitation project falling under the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! program was recently put out for bid and construction should begin in the next few weeks.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing rehabilitation project stemmed from a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) the city obtained in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>. There has also been additional monies in the form of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> for street and sidewalk improvements set aside.   By the time the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing project concludes, towards the latter part of the year, some 22 homes in the community will have been upgraded. Another 15 will have had extensive weatherization improvements done.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of some changes at the state level that could benefit the city with funding for upcoming projects. The CDBG program has changed its allocation process for grant applications. Until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, cities could only apply for one CDBG grant per year. Now, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX>, cities can apply for separate housing rehabilitation grants in addition to one other CDBG grant for funding any other needed projects.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> said the city could benefit greatly from these application process changes. He said the city has an excellent track record with CDBG funding, which will benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with its application process.   The city does have some time before having to submit the actual CDBG application, seeking funding for any new housing rehabilitation program, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> did caution the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that if the city does decide to pursue a more extensive housing rehabilitation program with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">COG</ENAMEX>, he would need some sort of direction within the next few weeks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> said he was looking at tackling an all-inclusive, city-wide housing rehabilitation program and it would take time to gather the needed data to go along with the application. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> said the city's application for CDBG funding would not be due until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-November</TIMEX>.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> had concerns about entering a new housing rehabilitation program, considering the fiscal problems the city is having. For the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing rehabilitation program, the city committed <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$110,000</NUMEX>.   "It is going to be a tighter year this budget year than last," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said if the city committed the type of money it did for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Up! housing rehabilitation program, it would cost the city at least two employees.   "I am not opposed to the program," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. "That match is just a killer."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> said she would like to see the city move forward with a new housing rehabilitation program. She felt a project such as this would greatly enhance the city.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> directed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> to research the ins and outs of entering into a new housing rehabilitation program and bring a report back to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Weinmann</ENAMEX> said he would also gather more financial data for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to review.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

