
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathway</ENAMEX> seeks volunteers
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pathway Foundation</ENAMEX> is seeking groups or individuals interested in adopting a section of the Yakima Valley Pathway for spring clean-up.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foundation</ENAMEX> is hoping interested groups will volunteer to help maintain the pathway which stretches between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, along Yakima Valley Highway, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Slupsky</ENAMEX>, a pathway spokesperson.   "We are also looking for people interested in serving on our board of directors," he added.   Those interested are encouraged to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Slupsky</ENAMEX> at 837-3342.   More <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> senior project judges needed   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior project coordinator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trish Nixon</ENAMEX> is anxious to fill all of the slots for her senior projects judging panel.   "We need 40 more judges to help evaluate the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004's</TIMEX> projects," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> said.   The judging will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, May 11</TIMEX> and 12, at the high school from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>   "We need people who can work one or both days," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> said completion of a senior project is part of the seniors' graduation requirements.   Those interested in seeing the type of projects chosen by the students are asked to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nixon</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, 837-2601, to volunteer.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

