
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX> inaugurates new acquisitions gallery
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GOLDENDALE</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum of Art</ENAMEX> has inaugurated a new gallery to spotlight its most recent acquisitions.
Nine acquisitions are currently in the exhibit, including an American Indian basalt sculpture gifted to the museum by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary Hoyt Stevenson Foundation</ENAMEX>, as well as a photograph by Native American artist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Williams</ENAMEX>, gifted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Schlick</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>
The basalt sculpture is several centuries old and was discovered near The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1910</TIMEX>. It stands over 20 inches high and is carved in a way that suggests an animal, perhaps a beaver.
"The scope of a museum's collections is enriched by the generosity of patrons who donate special objects," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Schafroth</ENAMEX>, the museum's executive director.
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, a castle-like chateau overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>, is open daily from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> Also on site is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> overlook and a cafe that features deli foods, drinks and custom desserts, plus a gift shop. General admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7</NUMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> for children.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX> to feature wine sampling <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Thanks to a revision in the state laws regarding the sampling of wines for special not-for-profit occasions, patrons at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> will have an opportunity to sample the winners of the fair's annual wine competition, all 10 days of the fair.
The revisions in the law were signed by Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Locke</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 24</TIMEX>.
"We have worked hard to help showcase and promote our region's wines and wineries," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Anglin</ENAMEX>, activities manager at the fair. "This revision will allow us to do a better job of exposing the wonderful wines that our state produces to our fair visitors."
The 23rd annual wine judging competition will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4-6 this year</TIMEX>. Winners will be announced at the annual Sunshine and Wine Festival, held at the fairgrounds in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>. The wine tasting at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fair will be in the historical <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag Building</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX> officials also report they are now taking applications from people or groups who are interested in participating in the fair's daily parades, or those who want to perform on one of the stages at the fair. The application forms are now available on the fair's website, and can be printed out and sent in to the fair office. Entertainers should include an audio or videotape showcasing their talent.
The website can be found at: www.fairfun.com.
</P> 
<P ID="5">‘Spring Ball’set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late April</TIMEX>
The Hap <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> Band will provide the live music for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Senior-Junior Spring Ball.
Sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School VICA Club</ENAMEX>, the formal affair is geared for those 55 years of age and older. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s dance will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 25</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at the local high school. All the senior prom decorations from the night before will be left in place to help create a ball-like setting for the senior citizen dance.
Admission to the ball is free, and refreshments will be provided at no cost.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York City</ENAMEX> police officer to perform here
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York City</ENAMEX> police officer who rose to prominence with his emotional renditions of "The Star Spangled Banner" and "God Bless America" at the funerals of his fellow officers and firefighters who died in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX> terrorist attacks on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>, will perform in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 26, 2005</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> will be a guest artist during the Yakima Symphony 2004-05 season.
His voice attracted the attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Placido Domingo</ENAMEX>, who invited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> to continue his vocal career with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Opera</ENAMEX>. Now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> is both recording and touring and will appear with the Yakima Symphony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
The Yakima Symphony season opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 13, 2004</TIMEX> with a rousing Russian program featuring guest artist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maxim Philippov</ENAMEX>, a pianist. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philippov</ENAMEX> played with the Yakima Symphony in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 2003</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is making his Carnegie Hall solo debut.
World famous violinist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ida Kavafian</ENAMEX> will be the guest artist on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 29, 2005</TIMEX>, playing Beethoven's "Violin Concerto."
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> will pay respects to his heritage with songs in both Spanish and English on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 26, 2005</TIMEX>, and will conclude with a tribute to the victims of 9/11 at the concert.
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 12, 2005</TIMEX>, "Fantastiquely French" will feature the Yakima Symphony Orchestra and Chorus performing three of French music's greatest hits—two of which will be <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maurice Ravel</ENAMEX>'s most beloved scores, "Pavane for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dead</ENAMEX> Princess" and "Daphnis and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chloe Suite</ENAMEX> No. 2."
On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 16, 2005</TIMEX>, the Yakima Symphony Orchestra will continue its partnership with the Seattle Opera Young Artists Program to present <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mozart</ENAMEX>'s comic opera, "The Marriage of Figaro," a musical "potpourri" based on a banned French play.
Season ticket prices range in cost from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$240</NUMEX></NUMEX> for all five concerts, and are available now from the Yakima Symphony Orchestra office (509-248-1414) Mondays through Thursdays from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> documentaryairs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 10</TIMEX>
A documentary chronicling the history of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, "from barren landscape to irrigated oasis," will air <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 10</TIMEX>, over KIMA-TV, Channel 29, cable 6,  at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
The special, "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> - Our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> in Transition," was produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Finch</ENAMEX> for KIMA-TV and will feature the voice of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwoodr Craig Galbraith</ENAMEX>, a popular KIMA-TV newscaster.
The hour-long documentary will offer a perspective of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s past, present and future growth, and will include segments on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> industries and the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

