
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> eyes downtown revitalization
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/3/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Downtown Grandview could be on its way to receiving a facelift if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> chooses to move forward with the creation of a downtown revitalization plan.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Dohrn</ENAMEX> of Wells and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stokes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX> talked to city council members about the planning that goes into putting together a successful downtown revitalization plan.   Downtown revitalization is a subject <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, have been discussing for several months. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Clerk <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anita Palacios</ENAMEX> told council members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> had already had a chance to sit down and talk about revitalization strategies with a small group of city representatives, including herself, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman Robert Morales</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX>, Public Works Director Cus Arteaga and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Huibregtse</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huibregtse Louman Associates Inc.</ENAMEX>   "We <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> down and talked about where we want to start and how we get going," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> told council members before anything can be done in regards to a downtown revitalization plan the council has to sit down and answer three questions. The three questions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> presented to council members were: Is the revitalization of downtown a high priority for city council? Is the council willing to spend time, money and commit resources to the revitalization process? And, is revitalization a priority to downtown businesses?   "The answer to all these questions has to be yes," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> told council members.   He said all of those questions have to be answered in the affirmative because downtown revitalization is a big project. He noted that you can't just wave a magic wand and have the project complete itself.   "It's not that easy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said.   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> told council members that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> does have a few things going for it already in terms of putting together a revitalization project. He said, for one thing, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> already has a downtown area, a main street with buildings on both sides. He said there are some communities Wells and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stokes</ENAMEX> is working with that are trying to not only revitalize their downtown, but also create one.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> also pointed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s recently completed infrastructure project that improved <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> leading into downtown and included the removal of a railroad overpass, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said used to cut off the downtown area from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> corridor. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said the increased interest in the area's wine industry could also help in the revitalization of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s downtown area.   "You have perhaps a number of options here," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said, noting that the Wal-Mart distribution center has also helped put <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> on the map. "I see a number of things that say the condition might be right," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> told council members.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>, one of the first things council members can do in order to get the ball rolling on a revitalization project is to head out into the community and evaluate what they have to work with. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> pointed out that in driving through the community <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier Monday</TIMEX> he had taken notice of the many interesting brick buildings that make up most of the downtown corridor, as well as the good condition of the buildings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said after evaluating what the downtown area has to offer, it is important to come up with several alternative plans for action. He said the city needs to define areas of interest in downtown, as well as places it would like to see highlighted by a revitalization project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said it is important for communities, like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, to customize a revitalization plan, making it work for what the city has to offer.   "You have to make it unique to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said, noting that not every community in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> can be like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX>.   Another important part of creating a downtown revitalization plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said, is implementing it. He said it's important to come up with a plan of action, a way to put the plan in motion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said by the time the project gets to this point there will be people who are very supportive of the plan, those who are very against the plan and those in the middle who will be looking for something to happen before getting on board.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> told council members when looking at downtown revitalization it is important to remember that the entire downtown area doesn't have to be done at one time. Instead, it is ok to focus on one place or on one thing before moving onto the next piece of the project.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> said in order for the revitalization project to succeed city council can't be the one driving force behind it. Instead, he said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> has to get on board, as well as local downtown business owners.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huibregtse</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>, noting that downtown businesses should be the driving force behind a project like this one.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX>, city administrator, said this isn't the first time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> has looked at creating a revitalization plan. He said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> steps were taken to improve the downtown area, including sidewalk improvements at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX> streets, as well as the creation of Stokely Square. However, he said when it came time to get the downtown businesses involved, the project fell flat.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said council members will discuss the revitalization plan during their upcoming retreat, scheduled to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said before coming together for the retreat he hopes to get a feeling of whether the revitalization effort is something both the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> and downtown businesses would support.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

