


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds sweep past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> managed another league win <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, sweeping past the visiting Naches Rangers for a three-game victory.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team beat the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX> by scores of 25-3, 25-16 and 25-13.
</P><P ID="6">   Despite dominating the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said he felt his team didn't play as well as it could have.
</P><P ID="7">   "The score was in our favor, but there are things we need to work on," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said, noting that it's still early in the season.
</P><P ID="8">   He said there are also a couple of players on the team who need to work on doing more for the team.
</P><P ID="9">   "We need to stay more focused and go through our routines," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   Despite feeling a need for improvement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> also noticed a lot of things his team did right. He said there are several members of the team who are getting used to new positions and others who have spent the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> adding new dimensions to their volleyball game, dimensions that are beginning to show out on the court.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> noted that over the course of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> senior Danelle Cowan worked on adding a new trick to her game. He explained that she typically runs a quick set, but over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> worked on being able to slow down her tempo.
</P><P ID="12">   "She added two different tempos, adding multiple dimensions to her game," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said. He added that it is a skill she has really improved on and one the team can utilize.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said junior Tonhya Wysong had a good game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   "She was pretty focused and did a good job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said. "She's a real leader on our defense."
</P><P ID="15">   He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX>, Kealey Johnston and Chante Bottineau also played well against the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cowan</ENAMEX> had 13 kills and 5 digs against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Johnston</ENAMEX> had 5 kills and 5 digs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solis</ENAMEX> had 4 aces, 23 service points and 3 kills, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bottineau</ENAMEX> had 16 assists and 17 service points, and Wysong had 10 digs.
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




