
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello Huskies</ENAMEX> ruin G'view Homecoming
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/4/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Ouch! The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello Huskies</ENAMEX> pinned a whopping defeat on the Greyhound football team during Grandview Homecoming this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huskies</ENAMEX> (2-1, 3-2) rolled into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> and escaped town with a 49-14 victory.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> is very young <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s first year coach, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dustin Lamb</ENAMEX>. "What's surprising is how tough they are."   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huskies</ENAMEX> are also very balanced on offense. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> rushed for 217 yards against the 'Hounds and picked up another 205 yards through the air. The end result was a pounding of the 'Hounds.   One of the few bright spots <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> could garner from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX> game was the play of senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX>. The talented running back rushed for a team high 135 yards on 22 carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> also scored both of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s touchdowns.   Part of the reason for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX>'s success on the ground was the realignment of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s offensive line. J.R. Camacho and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake Carpenter</ENAMEX> were moved to the left side of the line, and the duo opened some gaping holes for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> to rush through.   "Camacho and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>'s play kind of kick-started us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s undoing was turnovers. On the Greyhounds' first four possessions of the game, they coughed up the ball four times.   "You can't commit those kinds of mistakes against a team as good as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>, "Not if you expect to win."   Offensively for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX> threw for 112 yards on 13-of-27 passing numbers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> had five receptions for 25 yards, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> hauled in four of the passes for 47 yards and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Concienne</ENAMEX> tallied 29 yards on three catches.   On the defensive side of the ball for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, Camacho was in on 11 tackles, five of them solo stops. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concienne</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX> each had three solo tackles, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concienne</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mejia</ENAMEX> each recording five defensive assists.   The Greyhounds (1-2, 1-4) are scheduled to travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> (1-1, 4-1) this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

