
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Agenda</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Aug. 9</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>, 401 Homer Street.
</P> 
<P ID="4">1. Consent: Approve minutes of the regular meeting of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 26, 2004</TIMEX> (Motion to approve).
2. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member attendance: Percentage attendance based on 34 regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meetings from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11, 2003</TIMEX>, to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9, 2004</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 80 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 97 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 83 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 94 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 94 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 94 percent</NUMEX>.
3. Presentation by Yakima County Auditor Corky Mattingly regarding the electronic voting machines available at the upcoming election.
4. Consideration of an ordinance amending residency requirements for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> members (Motion to adopt Ordinance No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2081</TIMEX> and ordinance summary).
5. Consideration of a resolution authorizing the disposition of surplus property (Motion to approve Resolution No. 2004-40).
6. Consideration of a resolution affirming and adopting a policy of fair housing as required for Community Development Block Grant funding (Motion to approve Resolution No. 2004-41).
7. Consideration of an ordinance amending the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Municipal Code to regulate the use of motorized foot scooters within the city (Motion to adopt Ordinance No. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2080</TIMEX> and ordinance summary).
8. Items for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agenda for the regular meeting on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Aug. 23</TIMEX>.
9. Unscheduled appearances by citizens. Note: Citizens are advised that they must limit their remarks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to five minutes and that items presented may be referred by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to staff for review and/or additional information for presentation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at a future meeting.
10. Reports from department heads/responses to citizen inquiries.
11. Items from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members.
12. Executive session to discuss pending litigation (approximately 30 minutes).
13. Other items. Note: Citizens are advised that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> may take action as deemed advisable following the executive session.
14. Adjournment.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

