
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> top <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> firemen
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/16/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> volunteer firefighter started honoring paid fire department staff for their work in the department at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX> banquet held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December</TIMEX>. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, they chose firefighter/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">paramedic Bill Harris</ENAMEX>. It was the second consecutive year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> won the award.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>, 28, has been with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>. He moved to the community after working as a volunteer with another fire department as he went through paramedic training.   By training as a paramedic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> said job opportunities with fire departments open up.   With the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> has headed up the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> Adopt-a-Family project. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> 55</TIMEX> families were helped by the fire department.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> is a competent medic," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Fire Chief Jim Stanton. "He strives hard to do the job right and get ahead."   Also honored at the banquet was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Castillo</ENAMEX>, who received the Volunteer Firefighter of the Year award from his 35 volunteer peers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX>, 31, has been a volunteer with the local fire department for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>.   "I do what I can to help put up lights and take them down and put up flags," said "Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony</ENAMEX>" as he is known to the pre-schoolers he helps with at the United Methodist Pre-school. "A lot of the guys do as much as I do. They are all deserving."   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past year</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> also served as secretary for the local organization.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> made the third highest number of responses to aid and fire calls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> volunteer association. He was presented with a separate award for the number of calls he responded to.   Volunteers are asked to work one day (24 hours) a month, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX>.   "I really enjoy it so I like to stay there a lot," he said.   He tries to spend about 10 days a month volunteering at the fire department. He has had as many as 17 days in a month.   "The more days I spend there the more likely I will be able to go out on a call," he said   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Working</ENAMEX> at the pre-school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> mixes his work with young children with his volunteer work at the fire department. He gives the pre-school students tours of the fire department and during the adopt a family program <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX>'s students helped collect items for needy families.   "To be picked out of a group of really special guys is a pretty big deal," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX>.   As a volunteer for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> is an emergency medical technician.   "If we go to an aid call I help in any way I can. It can be doing anything from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX> to bandaging wounds," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX>.   He has also helped with extradition at accident scenes, which involves cutting up motor vehicles and strapping patients to backboards.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> helped with a call when a woman fell off a horse and hurt herself.   The ambulance couldn't get to where the woman was, so aid call responders had to ride in a 4x4 pickup to get to the call.   At the scene of a fire, as a volunteer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Castillo</ENAMEX> said he can be seen helping pull hoses and cleaning up, but <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> he was able to drive the truck to the scene on two calls and be the engineer.   "As you get more experience the paid guys allow you to drive to the scene and be the engineer," he explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County Fire District</ENAMEX> #<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">5 Chief Mark</NUMEX> Kimm also was honored at the banquet for his 18 years of service to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Fire Department</ENAMEX>. He retired from the volunteer association at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of 2003</TIMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

