
<P ID="1">'Rip, Roarin' Fun' will be had at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> fair
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/16/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The Wenatchee Youth Circus, the "biggest little circus in world" featuring clowns and entertainment for the whole family, will set the tone for the Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11-15</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Country Park</ENAMEX>.   Rodeo, Rides and Rip Roarin' Fun is the theme of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fair, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Fisher</ENAMEX> of the fair board of directors said is better than ever.   The youth circus will be the main attraction <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> nights of the fair. The circus will be performing both nights at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>   The youth circus acts with clowns and trapeze acts, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, who added that other acts seen at professional circuses will also be performed. The Wenatchee Youth Circus, however, does not have acts using wild animals, she said.   The Wenatchee Youth Circus is considered one of the top four non-professional troupes in the nation. Over the years, the circus has performed for more than two million people in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Western United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>. The troupe travels well over 12,000 miles per year to perform.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fair is reminiscent of past years with more booths, rides and entertainment than there has been in recent years.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> marks the beginning of the rodeo action at the fair.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the fair will feature a PRCA rodeo, rather than a ProWest rodeo, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>.   PRCA is the professional rodeo association which competes for positions at the National finals in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Las Vegas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nevada</ENAMEX>.   "It sounds like we're going to have a lot of contestants," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX> about 300 people competed in the ProWest Rodeo. She is expecting closer to 400 competitors <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   The rodeo will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> nights. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said they will also be running slack during the day on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.   One of the big advantages of having a PRCA rodeo at the fair, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>, is the interest of corporate sponsors at the rodeo.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> will feature entertainment geared towards the Hispanic community, which is still being lined up by entertainment chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Allec</ENAMEX>.   Also featured at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fair is a carnival.   "We haven't had a carnival in two years," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>.   She said the Paradise Amusement carnival will have 12 to 14 rides at the fair.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s fair will also have more vendors than ever before, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>.   "We've had to turn away food vendors," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX>. "We've had vendors ask us to keep them in mind for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>."   As part of the fair tradition, the Grandview Parade will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 12</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> The parade will run along Second Street in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Reesha and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nahum</ENAMEX> from the Morning Playhouse on 107.3 KFFM will be the emcees for the parade.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> will also be Yakima Valley Band and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Cheer Day</TIMEX> led by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington Band</ENAMEX> leader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad McDavid</ENAMEX>. The participants will perform in the parade and also prior to the Wenatchee Youth Circus, according to event organizer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX>.   Besides the fair entertainment, the fair will feature other specialty events, such as livestock showmanship competitions.   Rabbit showmanship will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m. Wednesday morning</TIMEX> followed by a horse show at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> Poultry showmanship is also scheduled for the first day of the fair.   Sheep and swine classification will begin the activities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> Dairy goat showing will be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> Beef classification and showmanship will be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, just after dairy judging at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>   On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> will be having a tractor driving contest at the fair at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>   Fitting and showing for sheep, swine and dairy cows will be at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 13</TIMEX>.   A diaper derby is planned for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m. Friday night</TIMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, dog and cat showing will be featured beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX>   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4-H</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> livestock sale is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m. Saturday morning</TIMEX>, which will be followed by a buyers barbecue at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>.   Tickets for the fair will be available at the gate. Tickets are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> per day for an adult or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16</NUMEX> for a week-long admission.   Student (ages 6 to 13) and senior citizen tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> per day or <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX> for an all-week pass.   A one-day family pass for two adults and two students is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> file photo   PRCA rodeo action will entertain fair-goers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at the fair. The rodeo is set to begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> both nights.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

