
<P ID="1">Testimonials for new restaurant
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">Date published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chez Becky</ENAMEX> is the hot new place to dine in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  Conveniently located uptown on Third, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky Ballenger</ENAMEX> is looking to delight a broad range of tastes with her menu that features linguine with prosciutto, squash soup, Alaskan salmon, crepe with sauteed mushroom, and be sure not to forget the Triple Chocolate Cake. Here are the results of a small survey of recent patrons:
</P>
<P ID="5">"Becky’s potato salad!! It is out of this world!" says <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Stringfold</ENAMEX>, owner of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>'s Bridal Shoppe (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX> will be offering catering services soon).
</P>

<P ID="6">"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chef Becky</ENAMEX> is the best chef in town!!" claims <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellie Calloway</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident.
</P>

<P ID="7">"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chef Becky</ENAMEX> serves yummy food for everyone - just exactly what you want at the end of a busy day. We look forward to each new dinner - always a treat!" reports the Funk Family of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>, who drive to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> weekly for a meal.
</P>

<P ID="8">"Is she Belgian? She uses a lot of Worcestershire. But I like Worcestershire. I will be back." notes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delwin Sanderson</ENAMEX>, off to catch a flight to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX> for another conference. You won't find this kind of food in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Argentina</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delwin</ENAMEX>!
</P>

<P ID="9">"Her Middle-Eastern style vegetarian offerings are a great success. Delicious!" adds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia Christian</ENAMEX>,  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tour Guide</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> Adventures. Middle Eastern cuisine might be next on your menu, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julia</ENAMEX>, for your river tours!
</P>

<P ID="10">"The Meatloaf and the Low Carb Pork Chops with Mustard Cream Sauce are spectacular," offers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlene Englefellow</ENAMEX>, Starbucks barista. 
</P>   
   
   
   
<P ID="11">   Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">     Copyright 
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="14">   , 
</P>   
   
   









