


<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JOHN R. DURSO</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   The first <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> has long been dedicated to the social and economic achievements of American workers. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1894</TIMEX>, when President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grover Cleveland</ENAMEX> signed the bill officially declaring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> a national holiday, it has been a day each year that we pause and recognize the contributions workers have made to our nation's growth and prosperity.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> was also a call to arms for the labor movement.
</P><P ID="6">   It is appropriate that our presidential elections come on the heels of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s decision is crucial, a watershed moment in the history of American politics and an opportunity for our nation to stand up for the nation's working class. This is also a time for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s workers to stand up for themselves and vote into office a president that will advocate on their behalf.
</P><P ID="7">   During this election season, there is much talk about George W. Bush's and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>'s varied positions on the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. While there is great disagreement about foreign policy, it is right here at home that their differences are most apparent. For starters, take a look at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> economy: never has the gap between the richest - those who own homes and stocks and received huge tax breaks - and the poorest Americans been more pronounced. According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Census Bureau</ENAMEX>, the wealthiest <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of households in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> accounted for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> of total <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> income. Their share jumped to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, while all other income brackets fell. For the bottom fifth, the share dropped from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.2 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.5 percent</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   While the average American is struggling to make ends meet, they are also facing an attack on the rights and protections that previous generations of workers fought for and gained in years past.
</P><P ID="9">   Even though <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX> was observed this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>, let us consider President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s record over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 42 months</TIMEX>:
</P><P ID="10">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> does not support the Employee Free Choice Act, which would allow workers to join a union, free from employer intimidation, harassment and threats. During his presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> has taken away the collective bargaining rights of 170,000 workers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department</ENAMEX> of Homeland Security.
</P><P ID="11">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> supports a privatization plan to hand over Social Security funds to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wall Street</ENAMEX> investment firms. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> also supports making tax cuts for the wealthy permanent, which <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Federal Reserve</ENAMEX> Chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan Greenspan</ENAMEX> has said may require cuts in Social Security benefits.
</P><P ID="12">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> wants to privatize 850,000 federal jobs.
</P><P ID="13">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> eliminated ergonomic regulations that protect workers.
</P><P ID="14">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ended overtime pay protections for many workers.
</P><P ID="15">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> refused to extend unemployment insurance for jobless workers.
</P><P ID="16">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> negotiated trade deals with weaker worker protections.
</P><P ID="17">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> denied airport screeners freedom to choose a union.
</P><P ID="18">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> supported legislation to eliminate virtually all civil service protections for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Defense</ENAMEX>'s civilian workforce.
</P><P ID="19">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> signed a Medicare prescription drug bill that created a huge gap in coverage that could cost seniors thousands of dollars a year.
</P><P ID="20">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> opposed increasing the minimum wage and has supported allowing states to opt out of the federal minimum wage law and backed creation of a sub-minimum wage for some workers.
</P><P ID="21">   If that's not enough to convince you we need a change, consider this: George W. Bush is the first president in more than 70 years to watch net jobs actually decline in his term. Not since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herbert Hoover</ENAMEX>'s 1929-1933 administration at the beginning of the Great Depression has a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> president managed such a feat!
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, has spent a lifetime defending the rights of working Americans, and he has a plan to build a stronger economy and create good-paying jobs for our nation. Under his plan, our economy will create 10 million new jobs in the first four years, middle-class taxes will decrease and middle-class incomes will increase.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> knows that our nation is stronger when we create good-paying jobs here, not when we ship them overseas. He understands that hard-working Americans - not his rich cronies - should be rewarded with tax breaks. And he understands that we can only grow our economy by strengthening our middle-class.
</P><P ID="24">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> Americans celebrated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX>. But we have one more important job - to raise our voices and vote for the candidate who will protect <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>'s working families.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John R. Durso</ENAMEX> is president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Local</ENAMEX> 338 of the RWDSU/UFCW, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>, which represents more than 16,500 supermarket, dairy and health care workers in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX>. It is an affiliate of the Retail, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wholesale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department Store Union</ENAMEX> and the 1.4 million-member <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commercial Workers Union</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AFL-CIO</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




