21 20 42 46 45 18
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  There is danger from all men. The only maxim of a free government ought to be to trust no man living with power to endanger the public liberty.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Adams</ENAMEX> (1735 - 1826), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Journal</ENAMEX>, 1772
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>