


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/18/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WENDELL HOMER MORGAN</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WENDELL HOMER MORGAN</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell Homer Morgan</ENAMEX>, 94, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 16, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Landmark Care Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10, 1909</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eurilla (Binkley) Morgan</ENAMEX>. He received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, graduating with the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>. During the great Depression he would ride the rails to work in agriculture, later he worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> as a lumberman. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17, 1929</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geneva Turnidge</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1940s</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell</ENAMEX> drove milk truck for Morning Milk. He worked in lumber retail for Garren Lumber and Bestway Lumber in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and for Grandview Lumber. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell</ENAMEX> also owned and operated a small farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and for several years owned and operated the A & W in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 1, 1960</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Richey</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> continued to make their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, until moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December of 2003</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell</ENAMEX> drove school bus for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian School</ENAMEX>. After retiring, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell</ENAMEX> was an active member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">He also enjoyed riding motorcycles, camping, traveling, hunting, fishing, woodworking, crossword puzzles and was active in a bowling league until age 93. For many years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendell</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Fire Department</ENAMEX> and was a regular blood donor.
</P>

<P ID="8">He is survived by his wife of 44 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Morgan</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Morgan</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shirley</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arizona</ENAMEX>; four daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valerie Cowles</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tish Cooper</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dianna Burton</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Velva Myers</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Aloha</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; 13 grandchildren; 24 great-grandchildren; and six great-great-grandchildren.
</P>

<P ID="9">He was preceded in death by his parents; first wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geneva Morgan</ENAMEX>; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>; and three brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>, Evertt and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 21, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 22, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Cemetery, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor Wendell’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clear Lake Camp</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




