


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> leads the way in dedication of new center
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/18/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was truly a momentous occasion for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   After nearly three decades, the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> finally have a community center to call their own.
</P><P ID="6">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> led the way <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> at the dedication ceremonies for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> conducted its regular <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> meeting at the community center to coincide with dedication ceremonies <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. There were also several special guests on hand, including former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Senator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Posse</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> opened the evening with some thoughts on the road that has been taken with the construction of the community center.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said for years the residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> have had in place recreation programs to keep them busy, but have never had a facility to utilize.
</P><P ID="10">   "Now, we have the facility," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>. "This is definitely a community center to be dedicated to the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Don Stiles</ENAMEX> provided those in attendance with some background on the community center project. While there has been discussions for decades about building a community center, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said he became formally involved with the idea in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> when a group of citizens led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Uberuaga</ENAMEX> talked about the possibility of having such a place. Discussions lingered until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1998</TIMEX> when a community center planning committee was formed, involving such people as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX>. The city began a feasibility study for the center in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1998</TIMEX>. The study was completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1999</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said the final feasibility study had the center at 26,000 square feet in size with a price tag of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 million</NUMEX>. Through the efforts of the city's architectural firm for the project, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvin Jordan Associates</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX>, the size of the community center was reduced to 9,850 square feet at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 million</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2001</TIMEX>, the city received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750,000</NUMEX> state grant.
</P><P ID="14">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2002</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> awarded the bid to lay the center foundation, putting into motion the construction phase for the community center.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said he is very proud of the work that was done with the community center by everyone involved. He said a lot of time and effort went into making sure the building is a quality facility.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> then opened the evening to the special guests in attendance.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> said he knows that there were discussions for a community center since he was appointed the city's first parks and recreation director in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1980</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX> gave a lot of credit to two current <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> councilmen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Greenway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>, for their hard work in helping bring the community center to life.
</P><P ID="19">   "I played a small role in this community center," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fonfara</ENAMEX>. "But I am as proud as anybody here."
</P><P ID="20">   "It is a needed facility," said Senator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> councilman. "It is something we have been looking for."
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> told the audience <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has desired to have a community center for many years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> said when he graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> the most common words that were uttered out of the mouths of young people were there was no place to go or anything to do.
</P><P ID="22">   "Kids, you can't say that any more," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>. "This is a great day for the town. I look forward to many great years and a lot of service out of this center."
</P><P ID="23">   Posse, a former mayor of neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, was on hand to extend his congratulations to the city. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX> also shared how <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has been discussing for many years the need for a community center. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX> said the new community center shows what people who work together can achieve.
</P><P ID="24">   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> is a blue-ribbon day for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Posse</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   Former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hughes</ENAMEX> wanted to extend his thanks to the current city council for the work members have done. He said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX> the discussion for a community center began, but at the time all that was taking place was discussions.
</P><P ID="26">   "Thinking didn't get it done," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>. "I hope all of you will join me in thanking this city council in front of you right now."
</P><P ID="27">   After a few comments from current <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rockford</ENAMEX>, who said he would do his best to ensure the community center is utilized properly for the citizens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> ended the evening thanking those involved. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said he is thankful for the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in the parks department projects. He cited the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s support with such endeavors as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>, the swimming pool and the various other projects taking place.
</P><P ID="28">   "This just adds another jewel in our crown," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="29">   The city has contracted with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> to manage the community center.
</P>





 










<P ID="30">Webmaster
</P><P ID="31">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




