
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> grads soughtto help with reunion planning
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX> graduates of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> interested in helping plan 10-year reunion activities are asked to call 830-0592 or visit the web site: jen_greene@hotmail.com.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Four <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> students <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Whitworth</ENAMEX> grads
SPOKANE - Four Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> students have graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Whitworth College</ENAMEX>.
Earning degrees were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacie C. Visser</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BA</ENAMEX> in athletic training (cum laude); <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chelsea P. McPherson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BA</ENAMEX> in elementary education; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Morales</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BA</ENAMEX> in art; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allan J. Prins</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BA</ENAMEX> in international business (cum laude).
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

