
<P ID="1">State leaders unhappy <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> outspoken
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/15/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s rebel opposition to the state's <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) graduation mandates is attracting the ire of state education leaders.   The attention is the result of a local newspaper headline proclaiming that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> school officials had voted to eliminate the state-mandated <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) from its programs. The action has caused an uproar in state education circles, according to local district leaders.   The newspaper story actually detailed that the local school board voted to submit a legislative proposal that called for replacing the WASL with other testing.   "We've succeeded in getting the undivided attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Bergeson</ENAMEX>," said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent.   In fact, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX>, who is a huge proponent of the WASL becoming a state high school requirement by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>, is not happy with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>'s action, he said.   The action by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> at its meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> could result in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> making a visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX>.   "We certainly want to invite her to come visit us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> will be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early August</TIMEX> when the state association of school superintendents holds its state convention in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   "We hope to have her meet with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> so the board might explain its position," he said.   He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> is hoping to clarify its position on the WASL in future talks with state education leaders.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Director Bill Wells</ENAMEX>, the board's action, taken at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 24</TIMEX> meeting, was unprecedented in the state. "But it reflects our concern, and that of other districts, about the state's plan to implement rigid testing requirements," he said.   "I think the state is confusing good teaching techniques with passing the test," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> made those comments during the school board's retreat held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at the district's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> administration office.   At issue is a growing realization among state educators that Latino students continue to score lower on the WASL than their <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angelo</ENAMEX> counterparts, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">School Board Director Lorenzo Garza Jr.</ENAMEX>   He pointed to a five-year trend of WASL test scores that show more than two-thirds of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>'s Latino seventh graders statewide are not on track to graduate, given the state's current policies.   While the state now allows "re-takes" of the rigid test, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> is concerned that even with re-takes the majority of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> students will not qualify for high school diplomas in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2008</TIMEX>.   "We feel that will be true in many other districts across the state," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX> said.   "The question is not, can all students meet the high standards," he stressed. "The question is, how do we make high standards the goal for all students without punishing them and those who are trying hard to teach them," he said.   "We are unfairly punishing teachers and learners when we set rigorous standards without allowing sufficient time to learn or without providing sufficient resources, especially for students who face immense barriers," he said.   Statewide on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> WASL tests administered to fourth, seventh and 10th graders, Latino students scored in the last three-fourths of the categories, and no higher than next to last. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, Latino students ranked last in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> in all WASL categories and those students made up nearly <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> enrollment, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   "But that is not to say that our students don't do well on other forms of assessments," he added. But the unfairness of the WASL is particularly apparent when it comes to immigrant students, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX>.   "Especially those students who speak little or no English and neither they nor their parents understand our system," he explained.   Additionally, some students are illiterate in their native language, like their parents, and they enter our system well after kindergarten or first grade, he explained.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, in an effort to address the language problem, moved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to adopt dual language classrooms in the elementary grades.   But the concerns about the WASL extends beyond the Latino children, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX>. He said learning is slowed by many factors, not the least of which is poverty and the societal afflictions that often come with it.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> has one of the lowest poverty rates in the state, and many of our students don't have the benefit of technology in their homes or parents who are strong advocates for their learning, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   In order to aid in removing some of the students' learning barriers, the district embarked on an ambitious plan <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX> to improve parenting education. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the board will place more emphasis on that component of its efforts to aid students.   "We hope that by helping parents to take advantage of our community learning resources, we can begin to improve their learning, which in turn will help the students, " <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> explained.   In the meantime, students are being expected to jump high academic hurdles without the benefit of having learning and economic barriers removed from their educational path, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX>.   "We are placed in a difficult position of advocating for a fair system without sounding like we are opposed to high standards," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX>.   "But to do nothing is far worse. We want to keep students in school, not push them out the door prematurely. We already know our prisons are well stocked with high school dropouts," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX> said he expects other school boards and educational organizations will be stating their concerns about the current direction of the WASL and education reform when the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State School Directors Association</ENAMEX> next meets.   He said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> plans to submit a legislative proposal to the state association to seek to do away with the WASL test and to find an alternative means to testing students.   The state association will meet in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Garza</ENAMEX> said.   "In the meantime, we look forward to meeting with Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> and having her meet with members of the community to explain our concerns," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

