
<P ID="1">Greyhounds breeze by Bulldogs
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Senior night for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> boys soccer team was indeed a true celebration.   With winds whipping around the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> players, the seven Greyhound seniors basked in the limelight, as accolades rolled down for their past and present contributions.   Despite the conditions looking like something out of a disaster movie, the Greyhounds still managed to put together a decent little game, as they flew by visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> 3-0.   "The wind was swirling," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Anne Holden</ENAMEX>. "There were very difficult playing conditions."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> brought up her seniors on the JV squad to play in the varsity game <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   The Greyhounds scored early on in the third minute of the opening half when freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abel Meraz</ENAMEX> scored off an assist by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Alvarez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> carried a 1-0 lead into the break.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> then popped in another goal for the Greyhounds at the 57th minute. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fernando Angel</ENAMEX> had the assist. The last goal truly made the game worthwhile, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. One of her seniors on the junior varsity team, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Barriga</ENAMEX>, scored at the 65th minute off an assist by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Glasenapp</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> dominated offensive play, outshooting Ellensburg 10 to 2 on goal. Greyhound keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gustavo Martinez</ENAMEX> had two saves while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Quint</ENAMEX> finished with seven saves.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said her team played very well <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> basically went with a defensive scheme, going five-to-six players deep in the box. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> credited her team with being patient in the difficult conditions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> was able to break through the Bulldog defense by playing a controlled type of game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said her players would hold on to the ball, forcing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> to come out of its set. When the Greyhounds saw the opening, they would attack offensively.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> was also pleased with the way her team kept its composure on senior night. She said with the celebration it is easy to get distracted, but her players remained focused.   "They played very well, considering," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> (6-6, 7-7) will finish the continuation of this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>'s game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> tonight (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>). <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s game was called because of a concussion Greyhound keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Pacheco</ENAMEX> sustained. Tonight's game will be played in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> at about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> Both teams have to wait until track practice is done at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wapato High School</ENAMEX>. The game will pick up from where it left off on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. The Greyhounds were ahead 3-1 with eight minutes left in the first half when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pacheco</ENAMEX> sustained his injury. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will then end its regular season at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "It should be a great game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. "I am looking forward to it."   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

