


<P ID="1">Black Rock Reservoir
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/22/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Being within shouting distance of having the full <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10 million</NUMEX> needed to complete the feasibility studying for a monstrous water storage project, Black Rock Reservoir promoters are again seeking the support of local leaders and growers.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima River Basin Storage Alliance</ENAMEX> is seeking the continued vocal and financial support of area residents in promoting the 10-mile wide Black Rock Reservoir, according to former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Klarich</ENAMEX>. To date, more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> has been donated locally to the cause in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klarich</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="6">   He said <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.3 million</NUMEX> has been allocated by the state and federal governments for the reservoir feasibility project, which is expected to double the region's water storage capacity.
</P><P ID="7">   Speaking <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Conference of Governments (YVCOG) members, city mayors and councilmen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klarich</ENAMEX> thanked the leaders for their past support of the giant reservoir being proposed north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the Black Rock Canyon.
</P><P ID="8">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Bureau of Reclamation</ENAMEX> is moving ahead with the reservoir feasibility study of the canyon area, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klarich</ENAMEX> told the YVCOG membership.
</P><P ID="9">   The group, meeting at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">El Valle Restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, learned that the reservoir project has also been approved as a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Bureau of Reclamation</ENAMEX>'s annual budget, bringing future funding of the project closer to reality.
</P><P ID="10">   But all of that positive activity has only been made possible because of the support of local growers, city leaders and the determination of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Basin Storage Alliance</ENAMEX>, said long-time storage advocate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Carpenter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said in order to have the project come to fruition, the communities from Snoqualmie Pass to the Tri-Cities need to continue to lobby for the project.
</P><P ID="11">   "This has to continue to be a people-driven project," he said.
</P><P ID="12">   "I believe people do understand the need for additional water storage infrastructure such as this reservoir," he said, noting the last new water storage facility added to the current 100-year-old water storage system was completed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cascade Mountains</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "It's time for us to provide adequate water for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 100 years</TIMEX>," he said.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> reminded the YVCOG members that the recent back-to-back droughts cost the region <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250 million</NUMEX> in the farm economy and more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$750 million</NUMEX> to the surrounding communities' economy.
</P><P ID="15">   "The Black Rock project is good for the agricultural region and it's good for the environment," he said, saying salmon recovery and preservation of water and streams are a major part of the overall project.
</P><P ID="16">   "It (the reservoir project) is also good for the economy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rocky Marshall</ENAMEX>, the newest member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Basin Storage Alliance</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX>, a spokesman for the Carpenters' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Labor Council</ENAMEX> is now actively lobbying for additional funding toward the completion of the Black Rock Reservoir.
</P><P ID="18">   "The reason for our support? Jobs," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> told the YVCOG gathering.
</P><P ID="19">   "We're talking about more than 2,000 new construction jobs during the five year-plus period it is expected to take to complete building the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 billion</NUMEX> reservoir," he said,
</P><P ID="20">   "That's more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.8 billion</NUMEX> in construction jobs alone," he said.
</P><P ID="21">   The increase in business to the area beyond the construction jobs also includes ancillary jobs, such as future recreational opportunities, which will bring additional millions of dollars to the region, he said.
</P><P ID="22">   "It's time to set aside all political differences and spend all our time promoting a project which will benefit the whole area," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marshall</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="23">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="24">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="25">Webmaster
</P><P ID="26">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




