


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Padelford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Underwood</ENAMEX> unite in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Year</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX> wedding
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Padelford</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Underwood</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Padelford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Underwood</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, were united in marriage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Dec. 31, 2003</TIMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">late afternoon</TIMEX> ceremony held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Courthouse.
</P><P ID="5">   The bride, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don and Colleen Padelford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, wore a red dress in the ceremony.
</P><P ID="6">   Ringbearers for the ceremony were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashlee Underwood</ENAMEX> and Timmothy and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Marshbanks</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   The couple's wedding certificate was signed by the bride's parents and the honorable <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Roy</ENAMEX>, who performed the ceremony.
</P><P ID="8">   The bride is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. She graduated with an Associate's degree in graphic design from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Al Collins Graphic Design School</ENAMEX>. She is currently attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>, where she is studying for a Bachelor of Arts degree in science. She plans to then attend classes at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University Extension</ENAMEX> for a degree in nuclear engineering.
</P><P ID="9">   The groom is currently office manager at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Underwood Oil</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   The couple is planning a honeymoon to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.
</P>   
   
   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




