


<P ID="1">Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">School board retreat scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board of Education</ENAMEX> will hold a special retreat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday, Sept. 23</TIMEX>, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="6">In addition to dedicating the school district's parent center, at 810 E. Custer Ave., the school board agenda includes discussing credit card use for travel and food, the district's dress code, the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> graduation ceremony, and salary schedules and agreements.
</P>

 


<P ID="7">Rate increase requested by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PacifiCorp</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> regulators will hold a meeting in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Sept. 27</TIMEX>, to hear the public's views on a request by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PacifiCorp</ENAMEX> for a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$26.7 million</NUMEX> rate increase.
</P>

<P ID="9">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Utilities and Transportation Commission</ENAMEX> has scheduled the public meeting for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> in hearing room B-33 at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Courthouse.
</P>

<P ID="10">If the rate request is approved, a typical residential customer will pay an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.45</NUMEX> a month. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> has thus far received 11 public comments, all in opposition to the rate hike.
</P>

 


<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bilingual</ENAMEX> election program meeting set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later today</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="12">The next <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Bilingual Election Program Advisory Committee</ENAMEX> meeting will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>) at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood's El Valle Restaurant</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">The meeting is being held to review and discuss the county's bilingual election program and to gather input on how to most effectively provide election materials,information and assistance to Spanish speaking voters, and to discuss ways to publicize the program.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




