
<P ID="1">Passion for teaching earns <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> state accolades
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">MABTON - One cannot listen to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara Steen</ENAMEX> talk and not be drawn into her web of enthusiasm.   Whether she is talking about organizing candlelight poetry readings for her reluctant teenage poetry students or spending her lunch hours teaching a senior how to read, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> oozes the passion she feels for her job as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> English teacher.   Her enthusiasm, as well as her novel approach to the dreaded, but necessary language arts, has earned the 22-year teaching veteran the state's highest education honor. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Late last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> was named <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s "Teacher of the Year."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX>, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School Principal Keith Morris</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>, traveled to Seattle, where <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> thought she was to be recognized along with eight other regional teachers of the year.   Her surprise at being named the state's top educator continues to stun the woman, who is never at a loss for words. "I'm still overwhelmed at the honor," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>) at a press conference held in her honor at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> library.   "I'm happy to be the recipient of this award," she said. "I truly believe there is no greater job than being a teacher," she added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> credited her fellow teachers, as well as her students, for making her job exciting and rewarding every day.   "It's frequently frustrating, but absolutely never boring," she laughed.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX>, who began her career teaching seventh and eighth grade English, has taught high school English for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 11 years</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> she was selected as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>'s literacy coach. She has taught all levels of students, from remedial to advanced placement English, a program she helped to establish for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> is a teacher who lives near her students and frequently invites them into her home for socials, which from time to time involve mystery theater dinners.   She demonstrates and uses her talent for inspiring others to adapt to the educational process, say her contemporaries.   "I've been impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara</ENAMEX>'s ability to acknowledge all of her students with humor, style and love," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>.   "We are part of a team," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> explained. "Every year, I claim I have the best students I've ever had. And I do every year," she added.   "I knew when I was eight that I wanted to be a teacher," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> said. "I love it and think teaching is the best job in the world," she said.   Her students also appreciate the love she brings to the classroom.   "I've looked forward to being in her classes all my life," said long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> native <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Beeman</ENAMEX>, one of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX>'s high school English honors students.   "She makes class fun and exciting, and material we don't understand she acts out to make it easier to understand and interesting," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beeman</ENAMEX> said.   "She always finds a way to help us understand," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alida Mendoza</ENAMEX>, who also is one of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX>'s English honors students.   "Her class is hard, but she makes us understand. We know she could go anywhere to teach. But she sticks with us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> said.   As the state's teacher of the year, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> will find that she will have to be out of the classroom. "She will be traveling a lot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, as an education ambassador to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Olympia</ENAMEX> to talk with legislators, and to other districts to share her special brand of teaching talents," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>.   "She will travel to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Huntsville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alabama</ENAMEX> to visit a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NASA</ENAMEX> space camp. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara</ENAMEX> will also be going to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> at the National Educator of the Year awards program," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> added.   "I have eight essays to write in order to compete for that honor," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Steen</ENAMEX> added.   "It's a good thing I like to write," she laughed.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

