


<P ID="1">Beef sales at stores, restaurants steady
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">When the discovery of a Holstein infected with mad cow disease was announced just before the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> holiday, people throughout the country reacted. There were questions, rumors and different theories circulating locally, as people tried to get their hands on as much information about the disease as they could.
</P><P ID="5">   Locally, the questions and concerns added up to one thing for local businesses - a slight change in purchasing trends.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dean Stokes</ENAMEX>, owner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Burger Ranch, said the first few days after the announcement by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> he noticed sales of hamburgers and other beef products at the restaurant dropped off. However, recently those sales have bounced back. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stokes</ENAMEX> added that although hamburger sales decreased for a few days, people were still coming into the restaurant and opting for items containing chicken or fish.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stokes</ENAMEX> said the local Burger Ranch either raises its own beef or purchases from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ray</ENAMEX>'s Meat, which he said doesn't use <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX> meat. He isn't sure if there was a true spike in the sale of chicken, fish and other non-beef items or if employees were just taking more notice.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, owner of the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A&W/KFC</ENAMEX>, said he had a few customers come in with questions after the announcement was first made. He said people wanted to know if the restaurant's beef came from any of the distributors named during the first few days after the discovery was announced. He assured them that it doesn't.
</P><P ID="9">   Other than a few questions, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said it has been business as usual at the local restaurant, noting that sales have been about the same as they were <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   At Mama J'z in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> an effect from the announcement has yet to be felt. According to the owner of the local restaurant, who refused to be named, the establishment has been closed for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two or three weeks</TIMEX> over the holiday season and will be closed for another week.
</P><P ID="11">   The local McDonald's restaurant could not comment on the recent announcement, however in a press release dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 19</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">McDonald</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USA</ENAMEX> noted that the case of the infected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX> found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> has "no connection to McDonald's or its suppliers."
</P><P ID="12">   The release also states that the incident has had no effect on business with guest counts being on track, if not higher, than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> and the sale of beef products at their restaurants staying steady.
</P><P ID="13">   The local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX> King restaurant also chose not to comment on the announcement of the discovery of mad cow disease in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. a But according to a press release dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 23</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX> King corporation confirmed that the packers named in the first few days of the investigation do not supply meat to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Burger</ENAMEX> King system.
</P><P ID="14">   Locally, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Martin</ENAMEX>, owner of The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s Market in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, said after the announcement was made the store saw a reduction in the sale of beef, in particular hamburger.
</P><P ID="15">   "We saw a significant decline in that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> said of hamburger sales.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> said he also noticed an increase in the amount of chicken and pork products people have been purchasing. He said people are still eating meat, they are just making a different choice.
</P><P ID="17">   However, he noted that in the last few days the sale of beef products seems be coming back. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> said he thinks that as people have learned more and more about the issue, they are beginning to understand it better and therefore are going back to beef.
</P><P ID="18">   "I think the trend is going to continue," he said of beef sales slowly increasing.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cherie Myers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">director of government and public</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> affairs for Safeway, said stores were hit with a lot of questions from customers after the announcement was made.
</P><P ID="20">   As for beef sales, she said it is something the company does not discuss.
</P><P ID="21">   "It will come down to what people think, what people want and it will go from there," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Myers</ENAMEX> said, noting that people will make their own decisions when it comes to what to eat.
</P><P ID="22">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




