


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman</ENAMEX> receives unexcused absence
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Councilman Tom Seeger received an unexcused absence from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s weekly meeting.
</P>

<P ID="6">Seeger made no contact with Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> prior to missing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, resulting in the unexcused absence.
</P>

 


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman</ENAMEX> votes against consent agenda
</P>

<P ID="8">At <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> voted against the approval of the consent agenda. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> gave no reason for his vote.
</P>

<P ID="9">Coming before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the consent agenda was the approval of five liquor license renewal requests. Requests coming before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> were from the Fraternal Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX>, 100 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East South Hill Road</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Golden Pheasant Restaurant</ENAMEX>, 632 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Edison Avenue</ENAMEX>; North Avenue Market, 701 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX>; Snipes Mountain Brewing, 905 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway; and Wal-Mart Supercenter, 2675 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Lincoln Avenue</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">Also coming before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the consent agenda was approval of the meeting minutes for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 10</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> also approved the payment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$574,696</NUMEX> in voucher expenses.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="11">Explorers to be recognized at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX> meeting
</P>

<P ID="12">At this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, it was announced the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> would be recognizing the police explorers who were involved with the free dump day residents were able to take advantage of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">The special recognition for explorers will take place at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P>

<P ID="14">Also on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 7</TIMEX> agenda is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agreeing to an engineering contract for remodeling of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail dispatch facilities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will also consider entering into an agreement to seek money from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> for a development <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Christensen</ENAMEX> in planning.
</P>





 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




