


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">WANDA C
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WANDA C. GRANT</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda C. Grant</ENAMEX>, 87, a long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and Outlook area resident, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Aug. 4, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 2, 1916</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ekalaka</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lonnie</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lola</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sturgill</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halsey</ENAMEX>. At an early age she with her family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Juneton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, where she received her early education and graduated from high school. Following her graduation the family moved to Outlook. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda</ENAMEX> later attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Simpson Bible College</ENAMEX> in Seattle, and then returned to Outlook.
</P>

<P ID="7">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Grant</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halsey</ENAMEX> family home in Outlook. Following their marriage they made their home in Outlook. Her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, died in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 1953</TIMEX> and following his death <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda</ENAMEX> made her home in Outlook before moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda</ENAMEX> was a serious Mariner fan.
</P>

<P ID="9">She attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Baptist Church</ENAMEX>. Her church family was very special to her. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda</ENAMEX> also cherished many friendships at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Uptown Mobile Court</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">She was a very devoted mother and grandmother.
</P>

<P ID="11">She is survived by her son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Grant</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RoeJean</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sammamish</ENAMEX>; her grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam and Rebecca Treat</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meghan and Andrew Grant</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Meyer</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; and numerous nieces and nephews including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanne Diegel</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kent</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">She was preceded in death by her parents; her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Russell Grant</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1953</TIMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marjean Gibson</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dell Halsey</ENAMEX>, in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">Viewing will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 6, 2004</TIMEX>, from 3 until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, followed by a time of fellowship for friends and family at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calvary Baptist Church</ENAMEX>, at 908 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodward</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 7, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>  
<P ID="14">Burial will be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at Normal Hill Cemetery in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Juneton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




