
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/7/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">PAID <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OBITUARY
CARL HOWARD STINSON
Carl Howard Stinson</ENAMEX>, 82, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sonoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, and former resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Sept. 29, 2003</TIMEX>, with his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark</ENAMEX> and daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy</ENAMEX> at his side.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 29, 1921</TIMEX>, at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl Elias Stinson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cynthia Graham Stinson</ENAMEX>. His mother died when he was five-years-old leaving his father, an immigrant Swedish farmer, with two step-sons, a daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dora Christine</ENAMEX>, and another son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>, to care for. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> worked hard on the farm from an early age and at one point was in charge of the cooking for the family and said he never wanted to cook again. Yet, he took it up again, when his wife of 57 years developed Alzheimer’s disease.
 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> during the Depression. It was there that he met <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Della Joy Matthew</ENAMEX>, who would later become his wife. Hard work was a constant element of his life and his personal motto printed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1939</TIMEX> yearbook summed up his restlessness and belief in his own abilities that defined him for the rest of his life. “If I could get out of here, I could get something done.”
An intelligent man with a photographic memory, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> studying engineering, but at the outbreak of WWII, he worked in the shipyards in Seattle before taking exams for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> Air Corps</ENAMEX>. Commissioned as an officer, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> piloted A-26 bombers over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX>, flying out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> and later <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">France</ENAMEX>. At the end of the war he ferried planes back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> via <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Africa</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South America</ENAMEX>.
Howard’s engineer’s mind served him well when he started his own construction company after the war using army surplus for equipment. He was active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Junior Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, as was honored as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> of the Year in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1950s</TIMEX>. He moved his family to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kingston</ENAMEX> and later The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, where he became a successful business owner along with his brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley</ENAMEX>, operating <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interstate Paving Company</ENAMEX>. He was the past president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Asphalt Paving Association</ENAMEX>, a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jaycees</ENAMEX>, The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalles Elks Club</ENAMEX> and The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dalles Country Club</ENAMEX>. Retiring from paving, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Della</ENAMEX> developed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pomona Mobile Home Park</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX> always loved the newest toy. He started his collection with army surplus airplanes, motorcycles and boats. He always had his own small plane, and also owned and flew a helicopter and in his 70s, an ultra-light. As a pilot he also loved to travel, enjoying trips to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Egypt</ENAMEX> with his wife.
Impatience was always with him and when age, diabetes and arthritis caught up with him he seemed truly surprised that he couldn’t do everything he had once done.
He is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Della Joy Matthew Stinson</ENAMEX>, son and daughter-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark and Celia Stinson</ENAMEX>, daughter and son-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christy and John Coulston</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sonoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, daughter and son-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Stinson-Chennell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Chennell</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McMinnville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Stinson</ENAMEX> of Anchorage, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>; sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dora Christine Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>; and brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanley Stinson</ENAMEX> of The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>; along with grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica and Andrew Stinson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mildred and Libby Chennell</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle and Corey Madden</ENAMEX>.
No funeral services were held at the deceased’s request however the family met at the Oregon Coast in a celebration of Howard’s life and to spread his ashes over an area he particularly loved.
</P> 
 


 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

