
<P ID="1">No settlement yet in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> drowning of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> child
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/6/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A lawsuit centered on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX> drowning death of a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> student is still expected to go to court by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late spring</TIMEX>, according to a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> official.   The lawyers for both sides of the issue are preparing to go to court sometime in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late spring</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early summer</TIMEX>, said Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>, district superintendent.   The lawsuit was filed in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Superior Court</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2003</TIMEX>, claiming the school district had been negligent in its supervision of the child. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> officials report the boy was prone to running away.   "We have no direct contact with the lawsuit as it is now in the hands of our insurance company," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   "I understand some attempts have been made for an out-of- court settlement," he said. "But it's also my understanding the case is still scheduled to go to trial in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late spring</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> added.   The lawsuit is seeking unspecified damages for the family of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Hui</ENAMEX>, an autistic 6-year-old student who wandered away from the Jackson Street school on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11, 2001</TIMEX>. The child was the subject of a city-wide search by the school district personnel and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>, before his body was found in the canal near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest Crescent Avenue</ENAMEX>.   The lawsuit is being handled by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevan S. Montoya</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Hui</ENAMEX>'s parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Qing-Fen Hui</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, who allege the school district failed in its duty to properly monitor the boy.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

