


<P ID="1">Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/1/2002</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> asks USDA to purchase more asparagus
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASHINGTON</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. - Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>) is leading a bipartisan coalition of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Michigan</ENAMEX> lawmakers in asking the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Dept. of Agriculture</ENAMEX> to make a bonus purchase of asparagus for the nation's federal nutrition programs.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said American asparagus growers compete at a disadvantage in the domestic market because of increased asparagus imports from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Peru</ENAMEX>. He explained Peruvian growers benefit immensely from the duty-free access to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> markets they were granted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX> by the Andean Trade Preferences Act.
</P>

<P ID="7">"A purchase <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this spring</TIMEX> would help our asparagus growers, who are working hard to meet the challenge presented by increased duty-free imports," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

 


<P ID="8">State charges two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> nursing assistants
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Department of Health</ENAMEX>'s Nursing Assistant Program has leveled formal charges against two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> nursing assistants.
</P>

<P ID="10">The state has charged <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viola Jones</ENAMEX>, an applicant to reactivate her nursing assistant certification, with unprofessional conduct. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jones</ENAMEX> allegedly pled guilty to obtaining or attempting to obtain a controlled substance by fraud, deceit or misrepresentation.
</P>

<P ID="11">Also charged from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabriela Madrigal</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> officials say while applying for reactivation of her nursing assistant certification, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Madrigal</ENAMEX> failed to disclose she pled guilty to burglary.
</P>

<P ID="12">Both women had 20 days from when the charges were leveled to respond to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX> in writing. Cases then enter a settlement process, but if no disciplinary agreement can be reached, a hearing is scheduled.
</P>

 


<P ID="13">Impact of when
a local story goes national topic
of public forum
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - A journalism advocacy group will hold a public forum on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 10</TIMEX>, at the Silver Dollar Cafe in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> to discuss the impacts to a community when a local story becomes national and international news.
</P>

<P ID="15">The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William O. Douglas</ENAMEX> chapter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Society of Professional Journalists</ENAMEX> is coordinating the event. It will include a panel discussion on how the news media directed its mad cow coverage and how that coverage continues to affect the community.
</P>

<P ID="16">The public is invited to the 7:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m.</TIMEX> free event, and questions from the audience will be encouraged.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




