


<P ID="1">Fixing cars in streets now a 'no-no'
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/11/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> adopted a new resolution banning the repair of vehicles on public property or in public right-of-ways.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rockford</ENAMEX> said he felt comfortable with recommending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> adopt the new ordinance. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he would rather see the city enforce the existing ordinances rather than adopting new ones.
</P><P ID="6">   The new ordinance adopted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> makes it illegal for residents to conduct any major repairs or change motor vehicle fluids on public streets, sidewalks, rights-of-way and other public property. The reasoning is any such repairs might create a safety or environmental hazard. The ordinance does allow for residents to make emergency repairs to vehicles on public property.
</P><P ID="7">   "It is unfortunate we have to pass these kinds of ordinances," said Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said the ordinance is not only for the safety of residents, but it will also help ensure that no environmental contamination takes place. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said the ordinance will help eliminate any possible contamination in the city's drain system. The mayor pro-tem said there are just too many unseen risks with allowing people to repair their vehicles on public rights-of-way. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> added this ordinance will also help with the development of properties in town.
</P>   






 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




