


<P ID="1">Vice President stumps for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KENNEWICK</ENAMEX> - As the Democratic National Convention was preparing to open its nearly week long convention of naming a candidate to unseat President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Boston</ENAMEX>, Vice President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Cheney</ENAMEX> was in the Tri-Cities <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> stumping for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Republican</ENAMEX> gubernatorial candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>, the man who made many of the early crucial decisions in the wake of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> attacks, was the featured attraction at a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250</NUMEX> per plate luncheon at the Three <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rivers Convention Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The vice president, who was accompanied by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX>, outlined why the Republican party would best be suited to lead the nation for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next four years</TIMEX> while mixing in a unique political sense of humor.
</P><P ID="7">   The vice president made a strong point of how important the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> will be in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s election. The Bush-Cheney ticket beat the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Al Gore</ENAMEX> campaign in 28 of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state's 39 counties. Bush-Cheney easily won heavily Republican led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> counties, collecting more than 75,000 votes in the two counties. Bush-Cheney also handily won <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane County</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX>, picking up 81,000 votes. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state with 1.12 million votes compared to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> ticket, which garnered just over 1 million votes.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>, 63, grew up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, where he met his wife. She recounted for the capacity audience, estimated in the neighborhood of 450 people, how she first came across the future politician at the age of 14 when he had an after-school janitors job.
</P><P ID="9">   "I didn't pay much attention to him at first," Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said, which drew an uproar of laughter from the audience.
</P><P ID="10">   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> talked about the growth of her husband into the politician he is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   Vice President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>'s political career began in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX> when he served under President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Nixon</ENAMEX>. He later served as the deputy assistant and chief of staff under President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerald Ford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> was elected congressman for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wyoming</ENAMEX>, being re-elected five times.
</P><P ID="13">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From March 1989 to January 1993</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> served as the Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Defense</ENAMEX>, leading military campaigns in Desert Storm and Operation Just Cause in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Panama</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   But his wife was most proud of the efforts of her husband on one of the most prolific days in American history. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynne</ENAMEX>, who was in the emergency bunker with the vice president on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>, told the audience of how her husband rose to the occasion when the country was under attack by terrorists.
</P><P ID="15">   "I saw how totally committed he was to our President and this nation," she said.
</P><P ID="16">   Before turning the spotlight over to her husband, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> encouraged those in attendance to keep the same Republican party in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "He (President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>) has been a magnificent leader the past three-and-a-half years," she said. "And if you permit me to say so, the vice president is no slouch, either."
</P><P ID="18">   "It is great to come back to the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>," the Vice President said in taking the podium. "The President and I are grateful for our supporters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is going to be part of the nation-wide victory."
</P><P ID="19">   The Vice President recounted for the audience he had been to the Tri-Cities before entering politics. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">50 years ago this summer</TIMEX> he can remember coming to a baseball tournament in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> as a youngster.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> carried an upbeat mood as he talked about the upcoming battles with Democratic presidential candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> and his running mate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Edwards</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said he contacted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> after it was announced he would be on the Democratic ticket and had a friendly conversation. The vice president pointed out to the audience that many say <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwards</ENAMEX> was picked for his good looks and charm.
</P><P ID="22">   "How do you think I got this job?" joked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> then turned his attention to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX>, who is the forerunner for the governor's mansion in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> knows exactly what people need in the state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>. "We are here <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> to make absolutely sure <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> is the next governor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> for the common sense approach he feels the gubernatorial candidate will bring to the governor's mansion, which hasn't been filled by a Republican for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two decades</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said he feels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> has solid direction in bringing new jobs to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, improving health care and addressing other issues concerning residents.
</P><P ID="26">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino</ENAMEX>'s campaign is based on strong convictions," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> is an outstanding candidate. He is going to be a great governor."
</P><P ID="27">   The Vice President then turned his attention to some of the issues facing the Bush-Cheney campaign. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said the country is facing a great threat from abroad, comparing the terrorist network that led the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> attacks to that of the enemy axis during World War II.
</P><P ID="28">   "What this enemy wants is to do away with democracy," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>. "This is not an enemy you can reason with."
</P><P ID="29">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said it is important to keep <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> in office because he knows the decisions that will have to be made to keep the country safe.
</P><P ID="30">   The Vice President then fielded some questions from the audience. One audience member asked how safety has improved in the country since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said he is in the process of reading the entire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX> committee report, but said the President is anxious to move quickly on those recommendations. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> gave as one example of how safety has improved is the meetings between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> that take place five days per week at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m.</TIMEX> with President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said the communication between those two organizations has improved greatly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said before, the two agencies never communicated because it wasn't the desire of the government to have the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CIA</ENAMEX> involved in domestic matters.
</P><P ID="31">   The Vice President also fielded a question on his health. When the president first took office, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> suffered a series of heart problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> just recently completed his annual health examine.
</P><P ID="32">   "They watch me very carefully," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>. "They just certified me for another 30,000 miles."
</P><P ID="33">   One audience member had a question on what Republicans can do to ensure Bush-Cheney gets re-elected.
</P><P ID="34">   "It is important for people to understand the significance of the decisions we are going to make," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="35">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> said it is important to get the word out to people to vote.
</P><P ID="36">   "It is really no time for anyone who cares about the country to sit out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="37">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> encouraged people to vote, become involved, because the decision made <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> will affect history for years to come.
</P><P ID="38">   "With your help <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> is going to be a great <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Republican day</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state and across the nation," said the Vice President.
</P>





 










<P ID="39">Webmaster
</P><P ID="40">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




