
<P ID="1">Science teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Stark</ENAMEX> earns <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein Fellowship</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">For the first time since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1977</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Stark</ENAMEX> won't be returning to her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> classroom when school starts up for the new year <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.   Instead, the award-winning high school science teacher will be on her way to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>., where she will spend the next school year involved in marine biology research and policy making as an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein Distinguished Educator Fellow</ENAMEX>.   Known for her devotion to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s science fair program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> will be taking a nine-month sabbatical from her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> teaching position to participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">NOAA</ENAMEX>) Emerging Young Scientists and Teacher at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sea</ENAMEX> programs, according to Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>, superintendent of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX>, who in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> was awarded the Presidential Distinguished Educator Award, was one of only 11 teachers nationwide to be awarded the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein</ENAMEX> fellowship after an intensive national screening process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said.   "She will be collaborating with personnel of other federal agencies and in Congressional offices, while living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. during the coming year," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said she will be living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silver Springs</ENAMEX>, just outside the nation's capital, while working at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department of Commerce Building</ENAMEX>.   As an <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Albert Einstein Fellow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> will be providing practical insights and real world perspectives to policy makers and program managers developing or managing education programs, she explained.   Saying she is excited to be given the opportunity to participate in the program, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> explained that she was chosen after going through three interviews. "I made the cut from 27 educators to be interviewed by members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX> and the NOAA," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> will begin her nine- month fellowship just after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Labor Day</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said the fellowship will provide her with a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,550</NUMEX> monthly stipend, plus moving expenses and a professional travel allowance.   Her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>, a college biology professor at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Basin College</ENAMEX>, will be joining her in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>., where he expects to be working during the coming school year.   "It's quite an honor to be chosen for the fellowship," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said. "I'm looking forward to doing research and working with the NOAA officials on public policy," she added.   The fellowship program was enacted by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> and is funded by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Energy Office of Science</ENAMEX> with participation from federal agencies, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Science Foundation</ENAMEX>, the NOAA and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Aeronautics and Space Administration</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> heard about the fellowship <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last November</TIMEX> during a trip to the nation's capital, where she learned that as a Presidential Educator Award winner she was eligible to apply for the fellowship program.   To be considered, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> had to show evidence of her excellence in teaching science, demonstrate her inquiry-based and innovative teaching style, her sustained professional growth, as well as her outstanding leadership ability.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> has long been active in developing and sustaining local science programs, organizing and hosting both local and regional science fairs for school-age students. She is the current chair of the Mid-Columbia Regional Science and Engineering Science Fair. In addition, she has been recognized on numerous occasions for her involvement with the development and expansion of the Washington State Science and Engineering Fair awards program.   Under her guidance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX>'s science fair students have repeatedly been selected for regional and state science championships, earning them all expense-paid trips to the prestigious International Science and Engineering Fair since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> can point with pride to many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> science champions who passed through her classes, who have gone on to be involved in science and engineering-related careers as a result of their science fair experiences.   "In fact, my very first international science fair champion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teri Alvarez-Ziegler</ENAMEX>, will begin teaching her own science students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX>," she said.   Despite her physical absence from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> science fair program during the coming year, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> still plans to be involved. She expects to be helping with the designing and editing of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> science students' <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> science fair projects.   "I'm still the co-chair of the Mid-Columbia Regional Science and Engineering Fair. So I expect to be in close contact with my co-chair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Gilmer-Dillman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Middle School</ENAMEX>," she said.   In addition to giving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> science fair participants access to her vast scientific knowledge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> expects to be giving her replacement, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Campanella</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, a helping hand as needed.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campanella</ENAMEX>, a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>, is excited to be taking part in the high school science fair, in addition to his high school science classes.   "He'll be working with fellow science teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Bryson</ENAMEX>, who will be heading up the local science fair program," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> explained.   She said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> science teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hayes</ENAMEX> will also be helping to coordinate the annual exhibition of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> science projects.   "The local science fair will go on, and I'll still be active in it," she said.   Excited to be living near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chesapeake Bay</ENAMEX> during the coming months, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said she also hopes to be allowed to do some experiments aboard the NOAA's research ships, which are docked near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silver Springs</ENAMEX>.   "I have several experiments I conducted while working on the Alantis that I want to continue," she said.   "This is going to be one exciting year," she said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

