


<P ID="1">Still time to register to vote in General Election
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The clock is ticking for those citizens who have not yet registered to vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>'s general election.
</P><P ID="4">   Anyone who wants to vote in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX> election still has until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 18</TIMEX> to register for the election.
</P><P ID="5">   Mail-in registrations must be postmarked no later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2</TIMEX> to be valid, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Beck</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Elections Department</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   "But if you haven't mailed in your registration form by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2</TIMEX>, you can still register in-person at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Auditor's office in the county courthouse to be assured a ballot on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>," she said.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beck</ENAMEX> said mail-in and absentee ballots will be mailed out <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13</TIMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




