37 2 21 35 15 39
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  He had learned over the years that poor people did not feel so poor when allowed to give occasionally.  Lawana Blackwell, The Courtship of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicar</ENAMEX>'s Daughter, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>