


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golob</ENAMEX> competes for State Dairy crown
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LYNNWOOD</ENAMEX> - Outgoing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendra Golob</ENAMEX> was one of nine young ladies competing for the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Dairy</ENAMEX> Ambassador <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   When the final tallies from the judges were computed, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McKenzie Klein</ENAMEX>, 18, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Whatcom County</ENAMEX> who was chosen to represent the dairy industry in the coming year.
</P><P ID="5">   Selected to serve as co-alternate state dairy ambassadors were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Irving</ENAMEX>, representing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">King-Pierce</ENAMEX> counties, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Nelson</ENAMEX>, representing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The six other young ladies competing for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX> ambassador crown were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golob</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meagan Groat</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clark County</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassandra Forar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grays Harbor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carissa Sauer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland Northwest</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Orange</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skagit-Island</ENAMEX> counties and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Neff</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snohomish County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Golob</ENAMEX> was the 2003-04 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess. The state event in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX> capped off her duties as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess. NiBones Linde of Outlook is the 2004-05 reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Dairy</ENAMEX> Princess.
</P><P ID="8">   The newly crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">state</ENAMEX> ambassador will represent the dairy industry through public appearances during her year-long term. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klein</ENAMEX> will also serve a 10-month paid internship with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Dairy Products Commission</ENAMEX> at its <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynnwood</ENAMEX> office. She will receive college credits for her internship, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,500</NUMEX> in college scholarships and extensive training in communications.
</P><P ID="9">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state dairy princess/ambassador program is open to candidates who possess dairy knowledge-either by being in a family that works in the dairy industry or having taken on a 4-H or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> dairy heifer or cow project for at least two years.
</P>





 










<P ID="10">Webmaster
</P><P ID="11">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




