


<P ID="1">Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">‘Doc’ to make <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> appearance in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S’side</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> normally meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> mornings. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tomorrow</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 17</TIMEX>, the local <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> leadership will instead gather at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>, in order to accomodate Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc Hastings</ENAMEX>' busy schedule.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> is scheduled to be <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">tomorrow</TIMEX>'s guest speaker. The public is invited to the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> luncheon meeting, to be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood's Sunny Spot Restaurant</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fourth District</ENAMEX> congressman from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> wasted little time following this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Tuesday</TIMEX>'s primary election before challenging his Democratic opponent to a series of campaign debates. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, one of his aides personally delivered a letter to his challenger, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Matheson</ENAMEX>, challenging her to contrast her views with his in a series of debates, forums and live radio call-in shows.
</P>

<P ID="8">His proposal has raised a few eyebrows, because traditionally it's the challengers who demand debates while incumbents seek to avoid them.
</P>

<P ID="9">"<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doc</ENAMEX> feels strongly that candidates should have an opportunity to question each other directly in order to give voters the clearest possible picture of the choice before them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Howe</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>' campaign manager.
</P>

 


<P ID="10">Parks and rec commission
to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 22</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="11">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Commission</ENAMEX> is scheduled to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Wednesday, Sept. 22</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5:30 p.m.</TIMEX> in the city conference room at city hall.
</P>

<P ID="12">Commission meetings are open to the public.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




