30 50 16 28 46 23
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Man</ENAMEX> is born a predestined idealist, for he is born to act. To act is to affirm the worth of an end, and to persist in affirming the worth of an end is to make and ideal.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oliver Wendell Holmes</ENAMEX> (1809 - 1894)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>