
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Leavenworthquilt show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7-12</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">LEAVENWORTH</ENAMEX> - "Spaziergang durch quilts in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX>." That's the message Familie Ereiqnise and Produktions von Leavenworth is trying to get out to the public.
Translated into English, the message is simple: "Meander through quilts in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX>."
Familie Ereiqnise and Produktions von Leavenworth are hosting their ninth annual quilt show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7-12</TIMEX>. Quilts designed by featured artist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kate Carroll</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Anaconda</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX> will be displayed at the show, as well.
Visitors to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leavenworth</ENAMEX> will find numerous quilts displayed throughout the community those six days. There is no fee to take in the beauty of the quilt-making.
A grand showing, though, is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 10-12</TIMEX>, and admission is set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX>.
Quilting workshops will also be offered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 10-12</TIMEX>.
For more information about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s show, go on-line to: www.quiltersheaven.com.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Baket-making class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PATERSON</ENAMEX> - Columbia Crest Winery will host a basket-making class <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> artist and gallery owner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanette Stark</ENAMEX> will demonstrate to those in the class how to create a hand-woven twill wool drying basket. An heirloom-quality basket, it is designed to be sturdy and useful for many tasks or decorative uses.
The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38</NUMEX> class fee includes all weaving materials. Participants should bring to the session a tape measure, a sturdy pair of scissors, an awl, 20 clothespins and a sharp pocket knife. Students are also invited to bring a picnic lunch for the hour-long lunch break. All participants will receive a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">25 percent</NUMEX> discount on all wine shop items the day of the class.
Participants must register by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 15</TIMEX>, at the Pateson winery (1-888-309-9463). Pre-payment is required.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Mendesat Jazz AlleySept</ENAMEX>. 16-19
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Jazz Institute</ENAMEX> at Dimitriou's Jazz Alley in Seattle will present Brazilian superstar <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sergio Mendes</ENAMEX> for four nights.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendes</ENAMEX> brought Brazilian music to the masses with his debut album, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brazil</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'66</TIMEX>. He was the first to present Brazilian music in the English language, and through collaborations with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burt Bacharach</ENAMEX>, the Beatles, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alan and Marilyn Bergman</ENAMEX> brought the Brazilian bossa nova/samba sound to pop culture.
After getting signed to A&M records by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Alpert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Moss</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendes</ENAMEX> and his band toured with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alpert</ENAMEX>'s Tijuana Brass, making him a household name in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX>.
Although he brought Brazilian sound to the mainstream, his desire to return to his roots led him to form the band "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Brazil</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'77</TIMEX>." Recording Primal Roots, a fresh tribute to indigenous Brazilian music that was critically hailed, it was commercially ignored. But, his effort laid the foundation for other musicians, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria Estafan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Ronstadt</ENAMEX>, to cut albums in their native tongues.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendes</ENAMEX> continued to pen hits throughout the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX>'s, including Never Gonna Let You Go.
The band members that will be appearing with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendes</ENAMEX> at Dimitrious's Jazz Alley <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 16-19</TIMEX> include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Taylor</ENAMEX> and Dawn Bishop (vocals), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Brendle</ENAMEX> (keyboards), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo Nobre</ENAMEX> (bass), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Shapiro</ENAMEX> (drums), Kleber Pimenta (guitar), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nailton Dos Santos</ENAMEX> (percussion) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Dos Santos</ENAMEX> (percussion).
Set times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday through Saturday</TIMEX> will be at 8 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:15 p.m.</TIMEX>, and at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:45 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>. Reservations for one of the shows can be made by calling (206) 441-9729.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Cask beer festival on tap for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 30</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - The fifth annual Washington Cask Beer Festival, a major highlight of the Seattle beer fest scene, will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 30</TIMEX>.
The event will feature many one-of-a-kind handcrafted, cask-conditioned beers from more than 30 of the region's most innovative microbreweries.
Providing food at the event will be Barking Dog Alehouse.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s festival will include two sessions—the first from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>, the second from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 p.m.</TIMEX> Separate tickets are required for each session.
Advance tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX>, are available on-line at: www.washingtonbrewfest.com.
Only 250 tickets are available for each session. A ticket entitles the holder to a souvenir glass and all 3-oz. sample tastes. Food and non-alcoholic beverages will also be available at the event.
The festival will be held in the Alki Room at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Center</ENAMEX>, located at the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Warren</ENAMEX> and Republican in Seattle.
</P> 


 




<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

