
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Final plat approvedfor housing development
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> voted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to approve the final plat for phase two of the Vista Villas development on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Highland Road</ENAMEX>.
The second phase of the housing development includes approximately 18 lots, in what will ultimately be a 50-lot subdivision.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Contracts approvedfor <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funding
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> approved two contracts for funding from the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX>.
The two projects that received funding from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board include <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30,000</NUMEX> for the installation of a playground structure at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>, as well as grant funds to help relieve some of the loan debt for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College Grape</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wine Education Center</ENAMEX>, set to be built in the old Safeway building on Grandridge in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> honored for 25 years of service
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Rodriguez</ENAMEX> was honored <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for 25 years of working for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>.
"He means a lot to our department," Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX> said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> received a plaque to commemorate his service.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

