


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood police</ENAMEX> sergeant dies on elk hunting trip
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">For the next few days the flags at city buildings will be at half mast in memory of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Evans</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, 50, died this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> while hunting elk above <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. The request to lowered the flags came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   They will remain lowered until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' funeral.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX> heard the news of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' death about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 p.m.</TIMEX> that night. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said the cause of death is believed to be a heart attack.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> recently celebrated his 27th year with the police department, where he had served as a sergeant for about four years. He also recently passed the police department's physical agility test, which tested seasoned officers on their physical fitness.
</P><P ID="8">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> was hunting with some other people and was left by a hunting partner, with plans to meet up at camp later. When he didn't return they went looking for him in the area where he was last seen.
</P><P ID="9">   "He was found sitting on the ground where he had been left. He was just waiting for an elk to come by," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   At this time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said the department is assisting the family in whatever way possible.
</P><P ID="11">   "He'll be very much missed within the department," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' death will also leave a hole in the community. Active in the town, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> was always willing to lend a helping hand to those who needed it.
</P><P ID="13">   It was his kindheartedness that earned him a letter of commendation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>. A member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New Zealand Parliament</ENAMEX> had written a letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>, pointing out his kindness when he went out of his way to put a young New Zealander whose passport had expired and was sitting in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail in contact with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Zealand</ENAMEX> consulate. The young foreigner was able to talk to his family because of what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> had done, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   He was also a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Volunteer Fire Department</ENAMEX> and, in the past, helped teach hunter safety courses.
</P><P ID="15">   The date of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX>' funeral service has not yet been determined.
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




