
<P ID="1">Outlook Grange still serving rutabagas at annual dinner
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">OUTLOOK - Originally, the Outlook Grange dinner menu consisted of chicken as part of its main course, but five years after the first dinner it was switched to roast beef and turkey.   One thing that has not changed is the rutabaga element of the meal. Rutabagas may be a vegetable more commonly associated with the fall and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> months, but if properly stored in a cool, dry place they will last until spring.   "Back then (in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>) rutabagas were a primary food people ate a lot of," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Barr</ENAMEX>, one of the organizers of the annual dinner.   She explained that originally farmers grew a lot of rutabagas in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> as a secondary crop. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, it is a little more difficult to find the slightly peppery vegetable, which is a cross between a sweet potato and a turnip. In the past farmers would donate rutabagas, but now the grange has to buy the vegetable from local farmers who still grow the root.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> said the rutabagas range in size from four to eight inches. She explained the grange members work together to prepare the vegetable for the dinner.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> we go down to the grange and peel them," she said. "They have a heavy skin. Then we simmer them with chunks of bacon."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX> members serve the soft rutabagas in chunks rather than mashing them, which is another way to serve it.   Not a common vegetable nowadays, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> said the dinner will be a good time for younger people to try the vegetable.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> said with an interest in nutrition and eating healthier foods, people might be glad to know that rutabagas are high in Vitamin A and have cancer fighting agents in them.   A cup of cooked rutabagas has 64 calories and is low in protein with only 15 carbohydrates, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>. She added that they are a good source of calcium and beta carotene, which is good for the eyes.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> the grange, which is located at 4400 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle Road</ENAMEX>, is gearing up for another annual dinner, which will be held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Leap Day</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 29</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">year</TIMEX> 300</TIMEX> people attended the dinner, which is the major fund-raiser for the grange.   "It keeps us busy," she said.   The first Outlook Grange dinner was served in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX> as a fund-raiser.   Rutabagas are not the only food on the menu for the annual dinner. Roast beef, turkey, mashed potatoes, green beans, apple salad, pie and a roll will also be served, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>.   The cost of the dinner is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for children.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

