
<P ID="1">Winners at Yakima Valley Fair and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodeo</ENAMEX> announced
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Yakima Valley Fair and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodeo</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> concluded one of its most successful runs in recent years <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Country Park</ENAMEX> and Fairgrounds.   The following is a list of winners from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s fair:   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIVISION 1 BEEF   Fitting & Showing   4-H   Junior   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nolan Saam</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   Intermediate   Gold - Stetson McMinimee - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hog Heaven Sheep Club</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JJ Wood</ENAMEX> - Country Kidz.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexandria Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   Senior   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Slater</ENAMEX> - Bickleton Hilltoppers.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Miller - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Thonney - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Pearson</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Thonney</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beef Market Steer   4-H   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Thonney - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Byron Hunt</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Thonney</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danielle Pearson</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beef Breeding   4-H   Jr. Yearling Heifer   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Slater</ENAMEX> - Bickleton Hilltoppers.   Overall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">4-H Female   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Slater</ENAMEX> - Bickleton Hilltoppers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Jr. Heifer   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cow & Calf   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   Overall <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA Female   Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division 2 Dairy   Fitting & Showing   4-H   Junior Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bos</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hog Heaven Sheep Club</ENAMEX>.   Intermediate Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Wedam</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   Senior Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Mensonides</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dairy Classification   Holstein Junior Heifer   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bos</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hog Heaven Sheep Club</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hog Heaven Sheep Club</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holstein Intermediate Heifer   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Wedam</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   2 - Corrin Veiga - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holstein Senior Heifer   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Bosma</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herd & Home</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holstein</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yearling</ENAMEX>   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holstein</ENAMEX> Junior <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yearling Heifer   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hog Heaven Sheep Club</ENAMEX>.   Holstein Senior Yearling Heifer - not milking   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Wood</ENAMEX> - Country Kidz.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holstein Cow 2</ENAMEX> yr - 3 yr   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Wedam</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Green Valley   2</ENAMEX> - Corrin Veiga - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holstein Cow 3</ENAMEX> yr - 4 yr   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red & White</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yearling</ENAMEX>   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nathan Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Red & White Jr.</ENAMEX> yearling   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Groth - Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Intermediate Heifer   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jimmy Wood</ENAMEX> - Country Kidz.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jersey Senior Heifer   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JJ Wood</ENAMEX> - Country Kidz.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">4-H Junior Champion Holstein   Melissa Groth</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">4-H Reserve Champion Holstein   Melissa Groth</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">4-H Grand Champion Holstein   Julie Wedam</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   4-H Junior champion <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jersey   JJ Wood</ENAMEX> - Country Kidz.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4-H Champion Red & White   Nick Groth</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Critters R Us</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA Grand Champion Holstein   Amy Mensonides</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIVISION 3 SHEEP   Fitting & Showing   4-H   Novice   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Thomas</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Livestock.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Lamb</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Thomas</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Livestock.   Junior   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacob Bos</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hog Heaven Sheep Club</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Ziegler</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaaBaa & Company</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Dezellem</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   Intermediate   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexandria Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Bos</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hog Heaven Sheep Club</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bayli Ziegler</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaaBaa & Company</ENAMEX>.   Senior   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany</ENAMEX> denHoed - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   Silver - Kasie Menzia - Naches Valley 4-H.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rebekah Hulse</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Gold</ENAMEX> - Kasie Menzia - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Naches FFA</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Ziegler</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah FFA</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   Market Lamb   4-H   Grand Champion - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abbie Ziegler</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BaaBaa & Company</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - Makaela Duim - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Livestock   FFA   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - Kilee Roberts - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Valley FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Ziegler</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIVISION 4 SWINE   Fitting & Showing   4-H   Novice   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Banzet</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Smasne</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Ag & Ec</ENAMEX>.   Junior   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Nichols</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey Hays</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grow Em & Show Em</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alexandra Hays</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grow Em & Show Em</ENAMEX>.   Intermediate   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Nichols</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darcy Morford</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey Dezellem</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   Senior   Gold - Carly Dahlstrom - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sun</TIMEX> County Livestock.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Pace</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herd & Home</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hulse</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Gold</ENAMEX> - Danelle Cowan - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview FFA</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Better</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goldendale FFA</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Logan Desserault</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview FFA</ENAMEX>.   Market Swine   4-H   Grand Champion - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darcy Morford</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - Geordon Skyles - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Livestock.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - Jordan Dill - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dirk Desserault</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview FFA</ENAMEX>.   SWINE BREEDING GILT   4-H Junior Gilt   Grand Champion - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maddie Morford</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Freepons</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA Junior Gilt   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - Danelle Cowan - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA Senior Gilt   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - Leanne Cohenour - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Valley FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIVISION 5 GOATS   Market Goat   4-H   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laine Baze</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goats Inc.   Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emily Blizard</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goats Inc.   FFA   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandy Baze</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiona Benton FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - Leanne Cohenour - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">East Valley FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIVISION 6</ENAMEX> RABBITS   and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CAVIES   Rabbit Fitting & Showing   4-H   Novice   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Lamb</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   Silver - Justin St. John - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grow Em & Show Em</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Banzet</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   Junior   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristen Wedam</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wyatt Baker - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Hall</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Ag & Ec</ENAMEX>.   Intermediate   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Victoria Hall</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Ag & Ec</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noelle Hall</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Ag & Ec</ENAMEX>.   Senior   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helen Shuttleworth</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Ag & Ec</ENAMEX>.   Silver - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Baker - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   Bronze - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amanda Myers</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Baker</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   Rabbit Meat Pen   4-H   Grand Champion - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Toni Adams - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooke Adams - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Grand Champion</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Baker</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   CAVIES   Grand Champion - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Haley Saams</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DIVISION 7 POULTRY   Fitting & Showing   4-H   Novice   Gold</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dannie Jo Kranz</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grow Em & Show Em</ENAMEX>.   Intermediate   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michelle Munck</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   Silver - Sharrae Villanueva - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   Senior   Gold - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tamara ESmart</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Ag & Ec</ENAMEX>.   LIVESTOCK   JUDGING CONTEST   4-H   Junior   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Dezellem</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Nichols</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rylee Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther Hayter - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   5 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Thomas</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Livestock.   5 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Hulse</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermediate   1</ENAMEX> - Chance Graff - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Livestock.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey Dezellem</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darcy Morford</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Nichols</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   5 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mikey Banzet</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Bonny</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joey Higginbotham</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Livestock.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany</ENAMEX> denHoed - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristin Slater</ENAMEX> - Bickleton Hilltoppers.   5 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Baker - Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA Team   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> # 1.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> # 1.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>.   5 - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA Individual   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey Dezellem</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Annie Garland</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellensburg FFA</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristy Andrews</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Zediker</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   5 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie McIntosh</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   DAIRY JUDGING CONTEST   4-H   Junior   1 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maddie Morford</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luke Nichols</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Dezellem</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Dezellem</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermediate   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Freepons</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah Bosma</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Herd & Home</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey Dezellem</ENAMEX> - Horse Heaven Ridge Riders.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Nichols</ENAMEX> - Bar. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">X. Eleven   Senior   1</ENAMEX> - Corrin Veiga - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul Nichols</ENAMEX> - Bar X Eleven.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natasha Daniel</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA   Team   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> # 1.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> # 2.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric LeyenSacher</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katherine Stancliffe</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish FFA</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie Suhadolnik</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   4 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bailey Dezellem</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   4-H HORSE SHOW   Fitting & <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Showing</ENAMEX>   Junior   1 - Tavi Wise.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX>.   3 - Kaylena Murray.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermediate   1</ENAMEX> - Annaka Erickson.   2 - Aissa Wise.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Welch</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kimber Tucker</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Arreola</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Better</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hunt Seatre   Junior Pleasure   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Woodard</ENAMEX>.   2 - Tavi Wise.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermediate Pleasure   1</ENAMEX> - Annaka Erickson.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Welch</ENAMEX>.   3 - Aissa Wise.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Pleasure   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Jo Mackie</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Better</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Bitz Richard</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermediate EQ   1</ENAMEX> - Aissa Wise.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Thomas</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Benjamin Tucker</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior EQ   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Bitz Richard</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Better</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heidi Arreola</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Advanced Jr.</ENAMEX> / <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Int</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EQ   1</ENAMEX> - Annaka Erickson.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Melissa Welch   Advanced Senior EQ   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sammy Jo Mackie</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Courbridge</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kristi Kilgore</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Stock Seat   Junior EQ   1</ENAMEX> - Tavi Wise.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Woodard</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stephanie George</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Intermediate EQ   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Annaka Erickson   2</ENAMEX> - Aissa Wise.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauren Thomas</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior EQ   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jessica Bitz Richard   2</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kimber Tucker   3</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Courbridge   High Point</ENAMEX>   Junior - Tavi Wise.   Intermediate - Aissa Wise.   Senior - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Bitz Richard</ENAMEX>.   Overall <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">High Point Trail   Stephanie George</ENAMEX>.   Round Robin Fitting   and Showing   4-H - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brittany</ENAMEX> denHoed - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pond R Roza Pardners</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandy Baze</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ki-Be FFA</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tractor Driving   4-H Demonstration   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jase Michner</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zach Faulk</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Ag & Ec</ENAMEX>.   3 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lane Baze</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Goats Inc.   FFA Career   Development Event   Team Placing   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> team 2.   2 - Prosser Team 1.   3 - Ki-Be.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Individual Placing   1</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   2 - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter Freepons</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   3 -<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hayter</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser FFA</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

