


<P ID="1">Family embraces challenges on way to achieving dreams
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/16/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Envision it and it will happen. That is the guiding force that drove one local family in achieving their dreams of finishing a college education.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario and Celina Martinez</ENAMEX> were among the graduates <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to earn a degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   But the road to achieving their dream was one filled with twists and turns that made the experience of obtaining a college degree even more rewarding.
</P><P ID="7">   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>, 28, is formerly <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina Garza</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>. And by all rights, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> native wasn't even supposed to have her high school diploma. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> is the first in her family, which also consists of five brothers, to earn a college degree.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>, 29, is from Seattle and is the first in his family of 11 brothers and sisters to receive a college degree.
</P><P ID="9">   Another notable part of the couple's success is that they went to college full-time while raising three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosalina</ENAMEX>, 4; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc</ENAMEX>, 3; and Berlyn, 9 months.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> received a Master's degree in family and consumer science education from Central <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>. She also earned a Bachelor's degree in the same field from Central in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2002</TIMEX>, and also holds a minor in psychology. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> gained an Associate of Arts degree in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Community College</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> is scheduled to teach <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> courses at Central in family and consumer science dealing with relationships/personal development. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> said she became interested in education because she wants to be able to influence people.
</P><P ID="11">   "I just like helping people out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> received his Bachelor's degree in secondary industrial education and will be teaching at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wapato High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> wanted to begin a career in education for similar reasons as his wife. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> said he learned from his father the importance of helping others.
</P><P ID="13">   One might find children as an obstacle to obtaining an education, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> said she never did. One of her children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marc</ENAMEX>, was born during finals weeks and her youngest was both during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> quarter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, but she still managed to keep up her studies.
</P><P ID="14">   "There are a lot of resources out there for parents to tap," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> said through her childhood she learned the value of hard work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> said she decided to pursue an education because she didn't want her family to have to scrap to make a living working in the fields.
</P><P ID="16">   "You have to have a vision," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>. "You also have to be committed to do it."
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> said having three children and continuing an education was a matter of learning to juggle a schedule. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> said there were plenty of times when he was going on a few hours sleep, wondering if he was going to make it through the day. It was during those times he would just look at his children and see them smile to realize everything was going to turn out alright. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> added anything worth attaining in life is going to be difficult and have its obstacles.
</P><P ID="18">   "Those bumps in the road provide greater meaning," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>. "The best investment a person can make is in yourself."
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> said he always knew he was going to earn his college degree, but he took a different road than others. He went to college for a few years, attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Puget Sound and CWU</ENAMEX> before leaving to head back to the Seattle area, where he started a non-profit organization, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Higher Vision Foundation</ENAMEX>, which worked with area high schools on promoting different aspects of education.
</P><P ID="20">   After earning her Associate's degree, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> went to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX> to further her education, but left after a year.
</P><P ID="21">   "I decided I wanted to go experience something else than what was in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> moved to the west side of the state, where she met her husband, and the two have been together ever since, married for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>, like her husband, never doubted she would finish her education.
</P><P ID="23">   "We had to get our education," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> said receiving her Master's degree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> was very meaningful.
</P><P ID="25">   "Education has always been meaningful to me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="26">   Even though she is finished with her classroom education now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> looks at every day as being in the classroom.
</P><P ID="27">   "Learning is a lifelong process," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>. "I am going to keep learning regardless of where I am."
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> also feels a sense of fulfillment in getting his college degree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="29">   "It has been both a marathon and a sprint for me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> believes his degree honors his family, who like his wife's worked in the fields.
</P><P ID="31">   "This degree not only belongs to me, but all of our ancestors," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>. "I am more proud for all of them than myself."
</P><P ID="32">   Mario plans to return to college to earn Master's and Doctorate's degrees.
</P><P ID="33">   "This is just the first step," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="34">   Through all of the past years of hard work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> said the most rewarding part is watching his wife and how she has grown.
</P><P ID="35">   "I know she is not going to stop," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="36">   "He was pretty amazing when I first met him," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX>. "His goals were very high. He is one of the reasons why I am where I am at."
</P><P ID="37">   Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario</ENAMEX> want to encourage people who may think they can't finish their education because they have children or might be too old or think they just can't do it, to reconsider.
</P><P ID="38">   "It has been an adventure," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Said Celina</ENAMEX>. "We have had our ups and downs. We always had that vision in our heads. Follow your dreams. Imagine it happening. Put in the effort."
</P>





 










<P ID="39">Webmaster
</P><P ID="40">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




