


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flory</ENAMEX> wins Mayor's Cup
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Grandview City Councilman Bill Flory won the annual Mayor's Challenge Cup during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> soap box derby race held over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> weekend.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flory</ENAMEX> bested <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> to take top honors in this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>'s race.
</P><P ID="5">   There were also four other divisions in the soap box derby on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robby Reid</ENAMEX> took top honors in the adult division. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Garza</ENAMEX> claimed runner-up honors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Hollmeyer</ENAMEX> was third.
</P><P ID="7">   In the youth red division race, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michele Rae Williams</ENAMEX> claimed the top spot, followed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Lubina</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drew Scheenstra</ENAMEX> rounding out the top three.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vaunce Montelongo</ENAMEX> was the winner of the youth blue division. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Garza</ENAMEX> took second place honors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Montelongo</ENAMEX> was third.
</P><P ID="9">   Earning the top spot in the youth green division was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendra Hollmeyer</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Seeger</ENAMEX> took runner-up honors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Rodriguez</ENAMEX> rounded out the top three.
</P>





 










<P ID="10">Webmaster
</P><P ID="11">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




