
<P ID="1">District enrollment down in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/10/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> saw a notable drop in enrollment in the month of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.   Enrollment counts for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> released at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> meeting had the district housing 5,271 full-time students. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>, the district was home to 5,310 students. Despite the drop in enrollment, the district is still above the projected amount of students it was expecting at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX>, 5,254 pupils.   The district has been having an average enrollment of 5,315 students throughout the school year. The district is well above the enrollment figures it had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2003</TIMEX> of 5,141 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> was the only building in the district to not see a decrease in student enrollment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. The K-4 elementary school had a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> enrollment of 750 students. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pioneer Elementary</ENAMEX> finished <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> counts with 750 pupils. The largest class at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pioneer Elementary</ENAMEX> is the first grade class with 205 students.   The most significant drop in enrollment was at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. High school enrollment dropped from 1,253 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> to 1,235 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. The largest class of students at the high school is the freshman class with 352 students. The senior class has 274 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> had the second biggest drop in enrollment in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> enrollment at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Elementary</ENAMEX> was 828. That figure dropped to 819 students for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. The largest class at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Elementary</ENAMEX> is the first grade group with 211 students.   Enrollment at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> fell from five students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from March to April</TIMEX>. The largest class at PRIDE is the seniors with 57 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> also lost five students from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> enrollment counts, coming in with 597 students in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>. The largest cluster of students at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outlook Elementary</ENAMEX> is the first grade class with 150 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Kamiakin Elementary</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> saw minimal declines in students, with each school losing three pupils from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> enrollment figures.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Kamiakin Elementary</ENAMEX> had an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> enrollment count of 915 students. The fifth grade class is the largest group at the school with 470 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> had an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> enrollment of 805 students. The seventh grade class has the largest enrollment with 406 students.   The first grade class is the biggest group of students in the district, totaling 566. The smallest class in the district is the kindergaretners with 227 students.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

