
<P ID="1">'Heartstrings' releases first CD
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/30/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Gospel singing group, "Heartstrings," has just released its first album on CD and cassette. The title song, "Between His Blood and His Mercy," was written by group member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gwen Lawson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debbie Skinner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robin Abrams</ENAMEX> also sing in the band, making it a family group of sisters playing guitars and singing in harmony. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Lawson</ENAMEX> plays steel guitar and the drummer is Thad White.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Lawson</ENAMEX>, the father to most of the group's members, is also included on the album. He added four songs to the production, including the song, "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> is Everywhere," written by Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1942</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawson</ENAMEX> also performs "Where the Roses Never Fade," "Across the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jordan</ENAMEX>" and "Thank You Lord."   The album was recorded at Rainmaker Studios in the Tri-Cities.   Some true-to-life songs, written by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skinner</ENAMEX>, also appear on the CD, such as "Build a Bridge and Get Over It," "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Angels</ENAMEX> are Watching" and "A Friend for Life." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skinner</ENAMEX>'s tribute to foster parents, entitled "From Your Heart," also appears on the album.   The "Heartstrings" band members say they hope listeners find the album inspirational, "...and it is our hope that it will lift up <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jesus</ENAMEX> and pull on the strings of people's hearts and lives," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skinner</ENAMEX>.   The album is currently available at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Songs</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Praise Christian Book & Bible</ENAMEX>, in both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX> malls.      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morelia</ENAMEX> exhibit opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 13</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX> will debut a new exhibit, "The Traditional Arts of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morelia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s Sister <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX>."   The exhibit will feature a variety of original arts and crafts from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Morelia</ENAMEX>, the capital of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Michoacan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, which also happens to be the sister city to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. The pieces will include ceramics, textiles, wood carving, copperware, ironwork and lacquerware.   The display will remain at the museum through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 6</TIMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> is now home to more than 80,000 residents with roots in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, and many of them have family or cultural ties specifically to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State of Michoacan</ENAMEX>. Several years ago the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Yakima</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Morelia</ENAMEX> became formally associated as sister cities to foster increased friendships, partnerships and understandings across barriers of international borders, language and backgrounds. The exhibit has been organized to encourage knowledge about one aspect of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Michoacan</ENAMEX> culture that is now enriching the Yakima Valley-the handcrafted tradition.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Museum</ENAMEX>, located at 2105 Tieton Drive, is open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday through Saturday</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>, and Sundays from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> Admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.50</NUMEX> for children.      Horse fair, expo returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Albany</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-March</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ALBANY</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - For the fifth year, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Horse Fair & Expo</ENAMEX> returns to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Albany</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, March 18</TIMEX>.   Headlined by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Lyons</ENAMEX> and Clinton Anderson, the event will also have six other leaders in the equine industry offering classes and seminars directed to a variety or riding disciplines and skill levels. There will also be commercial exhibits filling two separate buildings.   The fair and expo opens with a preview seminar on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, featuring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lyons</ENAMEX>. It will be followed with an impressive schedule of educational seminars and demonstrations all day <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 19-21</TIMEX>.   "The Horse Show LIVE!" with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Lamb</ENAMEX> will also be broadcast from the fair all weekend.   Advance tickets are currently available at select <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Allegra</ENAMEX> horse food dealers throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southwest Washington</ENAMEX> and on-line at: contact@coastalfarm.com. One-day tickets are priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX> for children.      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> drama club play to take stage for five-day run   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph</ENAMEX> and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat" will be performed on stage in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-February</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> drama club.   The five-performance run is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 19</TIMEX>, 20, 21, 27 and 28, with the curtain going up all five nights at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Ticket prices are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for senior citizens and students.      'Anything Goes' auditions planned for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - The Toppenish Creek Players will hold auditions for their production of the Bones Porter musical comedy, "Anything Goes," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 2-3</TIMEX>.   Auditions are scheduled those two nights for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish Masonic Temple</ENAMEX> (12 E. Third Ave.).   The director of the stage performance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginny Wells</ENAMEX>, said "Anything Goes" is filled with great music and should have great appeal to the public.   "There are parts for eight women and at least as many men," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>. "It's going to be a fun show to do."   "Anything Goes" will be the Toppenish Creek Players' 12th production, and the third melodrama.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said anyone interested in acting, stage production or just in getting involved in community theater should attend <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>'s auditions. Rehearsals will begin in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early February</TIMEX>, with the show tentatively set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX>, 27 and 28 and for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 3</TIMEX>, 4 and 5 at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakama Heritage Cultural Center Theater</ENAMEX>.      <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> winery presents chocolate and pinot during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Valentine's Day</TIMEX> weekend   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GOLDENDALE</ENAMEX> - The most decadent party of the year is back at Maryhill Winery on State Route 14, near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>.   The winery will host its third annual "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chocolate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pinot</ENAMEX>" party the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 14-16</TIMEX>.   Wine and chocolate lovers are invited to taste chocolates from around the world and be among the first to sample <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX>'s newest Pinot Noir release, a luscious <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> vintage from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Amity</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, area in the heart of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Willamette Valley</ENAMEX> appellation.   In addition to a variety of other award-winning <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Maryhill</ENAMEX> wines to sample with lovers, friends or family, regional entertainer Sandee Marshal will perform live during the event.   Maryhill Winery, perched on the crest of the scenic Columbia Gorge south of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>, is open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>      Beatlemania exhibit debuts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20</TIMEX> in Seattle   SEATTLE - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">2004 marks</NUMEX> the 40th anniversary of an event that upended the way youths listened to music. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX> is the day the Beatles appeared on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan Show</ENAMEX>, and created what was to become known as the British Invasion. In celebration of the Beatles' first trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Experience Music Project</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMP</ENAMEX>) presents Beatlemania! America Meets the Beatles, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>.   The exhibit, with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMP</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jasen Emmons</ENAMEX> as curator, opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 20</TIMEX> and will run through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of 2004</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMP</ENAMEX>'s special exhibit gallery space at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Center</ENAMEX>.   In addition to the show, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMP</ENAMEX> is sponsoring an essay contest for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington State</ENAMEX> high schools students, designed to inspire students to explore the impact of popular music on American culture. Four winners will be featured in the exhibit section about fans.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, no one could have anticipated the long-lasting impact the Beatles would have, not only on rock and roll, but also on fans and the media, merchandise and marketing, and virtually every other aspect of American pop culture. The Fab Four ignited an unprecedented frenzy among teenage fans and helped turn rock 'n' roll into a major business. Beatlemania! celebrates the Beatles and their fans, exploring one of the most influential and popular bands of all time.   "Looking back at the Beatles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1964</TIMEX>, it's interesting to see how anxious they were about whether American fans would care about them," said the exhibit curator, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emmons</ENAMEX>.   "They had no idea just how much they would mean to their fans, or what a profound effect they would have on popular music and culture," he said.   Through rare memorabilia to personal tributes; examples of commercial excess to quirky expressions of fan creativity, Beatlemania! demonstrates the power music has to impact individual lives. Artifacts include Beatles wigs; one of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ringo Starr</ENAMEX>'s collarless suit jackets from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1963</TIMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul McCartney</ENAMEX>'s handwritten set list from a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1962</TIMEX> performance by the Beatles; and a section of wall from the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan Show</ENAMEX> featuring the Beatles' signatures and caricatures.   The exhibit will feature an audio tour with interviews from the band and their fans as well as film footage from the Beatles' performances on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Sullivan Show</ENAMEX>.   In conjunction with the exhibit, educational curriculum is being developed for teachers and students.   For more information on the contest contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wendy Sauer</ENAMEX> at (206) 262-3253.      
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

