


<P ID="1">PRIDE High teacher demonstrates commitment by shaving off his hair
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/16/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">   by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="5">   It's the kind of love story that reminds a person of O'Henry's "Gift of the Magi," a story about a couple's sacrifices to please one another.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Shaffer</ENAMEX> is finding he is not as committed to having a full head of hair as he once was. A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> teacher, he gave up his hair as a gesture of love.
</P><P ID="7">   A personal development teacher, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX> talks about setting goals and making commitments every day to his students. To prove his point, this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Wednesday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX> demonstrated what he means by commitment.
</P><P ID="8">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past October</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX>'s wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dori</ENAMEX>, was diagnosed with an aggressive form of breast cancer. She is fighting the cancer with rounds of chemotherapy and radiation treatments.
</P><P ID="9">   "We always agreed to support each other no matter what, in sickness and health," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   So when his wife started losing her hair to the heavy doses of chemotherapy, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX> felt he needed to demonstrate his love and support in a very visible fashion.
</P><P ID="11">   So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX>, as a real life example of solidarity, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> in the front of his classroom for a session in the barber chair.
</P><P ID="12">   His head of curly gray hair quickly gave way to a smooth, shiny crown. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX> said his wife, who just finished her first round of chemotherapy sessions, will undergo treatment through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   The couple, who have been together 12 years, are finding that a lot of things have changed since her illness.
</P><P ID="14">   "I'm finding myself doing a lot more chores while taking care of her," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="15">   "I plan to keep my head shaved until <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dori</ENAMEX>'s hair all comes back," said the devoted husband.
</P><P ID="16">   While wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dori</ENAMEX> isn't very fond of her hair loss, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shaffer</ENAMEX> said he likes his new look.
</P><P ID="17">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dori</ENAMEX> can't wait for her hair to grow back, but I think I may keep my bald head. It sure is easy to take care of," he laughed.
</P><P ID="18">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="19">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




