


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> presidency
</P>

<P ID="5">I was catching up on the newspapers over the weekend and read "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Open Mike</ENAMEX>" (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6-2-04</TIMEX>), titled "Was life really that bad with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bill</ENAMEX> as president?" I thought that perhaps this was a joke, so I read his personal column. Maybe that is all <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> wanted to happen, was to get readers and start controversy. Our upcoming presidential election is not a joke, and yes, living under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> was bad. Being leader of the free world is not just a "gig to play."
</P>

<P ID="6">I did not enjoy the decision of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>. Does anyone remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gore</ENAMEX> had called and conceded the election? I do. For the sake of the system and country, he should have stood by his word, but instead the Democrats hoped for the usual victory in the courts.
</P>

<P ID="7">This brings me to one of many reasons to take this election seriously. It is the issue of tyranny of the judiciary. Certain appointed (not elected) federal judges are sending down decisions unraveling the fabric of our country. All it takes is one judge to take "Under God" out of our pledge of allegiance, halt the passed and signed partial birth abortion ban and mandate same sex marriage. It does not make news, but the Democrats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> have obstructed many of President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>'s nominees for federal judgeships.
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike</ENAMEX> asks, "Why not give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary</ENAMEX> a chance?"
</P>

<P ID="9">That, indeed, is scary. There are plenty of books on the market delineating how power hungry this woman is. In this terror-torn world, if ever she were elected, I would fear it would be our last free election.
</P>

<P ID="10">Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX>'s statement about not being better off under <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is simply not true. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is standing tall against the terrorist. He has kept us safe! He is restoring respect for the office of Presidency. He actually knows the difference between good and evil, and calling us as a nation to stand for good.
</P>

<P ID="11">Yes, I am sorry, that includes morality. A good leader stands up against terrorists, protects the unborn and the innocent, and reveres God. We had none of that under the not so good times under <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bill</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">In addition, I dare say we would not have good leadership under <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kerry</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">In reality, it is the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pannis</ENAMEX> of our country who will decide the election—the swing voter. The <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> of registered voters who are undecided and vote but who really aren't informed, do not care and think it is a joke or really doesn't matter. However, their vote will count, as evidenced in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="14">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Deon Herndon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 






 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




