


<P ID="1">Parents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> candidates upset
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/12/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">MABTON - While technically the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton City Council</ENAMEX> has no jurisdiction over Mabton Community Days and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> Mabton Pageant activities, parents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> candidates found themselves in front of the council <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>) with a laundry list of complaints.
</P><P ID="5">   The room was divided by those who had complaints about pageant director <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Ruelas</ENAMEX>' handling of pre-pageant activities and those who support her volunteer efforts.
</P><P ID="6">   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> chambers is the only public forum they have available to them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ildia Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton City</ENAMEX> Administrator.
</P><P ID="7">   "Technically, we have no say in the pageant program as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> don't give it any type of financial support. All support for the pageant is generated by the candidates under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX>," she explained.
</P><P ID="8">   Nevertheless, the candidates' parents voiced questions about the lack of advance planning and communication between them and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX>, who is in her second year as the pageant coordinator.
</P><P ID="9">   Saying there ought to be more communication with the parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Bonewell</ENAMEX>, the father of one of the candidates, said he was concerned about the negative impression the candidates are receiving about the program. "This no way to run a program," he said.
</P><P ID="10">   He said parents were not being kept informed of the activities required of the candidates. "We as parents are not allowed to help out and when we step forward to help, we are shouted down," he said.
</P><P ID="11">   As part of their pre-pageant activities candidates are asked to help raise funds via car washes and bake sales, in addition to attending area parades.
</P><P ID="12">   "That's all well and good, but we need more advance notice," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonewell</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   He was upset with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX>, who apparently became upset when his wife offered to help register the girls for an appearance in the recent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Cinco De Mayo Parade.
</P><P ID="14">   "But we had all agreed not to participate in the parade, because it was on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Mother's Day</TIMEX>," offered <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   "Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bonewell</ENAMEX> went ahead and registered them anyway without consulting me," she said.
</P><P ID="16">   "We can't have every parent scheduling the girls' time for things without my clearance," she explained.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Beltran</ENAMEX>, the mother of the current <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, said she also became concerned when her daughter was left out of recent parade activities.
</P><P ID="18">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sofie</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beltran</ENAMEX>) wasn't even invited," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beltran</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="19">   "We've not been invited to participate in any of the parades, but the candidates were," she said.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Sanchez</ENAMEX>, whose daughter is currently seeking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> crown, said her daughter was not notified of changes in the schedule, which includes pageant rehearsals, parades and fund-raisers.
</P><P ID="21">   "She had to find out from the other candidates, and that is not right," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> added.
</P><P ID="22">   "I hope this is not how everything is going to go for her," she said.
</P><P ID="23">   "I'd just like to know what is going on," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX> said she heard <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> that there was a move afoot to have her removed as the pageant director. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX> stressed she has no thought of stepping down at this time.
</P><P ID="25">   "I plan to go ahead with our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 11</TIMEX> pageant," she said.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX> said as the pageant coordinator, all activities involving the candidates must be cleared through her before they can participate in events.
</P><P ID="27">   "That rule is understood before we start, but apparently not by all parents," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX>, who only recently began preparing the five <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> girls for the pageant, said she has attempted to contact all of the candidates.
</P><P ID="29">   "I admit there has been difficulties with the communication, but as far as advance scheduling goes, sometimes events pop up quickly and we have to jump on the chance to participate in car washes or bake sales," she said.
</P><P ID="30">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Conradt</ENAMEX> said there wasn't anything the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> could do to solve the parents and pageant coordinator's problems.
</P><P ID="31">   "You'll have to work out these issues among yourselves," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Conradt</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="32">   "We are not trying to make light of your concerns. But our job is to pass laws and manage the city budget, not intervene in these types of disputes," he said.
</P><P ID="33">   At this point <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX> said she plans to proceed with the pageant, to be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX> gym.
</P>   






 










<P ID="34">Webmaster
</P><P ID="35">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




