
<P ID="1">Weekly Bowling Report
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/6/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
</P> 
 
<P ID="4">Valley LanesWeek #22
Early Birds
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-27-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Ewart</ENAMEX> 480 (178), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Duim</ENAMEX> 476 (171), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marla Campbell</ENAMEX> 463 (183), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Moomey</ENAMEX> 455 (161). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Holman</ENAMEX> +62. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 169. LL: Valley Lanes 15-9.
Sunny Valley Women
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-27-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Cromwell</ENAMEX> 643 (206-256), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deania Guy</ENAMEX> 567 (200), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcy Carl</ENAMEX> 560 (204-212), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Dawson</ENAMEX> 502 (212). High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christie Cromwell</ENAMEX> 194. LL: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banner Bank</ENAMEX> 14.5-9.5.
Late Ladies
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-27-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Dorsey</ENAMEX> 554 (205), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Dorsey</ENAMEX> 513 (187), Krisi Schooley 489 (199), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Patton</ENAMEX> 488 (183). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Dorsey</ENAMEX> +65. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Debra Brandmire</ENAMEX> 201. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janice Dorsey</ENAMEX> 169. LL: 10-4 Cafe 100-25.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> Mixers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-28-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Van Boven</ENAMEX> 618 (201-227), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charlie Tilley</ENAMEX> 524 (179), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Phillips</ENAMEX> 523 (190). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Robinson</ENAMEX> +71. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deania Guy</ENAMEX> 533 (183), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanne Bruinekool</ENAMEX> 510 (181), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tina Lopez</ENAMEX> 498 (201). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denise Williams</ENAMEX> +56. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Rice</ENAMEX> 224. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 169. LL: Pinbusters 22-14.
Inter-City
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-28-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 676 (268-218), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frank</ENAMEX> 669 (257-217), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Myers</ENAMEX> 625 (245-223), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 621 (243-213). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frank</ENAMEX> +87. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> 267, Swede <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dixon</ENAMEX> 231, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Puyear</ENAMEX> 224, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Berg</ENAMEX> 222. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 225. LL: <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bieber Bros.</ENAMEX> 172-98.
Coffee Trio
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-29-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty Moomey</ENAMEX> 559 (202), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Ewart</ENAMEX> 510 (177), Teny Heintz 504 (187), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Brown</ENAMEX> 492 (181). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jacquie Kovatovh</ENAMEX> +70. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 176. LL: 410 Market 7-1.
Commercial
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-29-04</TIMEX>
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mitoff</ENAMEX> 714 (234-245-235), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Poteet</ENAMEX> 673 (244-225-204), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Huth</ENAMEX> 669 (212-218-239), Brad Morrow 658 (211-236-211). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mitoff</ENAMEX> +114. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hill</ENAMEX> 267, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX> 257, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mashburn</ENAMEX> 257, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Peton</ENAMEX> 240, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Stegeman</ENAMEX> 235, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Story</ENAMEX> 232, Rayburn Borden 226, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Ulmer</ENAMEX> 226, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Hill</ENAMEX> 225, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoff Bowlsby</ENAMEX> 225, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Seifert</ENAMEX> 224, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hector Fonseca Jr.</ENAMEX> 221, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> 220. High average: Brad Morrow 210. LL: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Les Schwab Tires</ENAMEX> 192.5-77.5.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> Fun Bunch
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-30-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph LaClair</ENAMEX> 667 (236-238), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Haggerty</ENAMEX> 614 (246), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute Jr.</ENAMEX> 612 (211-224). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Olney</ENAMEX> +93. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 653 (201-258), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nadine Compo</ENAMEX> 509 (191), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine Sheets</ENAMEX> 454 (170). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Wilson</ENAMEX> +110. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gress</ENAMEX> 224, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecil Compo</ENAMEX> 221. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Haggerty</ENAMEX> 206. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 200. LL: Beer Dogs 27-17.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Preps & Bantams</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-31-04</TIMEX>
High boys series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Rice</ENAMEX> 482 (171), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andre Sarmiento</ENAMEX> 384 (139), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frankie Lopez</ENAMEX> 375 (136). Highest boys series over average: Primo Vargas +132. High girls series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Cruz</ENAMEX> 388 (155), Jadelynn Howard 376 (133), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leann Lopez</ENAMEX> 243 (103). Highest girls series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennifer Cruz</ENAMEX> +97. High boys average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Rice</ENAMEX> 128. High girls average: Jadelynn Howard 123. LL: 3 Muskateers 22-2.
Jrs. & Majors
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1-31-04</TIMEX>
High boys series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane Huth</ENAMEX> 667 (208-234-225), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Schaneman</ENAMEX> 608 (245), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Bieber</ENAMEX> 530 (209). Highest boys series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shane Huth</ENAMEX> +172. High girls series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Huth</ENAMEX> 515 (200), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Courtney Rice</ENAMEX> 463 (169), Aleshia Langworthy 392 (135). Highest girls series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenna Thomas</ENAMEX> +59. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Kilthau</ENAMEX> 211, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Huth</ENAMEX> 203. High boys average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Schaneman</ENAMEX> 202. High girls average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Cruz</ENAMEX> 159. LL: Team #8 92.5-57.5.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> Mixers
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-1-04</TIMEX>
High men's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hill</ENAMEX> 725 (260-202-263), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 719 (251-245-223), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 710 (227-224-259). Highest men's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Hill</ENAMEX> +149. High women's series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cruz</ENAMEX> 649 (255-201), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Rice</ENAMEX> 568 (214), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darlene Orr</ENAMEX> 503 (193), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Lallashute</ENAMEX> 503 (185). Highest women's series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cruz</ENAMEX> +112. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps</ENAMEX> 244, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Bieber</ENAMEX> 236, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabe Rodriguez</ENAMEX> 235, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute</ENAMEX> 225, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deania Guy</ENAMEX> 202. High men's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rob Rice</ENAMEX> 222. High women's average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cruz</ENAMEX> 180. LL: H&H Auto Glass 31.5-12.5.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Scratch
(5 games)
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2-2-04</TIMEX>)
High series: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Alvarez</ENAMEX> 1177 (220-203-257-249-248), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Curtiss</ENAMEX> 1157 (279-214-224-213-227), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frank</ENAMEX> 1147 (247-215-246-238-201), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Curt Poteet</ENAMEX> 1136 (225-248-238-228). Highest series over average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick Frank</ENAMEX> +172. Single game highlights: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Burton</ENAMEX> 279, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX> 269, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 267, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph LaClair</ENAMEX> 258, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Haynes</ENAMEX> 257, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Van Boven</ENAMEX> 253, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Huth</ENAMEX> 246, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">Sr. 244</NUMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Guy</ENAMEX> 240, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Snavely</ENAMEX> 239, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kim Smartlowit</ENAMEX> 237, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Virgil Lallashute Jr.</ENAMEX> 230, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corey Guy</ENAMEX> 229, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Butch Covel</ENAMEX> 228, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Mitoff</ENAMEX> 225, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Hicks</ENAMEX> 225, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andy Abrams</ENAMEX> 224, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Guy</ENAMEX> 223, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Corbus</ENAMEX> 220, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha LaClair</ENAMEX> 216. High average: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Cruz</ENAMEX> 221. LL: HAD 200.5-129.5.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

