
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Farm families offered help
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> has been designated as a natural disaster area based on damages and losses caused by adverse weather conditions during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23, 2003 through Jan. 8, 2004</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lisa M. Ruff</ENAMEX>, farm loan manager of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Farm Service Agency</ENAMEX>, said that family farmers who suffered losses as a result of the weather during that time frame may qualify for emergency loans. The loans carry a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.75 percent</NUMEX> interest rate and payment terms can extend up to 40 years.
Loan application forms are available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Service Agency</ENAMEX> office in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> (1606 Perry St., Suite A).
</P> 
<P ID="4">Grandview poolto close <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 21</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The Grandview municipal swimming pool will close for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> season <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 21</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">County-wideburn ban in effect
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Regional Clean Air Authority</ENAMEX> officials have called for a county-wide burn ban.
The reason—smoke from forest fires, high temperatures and stagnant air conditions are impacting the air quality. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Clean Air Authority</ENAMEX> expects air pollution to continue to build.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> officials said there is no determination on when the air quality will return to a condition where outdoor and agricultural burning will be allowed.
People with lung and breathing problems are cautioned to monitor the air quality when making decisions for outdoor activities.
The burn ban that has been put into effect applies to all otherwise permitted or unpermitted burning. Recreational fires are also banned, although the use of propane or gaseous appliances for cooking is allowed.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

