
<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SAM BOSTAPH   Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. will soon begin construction of a new taxpayer-funded baseball stadium at an estimated cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$400 million</NUMEX>, give or take <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50 million</NUMEX>. Thirty-three years after the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX></ENAMEX> left town to become the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX>, a majority vote of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. city council will fill the vacancy by providing the former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Montreal Expos</ENAMEX> the stadium that Montreal voters denied them. Touting the project, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Williams</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> claims that the revenue bonds that will be issued to build the stadium will be paid off completely by a lease payment of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15 million</NUMEX> a year, by taxes on facility revenues, and by socking large businesses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. with a new tax.   Coincidentally, about two and a half hours away by air is <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, home of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">former Senators</ENAMEX>, now the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Rangers</ENAMEX>, and the scene of another new stadium proposal. Local voters are being urged to approve a similar deal to build a football stadium to house the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dallas Cowboys</ENAMEX> just next door to the existing <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Rangers</ENAMEX>' stadium. The subsidy request comes from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Wells</ENAMEX>, the owner of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Cowboys</ENAMEX>.   The requested <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arlington-taxpayer</ENAMEX> subsidy is estimated by the city's treasury manager to be about <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600 million</NUMEX>, including interest. New taxes are necessary to get the money. Local politicians in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX> are trying to sell the deal to voters with the same promises <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>. officials made: lease payments to the city, jobs, redevelopment of surrounding areas, and higher revenues to local businesses. The job and multi-million-dollar local-business revenue projections all come from a study, funded by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Cowboys</ENAMEX>, that treats every dollar of revenue and every job created as new. This ignores the fact that since the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> stadium will be only a few miles away from the old one, current workers at the stadium will not have to move their homes or their spending and that construction employees will only be temporary. Also, the revenue projections are based on projections of future game attendance and other uses of the stadium that could easily prove wrong, and they ignore the "distribution effect" money spent on game attendance is money not spent on other entertainment and recreation.   What about the lease payment? In contrast to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>., the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX> will receive an insultingly meager <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2 million</NUMEX> a year in rental fees and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of the money paid for the naming rights to the stadium, up to a ceiling of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$500,000</NUMEX> annually. Obviously, the total won't even cover the interest payment on the bonds. Taxpayers will be out the principal and most of the interest. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> has offered to throw in another <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16.5 million</NUMEX> for "youth programs," to pay the local school district the revenue it would lose from any private property seized by the city for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>'s use, and to bribe local minority groups with discriminatory minority set-asides.   If the proposed stadium subsidy is not a shrewd investment opportunity for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX>, then what is it? Economists refer to such programs as "transfer programs" or, more honestly, "business welfare" programs. Money is taken from taxpayers, and real property is condemned, so that it can be transferred to those held in higher favor by public officials. In a word, thievery. This is most blatant in the plans to seize the property of those living south of the proposed building site. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> and local politicians propose to milk taxpayers and steal property to benefit <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>, subsidize football fans, favor businesses near the stadium, and provide local politicians with another costly monument to boosterism next to the one that was built for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX>.   The same sorts of promises that were made to voters to build <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX>' stadium are being made once again. In the case of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rangers</ENAMEX>, the results failed to match the hype. The stimulus to land development around the park failed to materialize and the park itself sits empty most of the year.   There is one substantive difference between the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>., situation and that in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">D.C</ENAMEX>., voters replaced three pro-ballpark council members with three opposed to the scheme; but the new members don't take office until after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 31</TIMEX>. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Williams</ENAMEX> and the majority of the old council are rushing to approve the issuance of revenue bonds before then in an end run around voters. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Arlington</ENAMEX> council occupies a higher ground. The proposal itself was put to voters on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2</TIMEX>. Lacking their approval, the deal is dead in the water. It should be.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel Bostaph</ENAMEX> is head of the economics department at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Dallas</ENAMEX> and an academic advisor to The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Future</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Freedom Foundation</ENAMEX> (www.fff.org).   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

