


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> exchange sharp words at meeting
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/20/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> put a stern halt this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to a war of words that seemed to be getting out of hand between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Angel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, brother-in-law of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>, by the time it was all said and done, ended up being escorted from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> chambers by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police</ENAMEX> Captain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Bank</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The fuse was lit for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> perhaps early in the evening.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> stepped to the podium to offer comments on a proposal of censure for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members, which was proposed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. But before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> could offer his comments on the matter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to close public input and put the matter, which in this case was the censure resolution, to a vote. Despite trying to offer his comments, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> would not hear from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, telling him to have a seat because he was out of order.
</P><P ID="8">   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> didn't go away. He reappeared during the unscheduled appearances by citizens portion of the agenda.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>'s comments started off innocently enough, as he asked for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to consider a resolution that would provide city staff with a paid holiday for Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Luther King Jr. Day</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said he felt the city should recognize the day, honoring the efforts of King.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> then turned his attention to the motion of censure, narrowly passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> earlier in the meeting.
</P><P ID="11">   "The amendment that was approved tonight was mean spirited," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> voiced his objections to not being allowed to be heard earlier by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> on the matter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> questioned the ideals of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in calling for the question on a resolution when not all of the public had been allowed to provide input.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> then turned his scrutiny to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> questioned the reason why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> proposed the resolution of censure and then left town for two weeks, not being able to meet with any constituents until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> accused <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> of running away from the situation.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> countered by saying he has never run away from anything in his life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> jabbed back, saying <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> was run out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> used to be a sheriff.
</P><P ID="15">   The mayor then demanded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> sit down after his comments. But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> interjected and pointed directly at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> in a heated exchange, saying he wasn't going to accept anyone questioning his integrity. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> rose up out of his seat and exchanged some words with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> again, at which point the mayor had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> escort <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> out of chambers. Before he left, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> apologized to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> for being out of order.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Partida</ENAMEX> expressed her disappointment with what she saw take place in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> chambers.
</P><P ID="17">   "You were voted to be the public. You were voted to be the best person," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Partida</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. "I did not see that here tonight. I am embarrassed not only for myself, but for you."
</P><P ID="18">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




