


<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/23/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">14th annual cheese festival opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">As part of the annual Spring Barrel Tasting weekend, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Dairy Women will host the 14th annual Washington State Cheese Festival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">Area residents and visitors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> this weekend—April 23-25—are invited to taste state and specialty cheeses, as well as enjoy delicious cheesecake at the event.
</P>

<P ID="7">The site of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s cheese festival will again be at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker Cellars</ENAMEX>, located at 70 Ray Rd. and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 


<P ID="8">Juried art show
set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4-28</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Association</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gallery</ENAMEX> will present the annual juried show regional exhibition <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4-28</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10">Many artists from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX> sent slides of their works in hopes of being selected for participation, but only the juror of the show will select which pieces will be exhibited. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s juror is Rie Palkovic.
</P>

<P ID="11">She holds a Master's of fine arts degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mexico State University</ENAMEX>. She is the department head at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Big Bend Community College</ENAMEX>. Currently, Palkovic teaches studio and lecture classes in art. She has received numerous awards in many solo and group exhibitions throughout the country.
</P>

<P ID="12">A public reception for the show is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, May 9</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Gallery</ENAMEX>, located at the entrance to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Howard Amon Park</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, 89 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Blvd.</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WrestleMania</ENAMEX> event headed
to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 15</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWE RAW WrestleMania</ENAMEX> competition will be staged at the Yakima SunDome <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 15</TIMEX>. Tickets go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 24</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley SunDome box office.
</P>

<P ID="15">Promoters are hoping to entice the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WWE</ENAMEX> faithful with a star studded line-up. Scheduled to appear are world champion <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Benoit</ENAMEX>, world tag team champions <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ric Flair</ENAMEX> and Batista, Edge, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Jericho</ENAMEX>, Christian, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trish Stratus</ENAMEX>, intercontinental champion <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Randy Orton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shelton Benjamin</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Hardy</ENAMEX>, general manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Bischoff</ENAMEX>, The Hurricane and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lita</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16">Ticket prices start at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20.50</NUMEX>, with the luxury seats retailing for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$45.50</NUMEX>. Besides the SunDome box office, tickets will also be available at all Ticketswest outlets, at the Red Lion at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gateway Center Hotel</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, by calling 1-800-325-7328 or on-line at www.ticketswest.com.
</P>

 


<P ID="17">Titanic exhibit
to be showcased
at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX> museum
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PORTLAND</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 29</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon Museum of Science and Industry</ENAMEX> will open a new exhibit entitled "Titanic Science: the Real Artificats, the True Stories."
</P>

<P ID="19">The 8,000 square foot exhibit, which will be showcased through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> months, combines real scientific findings with actual artifacts, creating a powerful educational experience. The highly interactive exhibit, sponsored locally by Comcast, will take visitors through an exploration of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 15, 1912</TIMEX> disaster and the emotional journey that resulted in the loss of more than 1,500 lives.
</P>

<P ID="20">Visitors will also get the chance to see the Titanic live. Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Ballard</ENAMEX>, the scientist who discovered the Titanic's final resting place in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> off the coast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Newfoundland</ENAMEX>, will be revisiting the ship in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> to conduct research. Visitors to the museum can watch live satellite broadcasts from the Titanic <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 4</TIMEX>, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 9</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> in the museum's auditorium. Viewers will see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ballard</ENAMEX> and his team studying the effects of deterioration from natural and human forces on the famous shipwreck.
</P>

<P ID="21"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, May 28</TIMEX>, the museum will open Titanica at its Omnimax Theater. Viewers will be invited to experience the Titanic life-size on the giant screen as Titanica takes audiences on an adventure of discovery to the site of the world's most famous shipwreck. Images of the Titanic as she now lies on the ocean floor are contrasted with well preserved archival photographs of the ship in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1912</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="22">Admission to the museum, located at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1945</TIMEX> SE Water Ave. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.50</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.50</NUMEX> for children and senior citizens. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Summer</TIMEX> hours are <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> daily.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




