37 35 21 50 32 31
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  If you are distressed by anything external, the pain is not due to the thing itself, but to your estimate of it; and this you have the power to revoke at any moment.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marcus Aurelius Antoninus</ENAMEX> (121 AD - 180 AD)
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>