
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/27/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> egg train pulls out of station <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 11</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">HOOD RIVER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - Box Car Bunny, with a basketful of goodies, will be the featured attraction on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood Railroad</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> egg train that is scheduled to leave the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood River</ENAMEX> station <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, April 11</TIMEX>.
The 44-mile round-trip ride, to begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX>, will begin in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood River</ENAMEX> and continue through thousands of acres of dramatic, colorful fruit tree blossoms in the region's many orchards. The turn-around point will be the quaint town of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Parkdale</ENAMEX>, at the foot of majestic <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood</ENAMEX>.
Once in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Parkdale</ENAMEX>, children aboard the train will be treated to an <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> egg hunt at the city park.  During the return trip, children will receive <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Easter</TIMEX> goodies. The train will arrive back in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hood River</ENAMEX> at about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:15 p.m.</TIMEX>
The 98-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Hood Railroad</ENAMEX> is designated as an historic site by the National Register of Historic Places. The railway company has been in continuous operation since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1906</TIMEX> as a freight carrier, and has carried passengers since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>.
Tickets for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 11</TIMEX> excursion, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25.50</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$17.50</NUMEX> for children, are available by calling 1-800-872-4661.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GHS</ENAMEX> crab feed slated for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The fourth annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School FFA</ENAMEX>/DECA crab feed, open to the public, is scheduled for this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 29</TIMEX>.
The 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> dinner fund-raiser will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> cafeteria. Tickets, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> for senior citizens, are available from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview FFA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DECA Club</ENAMEX> members. Some tickets will also be available at the door <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">‘Heartstrings’in concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - The Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Gospel</ENAMEX> singing group, "Heartstrings," will be in concert at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Church</ENAMEX> of God this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 29</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
The group's recently released first album, on CD's and cassettes, will be available for purchase at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s concert.
All <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents are invited to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 29</TIMEX> concert at the Prosser church, located at 1332 Meade Ave.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Kinderkoncertto be stagedat Capitol Theatre
YAKIMA - The Yakima Youth Symphony Orchestra will present its annual Kinderkoncert event <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 7</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>'s Capitol Theatre.
Kinderkoncert will feature performances by the youth orchestra, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Alexander</ENAMEX>. The group consists of more than 50 students from throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.
The musical event is billed as a special program for children and their families, and attracts patrons of all ages who enjoy listening to great music. Musicial selections are made especially with the young listener in mind.
The theme for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s program will be "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wolf</ENAMEX>." The "Radetzky <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX>," by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">J. Strauss Sr.</ENAMEX>, will also be performed.
Following the program, the audience will have the opportunity to meet with the musicians.
Because of a donation from Target stores, organizers are able to present <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s concert free of charge, although donations will be accepted at the door.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Buddhists</ENAMEX> host spring dinner
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WAPATO</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wapato Buddhist Church</ENAMEX> will host its 43rd annual sukiyaki dinner <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 7</TIMEX>, at the Buddhist hall, 212 W. Second Street, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>. Dinner will be served from 1:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$9</NUMEX> per person and will be available at the door.
</P> 
<P ID="8">‘Guys and Dolls’ tickets go           on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reserve</ENAMEX> tickets will go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 1</TIMEX>, for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Theater Company</ENAMEX> production of Guys and Dolls.
Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> for senior citizens and students.
Guys and Dolls opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19</TIMEX>, with additional performances set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>, 26 and 27, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, March 21</TIMEX>, matinee at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX>
All performances will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High school auditorium.
Tickets will be  on sale at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, the Grandview Safeway store and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>'s Elfers-Lyons Pharmacy.
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

