


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LORNA RUTH (WADDELL) GRAF</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LORNA RUTH (WADDELL) GRAF</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorna Ruth (Waddell) Graf</ENAMEX>, 48, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 15, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Crescent Convalescent Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">She was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 6, 1956</TIMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loren Paul Waddell Sr.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louella</ENAMEX> “Irene” (Pilcher) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddell</ENAMEX>. She graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> and was on the Dean’s list at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorna</ENAMEX> is survived by her daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laural Graf</ENAMEX>; and siblings, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">St. Clair</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodworth</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Korevaar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loren</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leah</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX>) Schaneman and Avon Jones.
</P>

<P ID="8">She was preceded in death by her parents; and son.
</P>

<P ID="9">Visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 17, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. A memorial service is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 20, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Timothy’s Episcopal Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>. A private family graveside service will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 18, 2004</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Jones Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

<P ID="10">Memorials may be made to HDSA NW Chapter, PO Box 33345, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Seattle</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98133. Please designate it to be used for research.
</P>

 


<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CHARLES EDWARD SHOCKLEY</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Edward Shockley</ENAMEX>, 92, a resident of Mill Creek Point Assisted Living Home in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 13, 2004</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shockley</ENAMEX> was born in Outlook on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 10, 1912</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George William Shockley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dora Ellen Partch Shockley</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="14">He began his education at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Independence School</ENAMEX> near the family farm in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">eastern Washington</ENAMEX>. He entered the fifth grade at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook School</ENAMEX> and graduated from high school in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>, followed by attendance at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hemphill Diesel Engineering School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shockley</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Lorraine Hill</ENAMEX> and began his career as an auto mechanic and owner of a service station in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sumner</ENAMEX>. During World War II he worked for Boeing Aircraft. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1944</TIMEX>, he and his family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>, where he worked as a mechanic servicing trucks for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meadowsweet Dairy, Inc.</ENAMEX> He married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viola</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hermann</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dickson</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1961</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16">He is survived by his daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deanna Lee Meyers</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Everett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Jean Strom</ENAMEX> and husband, (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Howard</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peggy Ann Adamich</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port Angeles</ENAMEX>; eight grandchildren; nine great-grandchildren; and one great-great-grandson.
</P>

<P ID="17">He was preceded in death by his wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Viola</ENAMEX>; his brothers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Shockley</ENAMEX>; and one grandson.
</P>

<P ID="18">Private family graveside services were held in The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalles</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ore. Spencer Libby</ENAMEX> and Powell Funeral Home of The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dalles Ore.</ENAMEX>, was in charge of arrangements.
</P>

<P ID="19">Memorials may be made to “Make A Wish Foundation” or the charity of your choice.
</P>

 


<P ID="20">MARGARET MAY <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">BOLIN EDES</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Edes</ENAMEX>, 90, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> went to be with her Lord <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 15, 2004</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor Nursing Home.
</P>

<P ID="22"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nampa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>. She graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Nampa High School</ENAMEX> and attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Nazarene College</ENAMEX>. During World War II she worked in civil service in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley Edes</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lamberton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minn.</ENAMEX> She has resided in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1966</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="23">She was a dedicated wife of 61 years and loving mother. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of Nazarene and served as church treasurer many years. She loved to play the piano and sing hymns. She enjoyed kittens, reading, The Art Linkletter Show and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Welk</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> most enjoyed giving loving, nurturing care to her grandchildren.
</P>

<P ID="24"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret</ENAMEX> is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wesley</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> and wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Audrey</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carolyn (Edes) Larson</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernie</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. She is also survived by two foster children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teana (Rector) Vannieuwenhuizen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger and Allen Carpenter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>; 10 grandchildren; and two great-grandchildren.
</P>

<P ID="25">A memorial service will be held in her honor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 19, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at Jones Funeral Home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="26">In remembrance of Margaret’s generous spirit, her family asks that you make a donation in her honor to The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gideon’s International</ENAMEX>, PO Box 1225, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 98944.
</P>

 


<P ID="27"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">RUTH MARIE (KRON) CULP HUNTER</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="28">Our dear <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Marie (Kron) Culp Hunter</ENAMEX>, 78, of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX> left us to join our Lord <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 16, 2004</TIMEX>, after her battle with cancer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> was born to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ernest R.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizzie Kron</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19, 1926</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Loup City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neb.</ENAMEX> A twin sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Mae</ENAMEX> died as a two-year-old. The family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> graduated from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland High School</ENAMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> closed school in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1943</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="29">She married a Richland friend, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Culp</ENAMEX>, who served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1943</TIMEX>. They were married for just two short weeks when his ship was one of three lost in a typhoon at sea.
</P>

<P ID="30">She later met and married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Wilbur Hunter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 8, 1946</TIMEX>, and when their first child, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Marie</ENAMEX> was just six-weeks-old they moved back to a farm in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. Two other children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Ralph</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Lee</ENAMEX> blessed their marriage.
</P>

<P ID="31">Her life was devoted to family and friends alike. She loved helping others and enjoyed attending all the sporting events with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> throughout the many years both sons played football, baseball, basketball or softball. She herself loved bowling and did so until becoming ill in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June of this year</TIMEX>. She worked the farm alongside <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph</ENAMEX> and also as a school cook in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="32"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth</ENAMEX> is survived by her family, daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Bruns</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>; son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steven Hunter</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy</ENAMEX>) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermiston</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>; and son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Hunter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; her grandchildren <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhonda Hutton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robyn Neumeyer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler and Trevor Hunter</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>; and her precious <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">great-granddaughter Morgan Hutton</ENAMEX>, also of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Yakima</ENAMEX>. She is also survived by her brothers and sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Kron</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anna Hunter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Velma</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culp</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott</ENAMEX>; and numerous nieces and nephews and friends.
</P>

<P ID="33">She was preceded in death by both parents, E.T. and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lizzie Kron</ENAMEX>; husbands, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donald Culp</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Hunter</ENAMEX>, her twin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Mae</ENAMEX> and sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hazel Books</ENAMEX>, as well as other loved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hunter</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kron</ENAMEX> family members.
</P>

<P ID="34">Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 22, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. In lieu of flowers those wishing to honor her memory may contribute to the Yakima Memorial Hospice or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immanuel Lutheran Church</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="35">Webmaster
</P><P ID="36">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




