


<P ID="1">Racers gather in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> looking to earn top honors
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Nearly 30 people participated in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s annual soapbox derby race, which took place this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The crisp, fall morning was filled with excitement as people from throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> came together to test which of the myriad of different soapbox derby racers would come out on top.
</P><P ID="6">   The 22 cars entered in the five different race divisions each took their turn racing down <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Road</ENAMEX> along the edge of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   Taking home awards from the local soapbox derby was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview City Councilman Bill Flory</ENAMEX>, who beat out <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> in the Celebrity 500 division to earn first place honors. In the corporate division, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Hollmeyer</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hollmeyer Farms</ENAMEX> earned first place honors. In the adult division, the Hollmeyers dominated with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Hollmeyer</ENAMEX> earning first place honors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheri Hollmeyer</ENAMEX> coming in second. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Garza</ENAMEX> rounded out the top three in that division. In the youth green division, which featured the faster youth competitors, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendra Hollmeyer</ENAMEX> finished in first place, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kennedy Sarmiento</ENAMEX> finished in second place and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Rodriguez</ENAMEX> took third place. In the youth blue division first place honors went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Briana Nettles-Biggs</ENAMEX>, second place went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marissa Leigh Boob</ENAMEX> and third place went to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Garza</ENAMEX>. The best of show award went to 12-year-old Bones Still, who was driving the Patriot.
</P>





 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




