


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tejano</ENAMEX> music promoters apologize to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">G'view Council</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Tino Patina and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruby Carbajal</ENAMEX>, board members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Tejano Music Association</ENAMEX>, publicly apologized to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, two days after one of their concerts got out of hand.
</P><P ID="5">   The concert was held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s Country Park Stage. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Robert Morales</ENAMEX>, who had been notified of the incident first, brought the issue to the city council at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s study session. But Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX> said that a formal statement by the Tejano music group would be made at the regular city council meeting, which followed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s study session. Most of the city council members were unaware of the incident, and didn't even know the park had been rented for the event.
</P><P ID="6">   Patina, who is the president of the Tejano group, apologized to the councilmen, saying the association is embarrassed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s events. He added that they should have had a tighter rein on the concert activities.
</P><P ID="7">   The concert, which featured young rappers, included inappropriate language and stage dancing in their portion of the concert, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carbajal</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="8">   "One of our missions is to assist young people who want to excel in the music business," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carbajal</ENAMEX>. "We thought, we'll give these young people a chance. Boy, were we wrong."
</P><P ID="9">   She said the musicians were warned to watch their language, but didn't. She said it all happened before they were able to stop it.
</P><P ID="10">   "It will not happen again," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carbajal</ENAMEX>. "We want to continue to do this. We learned."
</P><P ID="11">   She added that they hope to be able to hold future events on the Grandview stage, but they will not be opening it up to such young musicians.
</P><P ID="12">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> marked the third annual Tejano music festival sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> based organization. Along with the music, the group sponsored a car show.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> said he doesn't expect the city to keep the group from using the facility in the future.
</P>   
<P ID="14">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail msacher@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




