
<P ID="1">AHS spring sports award ceremony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/26/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> will open its doors to the community to come and celebrate the accomplishments of Grizzly student athletes on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, June 1</TIMEX>.   The annual spring sports award ceremony will be held on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> in the high school auditorium.   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past spring</TIMEX> sports season was another successful one for various Grizzly athletic programs.   The high school soccer team had its most successful season ever, ending just one game short of qualifying for the trophy round at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament.   The Grizzly baseball program also ended up one game short of making it to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament.   The Grizzly boys and girls golf programs qualified <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Lick</ENAMEX> and Jensie Hernandez for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament.   In track, Isley Gonzalez and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> will be representing the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzly</ENAMEX> track team in individual events at the 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> track and field meet.   The combination of brothers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Plesha</ENAMEX> qualified in doubles for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tennis tournament, after winning both the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Regional</ENAMEX> crowns.   And, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> fastpitch softball team had a competitive postseason.   Besides their athletic accomplishments, student athletes will also be recognized for their academic endeavors.   The community is encouraged to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 1</TIMEX> event.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

