
<P ID="1">Day reporting classroom puts routine back in to the lives of juvenile offenders
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/4/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Going from math class to English to reading may sound like just another day on a high school campus, but for students attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Day Reporting program going to class isn't an option, it's a requirement.   Students taking part in the program, which started in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 26</TIMEX>, are typically referred into day reporting by their parole or probation officer, or through a court order or referral.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> classroom, which is set up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">OIC</ENAMEX> building along Railroad Avenue, is also a little different from a traditional classroom in the staff members it employs. The teacher for the 16 enrolled students, who come from as far away as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Moyer</ENAMEX>, and the staff also includes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vianca Herrera</ENAMEX>, a juvenile detention officer. A case worker is currently being located for the classroom through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Comprehensive Mental Health</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said the idea behind the program, which used to be run solely out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, is to give students a place that gets them ready to be transitioned back into a traditional educational setting, be it an alternative high school or another <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> high school.   "Mostly we try to keep it as a regular class day," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said.   He noted that everyday he puts a schedule on the board, which sets the routine for the entire school day, which runs from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said different subjects ranging from English to math are covered each day, making the day reporting classroom much like any other classroom in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.   "They work hard and stay on task," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said of the students taking part in the program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrera</ENAMEX> said the important thing about having a schedule and keeping things regulated is that it gets the students, who range in age from 14 to 18, ready for the challenge of heading back to school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said there are two key things he tries to stress to his students, one is the day-to-day routine of going to school and the other is the routine and schedule that comes with the average school day.   "We want to help them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said, noting that when students leave the day reporting program they should be better equipped to make decisions regarding the next step in their education. "We want them to leave here a little better off than they came," he added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said students who are attending classes through the day reporting program aren't just learning the importance of getting to school on time and staying on task. They are also earning credits toward their high school diploma or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GED</ENAMEX>.   "Everything they do here is for credits," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said.   He added that although students are all working on the same subject at the same time, not every student is working on the same set of math problems or reading questions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said the students are able to work at their own pace. He noted that in subjects like math and reading, the students do packet work, which is one way students are able to earn high school credits.   Being able to work at their own speed is an important part of the day reporting program because the students aren't necessarily in the program for extended periods of time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said most of the students are in the program for quarter or semester periods.   Another challenge this brings is introducing a new student to the day reporting classroom. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrera</ENAMEX> explained that when a new student is referred to the program, they are told what the expectations are of them, then the student will typically join the classroom the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Monday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Day Reporting classroom can take a maximum of 20 students.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said since classes began less than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two weeks ago</TIMEX>, the students are already showing a lot of improvement. He said the first few days seemed to be a feeling out period. However, now students know what the expectations are and what is required of them.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said being in a smaller classroom environment, like the one day reporting offers, means students' individual needs are being met on a daily basis. He noted that when a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sing</ENAMEX> manager is hired for the classroom, students will have even more individual attention available to them. He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sing</ENAMEX> manager will be there to listen to any problems or issues a student is experiencing.   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX>, who earned his degree at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Washington University</ENAMEX>, working in an alternative classroom setting is something he had always been interested in.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrera</ENAMEX> said being a juvenile detention officer and working in a classroom gives her a chance to work more closely with the students and their families.   "There's more of an opportunity to assist," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herrera</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Day Reporting Program is something that took several months to set up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and now that it is officially up and running there are a variety of different agencies that are helping make the classroom possible.   "So far the collaboration has worked great," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moyer</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Partners</ENAMEX> in the day reporting program include the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, Yakima Juvenile Courts, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> 105, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Comprehensive Mental Health</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

