


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFW</ENAMEX> leader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolores Huerta</ENAMEX> to speak in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> tonight
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Farm Workers Union</ENAMEX> leader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dolores Huerta</ENAMEX> will be in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this evening</TIMEX> to help launch "Latinos for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>," an outreach effort to attract Hispanic voters to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> presidential campaign.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>, the 74-year-old co-founder of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Farm Workers Union</ENAMEX>, will be appearing at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navarro's Community Center</ENAMEX>, 548 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Sixth St.</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> Joining <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX> at the voters' rally will be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Phyllis Gutierrez Kenney</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> rally will be used to announce the members of the state's Latino Vote Campaign steering committee and the Democrats' outreach plan to attract large numbers of Latino voters to the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> presidential election.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Huerta</ENAMEX>, who co-founded the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UFW</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Chavez</ENAMEX>, is now the co-chair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Women</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>. She has been traveling around the country speaking to women's groups and Latinos.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenney</ENAMEX> chairs the state House Higher Education committee and grew up in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Tonight's rally is co-sponsored by the Washington State Democrats.
</P>





 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




