


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/3/2002</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

 


<P ID="4">Graffiti crackdown on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX> agenda
</P>

<P ID="5">An interlocal jail agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Yakima</ENAMEX> is expected to be approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX> meeting.
</P>

<P ID="6">The jail agreement is just one of the items on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX> agenda.
</P>

<P ID="7">Other items include a public hearing to accept input on rate increases in water and sewer services. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will also consider the extension of a housing rehabilitation contract with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Conference of Governments. Also, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is expected to formally grant <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> emergency power to deal with eradicating crows in the community.
</P>

<P ID="8">One of the more impactful items to come before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX> will be a proposal for a graffiti ordinance. The ordinance is expected to include a requirement that all city businesses not sell spray paint to minors, implementing some strict standards for purchase. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> is also supposed to discuss the city implementing a program where graffiti offenders would have to appear in civil court so victims could reclaim damages.
</P>

 


<P ID="9">Pavers program honoring long-term councilmen to be on hold
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> opted to delay her request for funding a pavers program at Centennial Square honoring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members who have served approximately 20 years or more.
</P>  


<P ID="11">At this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> explained the city is in a financial bind right now, so she opted to delay the program. She said each paver will cost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300</NUMEX> to install. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> did read the names of the five councilmen who would be honored under the program, the first of whom is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Bond</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX> served 19 years and six months on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Taylor</ENAMEX> represented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> for 21 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hughes</ENAMEX> has the longest term of any council member, having served 31 years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Errol Brown</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Anciso</ENAMEX> would be the last two councilmen honored through the program, having served 23 and 20 years, respectively.
</P>

 


<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agrees to meet with
school board
</P>

<P ID="13">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> collectively agreed to a joint meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said he would get in contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> to discuss a possible date, further suggesting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> come up with agenda ideas for the gathering.
</P>

 


<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> takes no action following executive session
</P>

<P ID="15">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> took no action this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> following a 15-minute executive session concerning legal issues.
</P>

 


<P ID="16">Mayor to miss next two meetings
</P>

<P ID="17">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> granted Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> an excused absence for this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> excused the mayor from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following week</TIMEX>'s meeting, as well. Councilman John Torch also received an excused absence for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 9</TIMEX> meeting.
</P>

 


<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX> holiday discussion to wait
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> she wanted to wait until Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> returned in two weeks to discuss making <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Martin</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Luther King Jr. Day</TIMEX> a recognized holiday by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




