
<P ID="1">Briefly
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
WASL success night planned
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 13</TIMEX>, will be a night to celebrate the academic successes of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> fifth graders, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julie Schmick</ENAMEX>, Chief Kamiakin principal.
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) celebration night will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX> said.
Parents are invited to pick up their fifth graders' 4th grade WASL scores from 6:45 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the high school.
"We will celebrate everyone's success and special recognition will be given to those students who passed all three portions (writing, reading and math) of the state assessment test," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schmick</ENAMEX> said.
She said refreshments will be served.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Community harvest festival set
 A harvest festival family event will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 23</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX>.
Participants will enjoy games, crafts and refreshments. All children must be accompanied by an adult.
</P> 
 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearl Hughes Guild</ENAMEX> meets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pearl Hughes Guild</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Children's Hospital</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Medical Center</ENAMEX> will meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Oct. 15</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunny Spot Restaurant</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernice Nederhood</ENAMEX> will provide the gift for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> hostess gift project, which benefits the Seattle center.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Carter</ENAMEX>, who is the guild calendar chairman, said the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> children's calendars are now available in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neva</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Beauty Salon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Food Pavilion and at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Scissor City</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Calendar</ENAMEX> sales benefit the Seattle children's medical center.
</P> 
 
 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

