
<P ID="1">School board dedicates new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> parent center
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/24/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has a new place to go when it comes to resources to help better the achievement of both children and parents in the local school district. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX>, as well as representatives from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Community Action Center</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Service District</ENAMEX> 105 gathered together to celebrate the dedication of the new parent center at 810 E. Custer Ave. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Garza</ENAMEX>, executive director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> Community Action Center</ENAMEX>, said his organization has been working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> on its parent center for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>. He noted that one of the things that helped make the center possible was a grant that was received through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Education</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Community Resources Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX> said the center will offer parents a place to come and learn about different resources available through both the school district and the community.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> also noted that the parent center includes a technology center. The computer lab serves as a place where parents can come in and take computer classes or simply take advantage of the technology.   "You never stop learning, no matter what the age," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> said.   Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> took time <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to congratulate everyone who was involved with making the center possible. He added that although the center will serve as a central hub for parent activities and resources, it does not diminish the parent involvement efforts taking place at the different schools in the district.   Following the dedication, school board members and several administrators walked across the parking lot to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Blaine</ENAMEX> building for the school board retreat. During the retreat the board members talked about a variety of topics, including further discussing parent involvement, looking at the salary schedule for all district employees and touching on school safety.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susan Martin</ENAMEX>, the parent involvement coordinator for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> 105, said she has been working with the local school district on its parent involvement component since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last May</TIMEX>.   "What I truly believe is that all families want what is best for their children," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> told board members.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> then commended the board on taking a proactive stance on parent involvement, noting that they are ahead of many districts when it comes to taking steps to actively include parents in their children's education.   "Family and school together, can help all students be successful," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> added that although the opening of the parent center is a big step, the process of getting parents involved in school is ongoing.   "You've laid a great path and it's going to be an exciting journey," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin</ENAMEX> said.   During the board retreat, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Human Resources Director Debbie Holwegner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Payroll</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pauline Schut</ENAMEX> took time to walk the board through the 2004-05 salary schedules and agreements for the different positions in the district.   As Holwegner and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schut</ENAMEX> showed some of the different salary schedules to the board members, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> made some comments about some of the changes that have taken place in regards to the different salaries scheduled for the 2004-05 school year.   He pointed to the salary schedule for classified administrators, which include positions like the transportation supervisor, noting that this is the first time there has been a salary schedule for these positions. He explained that in the past the different positions have each had their own salary range. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> all of those positions have been brought together, with all of the salaries also having been brought closer together and put in the same salary schedule.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said another change to the salary schedule involves principals in the district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said principals have been year-around employees. He said this is because many principals were often found in their buildings in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, dealing with everything from new hires to getting things organized for the next school year.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Hughes</ENAMEX>, safe and effective schools director, took time to talk to the board about the upcoming Washington State Health Youth Survey, which is administered every two years to sixth, eighth, tenth and twelfth graders. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will mark the third time the test has been administered in the school district.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> said the test will be administered sometime between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 11</TIMEX> and 15. He added that the surveys are anonymous and voluntary, and deal with everything from bicycle safety to drugs and alcohol.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> said the district has also been working on putting together a curriculum for younger students that deals with irrigation canal safety. He said the district received a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX> grant from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Power</ENAMEX> to work on the curriculum, which is being created with help from both kindergarten teachers and students. He told board members he is currently searching for an illustrator to draw the coloring books that will make up the curriculum.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> then talked about different subjects the school board would like to bring up when they schedule a joint meeting between the board and city council.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said he would like to talk about different partnerships between the two entities and working to ensure that services are not being duplicated. He said the different subjects he would like to see discussed include looking at aligning all of the early learning programs in the community on the same page, working to get children ready to enter kindergarten. He said he would also like to see the subject of technology discussed, because technology is something that affects everyone in the community.   As for the subject of adequate yearly progress, Executive Director of Instruction and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Learning Gary Vegar</ENAMEX> said many of the schools in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> are showing signs of making a lot of progress. However, schools in the district are still struggling to make adequate yearly progress.   "We just need to keep the course," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said, noting that the district has done a lot of work when it comes to literacy and trying to prepare students for the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> exams.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

