


<P ID="1">Lady '<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hounds</ENAMEX> head into postseason
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/16/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> may have had a tough weekend, but in the end the team was able to finish with a third place finish in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> going into the postseason.
</P><P ID="5">   The Lady 'Hounds lost to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> 59-46, but rallied back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>, finishing with a 56-38 victory.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adolfo Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the difference between <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> came in the form of added pressure.
</P><P ID="7">   "We picked up our pressure on defense," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said, noting the Lady 'Hounds also introduced a new defensive set against the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>. He said it's a defense he hopes the team will be able to put to use during postseason action.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the team worked hard against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX> to create turnovers, which the team was then able to turn into several easy lay-ups.
</P><P ID="9">   Leading the scoring efforts for the Grandview team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> was Danelle Cowan with 15 points and 12 rebounds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> explained that most of those stats were racked up in the first half of the match-up. Also scoring for the Lady 'Hounds were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Rodriguez</ENAMEX> with 13 points, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meghan Waddle</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anastasia Andrews</ENAMEX> with 8 points each.
</P><P ID="10">   On the offensive side of the game, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the Lady 'Hounds did a good job of moving the ball around against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   However, the night before against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, things were a little different.
</P><P ID="12">   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> was a war," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said, noting that the score was close throughout the game.
</P><P ID="13">   In the first half the Lady 'Hounds were able to keep up with the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX>, but when the second half started the Grandview team couldn't get its momentum going again.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> were able to break <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s half court defense.
</P><P ID="15">   "We were just not communicating on defense," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   He noted the Lady 'Hounds did do a good job <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> of running the court. However, he said the team didn't take advantage of several opportunities.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX> did a good job for the Lady 'Hounds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, scoring 12 points for the team.
</P><P ID="18">   "She played one of her best games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hinojosa</ENAMEX> said. "She really set the tone for our defensive pressure."
</P><P ID="19">   Also scoring for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> with 15 points, Keitha Robertson with 8 points and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Waddle</ENAMEX> with 5 points.
</P><P ID="20">   The Lady 'Hounds will play their first postseason game <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with the winner moving on to play <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




