
<P ID="1">Greyhounds earn a date with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s big man, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mejia</ENAMEX>, had his usual solid night, but fans of the Greyhounds boys basketball team can send their thank you cards to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake McFerran</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> donned his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Superman</ENAMEX> cape and helped pull the struggling Greyhounds back into <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s first round, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">loser-out Mid-Valley League District</ENAMEX> tournament game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   After a dismal first half, the Greyhounds charged back in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two quarters</TIMEX> to win 53-49.   The win propelled the Greyhounds into the Regional playoff tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>. The win also earned the Greyhounds a date with top seeded <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>. The two teams will be looking to add another chapter to their classic rivalry as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> will host <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> looked as if it was going to get off to a nice start in the game, opening with an 8-2 run behind two baskets from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX> and a couple of other buckets from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabe Reyes</ENAMEX>.   But about three minutes into the game, the momentum turned south for the Greyhounds, as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> had trouble running any set defensive plays against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. A couple of buckets by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Quirk</ENAMEX> and a 3-pointer from teammate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Griffith</ENAMEX> gave the Bulldogs a 9-8 lead with 3:26 left in the first quarter. It would be a lead <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> wouldn't relinquish for a while.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Gray</ENAMEX> ended the Bulldogs' first quarter heroics when he drained a 3-pointer to give the Greyhounds a 14-9 lead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX> drained a 3-pointer with 6:13 left in the second period to give the Bulldogs a 20-11 lead. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> had trouble boxing out in the second quarter, which led to several offensive putbacks by the Bulldogs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> had a three-minute stretch in the second quarter where the Greyhounds couldn't get anything to fall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX>, though, came through by scoring all seven of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s second quarter points. The Greyhounds trailed 25-16 at the break.   Greyhound fans, though, saw a much different <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> squad in the second half. The Greyhounds came out with a lot more energy.   The comeback for the Greyhounds started when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Andrews</ENAMEX> hit a 3-point bucket with 6:02 left in the third to pull <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> within 26-19. But it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> who had a key play with 4:27 to go. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> drove hard to the basket and was foul. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> converted the free throw for the 3-point play to pull <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> within 28-22. In less than a minute following that play, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> took it to the rack off a steal and then hit a nice little jumper to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> within two points at 28-26.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX> put the Greyhounds ahead at 29-28 with 2:37 remaining in the third by canning a 3-pointer.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nick Gray</ENAMEX> was huge down the stretch in the third quarter for the Bulldogs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> bounced off <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX> with under 30 seconds left to hit a shot and then later hit a free throw to put the Bulldogs ahead 32-29. With under 10 seconds to go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX> drained a long two-point shot to cut <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s lead to 32-31.   In the fourth quarter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> was instrumental early for the Greyhounds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX> put a rebound back in and then drained a 3-pointer off an assist from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> ahead 36-34 with 6:50 left in the game. The Bulldogs climbed back to take a 39-36 lead with 5:23 to go, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> hit a beautiful off balanced jumper to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> within a point. After a bucket from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX> hit a 3-pointer with 3:28 to go to put <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> up 43-42. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> gave the Greyhounds the lead for good when he was fouled inside with 2:55 to go. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> converted the 3-point play to give <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> a 46-42 lead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> finally got into the bonus with 2:09 left in the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX> hit six free throws down the stretch and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrews</ENAMEX> added another to put the Bulldogs away.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s defensive pressure, which was dominate in the second half, led to 20 points off 18 turnovers. The Bulldogs had 9 points off seven turnovers.   The Bulldogs outrebounded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> 32 to 22, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> could only manage 9 second chance points. The Bulldogs grabbed an impressive 25 defensive boards.   The Greyhounds statistically dominated the second half. After going 0-for-6 in the first half, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> hit 4-of-8 3-pointers. The Greyhounds were also 9-of-12 from the free throw line in the second half and 12-for-25 from the field. The Greyhounds hit 11-of-16 free throws for the game while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> made 8-of-15.   "I was happy with the first three minutes of the game and the second half," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Scott Parrish</ENAMEX>. "But we didn't have a lot of intensity during that stretch in between. They just didn't look like the Grandview Greyhound team we are used to seeing."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said it was nice to see <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> step up for the Greyhounds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McFerran</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mejia</ENAMEX> were both solid for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is ready to go into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   "We will just go in and give it a shot and see what happens," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Parrish</ENAMEX>. "Hopefully, we will catch a couple of breaks."   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   1 2 3 4 T   Ellensburg 14 11 7 17 49   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> 9 7 15 22 53   Scoring: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview-Chris Mejia</ENAMEX> 23, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake McFerran</ENAMEX> 14, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Anthony Andrews</ENAMEX> 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX> 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabe Reyes</ENAMEX> 2.   Ellensburg-Riley Sivak 16.   Rebounds: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Mejia</ENAMEX> 5.   Assists: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> 4.   Steals: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> 5, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blake McFerran</ENAMEX> 3.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

