


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> discusses mission statement and priorities
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members took part in their annual retreat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, taking time to sit together and review the city's mission statement and priorities.
</P>

<P ID="6"><TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members took time to revisit the work they did during the retreat, looking back over the priorities they had created.
</P>

<P ID="7">The list of priorities includes everything from continuing aggressive economic development efforts to revising the plan for an aquatic center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and re-submitting it to voters.
</P>

 


<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves changes to well
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Louman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Huibregtse</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louman Associates, Inc.</ENAMEX>, talked to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> about changes to the city's well seven project.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louman</ENAMEX> said the original plan for the project was to drill a well to replace well seven, which traditionally has high nitrate levels and only pumps at 190 gallons a minute. The water rights for the well is for 325 gallons a minute.
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louman</ENAMEX> said in drilling the new well a water supply was found with lower nitrate levels. However, the new well only has a pumping capacity of 80 gallons per minute. He also noted that it has been discovered that by raising the pump in the old well, its capacity was increased up to the water rights level of 325 gallons a minute.
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Louman</ENAMEX> suggested to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that water from the new well be blended with water from the original well to lower nitrate levels and maximize the city's water right.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




