
<P ID="1">Grizzly freshmen dump Wolfpack
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A team knows it is having a pretty good night when it racks up more than 500 yards offensively. This was how a wet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> went for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> freshman football team against visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies pounded <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> 56-20 <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to improve to 5-2 on the season heading into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX>'s game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s lone touchdown in the opening quarter was a 23-yard pass play from quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adrian Cantu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Salcedo</ENAMEX>. The Grizzlies made good on a two-point conversion attempt to lead 8-0.   The second quarter saw the Grizzlies tack on two more scores. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> scooted in from three yards out and the other touchdown was a 22-yard pass play from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Montelongo</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> padded its 22-0 lead with three touchdowns in the third quarter. The first was a 15-yard touchdown pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brice Rinehold</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX> scored next on a 41-yard run. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s last score of the third quarter was a 38-yard touchdown pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Villanueva</ENAMEX>.   Grizzly freshman coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glenn Braman</ENAMEX> went to his bench late in the third quarter.   After that, the Wolfpack took advantage of some less experienced players being in the game, scoring three rushing touchdowns. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> made good on one of three two-point conversion attempts.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> added two more touchdowns in the fourth quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> scored on a 70-yard run. The Grizzlies missed the extra point attempt. The last touchdown was from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX>, who ran 82 yards for the score.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> wasn't trying to score a lot of touchdowns against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>, but rather the Grizzlies were trying to work on executing some plays.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> had a nice night for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, rushing for 144 yards on 14 carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Montelongo</ENAMEX> had 139 yards on six totes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> rushed eight times for 90 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> also was 9-for-15 in the air for 219 yards.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

