
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> votes to eliminate WASL
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/25/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Looks of satisfaction in the crowd and a smattering of applause marked a decision made by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. The local school directors voted to submit a legislative proposal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State School Districts Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSSDA</ENAMEX>) that would call for the replacement of WASL testing.   The proposal was brought to the board by members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justice</ENAMEX>, a group that was organized by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nuestra Casa</ENAMEX>. Sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Rita Rhode</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nuestra Casa</ENAMEX> said the group began meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to talk about concerns they had regarding a variety of topics. However, in the end the group decided to focus their attention on one topic of concern for them, which ended up being the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) tests.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhode</ENAMEX> said the group slowly grew from its original 12 members to more than 24 parents who come together on a regular basis to talk about what they can do to make a difference, especially when it comes to the WASL.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhode</ENAMEX>, over the past several months the group has met with everyone from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Supt. Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> to Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rhode</ENAMEX> said the group asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> if he would work with the Circle of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justice</ENAMEX> to replace the WASL with a another test.   However, the group of dedicated parents didn't stop there. Instead, they decided to take their concerns one step further. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, they talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> about submitting a legislative proposal to WSSDA for inclusion in the organization's legislative program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luce Balderas</ENAMEX>, a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Circle</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justice</ENAMEX> and a mother of five children, talked to the school board on behalf of the group.   Speaking in Spanish she told the board members that children are making themselves ill thinking about the WASL test and what it could mean for them if they don't pass.   "There are other ways of testing to see if children are learning, such as the Measures of Academic Progress, which gives us, as parents, immediate feedback on how our children are doing in school," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Balderas</ENAMEX> said. "This kind of testing makes more sense to us and will help all in education provide for the gaps in student learning in a more timely manner than the WASL."   She told the board that this is the reason they were asking them to submit the legislative proposal to WSSDA.   The proposal, which school board members voted to approve, encourages WSSDA to support legislation that would "do away" with the WASL test and find other means of testing students across the state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> board member Bill Wells suggested that the board approach other districts in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> to see if they would also be interested in supporting the legislative call to action.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

