
<P ID="1">Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> bill would help people recover court judgments
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - The Washington State House of Representatives has passed a bill which would allow a prevailing party in small claims court to recover additional costs, including attorney fees, acquired by enforcing an outstanding judgment.
"House Bill 1572 sounds like a small bill, because it deals with small claims," said Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>). "But if you've ever been involved in small claims court, you know how important it is to you and your family.
"In some cases it may take years to recover a court ordered judgment.
"Many small claims simply go unpaid because they can't afford to hire an attorney. This bill would ensure the process is accelerated and payments won't take years to be made any more," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>, who co-sponsored the bill.
The piece of legislation passed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> unanimously, and is now headed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> for further consideration.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Valentine dance for youngstersset for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentine</ENAMEX> dance for youths will be hosted by St. Joseph's Parish this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Feb. 13</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 a.m.</TIMEX> dance will be held at the St. Joseph's gymnasium.
Concessions will be available. Dance organizers will also be selling roses, as well as photographs as special keepsakes.
</P> 
<P ID="5">G’view campusof YVCC offers <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX>, food handler classes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this month</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> campus is offering both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX>/first aid and food handlers permit classes in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>.
The two-day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CPR</ENAMEX>/first aid class is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 23-24</TIMEX>. The class fee is set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35</NUMEX> for those not presently attending YVCC, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> for current YVCC students. Pre-registration is not required to attend the two-day class. Those who want to attend need only show up at the front desk of the main building on the Grandview campus prior to the 3:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> class on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX> to enroll.
The food handlers permit class will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Feb. 26</TIMEX>, from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> Again, pre-registration is not required. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> class fee can be paid just prior to the class start time that evening.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Blood drawingin Grandviewset for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 3</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX> blood drawing will be held in the main building of the YVCC Grandview campus on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 3</TIMEX>. The drawing will take place that day from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="7">AHS <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX> plans game night for local families
A game night for community members has been planned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School Key Club</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX> spokesman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dionne Cohan</ENAMEX> said the event will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 5</TIMEX>, from 6:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> gym. The game night is open to all community members, and is being promoted as a family event.
"We'll have bingo, basketball and other fun games that night," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cohan</ENAMEX>. She added there is no cost to attend.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Boy Scoutssign-up tonight
Youngsters interested in joining the Boy Scouts organization can sign up tonight (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>) at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chief Kamiakin Elementary School</ENAMEX> cafeteria.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 10</TIMEX> sign-up session will be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had 11 separate Boy Scouts programs in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, including Cub Scouts, Boy Scouts, Venturing and Exploring. More than 200 local youths were involved <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>.
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

