


<P ID="1">Community center topic of discussion
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/14/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Antonio Santoy</ENAMEX>, who represents the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> on the board of directors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>, stepped before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX> wanted to voice some concerns he had with an article in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 9</TIMEX>, edition of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> regarding issues <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had with the operation of the community center by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSMC</ENAMEX>). The news article highlighted some concerns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voiced at its retreat <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> about WSMC's management of the city's community center. Some of the concerns included a lack of communication between WSMC and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX> said the board of directors has met at least four times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> that he knows of, and offered minutes of the meetings to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> for review.
</P><P ID="6">   "We are scheduled for more <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX> also said that it was his understanding the only time the board of directors had to come before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was for an annual financial report. He also invited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members to attend any of the board meetings.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX> also wanted to make clear to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the intent of the center's board of directors.
</P><P ID="9">   "We are here for the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX>. "We are not here for certain entities."
</P><P ID="10">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> is currently reviewing the situation. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Santoy</ENAMEX> to deliver any minutes or other items of interest concerning the community center to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> for review.
</P>   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




