44 45 7 18 10 14
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  Please write again soon. Though my own life is filled with activity, letters encourage momentary escape into others lives and I come back to my own with greater contentment.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth Forsythe Hailey</ENAMEX>, 'A Woman of Independent Means'
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>