


<P ID="1">Seven seek <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>'s vacated city council seat
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Community activism is alive and well in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Seven local residents met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s deadline in submitting their applications to be chosen as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX>'s replacement on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   The 22-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, elected just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> to his first term on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, abruptly resigned in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early July</TIMEX> when he was offered a job promotion in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> by the management of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX>/A&W chain.
</P><P ID="5">   Seeking the now vacated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> seat are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Drysdale</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ermenejildo Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The seven <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> hopefuls will make oral presentations at a future <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting, and will participate in a question-and-answer session with the public. Following that, the six remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> members will select <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>'s replacement. Whoever is named to succeed him will have to run for office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> if they intend on retaining the seat.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX>, who has been employed as the facilities foreman for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, unsuccessfully campaigned for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>. He lost a tight race against incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> that year.
</P><P ID="8">   In submitting his application for the vacated seat, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> said he wants to take the city in a different spending direction.
</P><P ID="9">   "I don't have a personal agenda," he wrote in his application. "I've been in private business and government, so I know both sides of the street.
</P><P ID="10">   "I've been responsible for government funds, always with a clean audit, so I understand how a lot of the spending works and how the funds cannot be co-mingled," he said.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> graduate, is the owner and operator of The Funny Farm, which also serves as a contract liquor store.
</P><P ID="12">   A past member of Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gary Locke</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Retail Liquor Task Force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hancock</ENAMEX> said the experience and talents she would bring to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> include being a life-long resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and a small business owner.
</P><P ID="13">   "I am open-minded and able to work by consensus," she added on her written application.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drysdale</ENAMEX> has been a resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1929</TIMEX>, when he was a fourth grader. His list of accomplishments include earning a Bachelor of Science degree in business administration from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Oregon</ENAMEX>. In his application he also lists having attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">New York University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oregon State University</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Nebraska and Central Washington University</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   He said early in his career he was employed as a caseworker for the state in its public assistance division. Later in life, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drysdale</ENAMEX> has been active in real estate sales, rentals and various bail bonds services.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> is currently employed as a clerk for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastway Video</ENAMEX>. Prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May of this year</TIMEX>, he worked at his father's auto body repair shop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> alumnus who majored in psychology, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> said he wants to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> because he enjoys "...communicating and connecting with other individuals and working in politics.
</P><P ID="18">   "Also, I've been fortunate enough to work with others in different realms of life, and I would like for this opportunity to be my stepping stone to work with other individuals on a larger scale of politics, from the county to the international level," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> wrote in his application.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> has been a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX>. He is employed as a supervisor for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Framatome-ANP Inc.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, responsible for the firm's quality surveillance department.
</P><P ID="20">   A <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Phoenix</ENAMEX> on-line graduate, with a Bachelor of Science degree in business management, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said he wants to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> because he is deeply interested in the future of the city.
</P><P ID="21">   "I believe that the knowledge and experience I can offer this position will allow me to make a positive contribution," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said one of the most important talents he brings to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is his ability to work well with others, "...but also having the fortitude to remain independent and make the tough decision when needed."
</P><P ID="23">   A <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High grad, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> is a journalist for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="24">   Formerly the co-chairman for the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Task Force</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> said being a life-long resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> he knows the issues the community faces and how <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has grown and changed over the years.
</P><P ID="25">   "The knowledge I have and the contacts I have at my disposal would be a great asset towards the betterment of the community," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Panni</ENAMEX> said in his application.
</P><P ID="26">   "I don't have any great answers as to why I want to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>. Simply put, I know I won't change the world or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> at the snap of my fingers," he related in his application. "What I do hope is that I can do enough for the community to make it a better place."
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High grad, said she wants to serve the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as their voice in city government. She promotes being fiscally responsible with the resources at-hand, and wants "...to help our city grow, prosper, better itself by always trying my best to do what is in the best interest of all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> citizens."
</P><P ID="28">   In listing her assets, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said she works and communicates well with others, is a good organizer and is committed.
</P><P ID="29">   "I am an independent person who likes solving problems, and I am an optimist," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stone</ENAMEX> said.
</P>   






 










<P ID="30">Webmaster
</P><P ID="31">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




