
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>
<P ID="4">Once again <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is made to look like a joke to the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>. I am referring to the little poem by our local councilman, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX>, in the latest editions of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Business Times</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, please start concerning yourself with city issues and quit bad mouthing agencies that don't agree with your sanctimonious views. Not all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> agrees with you.
Maybe you should try working with the other agencies and stop with the "If it's not my way, hit the hiway" attitude. That attitude alone has cost the city in revenue dollars. No wonder people give our city a wide berth when it comes to relocating businesses and opportunities.
And to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue and Rob Rice</ENAMEX>, congratulations on your new business. It will definitely be a great asset to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>. I wish you both nothing but success.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty S. Denson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> great city manager
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">I</ENAMEX> find it most interesting talking to citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The populace of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has so many opinions on so many subjects concerning our fine city.
Recently, everywhere I go I hear people talking about the purchase of the Monson feedlot. Several people say the purchase was the right thing to do, but they should have bought the mill, too. Others say it was a waste to have bought it at all.
Well, to me it doesn't matter. The smell of manure to me is much more refreshing than most of this perfume women wear. But if this community wants to move forward and not become stagnant as far as economic development goes, it was the right move.
It seems as though being the city manager surely must be a thankless job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> has done more for this city as far as economic development goes than any manager in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 20 years</TIMEX>. He has grabbed the reins and led the way. I am not saying the others weren't good managers. The others were more appeasing type managers.
It just seems to me that some groups of people in town want their projects done immediately. This city has fallen so far behind in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last decade</TIMEX> that it will take time to get to where we should be. I personally think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is a great manager and we will see some great movement forward with this city manager.
But for you that don't, I am setting up a collection at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sixth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Edison</ENAMEX>. Just throw your money in that manhole. I will collect the money and buy <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> a magic wand!
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Padelford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">Image vs. character
Recently, a contributor to this <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX> column wrote in espousing the "presidential charisma" of candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>. He specifically referred to how well Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> looked and acted in the third presidential debate. The writer seemed to be most impacted by the image Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> portrayed.
In this media saturated culture it seems that image is "everything." Granted, looks are important but when it comes to picking a president for our nation we need to look beyond the pretty package.
If we look back at two examples of previous presidents, we can point to glaringly stark contrasts. Remember <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ronald Regan</ENAMEX>. What a gentleman. A man with rock-solid principles, a fantastic marriage and a man whose word was as good as his handshake. Even his enemies, such as Gorbachev, came to respect him.
Contrast Reagan with Bill Clinton. Even before he won the presidency, a parade of "bimbos" gave witness to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX>'s marital indiscretions. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Foreign</ENAMEX> leaders mocked him behind his back. As Commander in Chief, Clinton gutted the military. For example, he reduced active <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Air Force</ENAMEX> personnel from 650,000 to 240,000 people during his two terms. Many of the best officers voluntarily took early retirement rather than serve under a man they could not respect. And then to top it all, he lied in court and to the American people. His own state took away his license to practice law.
So what does this have to do with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> election?
President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is a man of his word. He has principles and integrity. He stands for what he believes. Our military loves him as Commander in Chief. And he has a fantastic marriage.
Then there's Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>. Fresh from his four-month tour (others served one year) in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, he went before a Congressional hearing and confessed to war crimes while still a commissioned officer. Then he accused those he served with of crimes against civilians without one shred of evidence. He has voted against bills supporting new weapons and funding for the military. Yet, he claims that he has all the qualities to instill loyalty by our soldiers who daily lay their lives on the line to defend us from those who want to kill us and take our freedom. Give me a break!
Finally, I want to remind my neighbors how ancient <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Israel</ENAMEX>'s leader, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, was chosen. After all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jessee</ENAMEX>'s handsome sons had been paraded before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX>, one little shepherd boy became one of the greatest <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kings</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> in all history. When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">God</ENAMEX> why He chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">God</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samuel</ENAMEX> that "Men look on the outside (image) of a man, but the Lord looks on the heart (character) of a man."
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Herndon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="7">Defending <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> an attack on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> veterans
I was watching TV the other night when a representative from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Veterans Administration</ENAMEX> was asked whether Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> was telling the truth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, or whether the "Swift Vets for Truth" were. This man said that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> was telling the truth.
I was shocked. My understanding is that even <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> has said that he had no firm knowledge of atrocities to back up what he said back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. He admits that he stretched the truth. So why would one of our representatives say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> told the truth.
I was in college in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> and I remember how hard it hit me when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> told those lies. I also remember that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> was so upset by what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> had told them that they called in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Telford Taylor</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Law University</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX> to investigate the atrocities being committed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. You might recall that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> was the chief prosecutor during the War Crimes Trials in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nuremberg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Germany</ENAMEX> at the end of WWII.
After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s investigation he said that he found very few cases of true atrocities taking place in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX>. He did say that many times our soldiers had killed civilians, but in almost every case he investigated he found that it was not an atrocity at all. He said that these incidents were very sad and hard for soldiers to deal with, but they were not a crime according to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geneva Convention</ENAMEX>. The civilians were just in the wrong place at the wrong time, and that the aim was not to kill the civilians just for the joy of it. In fact, most soldiers felt guilty for having killed innocent people during firefights. It was not their intent.
In the end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> said the Rules of Engagement were impeccable. He said the Rules of Engagement were so impeccable that he found it difficult to believe that soldiers would follow them, as it would cost them their lives to do so. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX> said that the way in which we fought the war caused many soldiers to lose their lives, in order that civilians would be spared theirs. And he said that he felt that was unacceptable during war. In the end he said the Vietnam War was the cleanest war that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> had ever fought; that it had the fewest atrocities by any measure compared to other wars; and that he found a renewed sense of awe for those who were fighting the war, even though he was firmly against it.
To my knowledge no one has disputed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor</ENAMEX>'s assessment of the war with regards to war crimes having been committed by our troops, so why would one of our representatives say that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> was "right" back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>, referring to our fellow soldiers as war criminals?
I think <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> threw gasoline on the fire back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX>. He convinced people that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Fonda</ENAMEX> was right. And that caused the war protesters to harass the returning soldiers on college campuses at a higher level than what they had been doing before. I know, I was there. After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> spoke to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> it was very ugly for the veterans who were attending college and trying to further their education.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> I remember watching (from afar) an anti-war rally on campus one day, and watched as the students cheered when it was announced how many returing Vietnam veterans had committed suicide after coming home. They truly wanted to see us dead. Their level of cruelty was more brutal than any acts by infantry soldiers that I had ever seen.
The question remains: why doesn't <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> go on TV and debate these Swift Boat Veterans, and the POWs and the recipients of the Medal of Honor that have spoken out against him on TV ads? He could end this whole debate once and for all. He's a very good debater. He had the courage to debate George Bush, so why not do all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> veterans a great favor and debate these men as well? They have proven to be honorable men, thus I would like him to step up to the plate and discuss this whole matter on national TV.
That doesn't sound like much to me, especially if <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> thinks he's right.
I wish he would either defend himself against these veterans, or apologize for what he did. My view is that he needs to apologize for the lies he told, and the damage that those lies did to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> veterans. And he especially needs to apologize to family members of those returning <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> veterans who committed suicide when they were unable to stand up to the attacks committed on them by their peers. It must be remembered that these veterans returned home physically fatigued, mentally fatigued and spiritually fatigued. They required nurturing, not the attacks hurled at them.
But still <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> people come to the defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> and encourage others to continue to attack our veterans. For any defense of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX> is an attack on those who honorably served in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and who say that they are proud of their service in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, and who also say that they would serve again if asked.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Schlieve</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> veteran, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

