


<P ID="1">Selection of new city councilman scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The seven civic-minded candidates who have stepped forward to claim a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> vacancy will have just 10 minutes to impress the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The procedure for the candidate selection was outlined during <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s regular city council meeting.
</P><P ID="6">   While eight people have submitted applications for the spot left vacant by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, only seven met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>'s deadline, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Magali Betker</ENAMEX>, who <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> filed for election to the council, failed to meet <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s deadline, disqualifying her as a prospective candidate, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="8">   In the meantime, the eligible <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> candidates can look forward to meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Aug. 16</TIMEX>, in a special session.
</P><P ID="9">   The candidates' names will be put into a hat and drawn at random for the order of appearance before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said. Each candidate will then be given 10 minutes to tell the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> why they should be selected to fill the seat vacated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> will then adjourn into an executive session following the candidates' interviews to make their decision, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="11">   Seeking the seat left vacant by the 22-year old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, who has relocated due to his job, are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Theresa Hancock</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Drysdale</ENAMEX>, Ermenejildo Rodriguez, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   The candidate chosen to take the seat on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will have to seek election to the office <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> to fill out the remainder of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>'s four-year term.
</P><P ID="13">   It is expected that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will make its decision that evening, he added.
</P><P ID="14">   If not, the process may begin over, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said.
</P>





 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




