


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kirchner</ENAMEX>, Herndon plan afternoon nuptial ceremony <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 28</TIMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Kirchner</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Herndon</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Suzanne Kirchner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Douglas Herndon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will be joined in marriage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Feb. 28, 2004</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">First Lutheran Church</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> in an afternoon ceremony.
</P><P ID="5">   The bride-elect is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom and Florence Kirchner</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>. She is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Richland High School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>, where she studied education.
</P><P ID="6">   The groom-to-be is the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rose and Gary Herndon</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   He is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>. He holds a Bachelor of Science degree in agricultural business.
</P>   
   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




