
<P ID="1">Four teens vying for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> title
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Reigning</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Sophia Beltran</ENAMEX> will relinquish her crown tonight to one of four young ladies vying for her title.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Pageant</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX>. The doors will be opened to the public at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, with pageant festivities scheduled to begin half an hour later.   One thing that makes tonight's pageant special is that none of the teens vying for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> title will go away empty-handed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pageant</ENAMEX> coordinator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rachel Ruelas</ENAMEX> said all four young ladies competing for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beltran</ENAMEX>'s crown will represent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> in the coming year.   "One will be chosen <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruelas</ENAMEX>. "The other three will be either first princess, second princess or third princess."   Tonight's contestants will include 17-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marissa Angelique Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, and 16-year-olds <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayra Miranda Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adriana Maribel Cardenas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Lee Sanchez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, is a sophomore at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, as are the other three contestants. The daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iris and Pedro Lara</ENAMEX>, she now resides in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> with her grandmother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noemi Gonzalez</ENAMEX>.   With aspirations of some day traveling the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> said she intends on pursuing a career as a flight attendant. In the present, though, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> has been active in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> chapter. She also spent time at school serving as the manager of the boys basketball team. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> lists her hobbies as reading, walking and listening to music. In her spare time, she tends to the needs of her younger cousins.   The 16-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutierrez</ENAMEX> likes many of the same things teens her age enjoy doing in their "down" time. Dancing is one of the top things on her hobby list, as are watching movies, talking on the phone with her friends and just "hanging out" with her peers.   Her parents are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristobal Gutierrez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alida Miranda</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardenas</ENAMEX>, 16, perhaps is the busiest of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> contestants. Not only has she been active playing volleyball, basketball and softball for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardenas</ENAMEX> is a member of her school's 3-Sports <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletic Club</ENAMEX>. In addition, she has just wrapped up serving as vice president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> sophomore class, and was active in choir and the leadership club <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past year</TIMEX>.   The daughter of Yadira Escoto and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Celso Cardenas</ENAMEX>, she lists her hobbies as listening to music, singing and "...playing basketball at the green courts."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardenas</ENAMEX>' future plans include attending beauty school during her junior and senior years of high school. "So that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX> I can graduate from beauty school and high school," she said. Following that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardenas</ENAMEX> said she'd like to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Columbia Basin Community College</ENAMEX> to study dental hygenistry.   Cosmetology appears to be in the future plans of the 16-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>, who right now is leaning towards a career in that field. The daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ricardo and Rachel Sanchez</ENAMEX>, she, like <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cardenas</ENAMEX>, has been very active at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> is an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor Society</ENAMEX> member, and for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX> has served on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s townhall meeting committee.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX>, too, has played on the high school's volleyball and basketball teams, as well as being a member of her school's drill team. In her spare time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> enjoys listening to tejano music, watching movies, reading, playing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> basketball and visiting with her friends.   Tonight's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Pageant</ENAMEX> kicks off Community Days in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>. Admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for adults, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2</NUMEX> for students and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX> for pre-schoolers. A parade is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> through the downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> streets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, with food and game vendors set up at the city park both <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

