
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> rejects <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>'s plan for selling surplus property
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> is going to have to go back to the drawing board with plans he had for making the city's ordinance regarding the surplusing of property more reflective of current state requirements.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that the city's ordinance for surplusing property is not reflective of the current RCWs.   "This ordinance brings the city code up to date," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said of the draft he prepared for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.   Under the ordinance <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> would have to hold public hearings and set a minimum price for all property in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$50,000</NUMEX>.   The exceptions to the competitive bidding process include the city manager being allowed to negotiate the sale of real property less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,000</NUMEX>. Other exceptions include if the property is being surplused as part of an intergovernmental transfer, negotiations with adjacent landowners or part of a declared emergency.   The draft <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> presented on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> also covered the disposal of personal property. For property valued at more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>, the city manager could negotiate the sale, trade or other disposition with permission of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. For property valued at less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>, the city manager would be authorized to negotiate the sale, transfer or exchange.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> said he was concerned with how <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> would be kept notified of items disposed of that were valued below <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wouldn't have to be concerned with such items, as the city manager would be the one in charge of disposing of the property.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> was adamantly opposed to the proposal.   "This is property the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> have bought," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>. "I think we are cutting out the opportunity for our citizens to participate."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> clarified that any items the city would be disposing of, valued under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>, would be equipment that is no longer needed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said often times the city spends a lot more money advertising property to be surplused than the actual items cost.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> interjected and said just for accountability purposes he would like to see some sort of financial declaration to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> of items surplused that are valued under <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, suggesting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> see some sort of list. She also suggested the idea of bringing the amount down from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,500</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,000</NUMEX></NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Outhet</ENAMEX>, in attendance at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s meeting, agreed with the idea of letting residents see the items that are to be surplused.   "I know there are cases where city equipment is being borrowed by city employees," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> said he sees nothing wrong with the current process the city is implementing now to surplus property.   "I don't think the process is messed up right now," he said.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> said he has an enormous amount of trust in the city manager, but added the process of surplusing property doesn't take up much of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s time.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> didn't make a motion on the proposed ordinance and no official action was taken. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> did direct city staff to go back and review the proposed ordinance before bringing it back before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Pannican</ENAMEX> be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

