
<P ID="1">High school brings modern touch to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romeo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">When the audience sits down to enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> performance of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Romeo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX>, they should be prepared to see some modern-day touches. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> when the local drama students take to the stage they may be speaking Shakespearean language, but there will be no denying that the play is set in modern times.   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two and a half months</TIMEX> the more than 30 cast members have been working diligently, learning their lines and preparing to bring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romeo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX> to the stage.   Drama teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maisy Sylling</ENAMEX> noted that she tries to incorporate a Shakespearean play into the high school's repertoire at least once every four or five years in order to challenge her students to learn the language.   As for why she chose to do <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romeo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, Sylling said that she feels it's a timeless story and one with which students can relate.   However, she did decide to modernize the play a bit, replacing knives and swords with guns and holsters and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">16th century</TIMEX> garb with modern-day costumes.   "It's more powerful if it's set in present day," Sylling said, noting that it makes it easier for students to relate to.   Sylling said those sitting in the audience will have a chance to see a show that will make them think about the challenges young people face, especially if they are in love.   "I think they will be wrapped up in the story and impressed by the talent of the high school students," she said.   The cast of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Romeo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juliet</ENAMEX> is made up of about 30 students, with another 25 students working behind the scenes. Sylling said this season's play helped attract a lot of new students to the drama program. She noted that for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Magana</ENAMEX>, who will be playing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romeo</ENAMEX>, this marks the first time he has been on stage. In the past he has worked as a member of the crew. The role of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Juliet</ENAMEX> will be played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angela Marin</ENAMEX>.   The play is set to take to the stage at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 12</TIMEX> and 13, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 20</TIMEX>. The cost of admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> for students and senior citizens, and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for adults.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

