
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">PAID <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OBITUARY
LUCIO C. Martinez
Lucio “Julio” C. Martinez</ENAMEX>, 47, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 29, 2004</TIMEX>, in Seattle.
He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 5, 1956</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crispina</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX> received his education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, later moving to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 5, 1980</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Barrios</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. They made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX> worked as a farm laborer. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX> they moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Julio</ENAMEX> worked as a self-employed truck driver, hauling for various farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX> enjoyed fishing and watching sporting events, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington Huskies</ENAMEX> and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Mariners</ENAMEX>. He cherished time spent with his children, a real family man, a provider and protector.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucio</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
He is survived by his wife of 23 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; three daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lupe Loera</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Ramirez</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joel</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doralee Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Renton</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Martinez</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenna</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andres Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; and nine grandchildren. He is also survived by his mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crispina Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ariz.</ENAMEX>; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Efrin Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Paso</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leodegario Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Phoenix</ENAMEX>.
He was preceded in death by his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Martinez</ENAMEX>.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, March 4, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 5, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Wells Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 


 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

