


<P ID="1">Citizens expressed concern about yard upkeep
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Local resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Johnson</ENAMEX> came before the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to share some concerns he had about people maintaining their yards.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said he has noticed several homes and a couple of businesses in the community that have weeds and unkept lawns.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said he wasn't sure of the amount of time residents or business owners had to comply after being contacted by Property Maintenance Facilitator Bill Eikenbary before they received a ticket. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said he wants the city to look at some way of speeding up the process between warning people and citing them.
</P><P ID="6">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> said he would have city staff look into the matter and come back with a report.
</P>   






 










<P ID="7">Webmaster
</P><P ID="8">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




