
<P ID="1">Grizzly grid game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Athletic Director Bill Daley</ENAMEX> doesn't want Grizzly football fans trekking to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX>, to find an empty field.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX> said some of the schedules that were initially distributed at the beginning of the season listed this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s football game being played on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX>' home field.   "That isn't the case," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daley</ENAMEX>.   He reiterated that the game will actually be played on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> field. Game time is slated for <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>   The Grizzlies will be looking to knock off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>. A victory would square <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s record at 1-1 in the conference standings.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

