


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to probe voting machines
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="4">Republicans in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> joined Democrats <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> in criticizing the performance of the city's costly new high-tech voting system, saying that it may have disenfranchised voters in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 4</TIMEX> election. 
</P>
<P ID="5">The Republican commission scolded the city board of elections for minimizing problems with the touch-screen machines that the city purchased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.5 million</NUMEX> and asked Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> to investigate what went wrong before the machines are pressed into service again. 
</P>
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s touch-screen voting machines, which resemble laptop computers without keyboards, were supposed to simplify voting and tabulating results. But in a debut that mirrored many of the problems experienced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> in areas across the country, some voters found the machines confusing, and the reporting of vote tallies was delayed almost a day. 
</P>
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> responded that he would try to address the board's concerns. He said he has called for a public meeting of the three-member board of elections to go over the requests at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>. 
</P>
<P ID="8">"I pledge that I will answer every question as soon as I possibly can in the proper fashion," he said. </P>