


<P ID="1">Across Our <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/23/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Across the state, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>, there is one issue that the legislature hasn't dealt with for 70 years. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1934</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington State Grange</ENAMEX> sponsored an initiative to the Legislature allowing an open system of voting for candidates in the primaries. Because it was obvious that if presented to the people it would win, it was adopted by the legislature in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>. It was challenged by the political parties in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX>, but has been our state's primary law ever since.
</P><P ID="4">   Since it is evident from polls and emails that voters do not want a change, why is it coming to the Legislature <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>? I asked our <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State's</ENAMEX> chief election officer, Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX>, that question.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> was in his office having his morning cup of coffee from his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU Cougar</ENAMEX> cup, but he was ready for my questions. Remember, he said, that many of the people who first came to our state were getting away from political systems that repressed them. Some of them came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Asia</ENAMEX>, where there were <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">kings</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> or dictators. Some of them came from the eastern and mid-western parts of our country, where their were "city bosses" or organized groups that controlled the voters. The individual was not important and their vote could be denied.
</P><P ID="6">   These settlers wrote our State Constitution, purposely putting in a grassroots system allowing government to be by the people and for the people. That's why we have many elected officials, the initiative and referendum laws, and our open voting system that other states do not have.
</P><P ID="7">   In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990's</TIMEX>, a call came to the previous Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ralph Munro</ENAMEX>, from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, asking about our primary. When presented to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> voters, over <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of them approved it. The political parties in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> sued because according to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> election laws, the nominee is the standard-bearer of the party. The party lawyers argued that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> couldn't interfere with a private association. Their suit was finally upheld in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July of 2000</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Our Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> knew this could have an impact on our law, so he reluctantly agreed that if <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> could run their blanket primary yet in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 2000</TIMEX>, he would work on a change. He wanted that change to be as close to the blanket primary as possible.
</P><P ID="9">   Enter a new Secretary of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX>. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> session <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX> went to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> party caucuses to discuss possible changes, but very few in either caucus wanted anything other than our own blanket primary. If they vote one way, they would offend the party, but voting the other way would offend the people. So <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam</ENAMEX> and his staff investigated all the primary laws in other states. They found two options more like ours than others and called them by the states where they are used.
</P><P ID="10">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> system has no party registration, no party ballots, but the top two vote getters regardless of party advance to the general election. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> system has no party registration, but the voter must pick one party's ballot on which to vote. There is no record kept of which ballot the voter chose.
</P><P ID="11">   The implications are obvious. There would be changes to election outcomes in either method.
</P><P ID="12">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> method precludes cross-over voting or voting for an outstanding person of another party. Choice of ballot might occur because of a high-profile race and the other races would either have to get that vote or the voter wouldn't vote at all for those races. Only hard-core party voters would be happy with this system, which in our state is only about <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">30 percent</NUMEX> of the voters. It is discerning then that moderates in both parties may not want to vote.
</P><P ID="13">   The advantage of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> system is that people are still completely free to vote for the person of choice. However, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> or Cajun primary in some areas of our state might not really be a primary as we think of it. If two people of the same party advance to the general election, the parties would have to split their time and money, or would cause trouble in the ranks by supporting one candidate over the other. In addition, in those parts of the state, a certain number of people who always vote one ticket but who are the minority in that area would be somewhat disenfranchised. The parties do not prefer this system and would instead call for a change in election law to allow them nominating conventions.
</P><P ID="14">   The good news in all this is that there is still a chance for us to retain our well-loved system. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX> is still defending it! The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grange</ENAMEX> has joined with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX> in an appeal to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Supreme Court</ENAMEX>. We hope to hear by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 23</TIMEX> whether or not they will take the case. If they do, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sam Reed</ENAMEX> will ask for a stay on any proposed changes. We could continue to keep our current primary until the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> brings their judgment. The Legislature is preparing for both situations. They must have a law ready to pass during this session if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> will not hear us. Otherwise, the courts can dictate a primary system to us.
</P><P ID="15">   So voters, please let yourselves be heard. Call or email your legislator. How do you vote?
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerri Honeyford</ENAMEX>, wife of Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>), provides her "Across our state" column to give local constituents her take on the legislative happenings currently underway in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




