
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> grid team in 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> playoffs
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ENTIAT</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>'s dominating 35-7 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX> earned the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> football team a berth in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> playoffs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, which lost its first two league games of the season but bounced back to win six straight in conference play, will open the postseason against the Lind-Ritzville Broncos. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX>' first round <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> playoff opponent won the Northeast 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> with a perfect 9-0 record. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> (6-2, 7-3) enters the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> playoffs as the No. 3 seed out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX>.   Mabton Coach D.J. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said the site and date of his team's first round playoff game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ritzville</ENAMEX> is not yet decided.   He and the Ritzville coach have already swapped game films. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said he is optimistic his club can give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Broncos</ENAMEX> a stiff challenge.   "They're not a bad team," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said of the unbeaten Broncos. "Speed wise, I think we match up pretty well with them. But I think we're going to be more physical than them."   In knocking off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> showed it is a team that is ready for the postseason. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> not only ran the ball effectively, they also weren't afraid to put it up in the air.   Mabton QB Ryan Harris completed 11-of-21 passes against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX>, serving up only one interception while throwing for 174 yards.   "Those aren't bad numbers for high school football," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan</ENAMEX> is making good decisions on the field. He's progressively gotten better as the season has gone along," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' targets <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moises Gutierrez</ENAMEX>, who hauled in five passes for 77 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutierrez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pablo Sanchez</ENAMEX>, who caught two passes for 32 yards and also rushed for 60 yards on 13 carries, each caught a touchdown pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harris</ENAMEX>.   On the ground, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> tallied 309 yards against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX>. Junior Ray Elizondo was the workhorse for the Vikes, taking 20 hand-offs from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harris</ENAMEX> and picking up a season best 167 yards.   "It was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>'s biggest game of the season," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>, explaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX> didn't adjust to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s dives up the middle. "So we just kept feeding the ball to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>," he said.   The reason Elizondo had so much room in the middle to run, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>, was because of the play of the Vikes' offensive line.   "Our O-line did a great job of taking care of business," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said. "They played very hard."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> opened the scoring <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> on a 5-yard TD pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harris</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> in the first quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> increased their lead to 14-0 in the second period, on a 16-yard touchdown run by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Zavala</ENAMEX>, who carried the ball 11 times <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, tallying 59 yards in the process.   After <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX> picked off a <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> pass, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s 22-yard line, the home team notched its only score of the night to draw to within 14-7.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> ended any suspense that might have been left, though, when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> punched in a couple of TD's in the third quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> scored on runs of 4 and 2 yards, respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gutierrez</ENAMEX>'s five-yard touchdown catch in the final quarter accounted for the final 35-7 score.   Defensively, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said his Vikes turned in another splendid performance.   "Other than <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX>'s opening drive, when they got to our 4-yard line, and the one drive after they intercepted our quarterback, they never really challenged us again," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

