


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> lab now testing water for coliform
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">In the past, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Hall has served as a drop-off point for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> residents who wanted their drinking water tested for impurities. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Weekly</ENAMEX>, city officials would send the water samples brought in to city hall to a lab in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   That procedure is changing.
</P><P ID="5">   Because a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> agricultural laboratory is now certified to test for coliform bacteria, one of the most commonly tested-for impurities in drinking water, city leaders have opted to have all such tests done locally. The same option is open to local residents who want to use the services of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> lab.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Works</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Ott</ENAMEX> said local citizens, both those living within the city limits and rural residents, who want only coliform bacteria testing done, now have the option of dropping off their drinking water samples at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ag Health Laboratories, Inc.</ENAMEX>, located at 445 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barnard Blvd.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Those who are seeking to have their drinking water tested for other impurities, though, will need to use the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX> lab or a lab of their own choice.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ott</ENAMEX> said even though city hall will no longer be a drop-off site for those wanting their samples sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX> lab, there is still a place in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> that will collect all samples on a weekly basis.
</P><P ID="8">   "The new drop-off site is the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> operations office, at 625 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midvale Road</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ott</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   He explained that drinking water samples earmarked for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Analytical, Inc.</ENAMEX> lab can be dropped off at the Port office on Mondays, between <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> All samples are scheduled to reach the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union Gap</ENAMEX> lab by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cascade Analytical</ENAMEX> has made available at the Port office sample containers, analysis request forms and sampling instructions.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ott</ENAMEX> said the city has opted to have all of its coliform bacteria testing done at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> lab because city leaders believe in the philosophy of shopping at home whenever possible.
</P>   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




