


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds rush past Wildcat
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady 'Hounds finished the regular season with a quick victory over the Toppenish Wildcats <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The Lady 'Hounds won over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> in three with scores of 25-5, 25-4, 25-6.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> finished CWAC play undefeated. The Lady 'Hounds won all 12 of their league matches by 3-0 scores.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> marked the first time all season he has played every girl on the team during a match.
</P><P ID="8">   "They played pretty well," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of his team's performance. "They are stepping up and getting ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX>."
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team is trying to step up the intensity as they get ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   "We wanted to get the intensity of our group up for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX>," he said. "That's where our focus is."
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">underclassmen Christine Penwell</ENAMEX>, Logan Desserault and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danika Martinez</ENAMEX> played well for the team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   "They did a good job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Penwell</ENAMEX> finished the night with 2 kills and 1 block, Desserault had 1 kill, 1 ace and 5 service points, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> had 2 service points.
</P><P ID="14">   Also doing well for the Lady 'Hounds was sophomore setter Chante Bottineau. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said she has been playing really well all season. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bottineau</ENAMEX> had 3 kills, 12 service points and 19 assists against the Wildcats.
</P><P ID="15">   Also helping the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team push past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danelle Cowan</ENAMEX>, who had 7 kills, 2 aces, 8 digs and 2 blocks for the night, as well as Valetina Solis with 9 kills, 1 ace and 2 blocks, Kealey Johnston with 3 kills, 6 service points and 10 digs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> with 1 kill and 4 digs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> with 4 kills, 5 aces and 10 service points, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Clapp</ENAMEX> with 4 service points and 2 digs, and Tonhya Wysong with 14 digs.
</P><P ID="16">   The Lady 'Hounds (12-0) will play their first postseason match in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Nov. 4</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> against Cascade. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team will be playing for a berth to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>, explaining that four of the eight teams in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX> will move on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament.
</P>





 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




