


<P ID="1">School crosswalk volunteers needed
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Are you looking for something to do with your spare time? Consider volunteering as a school crosswalk guard.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Resource</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chico Rodriguez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> is currently seeking crosswalk volunteers.
</P><P ID="5">   "We need persons with time to devote to the safety of children before and after school," he explained.
</P><P ID="6">   People interested in crosswalk guard positions will be asked to help with morning crosswalk duty, from 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX>, or afternoon duty, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> explained.
</P><P ID="7">   "We have a critical need for such volunteers," he said.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> said the job is ideal for retired or semi-retired persons or anyone with extra time and a desire to help protect the children of the community.
</P><P ID="9">   Those interested are encouraged to call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> at 837-6211.
</P>   






 










<P ID="10">Webmaster
</P><P ID="11">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




