


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gibson</ENAMEX> deserves to be elected
</P>

<P ID="5">Many people don't give the candidates for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> judge a thought until they are in the voting booth. You are different, you are looking for information and reading this letter to the editor.
</P>

<P ID="6">We have had a chance to work with, and get to know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine Gibson</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine</ENAMEX> listens, he gets to the point, is timely and fair. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine</ENAMEX> has 26 years of courtroom experience and has acted as a judge pro-tem, or as an arbiter, in dozens of cases. He teaches ethics at bar association seminars at the county and state levels.
</P>

<P ID="7">In a recent peer survey, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine Gibson</ENAMEX> was voted 90 to 7 over his opponent to be "Best Qualified Overall to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> Judge."
</P>

<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blaine Gibson</ENAMEX> has the skills, the experience and the respect needed to be <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Superior Court</ENAMEX> judge.
</P>

<P ID="9">You cared enough to read this, please care enough to vote.
</P>

<P ID="10">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bernie and DiAnn Schutt</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="11">Your destiny
is in your hands
</P>

<P ID="12">I always admired <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state when they had <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>" Magnuson and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Henry</ENAMEX> "Scoop" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> in the "Place of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX>." They not only looked out for the best interests of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, but also <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>, especially <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boeing</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> needs and yearns for another <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX> or Scoop.
</P>

<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> belongs to the minority party and does not have a seat at the "table of power." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty</ENAMEX> votes her party line and is an obstructionist, a divider instead of a uniter in regard to the general good of the people. From your best memory, what has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty</ENAMEX> done for you?
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> has a seat at the "table of power" in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and also will have one in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, likely of his choosing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> is a uniter and has proved that by getting things done. The more I know about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, the better I like him. I see another "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maggie</ENAMEX>" or another "Scoop" in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> if the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> will give him a chance to prove himself.
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty</ENAMEX> hasn't displayed any of these attributes in all the years she has been in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>. Your destiny is in your hands.
</P>

<P ID="16">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Hauf</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Juneton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="17">Work appreciated on park programs
</P>

<P ID="18">If you read the letters to the editor, you probably notice that I am thanking a lot of people and businesses in our community for their involvement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and Recreation programs and facilities.
</P>

<P ID="19">Due to the fact that the budget for the department has been cut by <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> (<NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$156,730</NUMEX>) over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two years</TIMEX>, we are in need of volunteers helping us with programs and maintenance of our parks and facilities. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, the department had over 625 volunteers working more than 29,000 hours in programs, youth sports, special events and maintenance.
</P>

<P ID="20">I hear a few citizens tell me that they pay too much in taxes and do not use the programs, parks and facilities. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>, there were 17,000 participants in our recreation programs and classes for youth, adults and senior citizens. 35,500 used the swimming pool, and approximately 37,500 rented parks and facilities. These numbers total 90,000 individuals who were involved in the programs and facilities that are offered by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>. Over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX> the department is providing more programs and maintenance with less funding.
</P>

<P ID="21">Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> hosted a softball tournament with 20 teams playing. Of the 20 teams, 16 traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to compete in the tournament. Each team consists of at least 11 players. If you figure that some players have family that came with them to the tournament, you can guess that each team had approximately 50 people attending the tournament. Sixteen teams multiplied by 50 people equals 800 people. If over the three-day tournament each person spends <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per day on food, gas and lodging expenses, this would total <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$60,000</NUMEX> in business to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The city will expend approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32,000</NUMEX> to maintain this park for the entire year. This one example shows the need and rationale to continue support for the parks and recreation programs and facilities.
</P>

<P ID="22">The city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is very fortunate to have the parks and facilities within our community. The city council has been very supportive and proactive in maintaining the current assets and expanding with new parks and facilities, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Centennial Square</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX> and the new community center.
</P>

<P ID="23">With <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> having come to a close, I want to thank all the staff that has worked to make our parks, pool and programs successful. I would like to also thank the members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Recreation Commission</ENAMEX> for the time and effort that they volunteer to serve on the commission.
</P>

<P ID="24">I appreciate the work that all of the staff has done over the past months to make all our programs and facilities successful.
</P>

<P ID="25">/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Stiles</ENAMEX>, Director, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>
</P>

 






 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




