


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,500</NUMEX> expenditure for aquatics center project
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - When <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX> it approved spending almost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12,000</NUMEX> to make improvements to the pathway that surrounds <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, council members approved another expenditure. This time city council voted to allocate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,500</NUMEX> to help pay for architectural services and election costs associated with the proposal for a new aquatic center in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The funds being distributed by the city are being taken from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$71,000</NUMEX> in additional revenue that has become available in the current expense fund. According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX>, the additional funds are from utility tax revenues that are running ahead of estimates.
</P><P ID="7">   When the council was working to create the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last fall</TIMEX>, each of the department heads submitted a list of one-time capital items they would like purchased if funds were available. At the time, council decided to wait to make any decisions on the purchases until they had a better idea of what the revenue estimates would be for the year.
</P><P ID="8">   After making a decision <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX> to spend money on refurbishing the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX> pathway, council members decided to wait until they discovered the fate of Initiative 864, which would have had a significant impact on the city's budget. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> noted that the initiative did not make the ballot.
</P><P ID="9">   When council met <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> offered them several options of what they could do with the additional funds. He noted that they could simply save the money until it is needed to offset budget issues that have arisen since the passage of initiates like I-695, which he estimates will be just several years down the road. He said council could also choose to simply go down the list of capital items that were submitted by the department heads, and choose the items they wanted to purchase until they had gone through the additional funds.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Helen Darr</ENAMEX> said she would like to see council hold onto the money. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Robert Morales</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darr</ENAMEX>, with the exception of putting the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,500</NUMEX> aside for the aquatics center.
</P><P ID="11">   During the meeting, council voted to approve the expenditure for the aquatics center, with the exception of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Darr</ENAMEX> who voted against the measure.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that the funds will be used to pay for an architect to take a look at the aquatics center project and divide it into certain individual pieces that can be fit together to create an aquatics center that will be deemed affordable by voters.
</P><P ID="13">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




