
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Agenda</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Agenda</ENAMEX>
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 12</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>, 401 Homer Street.
</P> 
<P ID="4">1. Consent: Approve minutes of the regular meeting of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 21</TIMEX> (Motion to approve).
2. Consent: Approval of a list of vouchers for payment in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$567,497.50</NUMEX>. Copies of the vouchers are available at the office of the finance department for review.
3. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member attendance. Percentage attendance based on 35 regular <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meetings from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 14, 2003</TIMEX>, to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 12, 2004</TIMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">A.</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 80 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">B.</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 97 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 80 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">D. Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 94 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">E. Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 94 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">F. Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 97 percent</NUMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">G. Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">- 94 percent</NUMEX>.
4. Reports to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> - none.
5. Acceptance of the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> and a discussion of the process for appointment of his successor.
6. Discussion with regard to a request from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> for the sum of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,500</NUMEX> as matching funds for a grant the chamber has received from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Bank</ENAMEX>.
7. Consideration of a resolution declaring as surplus one Hewitt-Packard plotter (Motion to approve Resolution No. 2004-36).
8. Consideration of a resolution of support for the 3/10th of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> sales taxes to be used for financing law and justice programs (Motion to approve Resolution No. 2004-33).
9. Consideration of a resolution approving an agreement for engineering services for the wastewater treatment plant (Motion to approve Resolution No. 2004-34).
10. Consideration of a resolution approving an agreement for engineering services with regard to water resources (Motion to approve Resolution No. 2004-35).
11. Consideration of a resolution approving an amendment to the six-year street plan (Motion to approve Resolution No. 2004-37).
12. Review and discussion pertaining to the revised cross-connection ordinance.
13. Items for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agenda for the regular meeting of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, July 19</TIMEX>.
14. Unscheduled appearances by citizens. Note: Unscheduled appearances by citizens also appears before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> takes action on the consent agenda.
15. Reports from department heads/responses to citizen inquiries.
16. Items from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members.
17. Executive session.
18. Other items.
19. Adjournment.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

