
<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/2/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Bueno</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> isn't shy about telling people his age. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> gladly will say that he is 3, going on 33.   What has kept this long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> native so young at heart is his job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> is a classroom assistant with the EPIC childhood education program in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. His duties as a classroom assistant means he helps the head teacher prepare for each school day.   EPIC provides pre-school services to children ages 3-1/2 to 5 years old. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> said EPIC tries to fill the program with older children first and then if it can't it turns to the younger applicants.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> must really enjoy his job because he has been doing it for 14 years.   "I first started as a volunteer," he said. "Then I applied for an open position."   What keeps <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> at his job?   "I enjoy the interaction I have with the children and the families," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>. "That is what has kept me there."   Besides the children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> said the best part of going to work is being around his co-workers.   "It is kind of like my home away from home," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>. "The environment is very friendly."   Just how many children has <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> dealt with over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 14 years</TIMEX>? <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> took some time to count some of his past pupils and came up with 564 children he has helped prepare for the public school system.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> said his favorite part of seeing former students is being able to look at the progress each child has made.   "Looking at them makes me feel old," laughed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>.   When he is not at work, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> is busy taking care of his family. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX>, have three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Devina</ENAMEX>, 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Emilio</ENAMEX>, 3, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jonathan</ENAMEX>, 1, with another child on the way.   In his spare time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, enjoys reading books and collecting toys.   "I also try to spend as much time as I can with my kids," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>.   Right now, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> is splitting time between his family, work and attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>, where he is scheduled to earn his Associate's degree at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of winter</TIMEX> quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> will have an Associate's degree in pre-school education with an option in special education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> then plans to obtain a Bachelor's degree in education.   "My goal in life is to either work with pre-school children or be a kindergarten teacher," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> said what he enjoys about working with younger children is that they use their imagination in learning.   If there was a hard part to his job, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> said it is saying goodbye to the children at the end of each school year.   "I always feel like we have accomplished a lot in our nine months working with the kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX> always tries to teach the students he works with the power of thinking positive.   "I hope they learn from me to never say never when trying to accomplish a task," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bueno</ENAMEX>. "I try to let my kids know to just try your best."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

