
<P ID="1">Sports Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/24/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Football/cheer camp scheduled
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> is offering its annual football/cheerleading camp to boys and girls ages 6 to 12 on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, July 8</TIMEX>.
To be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rich Leenhouts Stadium</ENAMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> campus, the event will kick off at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> Football participants will compete in a punt, throw and sprint contest. Those interested in cheerleading will have the opportunity to learn moves, jumps and cheers from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> cheer squad.
Parents can register their child on-site, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 p.m.</TIMEX> The cost to participate is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1</NUMEX>. Ribbons will be awarded to each participant.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Wild cow milkers, mutton busters, mini-bull riders urged to sign up
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - Toppenish Pow Wow & Rodeo officials will be taking sign-ups for wild cow milking, mutton busting and mini-bull riding this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> rodeo will be staged <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1-3</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Cowboys</ENAMEX> and cowgirls interested in the wild cow milking, mutton busting and mini-bull riding competitions must register to compete <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 26-28</TIMEX>, by calling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Wells</ENAMEX> (865-5077) between <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
The mini-bull riding event is new to the rodeo <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. Each of the three nights, six mini-bucking bulls will be loaded into the chutes during the rodeo's intermission, giving youngsters a chance to ride like the professionals.
The entry fee for each mini-bull rider is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>, and only six entries will be accepted for each night. Entrants must be between the ages of 9 and 14. A buckle will be awarded to the winner each night.
For wild cow milkers there will be two divisions—an open category and a 40 and over category. Engraved Montana Silversmith buckles will be given to the winners in both divisions. Entry fees are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100</NUMEX> per team. Entries will be limited to six teams per night.
Aspiring rough stock riders, 3 years of age and up, are invited to sign up for the mutton busting each night. Participants must weigh <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">50 pounds</NUMEX> or less. Trophies will be given to each rider. The entry fee is the price of admission to the rodeo.
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

