


<P ID="1">Death Notices and Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/29/2003</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">PAID OBITUARY
</P>

<P ID="4">DEATH NOTICE
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CANDELARIA ALCAZAR-GONZALEZ</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Candelaria Alcazar-Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, 43, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Dec. 24, 2003</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Healthcare Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2, 1960</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agustin</ENAMEX> and Irinea (Sotelo) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. She received her early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> she moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, where she made her home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January of 1997</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genaro Alcazar</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Church</ENAMEX> of Jesus Christ of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Latter Day</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Saints</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Following their marriage they made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. She worked for Independence Warehouse.
</P>

<P ID="8">She is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Genaro Alcazar</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; one son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agustin Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; one daughter, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cindy Larios</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vicente</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ohio</ENAMEX>; one granddaughter; her father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agustin Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>; four sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clementina Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beatriz Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paula Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, both of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Concha Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agustin Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">She was preceded in death by her mother.
</P>

<P ID="10">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Dec. 29, 2003</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, with a Rosary to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Dec. 30, 2003</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, with burial to follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens. Jones Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P>

 


<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JAMES FORREST MAULDEN</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="12"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Forrest Maulden</ENAMEX>, 85, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> resident died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Dec. 22, 2003</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kennewick General Hospital</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="13">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2, 1918</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Trout</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">La.</ENAMEX>, to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James L.</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Pearl (Nugent) Maulden</ENAMEX>. Later that year the family moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> and engaged in farming.
</P>

<P ID="14">After graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Toppenish High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> he attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State College</ENAMEX>, receiving a Bachelor of Science degree in agriculture-economics in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1941</TIMEX>. He was then employed by Safeway as a vegetable and fruit buyer in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, Seattle area, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Visalia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Carlos</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="15">On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 5, 1942</TIMEX> he married Luvena Arnett of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Salmon</ENAMEX> and he was drafted into the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September 1942</TIMEX>. After finishing Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Candidate School</ENAMEX> he was assigned as mess officer for a general hospital in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Walla Walla</ENAMEX>, which was later moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Medford</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> and then to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">southern England</ENAMEX> for the duration of WWII. He attained the rank of captain prior to discharge in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 1945</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16">In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February 1946</TIMEX> the family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, and Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maulden</ENAMEX> was employed by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Perham Fruit Corporation</ENAMEX>. He later became manager of their packing plant and orchards in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> area. He retired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="17">Funeral services were held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Dec. 29, 2003</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, with burial in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> cemetery immediately following. In lieu of flowers, donations may be made to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Shriners Children’s Hospital</ENAMEX>, PO Box 2472, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WA</ENAMEX> 99210-2472 or to a favorite charity.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="18">PAID OBITUARY
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">FLORENCE ELLEN OKERSTROM</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="20"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Florence Ellen Okerstrom</ENAMEX>, 87, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Dec. 28, 2003</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Healthcare</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="21">She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 28, 1916</TIMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Augusta and Edna Okerstrom</ENAMEX>. She lived all of her life in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> as part of a family that raised cattle and farmed in the Wapato area, raised crops in the Zillah area and ran a jersy dairy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="22">She enjoyed traveling in her younger years and in later years was very busy volunteering for numerous organizations for which she received many certificates of thanks. She was very active in the Pomona and SunnyValley Granges, serving as secretary/treasurer for close to 30 years for them.
</P>  
<P ID="23">She was also involved in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Golden Agers</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Senior Citizens group. She belonged to numerous card clubs and loved to play pinochle.
</P>

<P ID="24">She is survived by two nieces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wanda Clark</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna Feldman</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bothel</ENAMEX>. She will be greatly missed by her many, many friends.
</P>

<P ID="25">She was preceded in death by her father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Agusta Okerstrom</ENAMEX>; her mother <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edna</ENAMEX>; step-father <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gus Delmonico</ENAMEX>; and two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clinton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edwin Okerstrom</ENAMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="26">At Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Okerstrom’s</ENAMEX> request no funeral services will be held. Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Dec. 30, 2003</TIMEX>, from 1 until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Internment will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, under the services of Jones Funeral Home.
</P>

<P ID="27">Gifts in her memory can be made to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian School</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="28">Webmaster
</P><P ID="29">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




