


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzales Housing Authority</ENAMEX> board member
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/20/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesse Gonzales</ENAMEX> received the full support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to serve on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority Board</ENAMEX> of Directors.
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX> was appointed to the board by Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> support.
</P><P ID="5">   "He is excited about joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Housing Authority</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>. "This appointment is forwarded to you (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>) with my full confidence."
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX> is the current manager of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> branch of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> of the West. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> cited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX>' vast financial experience as an asset for him to be able to serve on the board of directors.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzales</ENAMEX>' term on the housing authority board of directors will expire on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 7, 2008</TIMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




