


<P ID="1">Briefs
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/28/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4">Children’s theater performance set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5">Community residents are invited to view "Funny Sunny Fairy Tales" this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 30</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> performance at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium will be staged by a children's theatrical group, sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="7"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s play was written and is being directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Berkompas</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> parks and rec staff member.
</P>

<P ID="8">Admission to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s on-stage production is free. The play is approximately 30 minutes long.
</P>

<P ID="9">Theater-goers are invited to stay after the presentation and visit with cast and crew while enjoying refreshments.
</P>

 


<P ID="10">Cal Ripken Baseball meeting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Wednesday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="11">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area Cal Ripken Baseball group will be holding a parent meeting this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Blaine</ENAMEX> technology building on Custer Avenue.
</P>

<P ID="12">At the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 28</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> meeting an election will be held to select the 2004-05 board of directors.
</P>

 


<P ID="13"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> re-appointed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment Board</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="14">Retired <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Craig Miller</ENAMEX> was re-appointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX>, per Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>'s recommendation during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting.
</P>

<P ID="15"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> has previously served on the city advisory board.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




