
<P ID="1">Grizzlies sink the Pirate ship
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/17/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The best way to describe what the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> boys soccer team did to 4A <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s non-league season opener might be to say the Grizzlies took it to another level.   Amazing ball movement, reacting to every play, backing up each other on the field. All of these vital elements to playing a successful soccer game were present <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> for the Grizzlies as they shut out <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Pirates</ENAMEX> 7-0.   "It is the same system as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Juan Pineda</ENAMEX>, who took the Grizzlies to the 3A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> tournament <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> for the first time in a decade. "We are doing the same good things we were doing at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of last year</TIMEX>, but we are doing them at a different pace."   The first half of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s game saw both teams trying to dictate the pace of the game. The Grizzlies finally broke through when Junior Martinez, the reigning <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> player of the year, scored at the 21st minute. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Martinez</ENAMEX> would add another goal right before the end of the first half at the 36th minute. Teammate German Torres had the other first half goal, coming at the 26th minute.   Leading 3-0, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Galvan</ENAMEX> took away any hopes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Pirates</ENAMEX> had of coming back when he scored a goal at the 54th minute of the second half. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teammates Miguel Galvan</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario de la Torre</ENAMEX> all scored in the final couple of minutes to give the Grizzlies the 7-0 shutout victory to start the season.   Grizzly keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnny Hernandez</ENAMEX>, who had nine saves on the day, preserved the shutout victory for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> when he stopped a penalty kick with 16 minutes to play in the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said he was very pleased with how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> played in the box for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hernandez</ENAMEX> showed <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> he was capable of replacing the big shoes of former Grizzly keeper <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David Ruelas</ENAMEX>, who graduated after last season.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> had 12 shots on goal. Acension Abundez had 12 saves in what was a busy night for the Pirate goalie.   The Grizzlies had 14 shots on goal.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said he is working on implementing a rotating system that has everyone involved in the game. The system would involve players moving up in different spots on the field while other teammates fall back to fill the voids.   "We kept improving our play during the game while the other team couldn't stand our pressure," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said his players still need to work on picking up players faster. The Grizzly coach said during the game <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Pirates</ENAMEX> were able to move players around quickly and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> struggled to find them on the field.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX> said he was very impressed with his team's outing for the first game of the season.   "I think the difference was our team came out hungry," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pineda</ENAMEX>. "The difference is now (compared with last season) they are playing by instinct. This is the next level."   The Grizzlies (1-0) are off until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 23</TIMEX>, when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> travels to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> game. The league game will be played at the football stadium.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

