
<P ID="1">Teacher looks for gaps in curriculum to help build better students
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">During her principal internship <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lori Froese</ENAMEX> determined that her calling maybe wasn't heading a school, but rather crunching the numbers and looking for patterns in student test scores to see where there are gaps in the curriculum.   "During my internship I found that I really enjoy working with the numbers and data, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Davis</ENAMEX>, my mentor, gave me the freedom to do so," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX>, who is the new assessment coordinator for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>.   At the end of the school year she made a proposal to Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>, who approved creating the new position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> competed against several others during the hiring process, but in the end was hired.   For eight years <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> was employed as a teacher in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>. Four of the years she taught sixth grade and the other four she had a fourth grade classroom, so she knows about the testing processes the students undergo every year.   She has had classrooms of students take the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) test, as well as a plethora of other tests used to assess students.   Her familiarity with the tests and testing process has helped her as she looks at test results from the WASL, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> (Measures of Academic Progress), Iowa Test of Basic Skills and other tests used to measure students' progress.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> explained that the district decided that now that it has all the information, it hired her to find a way to use it and make it user friendly.   "I do a lot of graphing so administrators have a visual and it makes more sense," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX>.   Part of what she does is a correlation study between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> testing results and WASL results.   "We hope to predict individuals who have a chance of passing WASL but maybe need a little extra help," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX>.   By comparing the two tests, she hopes they will be able to see gaps in the curriculum that will help students in the testing processes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> explained that both the WASL and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX> tests cover broad areas and have several strands to them. She said that by comparing strands and finding trends they can find weaknesses and fill it with supplemental material.   To start off, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> is looking at the test scores as a whole and the trends. In the future she hopes to be as individualized as being able to find individual students consistently scoring low and finding them the extra help they need to pass the tests.   Although right now <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> is working primarily with school district principals, she hopes to work more with parents and students in the future.   "I hope to work more with them so they have a better understanding of why we're taking all these tests," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX>.   Her job description has her working with students from kindergarten through 12th grade, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> said most of the assessments occur between third and 10th grades.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Froese</ENAMEX> misses working with students, but she said she is enjoying her new position.   Currently, she is mapping the school district's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grade Level Expectation</ENAMEX>'s (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GLE</ENAMEX>), which are tasks students should be able to complete at each grade level. She explained that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GLE</ENAMEX>'s are used to focus instruction.   She hopes this will be the first step to refining the curriculum, meeting the needs and doing away with gaps and deficits in the learning materials used by the school district.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

