


<P ID="1"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> session ends with a flourish
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> of a legislative session usually sees a flurry of activity as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> try to agree on key issues before session ends. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> was no different as the Legislature reached compromise on the supplemental operating, capital and transportation budgets, and a replacement for the blanket primary.
</P><P ID="4">   ? The supplemental operating budget was passed 34-15 by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> and 84-12 by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>. There were several reasons why I voted for the budget. It adds roughly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$145 million</NUMEX> to the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23.2 billion</NUMEX> 2003-05 operating budget. It leaves more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300 million</NUMEX> in the state's emergency reserve account, contains no tax increases or "budget gimmicks," and is one of the slowest-growing budgets in state history. Because it leaves a sizable reserve, it helps minimize the budget situation we'll face <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> when the state is expected to have a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 billion</NUMEX> revenue shortfall due to necessary spending increases in necessary services and programs. However, the budget kept our commitment to the state's most vulnerable by fully funding nursing homes, supporting community mental health, enhancing domestic violence services and shelters, enhancing agencies on aging funding to lower the caseworker-patient ratio for in-home long-term care, and providing more employment and day services for people with developmental disabilities.
</P><P ID="5">   ? Since <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s unemployment rate is still one of the highest in the nation, it's important to protect existing jobs in our state, as well as helping to create more jobs. Early this session, the Legislature did this by extending certain tax credits to high-tech businesses. The bill (ESHB 2546) requires annual surveys regarding job creation and retention to ensure that these tax credits do as planned. We also passed a measure (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SSB</ENAMEX> 6240) extending the rural county sales and use tax deferral and B&O tax credit for software job creation. Under the bill, a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> B&O tax credit is available for each new software manufacturing or computer-programming job created in a rural county.
</P><P ID="6">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s aluminum smelting industry has declined in recent years because of lower aluminum prices in the global aluminum commodities market and local increases in the price of electricity, a major cost driver in aluminum prices. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, the industry in the state employed over 5,300 people. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, only 2,200 persons were employed. Late this session, the Legislature passed a measure (2SSB 6304) providing tax incentives to protect jobs in the aluminum industry through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2006</TIMEX>. Under the bill, smelters must submit annual reports for accountability. This measure should help our aluminum companies.
</P><P ID="7">   ? The passage of the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$202 million</NUMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> supplemental capital construction budget marks the first time in state history that a capital budget has passed by the Legislature without new bonds. The capital budget includes funds for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Klickitat County</ENAMEX> to address the tire pile problem near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   ? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the Legislature was forced to adopt an alternative to the state's blanket primary when it was ruled unconstitutional in federal court. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> agreed on an alternative (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESB</ENAMEX> 6453) called the Top Two system, which has one ballot at the primary election on which all candidates appear. The two candidates in each race who receive the most votes, regardless of party, advance to the general election. This means it's possible for two candidates from the same party to wind up in a general election. The bill will insert the Montana-style primary if the Top Two system is thrown out by the courts. Gov. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Locke</ENAMEX> has hinted that he might veto the Top Two system, which would give us the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> system, in which voters would have to pick one party's ballot, although their privacy would be protected.
</P><P ID="9">   ? On the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> of session, the Legislature passed a bill (ESHB 2460) reforming the small-market health insurance system. The bill was expected to help provide more affordable health care coverage for thousands of workers employed at small businesses in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>. The final version of the bill made some changes to the state's insurance mandates but still requires any product to cover "every category of provider." Some believe removing this mandate is the key to driving down health insurance costs for small employers.
</P><P ID="10">   ? <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, the Legislature unanimously passed a bill (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SB</ENAMEX> 6615) I prime-sponsored that encourages employment of injured workers with developmental disabilities.
</P><P ID="11">   ? One disappointment was the failure for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> to agree on a liability reform package. This also is known as tort reform. A proposal (ESSB 5728) passed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> sought to make changes to medical malpractice liability modeled after <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX>'s law.
</P><P ID="12">   ? <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skamania County</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> is celebrating its 150th anniversary. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> recognized this special occasion by passing a resolution that I introduced. The resolution recognized the rich history of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Skamania County</ENAMEX> and acknowledged the 150th birthday celebration on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 9</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Stevenson</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> (R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>) serves the 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Legislative District</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




