


<P ID="1">City council learns some are against privatizing public works
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> has said all along that it can't hurt to at least hear presentations from different companies about privatizing the city's public works department in order to save taxpayers money.
</P><P ID="5">   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> heard an earful from several residents who adamantly oppose privatizing city services.
</P><P ID="6">   The city is currently in talks with three companies about possibly privatizing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s public works department. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is expected to address the matter <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later this year</TIMEX> or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early next year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Epps</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> he has spoken with a number of residents who are against privatizing city services.
</P><P ID="8">   "If you have researched this at all, you have found a lot of towns with problems," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> cited the fact that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Bremerton</ENAMEX> recently took back operation of its water and sewer system from a private firm. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX> officials took back the system because the private firm left operations in disarray. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> said residents in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX> had to endure a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> increase in water and sewer rates every year during the four years the service was operated by a private firm.
</P><P ID="10">   "We don't want to take this out of house," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> in regards to privatizing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s public works department.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> cautioned <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members that they are going to meet opposition to privatizing city services.
</P><P ID="12">   "I think you are going to find a lot of people irate over it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jay Alvarez</ENAMEX> expressed to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that operating such services as water and sewer should fall under the responsibility of the government.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> said that privatizing the public works department may lead to a lower quality of water being distributed to city residents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> also said he feels that national companies don't have a stake in the smaller communities, such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and won't do as good a job.
</P><P ID="15">   "You guys have a duty here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "We definitely need to look into this deeper."
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> said she has received a number of negative comments from community members about privatization.
</P><P ID="17">   "I haven't had one citizen approach me who thinks it is a good idea," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>. "The citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> are not pleased and we need to listen to our citizens."
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> pointed out the city's governing body is simply considering options, and asked how does it hurt to hear presentations from the different companies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said the city has no idea what the cost benefits to privatizing the public works department will be for residents.
</P><P ID="19">   "The way to know is to have (these) firms make a presentation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will be looking for citizen input when the time arrives.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Martinez</ENAMEX>, who is a small business owner in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, said she likes being able to know she can quickly get the assistance of the local public works department and doesn't want to see a private firm come into town. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said she doesn't think it is fair to the employees of the public works department, their families, residents and business owners to be in a waiting mode while decisions are being made about privatizing the public works department.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Johnson</ENAMEX>, teamsters representative for the public works department, presented <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with a letter from the wastewater manager in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX> dated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 13, 2004</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> read the letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, detailing how privatization would be a mistake. The letter detailed how the residents of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> would be the "losers" if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> did decide to privatize the public works department.
</P><P ID="23">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> told the audience that staff is currently dealing with the matter and will be making a presentation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at a later date. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said at which time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will be taking into consideration all of the public's concerns about privatization.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Epps</ENAMEX> ended the discussion by saying this won't be the last time <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> hears from the public about privatizing city services.
</P>





 










<P ID="25">Webmaster
</P><P ID="26">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




