


<P ID="1">City officials still undecided on where to build skate park
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">At this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> moved forward with a grant application process to help fund the construction of a skate park at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Don Stiles</ENAMEX> is preparing a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$66,500</NUMEX> grant application to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interagency Committee for Outdoor Recreation</ENAMEX>. If the city is successful in obtaining the grant it will use the money to help construct a skate park at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   But, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> is not entirely sold on building the skate park at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView</ENAMEX>, which the city took possession of from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> recently.
</P><P ID="7">   At its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> meeting, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> suggested the possibility of moving the skate park to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX> to complement the newly built community center and to make the facility easier for local youths to access. During the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> meeting, it was determined staff would look into the possibility of moving the skate park to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill</ENAMEX> on the site of the battered tennis court facilities.
</P><P ID="8">   At this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that changing the site of the skate park could ruin the city's chances of obtaining the grant it is applying for. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> also told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> the city would still have to place the tennis courts at some other location in town to ensure such a facility was in its system.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> is scheduled to make his presentation to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Interagency Committee for Outdoor Recreation</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 17</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said too much work has gone into the grant application to change things now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> did say there is the possibility the city could change the location of the skate park after it obtained the grant, but added he was saying that with no certainty. The parks director added that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> along with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> have been working on developing the skate park for six years and he doesn't want to see the opportunity slip away.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> expressed a change of heart this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX>, saying she talked with several youngsters the previous week and asked them where they want to see the skate park. She said the youngsters told her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX> because it would be easier for them to get there.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> informed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that it would more than likely have to return some of the money that was donated by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> if the site was switched to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> said money was donated by different entities in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> to help fund the skate park at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sunny View Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stiles</ENAMEX> has already spoken with several people in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> who have said they want their money back if the skate park goes to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   Councilman John Torch suggested the city use money from other avenues to fund any shortfall with the skate park if people from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> want their money back.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellen Bird</ENAMEX>, who sits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Commission</ENAMEX>, felt something needs to be done now to build the skate park.
</P><P ID="14">   "It is high time we put up or shut up," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bird</ENAMEX>. "We have got the chance to get this money. Let's not ding around."
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> said he could see both sides of the issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vleiger</ENAMEX> said he was working around a skate park a while ago and found them to be really noisy. He said the noise from a skate park would more than likely disrupt the residents living at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he felt the city was inviting problems by having the skate park at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>, where there would be no supervision.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> wanted the input of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Police</ENAMEX> Chief <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Mana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fire Chief Jim Stanton</ENAMEX> on their response times to both sites.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said the police department wouldn't be able to oversee the skate park to ensure there are no problems. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said skate parks usually have few problems requiring the police. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stanton</ENAMEX> said his department's response time would double if the skate park was at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>, compared to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   Responding to some concerns from council members about liability, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said the city can only be held liable if officials knew there was a problem and did nothing to fix it.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> said the key to liability is ensuring something is built properly and well maintained. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>, who has dealt with skate park issues in other communities he has worked in, said he has found such facilities to be a valuable asset to the area.
</P><P ID="20">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> was a bit distressed about hearing the news that people from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> would want back the money they donated to the skate park if it was moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said he felt the skate park would receive much more use if it was in town, compared to being out in the middle of the two area communities.
</P><P ID="21">   The possibility exists that if <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is successful in landing the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$66,500</NUMEX> grant, it may try to switch sites to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Park</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




