
<P ID="1">Grizzlies clip Falcons for first <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mid-Valley</ENAMEX> win
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/14/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WEST RICHLAND</ENAMEX> - After starting the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> season an uncharacteristic 0-2, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> wrestling team got back on the winning track with a convincing 46-20 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>.   "We wrestled well <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach George Paulus</ENAMEX>. "We wrestled with a bit of emotion <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, which we have been trying to do (all season)."   It didn't look promising at the beginning for the Grizzlies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Christensen</ENAMEX> made some mistakes late in his match at 119 lbs. with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Pulsiphe</ENAMEX> and was pinned in 5:37. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulus</ENAMEX> said he felt this was a match <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christensen</ENAMEX> could have won, but got caught off guard late in the bout.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Burbidge</ENAMEX> won by injury default in the first round of his match at 125 lbs. for the Grizzlies.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Martinez</ENAMEX> had a convincing win for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> at 130 lbs., taking a 7-2 decision over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Edmonds</ENAMEX>.   At 135 lbs., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Omar Magana</ENAMEX> pinned <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Taylor Gropper</ENAMEX> in 5:50.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rudy Martinez</ENAMEX> picked up a first round win in his 140 lb. match over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dillon Roueche</ENAMEX>. The time of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>'s pin was not available.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Romero</ENAMEX> had an easy night for the Grizzlies at 145 lbs., pinning <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s Kellan Cox in 1:16.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniel Mendoza</ENAMEX> lost a 9-2 decision at 152 lbs. to one of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s big guns, Clay Underwood. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulus</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> made some mistakes late in the match that accounted for the final deficit.   At 160 lbs., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reece Paulus</ENAMEX> met up with another of the Falcons' top dogs in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jared Stoker</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paulus</ENAMEX> wrestled well, despite losing a 9-5 decision. The coach said his son was only behind 6-5 going into the final round.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Evans</ENAMEX> made a couple of impressive statements in his 171 lb. match with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evin Dodson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> won his match by pin in 1:55, but recorded six takedowns in the first round. The six <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">takedowns Evans</ENAMEX> scored boosted his season total to 82. His effort <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> set a new Grizzly wrestling takedown record. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evans</ENAMEX> surpassed the record of 80 set by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Espinoza</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> season.   At 189 lbs., <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos Padilla-Garza</ENAMEX> lost a 10-0 decision to another of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s top wrestler's, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Bradshaw</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gabe Lara</ENAMEX> manhandled <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s Logan Romhe at 215 lbs., winning a 10-2 decision.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Garza</ENAMEX> got back on track for the Grizzlies at heavyweight with an impressive 10-6 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Myers</ENAMEX>, another one of the Falcons' notable wrestlers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Alquicira</ENAMEX> won by forfeit at 103 lbs. for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Valencia</ENAMEX> ended the night for the Grizzlies at 112 lbs. with a 15-7 loss to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Edwin</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will be at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

