


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> OK's annexation
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A 3.24-acre parcel of land located near the corner of North 16th Street and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX> has been recommended for annexation into the city limits of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The annexation request was reviewed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Property owners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rene and Paula Lemos</ENAMEX> filed the petition that would annex their property into the city limits. They requested that the land be zoned as R-3, high density residential.
</P><P ID="6">   Developer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Probst</ENAMEX>, who has been involved in annexing more than 400 acres of land into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city limits, spoke on behalf of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemos</ENAMEX> family. He is currently working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diocese</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Housing Services</ENAMEX> on the feasibility of developing a multi-family housing project, similar to the one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said the city also has a notice of intent to annex from the property owners to the east of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemos</ENAMEX> property, which is owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> family. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX> is also working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX>'.
</P><P ID="8">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemos</ENAMEX> annexation was first scheduled for public hearing on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 18</TIMEX>, but was postponed due to lack of planning commission quorum on three occasions.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX> said that canvassing the maps of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> there is very little R-3 zoned property in the city that is not developed.
</P><P ID="10">   He said the Catholic diocese is looking to build a 51-unit townhouse development, but the agency is still in the early planning stages to see if the property would be viable. The housing in the development would be consistent with an R-2 zoning, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX>. Initial plans are to build about 9 units per acre over the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemos</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Burns</ENAMEX> property. He added that the plans call for green space, three playground areas and a small play field. A community building would also be in the plans.
</P><P ID="11">   "We don't like ultra-high density," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   Multi-family townhouses are a conditional use in an R-2 zone. The reason the R-3 zoning was requested, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX>, is because the diocese would also like to build a 2,000 square foot office building with six offices and a library on the property. He said the diocese would like to unite their services in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> under one roof.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX> said he is currently working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Irrigation District</ENAMEX>, which is putting together a cost estimate to pipe the canal on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemos</ENAMEX>' 16th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Avenue</ENAMEX> frontage.
</P><P ID="14">   "Right now it's all conceptual," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   Traffic was a concern voiced by residents and echoed by Planning Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brent Cleghorn</ENAMEX>. With two new schools slated to be built just off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX>, the possibility of a bottleneck at the four-way intersection of North 16th Street, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller</ENAMEX> roads was a concern to neighbors and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleghorn</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   "When the school is constructed, as things stand now, it would not be within the city limits," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> is studying how wide <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX> should be, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>, who added that most likely the road will be widened to three lanes.
</P><P ID="18">   The planning commissioners questioned as to if there is a possibility of putting a stop light where the four-way stop signs are currently located.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said most of the time, because of the costs, stop lights are not installed until there is a need. When a need is evident then grant funding is sought, he explained.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> cited the recent study of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Midvale</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alexander</ENAMEX> roads, when it was determined that there wasn't enough traffic to warrant a stop light. He said that experts said it would most likely be another 20 years before there is enough traffic to warrant a stop light at that intersection.
</P><P ID="21">   "There has to be a lot of traffic for a stop light to be put in," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleghorn</ENAMEX> wondered if it wouldn't be better to wait for the new schools to be established before the annexation decision is made.
</P><P ID="23">   Neighborhood resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stan Bos</ENAMEX>, whose home looks onto the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lemos</ENAMEX> property, said there are currently a lot of low income apartments in his neighborhood.
</P><P ID="24">   "Currently, we are surrounded by a lot of high density residential," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bos</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   In the 27 years he has lived in his neighborhood he has seen a change in traffic patterns, he added. Now, 16th Street is a major thoroughfare.
</P><P ID="26">   "As I see it now I feel this is a plan that needs some work and I don't support it," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bos</ENAMEX> added.
</P><P ID="27">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron Hochhalter</ENAMEX> said, "I have no objection to your plan, but I think we have enough of this housing on this side of town. We don't need more of this low income housing on the north side of town."
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleghorn</ENAMEX> said he felt uncomfortable making a decision on the annexation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> with so many questions unanswered.
</P><P ID="29">   Unfortunately, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX> said, his time to apply for funding is running to an end. His grant deadline is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 29</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thirty or sixty days ago</TIMEX> I could have said I will get you that information, but time has been ate up," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX>, adding that the issue was originally set for public hearing earlier <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="31">   "I have problems with this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleghorn</ENAMEX>. "I feel my back's against the wall. It bothers me to push it through.
</P><P ID="32">   "I'm concerned with the development of the schools. I have concerns with the amount of low income housing in the city. Although, your's would be the nicest here in the city," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleghorn</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Probst</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="33">   At the request of Planning Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barry Weaver</ENAMEX> the vote was split into two separate issues. The first issue was whether the property should be annexed into the city and the second issue was to decide if it should be zoned R-2.
</P><P ID="34">   Both votes by the seven-person commission were affirmative. Commissioners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleghorn</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ken Bierlink</ENAMEX> were the only two to oppose annexing the property into the city limits, and Commissioners <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cleghorn</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rolando Alvarez</ENAMEX> were in the minority in opposing the rezone of the property to R-2.
</P><P ID="35">   The official recommendations of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> will be forwarded to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> for final adoption.
</P>





 










<P ID="36">Webmaster
</P><P ID="37">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




