
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grape</ENAMEX> society trade show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The two-day <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Grape Society</ENAMEX> trade show will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Thursday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Nov. 11-12</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Church</ENAMEX> of the Nazarene, 500 N. Elm St., <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Wample</ENAMEX>, director of viticulture and enology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">California State University</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fresno</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>, will be speaking on what's happening in the wine and grape industries at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:15 p.m.</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>.   Other speakers from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> and the extension service will be discussing the current and future grape market trends, new cost studies on wine grapes and they will be taking comments on new mechanical pruning methods.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> there will be speakers discussing improving biological pest controls, pesticide updates, and organic grape production.   Controlling bunch rod and nematodes will also be discussed.   For more information about the annual meeting and trade show contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Deb Heintz</ENAMEX>, (509) 786-7888.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

