


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget relatively unchanged
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/16/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget study session combing through several department budgets, including the legislative fund.
</P><P ID="5">   The legislative fund is allocated for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> operations. The proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget for the legislative fund is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$38,210</NUMEX>, which is up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$37,740</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   One of the significant expenditures in the legislative budget totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,000</NUMEX> for salaries and wages. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members pointed out to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> that there will probably be money left from the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> budget since <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> scaled back the number of meetings it has each month from four to two. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members are paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> for each meeting they attend. The mayor receives <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$200</NUMEX> a month, while the mayor pro-tem is paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90</NUMEX> per month.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> did approve moving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,000</NUMEX> from the salaries and wages line item for other services and charges. This will help cover expenses for trainings and various organizational meetings.
</P><P ID="8">   The legislative fund also has <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,000</NUMEX> set aside for expenses such as travel, insurance and office supplies. Funding for the beautification awards also comes out of this fund.
</P><P ID="9">   The largest expenditure in the legislative fund is for intergovernmental services, which totals <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$16,000</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said this is money <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> charges for election costs.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> did incur a large travel budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. There had only been <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> budgeted for travel, but the amount so far charged to the account is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,100</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the extra expense is from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> searching for a new city manager.
</P>





 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




