


<P ID="1">School bonds go on sale <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/1/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Based on a recommendation from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Gores</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle-Northwest Securities Corporation</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> opted to fast-track plans to sell bonds to help finance the construction of a new school voters approved during an election at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of February</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Voters on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX> approved a bond/levy measure that could bring in as much as <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$46 million</NUMEX>. Under the approved measure, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents will be paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.41</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value to pay for the levy. The district devised a method where patrons wouldn't have to pay for the bond debt as long as the levy issue passed. The four-year levy voters approved is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> annually. The bond issue approved is for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX>. The district will utilize state matching dollars to construct a new middle school and a new kindergarten through fifth grade elementary school in the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle Road</ENAMEX>. The district will also be able to utilize state money to modernize <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> told the school board <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> the district has several positives going for it as it tries to sell the bonds voters approved. He said the district has a quality triple A credit rating. The district will also be able to take advantage of the state's credit rating in the selling of bonds.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> was originally looking to sell the bonds later in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>, but wants to move the date to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX> to take advantage of the market right now. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> told the school board the bond market is volatile right now and the district would do well to sell the bonds as quickly as possible.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> wants to sell the bonds on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>, between 6:30 and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> Once the bond prices are set by buyers, the school board will meet to approve a bond resolution, authorizing the sale of the bonds. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board</ENAMEX> members opted to meet at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> in the meeting room on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   The bonds will be sold <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX> with the district to receive the money by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   "Now is a great time to sell bonds," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




