
<P ID="1">Senate honors <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter George</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/4/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - The Washington State Senate honored <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> water conservationist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walter George</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>) for his work on water issues on behalf of the people of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, who retires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> after nearly 26 years as an unpaid district supervisor for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Conservation District</ENAMEX>, was honored by the passage of Senate Resolution 8698, which praises him for his "extraordinary volunteer efforts and achievements."   Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, who sponsored the resolution, said it is important to recognize <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> for his many contributions to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Walt</ENAMEX> is going to retire from the conservation district," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Republican. "He is going to be sorely missed. It's special to honor him and say thank you for all his service."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> served as the chairman of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Quality Committee for Yakima County</ENAMEX> and as chairman of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Quality Committee</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Association of Conservation Districts</ENAMEX>.   A World War II veteran, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> continues to farm on 40 acres east of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, growing corn and native spearmint.   Following the passage of his resolution, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> told the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> about his work on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Conservation District</ENAMEX>.   "This doesn't happen just with one person," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> said. "A little bit of leadership from me, but I had a board that supported me, and citizens - with a little technical help and some cost share - did this job.   "If the citizens and the farmers in my area hadn't been willing to cooperate and do the job, it would have never happened. Thank you all. This is a great honor," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> said.   In addition to his other volunteer activities, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> served as the director of the Diamond Fruit Growers board, Supervisor of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Drainage District</ENAMEX> #19, chairman of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Quality Committee</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Association of Conservation Districts</ENAMEX>, and as area president for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Central Area</ENAMEX> for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Quality Committee</ENAMEX>.   Born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ala.</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 20th, 1924</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> has resided in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1932</TIMEX>. He started farming with his father and brothers in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. In addition to the countless years of service to his community, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> honorably served his country in the armed services, fighting in the Battle of the Bulge, and attaining the rank of Sergeant Major. He also served 30 years of active service in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Army Reserve</ENAMEX>.   He continues to serve his country as the commander of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Legion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 73, and is an active member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunnyview VFW Post</ENAMEX> #3482 in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   This <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past winter</TIMEX>, he and his wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Betty</ENAMEX> served as the grand marshals of the 15th annual Country <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> Lighted Farm Implement Parade for their contributions to the community.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

