
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> enters into agreement with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/18/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Later this year</TIMEX> work is scheduled to begin on the installation of two traffic signals along <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> commissioners approved an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> for certified acceptance services for the two projects.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> explained that since funds from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Transportation Improvement Board</ENAMEX> are being used to help pay for the signalization projects a certified acceptance agency needs to ensure on behalf of the state that the funds are being used properly. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> said this a role the county plays for many smaller communities within its boundaries.   The signalization projects include the replacement of the current signal at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandridge Road</ENAMEX>, and the installation of a new signal at the intersection of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elm Street</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

