
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girls humbled by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/12/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The time has come for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> girls basketball team to do some soul searching.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> were literally humbled this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> at home by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. The loss dropped the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> to 0-2 in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> play (3-5 overall), putting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> into a must-win situation at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.   Simply put, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> were dominated by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiffanie Ulmer</ENAMEX>-led Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s pairing, losing 62-28.   "They are a good team," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Leo Gomez</ENAMEX>. "I know we can play with them."   About the only thing that went right for the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> was the first few minutes of the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> led 7-5 to open the first quarter, but the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> went on an 11-2 run to finish out the opening period. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> couldn't take advantage of the opportunities <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> gave in the first quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> ended up in foul trouble in the first period and had to go to the bench. But with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s best player sitting down, the rest of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> stepped forward. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said he credits an experienced <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> roster with being able to come to the forefront when needed.   "Everything was going great," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> of the game early on. "But the other kids stepped up for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. I think we stood around too much. My kids aren't stepping up."   The evidence of the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> standing around was in their offensive output. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> didn't break double digits in the scoring column in any of the four quarters. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> trailed at the end of the first half, 34-15. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> were outscored 28-13 in the second half.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> put their mark on the game in the second quarter. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> hit four field goals and sank 10 foul shots in the second quarter while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s scoring consisted of a pair of field goals and two free throws.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s 21-5 run in the third quarter, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> hit nine field goals while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> made only two from the field.   "They couldn't miss," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "They just had everything going. We couldn't take advantage of what they gave us."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> was the leading scorer for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with 6 points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> led the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> with 13.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said his Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> have to step up to the plate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s game against the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vikings</ENAMEX> was postponed from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan. 6</TIMEX> because of the weather.   "I have a young team," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "We just need to win."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> feels his eight juniors need to put forth more productivity as the season goes on for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to be successful.   "The juniors have to realize what they need to do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com               1 2 3 4 T   Ellensburg 16 18 21 7 62   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 9 6 5 8 28      Scoring: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwood-Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erica Mendez</ENAMEX> 5, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX> 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kacee Jo Bootsma</ENAMEX> 3, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Alvarez</ENAMEX> 3, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Daniela Rivera</ENAMEX> 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monique Montelongo</ENAMEX> 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lana Pangle</ENAMEX> 1.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg-Tiffanie Ulmer</ENAMEX> 13.   Rebounds: Bobi Haringa 6.   Assists: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Phillips</ENAMEX> 2.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

