
<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">DON <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. BRUNELL   Louisiana</ENAMEX> has 16 chronically failing public schools, 15 of which are in the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Orleans</ENAMEX>. After years of infighting and finger pointing, the state has finally taken a bold step to solve the problem. The state of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> took over a public school. If we don't stick to our <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1992</TIMEX> school reforms here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, the same thing could happen here.   The P.A. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capdau Middle School</ENAMEX> had floundered for years. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last spring</TIMEX>, more than half of its eighth-graders failed the LEAP test, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX>'s version of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s WASL. The school's seventh-graders fared even worse, scoring lower than <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">81 percent</NUMEX> of their peers nationwide on the Iowa Test of Basic Skills. The school has had eight principals in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 10 years</TIMEX> and changed its education programs three times in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past three years</TIMEX>.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>, following years of warnings and second chances, the state took over the school and turned it over to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of New Orleans</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> has had a plan in place since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> to create a charter school district of as many as ten troubled schools, but opposition from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> and the teachers union stopped the plan dead in its tracks. But with Capdau, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> finally got its chance to try a different approach.   The changes came swiftly. Using a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> donation from a local bank, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> gave the neglected school a fresh coat of paint, repaired leaky ceilings and installed new lights to brighten its dark and dingy hallways. Next, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> hired a veteran local principal with a get-tough reputation, replaced all but one of Capdau's teachers, and implemented a new curriculum that tailors instruction to each student. The idea is to help students learn at their own pace, rather than promote them to the next grade whether or not they'd learned the material. As with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state's education reforms, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> wants to make sure its high school diplomas are more than just a record of attendance.   With the curriculum in place, the search for students and teachers began. More than 500 students applied for the 264 spaces available at the school. Students were selected by lottery from applicants who lived within a five-mile radius of the school. The grandmother of two students selected for Capdau told state and school officials that the school takeover was the answer to her prayers.   Teachers were not as impressed. Applications to work at Capdau came in slowly. Soured by years of failed school reform efforts, teachers were wary of signing on to yet another experiment in education reform. Eventually, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> officials overcame their concerns, and more than 60 teachers applied for 16 available teaching positions.   At a training session two weeks before the start of school, teachers were warned to discard their old ideas. "Perception is reality," the trainer warned, and if they expected their students to be unruly and incapable, the students would respond to those expectations. "I want you to grab those perceptions," said the trainer, "and toss them on the floor."   Of course, the teachers aren't naïve; they understand the difficulty of their challenge. But they are optimistic that they and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> will be able to change the lives of hundreds of students for the better.   The school year at the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Capdau Charter School</ENAMEX> has just begun. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, they're focusing on K-3 and the 7th and 8th grades, but eventually, Capdau will be a K-8 school. Parents, teachers and elected officials throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Louisiana</ENAMEX> and the nation are watching closely. A success at Capdau could serve as a model for thousands of failing schools across the country.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Orleans</ENAMEX>, a single charter school has brought hope and optimism to hundreds of parents. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> voters will decide whether to keep our state's charter schools alternative. By approving Referendum 55, we can ensure that parents and children in our state have an alternative to failing schools.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don C. Brunell</ENAMEX> is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

