
<P ID="1">Mabton residents asked to conserve water
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/14/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> residents are being asked to conserve water during the coming dog days of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>.   The community is experiencing a drop in water pressure in the city system, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ildia Jackson</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton City</ENAMEX> administrator.   She said notices have gone out to city water customers to refrain from irrigating their lawns and gardens every day. Residents are being asked to restrict their use of water for such things as watering cars, she said.   "We are asking residents on the north side of town to water on even days of the week and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">south Mabton</ENAMEX> residents to water on odd days of the week," she said.   The city, which is in the process of seeking state and federal funds to drill a new city well, noticed a dramatic drop in water pressure <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, when the first hot spell hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.   "We have this happen every year when water demands increase," she explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said the city crews and engineers have tried several methods of elevating and maintaining the water pressure to no avail.   "We're not having a lack of water, it is just that our booster pumps can't work fast enough to replenish the system," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> has seen a drop in the aquifer during the past several years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> said. "Which is why we are petitioning the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Water Conservancy Board of Yakima</ENAMEX> for permission to drill a new well," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> explained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> engineers will meet with the conservancy board <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>) to explain <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s need for a new well, which is expected to cost between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.3 million</NUMEX></NUMEX> to drill, and install, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jackson</ENAMEX> added.   She said the city was recently denied a state community block grant, which would have aided in funding the new well construction. "We plan to reapply for the state grant, as well as investigate other avenues of funding," she said.   Historically, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> water users have experienced noticeable drops in water pressure every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> when demands on the aging water system increase as residents use more city water for outdoor uses.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> in order to handle the pressure drop, city water crews are turning off the system between the hours of <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">midnight</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 a.m.</TIMEX> in order to allow the reservoirs to recycle," she explained.   "We should see a slight increase in the water pressure as a result of that action," she added.   "We just ask that residents be patient and help us with our conservation efforts until fall, when the system should return to normal," she added.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

