
<P ID="1">Wanita Grange donates dictionary to school students
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/31/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Across the state <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grange</ENAMEX> members are going into the classrooms and giving students an educational resource as part of a project known as "Words for Thirds."   Members of local <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grange</ENAMEX> halls are giving third grade students a dictionary of their own as a part of the state-wide five-year project.   One of the Granges participating in the "Words for Thirds" program is the Wanita Grange located on Mabton-Alderwood Highway.   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bettie Baser</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grange</ENAMEX>'s secretary, 90 student dictionaries were given to third graders at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Artz-Fox Elementary School</ENAMEX>, the school closest to their hall. Other Granges around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> are raising money and providing dictionaries to students in communities near their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grange</ENAMEX>.   Each Grange is using funds raised throughout the year to purchase the dictionaries for the students. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baser</ENAMEX> said that the dictionaries given to the students are theirs to keep.   "The students can take them home, it's theirs, not the schools," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baser</ENAMEX>. "The kids were really very enthused that we took the dictionaries to them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baser</ENAMEX>.   The dictionaries were hand-delivered to the students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>.   The Granges are teaming up with "The Dictionary Project," a national non-profit group, with the goal of providing dictionaries for third grade students.   Organizers for "The Dictionary Project," as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grange</ENAMEX> members from around the state, believe that by giving away dictionaries, they can encourage reading and the development of problem solving that arise as a child develops reading, writing and creative thinking abilities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Baser</ENAMEX> said the books also provide each student with a reference book they can use while completing homework.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

