
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> wants to reach for new heights
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/16/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Basketball has become a passion for her, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa Alvarez</ENAMEX> wants to jump through some new hoops.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> is one of eight young <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> ladies vying for the title of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 18</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>, 17, will be a senior <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. She is the daughter of Catalina Espindola of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alejandro Alvarez Jr.</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> is being sponsored by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Catalina</ENAMEX>'s Hair Care and Audel's Fashion and Music store.   One of the reasons why <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> decided to run for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was because she wants to become more involved with the community. She also wants to be a role model for the younger children in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and feels representing the community on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court would be a good step.   "I know a lot of kids look up to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "We need to have good role models."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> also admitted she felt running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> would be a fun experience that she will remember for years to come.   At school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> is involved in a slew of activities. She will be the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associated Student Body</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASB</ENAMEX>) president her senior year. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> was the previous <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ASB</ENAMEX> business manager. She is also involved with several different school organizations, including the Link Crew, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor Society</ENAMEX> and Leaders in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Action</ENAMEX>. One of her favorite school activities is the Interhigh Program. It involves a group of students visiting other schools in the area to learn more about what is going on.   Basketball has also become another passion for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>, who also plays volleyball, has been playing hoops since she was in the third grade. But she lost her desire for the sport until this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past winter</TIMEX>, when Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzly</ENAMEX> head coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Gomez</ENAMEX> rekindled her love for the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> said she likes basketball because it is a team sport.   "But it has a lot to do with your mentality," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "The game is <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> mental."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> helped her overcome her doubts about her ability to play the game.   When she has spare time, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> loves to be involved with her family, who are strung up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.   "Family in general takes up a lot of my time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "I am really close with my family. Spending time with my family is important to me."   After high school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> has plans to attend a four-year university in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> to study international business.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> said it has been a goal of her's to be more involved with the community.   "I love being involved with stuff," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "I think (running for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>) will get me involved with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is a unique place, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> said she was homesick for the community after taking a three-week vacation.   "I got so homesick," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "The atmosphere here is so nice. You know people around here. It just feels like home."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> feels what makes <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> stand out is its rich agricultural history. She said the small town atmosphere combined with the agricultural backdrop helps attract people to the area.   "I love just driving in the country," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "I wouldn't like to see <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> be a big city."   One of the issues facing the community, feels <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>, is finding something teens can do.   "That is why you constantly have your alcohol problems around here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "It is kind of boring for high schoolers."   Besides trying to promote more activities for teens to be involved with, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> would like be involved with the Locks for Love program, which she singled out as her community service project on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court. Locks for Love is an organization that takes people's donations of hair and makes wigs, usually for terminally ill patients. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX> said she also plans to take great pride in the community float the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> court rides on at different parades.   I want to keep the winning float tradition going," smiled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>, who describes herself as a friendly, outgoing, determined young lady, is looking forward to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pageant and the opportunity to serve on the court.   "I would be very honored if I was crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alvarez</ENAMEX>. "If I am crowned <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, hopefully I can give back to the community."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

