

 
<P ID="1">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">12-24 Letters to editor   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bond</ENAMEX>/levy support   I support community education and the upcoming special levy and bond issue as approved by the board of directors of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>.   The literature shows a growing enrollment in the district and a need for additional schools. The cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.61</NUMEX> per thousand (of assessed valuation) when these two issues are approved is a good buy to the taxpayer.   As a former board member, I encourage <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents to vote "yes" on these two issues.   /s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Miller</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>      <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> project a success   The first grade students and their families at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX> participated in a night filled with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> projects, singing and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa</ENAMEX>. It was a great family experience.   We would like to thank Wal-Mart for its generous donation that helped make the evening successful.   /s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Matson</ENAMEX>, first grade teacher, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>      Trip a delight   This is just a note to express our "thanks" to the staff of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>, the participating merchants and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dottie Cervantes</ENAMEX> of the travel agency (for the trip we won in the annual Hawaiian getaway promotion).   We have returned from a most delightful sojourn in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hawaii</ENAMEX>. The weather was magnificent. The accommodations were very comfortable. Our flight over and our return flight were smooth, uncomplicated and on time.   Fortune must have been continuing to smile upon us, vis-a-vis, the weather. The much anticipated long lines at the security and inspection stations did not materialize or dampen our enthusiasm in any way.   Once again, we both desire to thank all of those nice folks who made it possible with all our hearts.   /s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cloe and Roger K. Garrison</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>      Food, toy drive   For the past few years I have been involved in the food basket and toy drive at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>. During that time the caring and generosity shown by the citizens and businesses of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has been tremendous each year.   However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> has been truly amazing. Nearly every grocery store in town donated food. Many other businesses gave everything from batteries to wrapping paper. We received huge food, gift or cash donations from school children, church organizations and countless individuals.   One little boy brought us the contents of his piggy bank. Another little girl brought us her own dolly because she thought another little girl could use it more.   All of these acts have shown myself and everyone involved here that we live in a great community, where many place the welfare of others high on their list of priorities.   With the help from all of our community members, 50 families were hopefully given a better <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> than they otherwise might have had. I know this was not the only food and toy drive in town. I can't imagine how much good was done if the other organizations were shown the support that we were.   It has been an honor for all of us here at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> to work with you <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Christmas</TIMEX> season. We want to wish all of our citizens a merry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> and a safe new year. We also want to thank all of you for making <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a wonderful community to live and work in.   /s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Harris</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX>   
</P>

 




<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

