
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> boys drop two conference games
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Despite losing a pair of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> games <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> boys basketball team maintained its grip on the No. 6 spot in the conference standings.   The Grizzlies were pounded at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selah</ENAMEX>, 72-53, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and absorbed a tough 65-61 loss at home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> against visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> (3-7) and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> (2-8) are currently vying for the sixth and final berth to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> tournament. The two clubs have a return engagement scheduled for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last weekend</TIMEX> of regular season play, on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 13</TIMEX>. The Wolfpack won the first meeting, defeating the Grizzlies on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s home floor by a 57-56 count back in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">mid-January</TIMEX>.   In looking ahead to this coming weekend, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> travels to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> (5-5) <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> and hosts <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> (10-0) on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Steve Urrutia</ENAMEX> admits that nabbing a victory against either the Bulldogs or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> at this point in the season would be akin to stealing a win, saying that it's always tough playing at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> is...well, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>.   "Our hope this coming weekend is to get a win, to solidify our number six spot in league," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX>. "It will be difficult, but it can be done."   If the Grizzlies are to turn the corner, so to speak, they'll need their perimeter players to start knocking down 3-pointers on a much more regular basis, which in essence should open up the middle of the lane a bit more for 6'6" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Thomas</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selah</ENAMEX>, the Grizzlies weren't effective at all in bombing in their long range shots, which allowed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> to sag off the perimeter and clog the lane.   "The less effective we were outside, the more they packed it in on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX>)," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX>.   The end result was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selah</ENAMEX> holding <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s big man to just 12 points in the contest. No other Grizzly scored more than nine points against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selah</ENAMEX>, on the other hand, had four players score in double figures, including unheralded <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dane Peterson</ENAMEX>, who knocked down a game high 25 points.   "We didn't plan on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peterson</ENAMEX> kid going off on us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX>, explaining that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> stuck its defensive specialist, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pete Marquez</ENAMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Selah</ENAMEX>'s top scorer this season-Eric Bell. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marquez</ENAMEX> did a superb job in limiting Bell's effectiveness, holding <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>' scoring threat to just 14 points.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> at home against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX>, the game could have easily gone the Grizzlies' way. The Falcons, though, prevailed in the end, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adam Dabney</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tyler Cathey</ENAMEX> combining for a 41-point effort to lead <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> to a hard fought 65-61 victory.   The Grizzlies rallied from a one-point halftime deficit to take a four-point lead late in the third period, only to watch as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> closed out the third quarter with four straight points to square the contest at 44-all. In the final period, a back-and-forth affair, the Falcons ended up outscoring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> by a 21-17 margin.   The 6'6" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> threw in 17 points for the Grizzlies in the losing cause. Perimeter shooters <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Heckert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX>, the latter who just got called up to the varsity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>, each bombed in a pair of 3-pointers enroute to scoring 18 and 8 points, respectively, for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The Grizzlies outscored <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> from beyond the 3-point arc, knocking down 6-of-18 shots. The Falcons connected on 3-of-8 3-point attempts.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

