


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Council</ENAMEX> signs off on project completion
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Grandview Public Works Director Cus Arteaga <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> requested the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> accept the city's new public storm water retention project as complete. The council voted unanimously to accept the project as completed.
</P><P ID="4">   The new storm water retention pond is located on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bethany Road</ENAMEX>, north of the Wal-Mart distribution center, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artega</ENAMEX>. The pond collects storm water run-off.
</P><P ID="5">   "We'd like to move forward with the project," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artega</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   With the project marked as completed, the retainage fee of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4,443.89</NUMEX> will be released to Contractors <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Equipment Maintenance, Inc.</ENAMEX> once the city engineer is satisfied the closure requirements are made, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artega</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   When asked how the new storm water pond worked on the downpour <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artega</ENAMEX> said, "I wish we had that in town in a couple of places. It worked really well."
</P>   
   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




