
<P ID="1">Police captain regales Kiwanians with accounts from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> academy training
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/14/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Captain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Bank</ENAMEX> falls into an elite group law enforcement officers in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>, all of whom have attended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FBI</ENAMEX> leadership academy in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quantico</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Va.</ENAMEX> It is one of the best leadership training opportunities in the world for law enforcement officers, said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>.   He shared with members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> about his 12-week training at the prestigious <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National FBI Academy</ENAMEX>, which he returned from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 5</TIMEX>.   About <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX> nominated <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> for the academy.   "Normally, there is a seven to 10-year waiting list," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>.   Each state is allowed three students at each of the four sessions held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Quantico</ENAMEX> annually. The session <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> attended had four <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state law enforcement officers attending.   With classes filled with 240 police chiefs, captains and lieutenants from around the world, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> said he had the opportunity to learn about other ways law enforcement is conducted. A friend from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colombia</ENAMEX> shared with him that police work in his South American country consists of strapping on a backpack and a machine and being dropped off in the jungle for a week to bust drug manufacturers. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> also made friends from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gambia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nepal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colombia</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX>. There were participants from 48 states and 21 countries.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> said he was fortunate in that he had a year to prepare for the academy. He lost <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">15 pounds</NUMEX> in preparing for the physical fitness aspect of the academy.   "It was like boot camp," said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX>.   Every week there was a challenge run the students would participate in. The run started at about one and a half miles and each week half a mile to a mile was added. At the end of the 12-week session, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> went on the "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yellow Brick Road</ENAMEX>," a Marine obstacle course that is about five miles long. Before going through the obstacle course he had to run three miles down to it. His reward for completing the course is a painted yellow brick, which now sits in his office at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>.   Besides the physical aspect of the academy, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> said there was an academic component.   He received extra college and graduate credits through the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Virginia</ENAMEX> in managing organizational change, public speaking, extremist groups and labor law.   "I actually doubled up on the communication courses," he said.   He also applied to be a part of the "leadership challenge." He was one of 16 chosen to participate in the leadership group for his class of 240 at the academy.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> said he hopes to use his new skills to help the police chief in making the department better.   "This was really good leadership training," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> is only the second officer from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to attend the academy. Retired police officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Alvord</ENAMEX> also attended the academy. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX>'s police chiefs have also attended the academy, as well as a handful of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> officers.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

