




 


<P ID="1">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">DEATH NOTICE
</P><P ID="3">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LETA MARIE BLOOMFIELD</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leta Marie Bloomfield</ENAMEX>, 84, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Dec. 21, 2003</TIMEX>, at Hillcrest Manor.
</P><P ID="5">   She was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 16, 1919</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Elsie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neb.</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Ellen</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rowley</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilbert Fosbinder</ENAMEX>. She received her education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Nebraska</ENAMEX> and moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1946</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 10, 1952</TIMEX> she married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Bloomfield</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sterling</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX> They returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to make their home. She was employed at Hillcrest Manor in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for more than 20 years.
</P><P ID="6">   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bloomfield</ENAMEX> is survived by three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Kennedy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elston Kennedy</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doris Kennedy</ENAMEX> of Edmonds; seven grandchildren; seven great-grandchildren; one great-great-grandson; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LeRoy Fosbinder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Plate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neb.</ENAMEX>; and one sister, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> Stock of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fleming</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="7">   She was preceded in death by her parents; husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Bloomfield</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leycester Fosbinder</ENAMEX>; and two half sisters.
</P><P ID="8">   Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Dec. 23, 2003</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Graveside services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Dec. 24, 2003</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Park</ENAMEX>. Jones Funeral Home is in charge of arrangements.
</P><P ID="9">   PAID OBITUARY
</P><P ID="10">   W/PHOTO
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ORVILLE LEE LUTHER</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville Lee Luther</ENAMEX>, 74, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Dec. 21, 2003</TIMEX>, at home surrounded by his family following an extended illness.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31, 1929</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eldorado Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mont.</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edward Levi</ENAMEX> and Zella Vergi (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> family moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> area in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1935</TIMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 27, 1947</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Jean Worms</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Following their marriage they made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, where they farmed and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> was a crane operator for various <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> projects.
</P><P ID="14">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1971</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> founded O.L. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Luther Company</ENAMEX>, an asphalt and gravel company that continues under the name O.L. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> and operated by his son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>", and grandsons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Luther</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta</ENAMEX> resided for 52 years in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> and for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX> had made their home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Operating Engineers</ENAMEX> for more than 20 years and a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Liberty Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> was very devoted to his business, cherished time spent with family and had a passion for fishing.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX> is survived by his loving wife of 56 years, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>; three children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arnold</ENAMEX> "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe</ENAMEX>" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luther</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Susie</ENAMEX>, of Outlook, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeaneva Hallett</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diane Jones</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>; seven grandchildren, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Shannon Luther</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lee Luther</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanelle</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joseph Luther</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kendra</ENAMEX>). <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wes Hallett</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cristie</ENAMEX>), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matthew Hallett</ENAMEX> (Asayo), <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hillary Nesary</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mallory Jones</ENAMEX>; four great-grandchildren; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joleen Buckingham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raelynn Nesary</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Owen Luther</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tomi Luther</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leo Luther</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX>; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vera Barbour</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kansas City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mo.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="17">   He was preceded in death by his parents; two brothers, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Claude Luther</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Norman Luther</ENAMEX>; one sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy Gates</ENAMEX>; several other brothers and sisters; and nieces and nephews.
</P><P ID="18">   Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Dec. 26, 2003</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Dec. 27, 2003</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orville</ENAMEX>'s memory may contribute to the cancer memorial of the donor's choice. Memorials may be left at Jones Funeral Home at the time of service.
</P>   






 










<P ID="19">Webmaster
</P><P ID="20">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




