


<P ID="1">County commissioner candidate says <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has much to offer economically
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/21/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Yesterday</TIMEX>, in the ballroom of H&H Furniture in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Leita</ENAMEX> announced his intentions to seek the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Position</ENAMEX> #1 vacancy <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX>, who is the founder and co-owner of Right Hardware in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, said as county commissioner he wants to assure government accountability, promote more jobs with better wages in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>, fight for less government regulation and strive for cost effective crime control.
</P><P ID="6">   "I'm running for county commissioner for two primary reasons," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said. "First, I care about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>. Having lived here, raised a family here and operating two businesses in our county, it hunts me to see our county struggle with failing leadership. This county has great assets with its people, location and natural beauty and yet it seems to fall short of its potential."
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> added that he believes he can make a difference drawing on his ability to lead.
</P><P ID="8">   "In recent months, I have met with numerous elected county officials and department heads. They are dedicated to their positions and want to make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> better. But, as a whole, they are frustrated by a lack of clear direction and silent county leadership," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   With reserves down, revenue flat and expenses climbing, the county is at a critical financial point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said. He said the county government needs to live within its means and use existing resources wisely.
</P><P ID="10">   He said that the proposed tax increase for the county justice system needs to be clearly defined and show how the new tax revenues will directly impact crime.
</P><P ID="11">   "Until this detail is provided I can not endorse this initiative," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> of the issue that will go before the voters <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   He said rather than finding quick fixes he would rather look at long-range policies to reverse our economic shortfalls.
</P><P ID="13">   Although long-range planning needs to be made, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> said the new jail should not be looked at as a long-term fix for financial problems.
</P><P ID="14">   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> jail project currently underway, in its original form, had merit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX>. "The process by which it has evolved has been flawed," he said. "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> this project has diminished in value to our county. Only good future management will keep this project viable and meet its expectations."
</P><P ID="15">   He added that jail rental income shouldn't be viewed as a "...panacea for county revenue shortfalls, but rather as a short-term marginal revenue enhancement."
</P><P ID="16">   He said that the port districts of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> have been beneficial to the community and the county.
</P><P ID="17">   "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is the anchor for the southern part of the county," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX>, adding that one of the greatest benefits to the county is the property and open land in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> where additional economic development is possible.
</P><P ID="18">   "There's future potential for other large sites to be developed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leita</ENAMEX> also supports the Black Rock Reservoir project and said he would commit county resources to move the project forward.
</P><P ID="20">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Rock</ENAMEX> stands to be a long term solution for managing our water commitments for all parties within our county," he said.
</P>





 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




