
<P ID="1">High school graduation exercises begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">From <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, high school seniors are counting the days until graduation.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Christian high schools will all turn their graduates loose <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, June 4</TIMEX>.   Sunnyisde High will graduate approximately 270 seniors, the largest class to date, according to school officials. Academic class leaders include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Barr</ENAMEX>, who will share valedictorian honors, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Kilian</ENAMEX> as class salutatorian. The class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> will receive diplomas at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX> on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clem Senn Football Field</ENAMEX>, on South 16th Street.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>, the 45 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> seniors will gather in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Todd Gym</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> in front of families and friends to accept their diplomas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Mayra Aviles</ENAMEX> is class valedictorian and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roberto Carlos Brambila</ENAMEX> is salutatorian.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> seniors will gather for graduation ceremonies at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Church</ENAMEX> of the Nazarene, 500 N. Elm St., for their graduation ceremonies on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 4</TIMEX>. Beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, the 20 SCHS graduates will be awarded their diplomas. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vanessa DeJong</ENAMEX> is class valedictorian and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alyssa Groenewold</ENAMEX> is salutatorian.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 5</TIMEX>, the nine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton High School</ENAMEX> graduates will meet at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> in the high school gym for their graduation ceremonies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dana Hodge</ENAMEX> is class valedictorian and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Whitmore</ENAMEX> is salutatorian. The Bickleton baccalaureate ceremonies will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, June 2</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> will see 130 seniors step onto the infield at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Leenhouts Stadium</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, June 5</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> graduation ceremonies. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Waddle</ENAMEX> is class valedictorian and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeanette Villanueva</ENAMEX> is salutatorian.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> graduation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, June 7</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium. The class speakers are still being determined, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Babcock</ENAMEX>, school administrator. He expects 35 students to be presented with their diplomas.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

