44 5 34 17 2 41
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  I'm a bit of an abstract figure that people can project their fantasies on; it's pretty much what we all are, otherwise we wouldn't be stars, and people wouldn't be interested. But people project things on you that have nothing to do with what you really are, or they see a little something and then exaggerate it. And you can't really control that.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salma Hayek</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>