
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roberts</ENAMEX> ready to rebuild
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/19/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A fire destroyed one of the warehouses at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrus and Roberts Produce Company</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. The owners of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> business are getting ready to rebuild.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last month</TIMEX>, Columbia River Steel and Construction Incorporated applied for a building permit from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building Division</ENAMEX> for the construction of a new warehouse on the site where the old warehouse once stood. The permit assesses a project valuation of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$800,000</NUMEX>, with the permit fee alone costing <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7,691</NUMEX>. The permit for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roberts</ENAMEX> project was one of 75 permits issued by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Building Division</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Roberts</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Andrus</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Roberts</ENAMEX> said the new warehouse will be the same size as the previous facility. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy Roberts</ENAMEX> said the building should measure approximately 225x80 feet, and will include two cold rooms and a potato packing area on one end of the warehouse.   He said the new warehouse will be newer and therefore a little more attractive than the building that previously <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">sat</TIMEX> at the site. He said the building that was ravaged by fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> was one of the company's original buildings.   The warehouse was destroyed by an <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">early morning</TIMEX> fire in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, which closed Yakima Valley Highway and Highway 241 while firefighters battled the blaze. At the time of the fire, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> estimated the cost of damages to be around <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy</ENAMEX> said construction of the new warehouse should begin soon, noting that the building should be completed by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of next year</TIMEX>. He added that the new warehouse will also include a new potato packing line, as well as other new equipment and machinery.   The warehouse should be ready for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s potato season, which runs for several weeks toward the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of summer</TIMEX> through the beginning of fall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guy</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s potato season just started about <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three weeks ago</TIMEX> and should continue for several more weeks.   Other projects that were issued permits by the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX> include a construction project at 625 Midvale Rd. A building permit was issued to the Port of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for the construction of a new operations office, which is part of the Sequence Batch Reactor project the Port has been working on for some time. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> was also issued several permits <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last month</TIMEX>, including building, plumbing and mechanical permits for work to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football field concession stand at 1801 E. Edison Ave. Over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> the concession stand was remodeled. The project included enlarging the stand and adding on to the restrooms.   During <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, the city's building division conducted 294 inspections and collected <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$23,704</NUMEX> in permit fees for projects with a total valuation of more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.96 million</NUMEX>. The permits issued included 33 building permits, 13 mechanical permits and 11 plumbing permits, as well as four sewer connection fees, six water connection fees, one water meter permit and three public works permits for curb, gutter and sidewalk work.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

