


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> to close Main Street bridge to all vehicles
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1996</TIMEX> access to the Main Street bridge in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> has been limited to vehicles carrying less than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">8,000 pounds</NUMEX> per axle. However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">following Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> meeting, access to the bridge will soon be limited to pedestrians only.
</P><P ID="5">   "The repairs just keep adding up," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Public Works Director Cus Arteaga</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   He explained that the bridge, owned by Burlington Northern Santa Fe, is not being kept up by the railroad and by the last calculation the cost to make the necessary repairs to the structure would be in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "That bridge has been forgotten by the railroad," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="8">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX>, this means that over the years the railroad has failed to have the bridge inspected and is no longer working to make repairs on the structure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1990s</TIMEX> the city talked to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX> about the bridge and at that time learned there were funds available for the reconstruction of the bridge. But, the amount of matching funds needed was too great for the city to take on and the railroad was not interested in pursuing the funding.
</P><P ID="9">   It was following that meeting that the current weight limit was imposed on the structure.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members that the city has two options when it comes to the bridge that helps connect Avenue G to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway, spanning the railroad tracks that divide the community. The options include either closing off the structure to vehicle traffic all together or making the necessary repairs to the bridge.
</P><P ID="11">   "The railroad is not going to put up any money," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="12">   He told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members that the county was ready to inspect the bridge several weeks ago, however <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> asked them to put it off until after <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> had made a decision on the fate of the structure.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> said he supports the recommendation from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Public Works</ENAMEX> to stop vehicle traffic over the bridge, noting that the city doesn't own the bridge or have the funds available to repair it.
</P><P ID="14">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview City Council</ENAMEX> members voted to close the bridge to all vehicle traffic effective on or before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 1</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Administrator <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sewell</ENAMEX> said the closure of the bridge will be in effect until the structure is either demolished or repaired by Burlington Northern Santa Fe.
</P><P ID="16">   Originally, the recommendation to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was to close the bridge to all traffic, including pedestrian traffic. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arteaga</ENAMEX> noted that the pedestrian walkway that runs alongside the street on the bridge is a boardwalk-like structure, which over the years has needed a significant amount of repair. He said the city has replaced a number of broken and cracked boards, and noted that if anyone tripped or fell over the planks the city could be held liable.
</P><P ID="17">   However, after some discussion <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members decided they didn't want to limit pedestrian access to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Side Park</ENAMEX> and the community's rose garden. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members decided instead of keeping the current walkway open over the bridge, pedestrian traffic will be funneled into the center of the structure.
</P><P ID="18">   "I would feel better about that," said Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sewell</ENAMEX> also noted that in the future the city might want to look at working with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Transportation</ENAMEX> to try and obtain grant funding to build a proper pedestrian walkway over the active railroad line,
</P><P ID="20">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




