


<P ID="1">Earlier report of cuts to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> much rosier now
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Prior to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> budget study session, life at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> looked pretty grim for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> released a memo at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of November</TIMEX> that detailed where proposed budget cuts would be made in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> to help offset a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$393,910</NUMEX> revenue shortfall.
</P><P ID="6">   One of the areas that was proposed in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget to help save money was not filling four positions at the police department, three of which were vacant at the time.
</P><P ID="7">   But thanks to voters in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> passing a 3/10's of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">1 percent</NUMEX> sales tax with the money to go towards law and justice county-wide, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> has found new life.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chief Ted Mana</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> outlined his plans for utilizing the money from the county sales tax in the coming year.
</P><P ID="9">   In all, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> has four vacancies-one vacancy in the corrections department, one from the death of Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Evans</ENAMEX> and the other two from two patrol officers leaving for other positions.
</P><P ID="10">   "No one currently employed is going to be losing their jobs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> he wants to use the county tax money to hire an officer at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX>. This will allow the department to retain the traffic officer position, which is currently being held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent Coffman</ENAMEX>. Without hiring an additonal officer at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coffman</ENAMEX>'s services would have had to be used elsewhere in the department to cover vacancies.
</P><P ID="12">   "We believe that is an important enough function," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">middle of the year</TIMEX>, Mana plans to hire another officer in hopes of providing the detectives division with some additional assistance. Also at mid-year, Mana plans to create an administrative secretary position, replacing a data entry person that will be leaving.
</P><P ID="14">   The proposed law enforcement budget for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.1 million</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   The major expenditure in this department is salaries, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.2 million</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> about a plan he has to lease police vehicles in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. As a result, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> was able to take <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> from the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$163,760</NUMEX> set aside in the line item for other services and charges. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$35,000</NUMEX> will now go to help operate the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   One significant expenditure in the law enforcement budget deals with overtime. For <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> has set aside <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$92,000</NUMEX> for overtime, which is up considerably from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$56,420</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> amount was based in part on a strong desire by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to reduce the overtime budget. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, the police department had an overtime budget of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$103,395</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said his overtime budget is based on past usage. The most difficult problem with overtime in the police department, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>, is having to fill positions when staff members are gone. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said the amount being set aside for overtime is still less than it would cost to hire people for the actual positions.
</P><P ID="18">   Of the 34 current staff members at the police department, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said 22 of those are commissioned officers. The police department is currently at staffing levels for officers that it had in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1991</TIMEX>, the chief told <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> said he was worried about how overtime would be affected once the new dispatch center at the law and justice center is completed by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">middle of next year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said overtime will be a concern at the new center.
</P><P ID="20">   However, the city will be having some new revenue from housing prisoners that will assist in paying for overtime expenses, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Marshal Service</ENAMEX> is closing some of its locations around the state and will now be using the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> jail to house prisoners.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> was also concerned with the city's involvement with the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas (HIDTA), a program operated by the Washington State Patrol. . The police department currently dedicates one office to working with HIDTA. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said there is benefits to the partnership, such as having an officer working with HIDTA on a full-time basis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> wanted to see what kind of cost benefits there is to the city to continue this partnership.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> was also curious about the partnership the city has with the school district for funding the two school resource officers. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said the school district has increased its funding for the positions to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> annually. The city pays about one-third of the costs to have the officers in the schools. The police department gets the services of the two officers back during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> months. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mana</ENAMEX> said an issue is that during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> months, the officers usually take their vacation, so there is no real benefit to the city.
</P><P ID="23">   The budget for the corrections department is a separate item. The proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> corrections department budget is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$537,410</NUMEX>, which is an increase from the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$516,010</NUMEX> budgeted in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. The increase in the budget comes under the line item for supplies, which increases from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$97,300</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$157,500</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. Captain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Bank</ENAMEX> said the primary expenses in supplies are the meals for prisoners and cleaning supplies. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bank</ENAMEX> said the corrections budget is a conservative estimate of where it should be.
</P><P ID="24">   The proposed communications department budget at the police department is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$492,190</NUMEX> for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. This budget covers the dispatching services.
</P>





 










<P ID="25">Webmaster
</P><P ID="26">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




