


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> hired as new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> superintendent
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/10/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - There will be a changing of the guard in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="4">   Following an executive session <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School Board</ENAMEX> announced the hiring of current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX> as the new superintendent.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> will replace current <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mathis</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> has been head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past seven years</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> is credited with bringing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> into the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">21st century</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> is also credited with being instrumental in helping pass a bond issue that resulted in the construction of several new, modernized schools in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathis</ENAMEX> is retiring as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> superintendent after 35 years in education.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> beat out two other finalists for the position of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> superintendent. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late April</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mary Walker School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard Couley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ellensburg School District</ENAMEX> Assistant Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Sheldon</ENAMEX> went through an extensive interview process, which included meeting with community members.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> will assume the role of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> superintendent starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> has been the superintendent of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>. Prior to that, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> served as the assistant superintendent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> for one year. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1994 to 1997</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> was the assistant principal at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> was also a vocational agriculture teacher in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX> high schools for several years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> received his Bachelor of Science degree in agricultural education from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>. He also obtained his superintendent credentials from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSU</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> also has a Master's of Education administration degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="8">Webmaster
</P><P ID="9">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




