


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/9/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> holds off on renewing liquor license
</P>

<P ID="5">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> opted to hold off on approving a liquor license renewal request.
</P>

<P ID="6">Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> needs more information on a liquor license renewal request from Ricos Tacos Guadalajara, 809 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway, before it could grant its approval.
</P>

<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> did grant the liquor license renewal requests from Playa Azul Sports Bar, 627 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Edison Avenue</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mariscos Playa Azul Restaurant</ENAMEX>, 633 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Edison Avenue</ENAMEX>; and El Senor Camaron, 1501 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to begin collective bargaining process with police guild
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> informed the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Officers <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Guild</ENAMEX> had contacted him to begin contract negotiations for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said he wanted to meet with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> in executive session to discuss the initial strategy the city is taking in contract negotiations. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> did meet in executive session on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> to discuss the initial strategy the city will be taking in contract negotiations, but released no details.
</P>

<P ID="11">The city and the police guild are scheduled to hold their first talks on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 16</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">Under an ordinance the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> adopted <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, the city will release all details of collective bargaining sessions with city employees' unions to the public in open session with the exception of the initial strategy discussion.
</P>

 






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




