
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s objections to WASL to be heard by state leaders tonight
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> recently drew the attention of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State</ENAMEX> Superintendent of Public Instruction Terry Bergeson.   At their <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> meeting, local board members voted to support concerns of a group of local parents represented by Nuestra Casa, led by Sister <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Rita Rhode</ENAMEX>. The parents group voiced their concerns about the difficulties students who can't understand English have with taking the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (WASL) tests. At the meeting, the school board voted to draft a measure to present to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State School Directors Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSSDA</ENAMEX>) that calls for the replacement of the WASL in favor of the Measure of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Academic Progress</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MAP</ENAMEX>) test.   The local school board revisited the WASL issue at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>'s regularly scheduled meeting.   Before getting into the gist of the conversation <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> told the board about a couple of meetings that would be taking place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>). The first of the meetings was <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Education Service District</ENAMEX> 105 Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Gutting</ENAMEX> invited all superintendents in the district to a meeting to discuss graduation requirements for monolingual Spanish speaking students. The meeting was also set to discuss alternative assessments for taking the WASL for monolingual Spanish speaking students. Tonight, board members and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> were invited to share their concerns in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX> 105 office about the issue they have with the WASL. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said representatives from the state superintendent's office are scheduled to be on hand.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last week</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> board member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Wells</ENAMEX> said he was concerned with the amount of learning time taken away from students with the administration of the WASL, which takes eight days of class time away from students.   "I am not convinced the WASL is the ultimate standard for achievement in learning," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>. "I think the whole WASL is flawed, but I may not know enough about it."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> encouraged the state superintendent's office to take an educational stance with school districts and the public.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said he is glad the dialogue that has been ongoing within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> district supporting the stance of the parents to eliminate the WASL has caught the attention of state leaders. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> said he also had concerns of how much it will cost state taxpayers to teach students who don't pass the WASL.   "Let's start a dialogue and talk about what is best for the students," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> board member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Kilian</ENAMEX> agreed with a comment by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> that the concerns the district has with the WASL is not just about Hispanic students.   "I am worried about all students," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> added that there is something wrong with a test such as the WASL when <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor Society</ENAMEX> students who already have their Associate of Arts degree in hand don't pass the test. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX> pointed out how at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s graduation a number of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Honor Society</ENAMEX> students weren't wearing the tassel signifying they had passed the WASL.   At the end of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX>'s discussion, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> asked for input from the school board members to clarify their position concerning the WASL controversy. The clarification basically states that while the school board is in favor of establishing academic requirements for students, it is concerned about students with limited English skills being required to take the WASL. Other concerns expressed by the school board include increased dropout rates and the amount of learning time students lose by taking the WASL.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> also shared that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">WSSDA Legislative Committee</ENAMEX> gave its approval to the district's legislative proposal, requiring districts to prepare a plan that would exempt students who don't read or understand English from taking the WASL until they have passed the state language proficiency tests. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board Vice</ENAMEX> Chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Garza</ENAMEX> is scheduled to make a presentation to WSSDA at its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> assembly.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

