
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pritchett</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> spark <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> girls to tie
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> girls bowling team claimed its first "non-loss" decision of the season this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>, tying the Pasco Bulldogs, 2-2.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Junior Desiree Pritchett</ENAMEX> and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Gonzalez</ENAMEX> were the catalysts for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pritchett</ENAMEX> rolled a match best 299 two-game series on efforts of 169-130. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> added games of 153-127 for a 280 two-game series.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> topped <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> in the opener, 682-634. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pritchett</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX>'s games of 169 and 153, respectively, paced <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to the win. But, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> also got worthy efforts from senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cassie Coder</ENAMEX> (146) and sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Katie Weets</ENAMEX> (122). Freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Veronica Uribe</ENAMEX> rounded out the scoring for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the first game with a 92.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> rebounded to win the second contest, 634-600. Freshman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Weise</ENAMEX> led the Bulldogs to the second game win, rolling a 148. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s best effort in the second game was a 132, tossed by Weets.   The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> clinched at least a tie in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s match, staged at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Valley Lanes, by winning the first of two Baker games, 128-127.   The Baker format calls for each member of the five-girl squad to alternate taking turns throughout the 10 frames.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> rallied in the second Baker contest, winning 142-121, to square the match at 2-2.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV</ENAMEX> action <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> followed the varsity's lead and tied the match at 2-all. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grizzly JV</ENAMEX> won the opening game, 555-530, and claimed victory in the second Baker game, 113-110. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV</ENAMEX> top bowlers on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> included <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josefina Ramirez</ENAMEX> (122-113) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cora Rodriguez</ENAMEX> (111-118).   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

