
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funding announcement expected by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX> meeting
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/28/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">No announcement came this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on whether or not <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had been granted the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> it was seeking from the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>).   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> that he is expecting an answer from the non-profit agency within the next few days. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> is expecting to have a decision from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>, which oversees the management of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> group, by the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 2</TIMEX> meeting.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX> is one of several entities vying for more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> group will be awarding for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> projects. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> leaders submitted a proposal for all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds to help with the maintenance of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>, including the construction of a skateboard park, which <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX> has been trying to put together for numerous years.   Other projects in the running for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> funds include a proposal to install playground equipment in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> parks, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> proposal for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> to fund youth programs at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Center</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview Port District</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> requesting <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$72,500</NUMEX> to help fund the establishment of a grape and wine education center at the former Grandview Safeway store.   Some of the other projects include a request from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> to provide funding for health care career projects and from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inc.</ENAMEX> to aid with holding seminars for small business owners.   Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Stevens</ENAMEX> stepped before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> asking for the body's support of the skateboard project even if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> group doesn't provide funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> said he felt what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> has been trying to do with constructing the skateboard park is "incredible." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> said he felt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and the entire community should assist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mendoza</ENAMEX> with his project.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

