
<P ID="1">Calendar
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/24/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">4-calendar rev.
updated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/24/04</TIMEX>
calendar
Mondays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meets Mondays at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX>, Homer Street.
Mondays
Al-Anon meetings are held Mondays 7 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> in the main lobby.
MONDAYS
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> TOPS (Take Off Pounds Sensibly) Chapter meets 6:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Citizen Center</ENAMEX>, 1400 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Federal Way</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 839-4992 for details.
Mondays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Noon</TIMEX> Rotary meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Snipes Mountain Brewery</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Restaurant</ENAMEX>, Yakima Valley Highway.
second mondays
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Caregiver Support Group</ENAMEX>, sponsored by Aging and Long Term Care of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Southeast Washington</ENAMEX>, meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> in room 7 of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Parish Center</ENAMEX>, 907 S. Sixth St. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. For more information about the group call 837-2243 or 837-4436.
Third Mondays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Christian Women meet at The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barn Restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 894-4610 for information.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuesdays</ENAMEX>
An eight-week session on grief support, sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Grief and Bereavement Committee</ENAMEX>, is currently taking place every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> in the Reinhold Memorial Library at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Parish Center</ENAMEX>, 907 S. Sixth St. in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. The two-month session began <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 17</TIMEX>, but each meeting, which addresses both educationnal and support issues, is open for anyone to attend. For more information about the sessions call 837-2243.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuesdays
KOSMOS</ENAMEX> - over 50 singles group meets 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> For meeting place call <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Cronin</ENAMEX> at 836-2921 or Bob Van Horn at 837-8485.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuesdays
Compassionate Connection Support Group</ENAMEX> meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunny Spot Restaurant</ENAMEX>, Yakima Valley Highway. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-2339 or 837-5406 for more information.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Tuesdays
Community Service Food Bank</ENAMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seventh-day Adventist Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Lincoln Avenue</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Winter</TIMEX> hours are 9 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
first <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> committee of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW Sunny View Post</ENAMEX> #3482 meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at the post home, 615 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Ave.
Second</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
Horizon Quilters Unlimited of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immanuel Lutheran Church</ENAMEX>, 300 S. Euclid and 3rd, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. For more information call 837-7069.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Second</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW Sunny View Post</ENAMEX> #3482 and Ladies Auxiliary meet at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the post home, 615 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Ave.
Second</ENAMEX> and fourth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Food Bank</ENAMEX> open from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>  for pick-up or donations of food items at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton V.F.W</ENAMEX>. Hall across from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 894-4273 to arrange donations.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Third Tuesdays
American Veterans Post</ENAMEX> #95 meets at 132 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 882-1058 for more information.
Fourth Tuesdays
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Masonic Lodge No. 138, F.&A.M., meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> Call Bill Flower, 837-3505 for details.
Fourth Tuesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Garden Club</ENAMEX> meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:00 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-4138 for location.
Wednesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Daybreak Rotary meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
Wednesdays
Moms in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Touch International</ENAMEX>, a non-denominational group that prays for children and schools, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-3459 for day and location.
First andthird Wednesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Chapter #134 Order of Eastern Star, meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Masonic Temple</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sixth</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Harrison</ENAMEX>.
Second Wednesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School Booster Club</ENAMEX> meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:15 p.m.</TIMEX> at the middle school library.
Second Wednesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton VFW Post</ENAMEX> #10384 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Barnard R. Christiansen Post</ENAMEX>  meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> post home, B. Street.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Second</ENAMEX> andfourth Wednesdays
Golden Agers potluck dinners and meetings at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senior Citizen Center</ENAMEX>, 1400 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Federal Way</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-5572 for details. All persons age 55 and older are welcome.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Second</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Credit Professionals International</ENAMEX> meets every second and fourth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call Joyce Wells</ENAMEX>, 882-2248 for details.
second Wednesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Regional Clean Air Authority</ENAMEX> meets the second <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> of every month at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1:30 p.m.</TIMEX> in room B33 at the Yakima County Courthouse.
Fourth Wednesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmVets Post</ENAMEX> #3733 meets at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SunnyView VFW Post</ENAMEX> #3482, 615 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX>. <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
thursdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX> meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:45 a.m.</TIMEX> at El Mejor Taquito, .544 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">S.</ENAMEX> 6th Street.  Meetings are open to the public.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Thursdays
Cribbage Club</ENAMEX> meets every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eagles Lodge</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill Road</ENAMEX>. For more information, contact <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linda Johnson</ENAMEX>, 837-5636.
Thursdays
TOPS #<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>. 1232 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> through <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Immanuel Lutheran Church</ENAMEX>, 300 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S. Euclid</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 882-5525 for more information.
Second Thursdays
The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fibromyalgia Support Group</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Hospice Education Outreach Program, meets at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Methodist Church</ENAMEX>, Ninth Street and E. Edison Avenue, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6-7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>, Edison Avenue entrance. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-4818 for details.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second Thursdays
Grandview VFW Post</ENAMEX> #6929 meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the post  home, 132 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Division St.</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
SECOND <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">THURSDAY</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ministerial Association</ENAMEX> meets second Thursdays of each month. For more information call 837-2734.—(not meeting in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>, or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August</TIMEX> or the first <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX>.)
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Second</ENAMEX> and fourth Thursdays
Regular meeting dates for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Lions Clubs. Meetings are held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Library <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 839-2574 for membership information.
Fourth Thursdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> meets the  <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Thursday</TIMEX> of each month at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denny Blaine Building</ENAMEX>, Custer Avenue.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bridge Club
Meets Thursdays</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX>, and Mondays at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banner Bank</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Edison Avenue</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Thursday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diabetic Support Group</ENAMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Health</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Information Center</ENAMEX>, Ninth Street and Franklin Avenue, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> No charge for attending. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-1624 for details.
Second Fridays
Sunny Valley Grange #870 meets at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at the grange hall, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Factory Road</ENAMEX>. A potluck and social is held on the fourth <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> of each month at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fridays
Consumer Credit Counseling</ENAMEX> every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Banner Bank of Washington</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 1-800-273-6897 for an appointment.
Wednesdays
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Toastmasters meets  at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> administrative conference room. Call Bac Nguyen at 882-6120 for more information.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FRIDAYS
Adolescent</ENAMEX> pregnancy and parenting program in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> at Planned Parenthood office. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-5005 for more information.
mondays and wednesdays and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">fridays
Ministerial Food Bank</ENAMEX> at 8:<TIMEX TYPE="TIME">30-11:30 a.m.</TIMEX> at 8th and Decater in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Call</ENAMEX> 837-6754 for details.
</P> 


 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

