
<P ID="1">Veteran police officer moves to detective position
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> native and 18-year police officer veteran has been named to the detective's division of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Orth</ENAMEX> will begin his duties as a detective <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> is no stranger to the detective's division. He has spent almost half of his time as a police officer working as a detective. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> was the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood police</ENAMEX> officer assigned to the Law Enforcement Against Drugs (LEAD) task force, a job he held for five years. He also served as a warrant officer and investigated drug and general crimes.   "I wanted to make a dent in the drug world," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> of his time investigating drug crimes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> started his career in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">18 years ago</TIMEX>. He got a job with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.   "The reason I came to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was I was born and raised here and my parents lived here," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX>.   Before <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> became a police officer he was working at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> area dairy, but a friend convinced him to go on a police ride-along in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>.   "What got me hooked was the first day I was riding with the chief and we got in a pursuit with a motorcycle," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX>. "I was hooked."   Interested in the field he became a reserve officer in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger</ENAMEX> for about a year before he was hired by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX>. He became a police officer for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX>.   With an opening in the detective's division, which currently has two officers investigating crimes, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> decided to apply. As a detective he will be working <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday through Friday</TIMEX> and be on call. "You can get called out in the middle of the night or at family functions, but that's the trade-off," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX>.   Hiring a detective with past experience will save the city money, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX>.   "What this does, since I already have experience and training, is it cuts the six months needed to train someone to be a detective," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX>. "This is going to save the department a lot of time and money."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> will be investigating a variety of crimes in the community as the new detective, under Det. Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Trevino</ENAMEX>.   He said one area he anticipates spending some time investigating is the graffiti in town.   "We've got some kids out there doing graffiti and that needs to be stopped," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Orth</ENAMEX> has been married to his wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances</ENAMEX> for 25 years. The couple has two adult children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiffany</ENAMEX>, 24, and T.J., 21.   He is an avid hunter and a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s Wine Country Rides chapter of Backcountry Horsemen of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

