
<P ID="1">Grizzlies end season with a loss
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> season didn't end on a bright note for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> football team.   The Grizzlies ended their year with a lopsided 31-14 loss <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to 2A <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>, which was the number five seed out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Athletic Conference</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Mark Marro</ENAMEX> didn't offer any great excuses for the loss.   "We just didn't play real well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>) came out fired up."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the Grizzlies have been in a bit of a downslide since having to go into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> only at half strength with its roster. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said it has been hard for his team to get out of the mode.   "We really dropped at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of the year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "It is difficult to keep that intensity level."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said the last game of the season was also difficult for his team because there wasn't much left to play for, with the Grizzlies being out of the playoffs.   After a scoreless opening quarter, the Grizzlies pulled ahead 7-0 when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greg Gilleland</ENAMEX> dashed in from five yards out. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>, though, answered back, scoring with about 30 seconds left in the first half. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> took a 7-6 lead into the break.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> went wild in the second half on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> defense, scoring 25 unanswered points.   "We gave up a couple of deep balls and that just gave them life," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s last touchdown of the year came in the fourth quarter when quarterback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Cantu</ENAMEX> hooked up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Noe Zamarron</ENAMEX> on a 21-yard touchdown pass.   The Grizzlies posted mediocre statistics in the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cantu</ENAMEX> was 4-of-11 in the game for 79 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gilleland</ENAMEX> had eight rushes for 49 yards.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX>' defense did a great job of stopping <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s rushing game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rangers</ENAMEX> also put together an effective ground attack, spreading the ball around between three players for nearly 150 yards.   "They were faster than us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marro</ENAMEX>. "They had the best game of their season."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> finished its season with a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> record of 2-4, good for fifth place. The Grizzlies were 4-6 overall on the year.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

