


<P ID="1">Guest Editorial
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">DON <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">C. BRUNELL</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United Nations</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">90 percent</NUMEX> of eligible Afghans have registered to vote in that country's landmark <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">October</TIMEX> elections - a resounding endorsement of a democratic experiment that may help <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Afghanistan</ENAMEX> turn its back on years of debilitating war.
</P><P ID="5">   The Afghan people realize the importance of voting in a democracy. But the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state seem to have forgotten.
</P><P ID="6">   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1952</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ike</ENAMEX> was elected President and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Arthur Langlie</ENAMEX> was elected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s governor, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">91 percent</NUMEX> of eligible citizens in our state were registered and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">80 percent</NUMEX> of them voted. But in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">70 percent</NUMEX> of eligible voters were registered and just over half of those people voted. That means that only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">35 percent</NUMEX> of eligible state residents voted.
</P><P ID="7">   Even though our state's population has grown four-fold since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eisenhower</ENAMEX>'s time, the percent of people registering and voting is steadily declining - despite the fact people can register online and plop their ballots in the mail rather than trekking off to polling places.
</P><P ID="8">   Watching this trend, it is no wonder union leaders are pushing their "labor-neighbor" program. "Labor-neighbor" is simple. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Union</ENAMEX> members encourage their family, friends and neighbors to register and vote. Most importantly, they make sure they vote.
</P><P ID="9">   As a kid growing up in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX>, I saw it work first-hand. My father was treasurer of his union and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Democrat Party</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Silver Bow County</ENAMEX>, and in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brunell</ENAMEX> household, the "get out the vote" effort was a family affair. During election time, one of my jobs was to go through the new telephone book and make sure that the phone numbers for union members, their friends and families were accurate. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Election Day</TIMEX>, the union poll watchers used my list to call people who had not voted. Sometimes cars were dispatched to pick them up and drive them to the polls. My Dad joked, "Whether they got a ride home depended on how they voted!"
</P><P ID="10">   Joking aside, voter turnout will determine who sits in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Oval Office</ENAMEX> and who controls the state legislature. It is essential that employers encourage their families, friends and associates to register and vote. If you think a few votes here or there don't matter, consider what happened in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX> when the Bush-Gore race came down to a few hundred votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX> and the infamous "hanging chads."
</P><P ID="11">   Then in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX>, six <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> seats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> legislature were decided by fewer than 600 votes. Republican Jack Cairnes won by a mere 92 votes of the 32,000 votes cast in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kent and Democrat Debbie Wallace</ENAMEX> edged out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Dunn</ENAMEX> by 376 votes out of 29,000 cast in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>. In the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, four of the 24 seats were decided by fewer than 1,300 votes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Republican Bob Oke</ENAMEX> beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Betty Ringlee</ENAMEX> by 343 votes with more than 41,000 votes cast.
</P><P ID="12">   Voting is a right and a privilege that citizens in many other countries wish they had. The deadline to register to vote in the primary is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">August 14</TIMEX>. Get your friends and family members registered, and make sure they vote.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don C. Brunell</ENAMEX> is President of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Association of Washington Business</ENAMEX>.
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




