
<P ID="1">Local men on duty this holiday
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">While <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> families are preparing for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> celebrations, Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Navarro</ENAMEX> is already back on duty in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mosul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> communications specialist, is one of the thousands of American men and women serving in the war zone and other outposts around the world. He is also one of several <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> young people, who for a brief moment, came home on leave from the war front.   But <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX>, like many of the local young servicemen, says he is OK with heading back to the war front. He considers himself one of the lucky one.   "I got to be home to celebrate <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with my family, even if it was two weeks early," he said.   He, along with his wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizabeth</ENAMEX>, just completed a two- week leave, coming home for the first time in years to spent <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with his parents, Mr. and Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Navarro</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   The Navarros' also have another son serving in the military this holiday. Their son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick</ENAMEX> is a tank commander at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fort Stewart</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> and served along side his brother in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kuwait</ENAMEX> during the earlier stages of the Iraqi War.   While on leave, the young soldier visited his family and cousins, and took out time to talk about his job with area school students.   "I spoke to students in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> classrooms telling them that part of my job in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> is to help rebuild the country," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX>, who just celebrated his 31st birthday, said he also stressed the importance of education to the students.   "One of the things we're rebuilding in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> is the schools," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX>, who one day hopes to become a teacher, said for the time being he is committed to serving his country as a solider.   "We have a lot of hard work ahead of us in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, especially now that we captured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX>, who enlisted following high school graduation, is attached to the 101st Airborne 2nd Infantry currently stationed near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mosul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mosul</ENAMEX> is located about a six hours drive north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baghdad</ENAMEX>.   As the communications specialist for his unit, he is in charge of eight servicemen who handle the group's communications, from military movements to wireless services used by the soldiers to keep them in touch with their families.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Navarro</ENAMEX> is just one of several <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> natives who returned home for a short break from their military duties.   Much to her joy and that of her family, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marty Clemmens</ENAMEX>' son-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoff Black</ENAMEX>, was home on leave <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>.   "We felt very fortunate that he got to come home even for just a few weeks," she said.   While home, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> was invited to participate in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">SunnyView VFW Post</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Pearl Harbor Day</TIMEX> Remembrance program held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 7</TIMEX>, in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "It was a real honor to visit with the veterans of other wars," he said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX> said he also felt honored to have met <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pearl Harbor</ENAMEX> survivor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Fairbanks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Black</ENAMEX>, who is attached to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>'s 125th Forward Support Battalion, is now back on duty in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baghdad</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick and Mary Melendrez</ENAMEX> are excited to have their soldier sons home for the holidays.   Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Melendrez</ENAMEX>, who is scheduled to arrive home on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eve</ENAMEX>, will leave for active duty as a tank engineer with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">81st Brigade</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 27</TIMEX>.   Son Chris, a first lieutenant with the 1/5 Cavalry at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Hood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, will be home until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 29</TIMEX>, before reporting back for overseas duty, said his mother.   "I'm so happy to have them home for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>," she said. "I'm making sure we all have a family photo taken as a part of our celebration," she added.   She said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melendrez</ENAMEX> brothers will both be overseas by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX>, after undergoing training at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next month</TIMEX>.   Also home for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> holiday is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Second</ENAMEX> Lieutenant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Crysti Greenway</ENAMEX>, 30, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. While she hasn't yet served in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said she is anxious to do her part.   "As an officer, I'm proud to be able serve with those men and women who volunteered to fight for our flag and country," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>, who just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">six months ago</TIMEX> decided to re-enlist in the military, will be a member of the 18th Airborne, which has a major part of its troops stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>.   She said there is a high probability she will eventually rotate in to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. "I've requested that posting," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> history major.   The daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary and Terry Pearson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>, she comes from a long line of military personnel. Her parents and her grandparents all served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> military. Her mother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX>, served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Persian Gulf</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> first enlisted in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Navy</ENAMEX> following high school graduation. She worked her way up to Petty Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Second Class</ENAMEX> after six years, before deciding to become a civilian again. But upon enrolling at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>, she joined the ROTC. She also served for three years in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX>'s 790th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chemical Company</ENAMEX>, stationed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "At the urging of 1st Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jack Emler</ENAMEX>, I decided to enlist in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said she has more training to complete before she will be fully prepared to head overseas.   "I just finished my transportation corps officer basic at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Eustis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Virginia</ENAMEX>," she said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said the transportation corps is responsible for getting food and military supplies to the "war fighter."   At the end of her two-week leave, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> will be training at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Benning</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Georgia</ENAMEX> in day and night jumping. Later, she will be stationed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Bragg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">N.C</ENAMEX>. with the 18th Airborne.   "I think it surprised my family when I decided to go back into the services," she said.   "But it's the best job in the world," she said.   In the meantime, a young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> recruit, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeremy Snyder</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is preparing to leave for boot camp in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Carolina</ENAMEX>.   "I'm going to be training as a light wheel mechanic," said the young man, who is currently employed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Bi-Mart store.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Snyder</ENAMEX>, 24, said he won't leave for boot camp until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Jan 15</TIMEX>.   "So I'll get to have <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> with my family <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," he said.   Even though he knows there is a chance he may end up overseas serving with other army troops, he said he is not worried.   "At least I know what I signed up for and what I'm getting myself into," he said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">jSmart@hawkpress.com   Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>   Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Navarro</ENAMEX> (R), pictured with his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> businessman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Navarro</ENAMEX>, recently completed two short weeks of leave before being sent back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The young <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> sergeant is stationed near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mosul</ENAMEX>, north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, with the 101st Airborne.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Daily News   Pearl Harbor survivor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Fairbanks</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> wishes <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Geoff Black</ENAMEX> well as the young soldier heads back to active duty with American troops stationed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>.   Lt. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chris Melendrez</ENAMEX>   Sgt. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Melendrez</ENAMEX>   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

