
<P ID="1">Palacios returns from national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motocross</ENAMEX> race
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">With age and experience comes wisdom. Case in point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon Palacios</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> qualified for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Motocross Association Amateur</ENAMEX>/Youth National Motocross Championship at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Lynn</ENAMEX>'s ranch in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tennessee</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 2-7</TIMEX>. Turning 7 in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late June</TIMEX>, he is now more experienced after being able to compete at a race not too many <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motocross</ENAMEX> riders his age get to take part in.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> was one of 42 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motocross</ENAMEX> racers in his classification, the 51cc 4-6 Stock Oil Injection division, to compete for national championship honors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> ended up finishing 36th out of the pack. The field featured <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motocross</ENAMEX> riders from all over the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Minnesota</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Florida</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">California</ENAMEX> and even <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bermuda</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> was one of only a couple of riders from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> qualified for the prestigious national race by winning a Regional qualifying event in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washougal</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>'s father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>, said his son didn't catch much of a break right from the start, getting handed the 38th spot in the gate pick, which put him on the difficult opposite side of the first turn.   "It was strictly luck of the draw," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> said he had never raced on a course like the one at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loretta Lynn</ENAMEX>'s estate at Hurricane Mills.   "The course was hard," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> added he had never seen so many expert riders as he did at the national championships.   The most difficult spot on the course, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>, was an area referred to as "The 10 Commandments." The commandments are a set of 10 hills that riders hit in consecutive stride.   "There are a lot of ruts on them," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> said the commandments were very chLofferging because as soon as he would come down one hill, he would hit another that would send him shooting back into the air.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>, though, said he was pleased for the most part with how he rode.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> thought his son did well at the event, even though he said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> would have liked to done better. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> said on a couple of the turns his son was dead last and worked his way back through the pack.   Besides competing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> said he had a great time watching the "big guys" race. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> said it was exciting to see them speed around the course.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> also had a good time playing in Hurricane Creek, a river running through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX>'s estate. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> said he saw all sorts of creatures such as crawfish and frogs.   "It is very kid oriented there," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX>'s estate had all kinds of areas dedicated to keeping youngsters busy, including an arcade.   "It is something a kid would dream of," grinned <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> also had the opportunity to see two of his idols at the event, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motocross</ENAMEX> riders Bubba Stewart and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ivan Tedesco</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> and his parents took time out during their two-week excursion to see some of the sights along the way. Among the places the family stopped at were <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mt. Rushmore</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">St. Louis</ENAMEX> arch, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Graceland</ENAMEX>, the Sears Tower in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Abraham Lincoln</ENAMEX>'s birthplace and the Crazy Horse memorial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> said they also had a chance to tour <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX>'s home.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> also had the chance to take his first taxi cab ride, which he said was something to experience in a "big city." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> said his favorite stop on the tour was the Greyhound Hall of Fame in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Abilene</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kansas</ENAMEX>, a museum dedicated to dog racing. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Damon</ENAMEX> said he liked looking at all of the dog items in the museum.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX> said he was very proud of how his son did.   "A little better gate pick and he could have easily been in the top 20," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Palacios</ENAMEX> said there are a lot of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">motocross</ENAMEX> races that a person can compete at, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn</ENAMEX>'s is the biggest one.   "This is by far the most prestigious one to go to," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave</ENAMEX>. "It is kind of like the Rose Bowl."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

