
<P ID="1">Grandview fair takes on new look
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/14/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo is going to look a little different <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX>, according to fair and rodeo representatives <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Fisher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX>. Instead of being spread over 11 acres the fair will be more compactly laid out. The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> event will include a carnival and there will be more events, activities and sights for people to take in during their visit to the fair and rodeo.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>, who together served as the guest speakers for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> people can expect to see some changes at the fair and rodeo.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said the fair is an event that started in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> approximately <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">77 years ago</TIMEX>, noting that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">13 years ago</TIMEX> the fair was moved from its downtown location to its current location along <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Way</ENAMEX>. She said when the fair was moved from its small downtown location to its new 11-acre home, people coming to the fair didn't see as much there because it was spread over a considerably larger area.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX> we're trying to get it closer together," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> later added that bringing the event together will mean that people visiting the fair and rodeo will no longer have to walk what seems like half a mile to get to the carnival or other sights the fair has to offer.   The fair isn't the only thing getting a light makeover <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> told Rotarians that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> the rodeo, which up until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> was a ProWest rodeo, will be a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Professional Rodeo Cowboy Association</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRCA</ENAMEX>) rodeo event.   "It's a new venture for us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said. She added that she is hopeful that the new PRCA designation will mean that even more people will come out to both take part in and support the local event.   "We're really excited about this and we're hoping to get support for this," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said, noting that the rodeo is made possible through the use of donations from the community.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> said the fair board is also trying to reach out to other neighboring communities for support.   "We're not a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> rodeo and a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> fair," she said. "We're called the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Fair</ENAMEX> and Rodeo."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fisher</ENAMEX> added that looking at the students who regularly show animals during the fair it is easy to see the many different communities that are represented. She noted that there are typically more students who show animals from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> at the Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo then there are from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said he is hoping to see more commercial booths at the fair <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>, noting that he is also looking to other neighboring communities for people to come in and showcase their businesses at the fair.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> noted that in addition to trying to attract people from up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> to support the fair and rodeo, the fair board is also looking to bring more people in from these neighboring communities to take part in the event. He said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> the Wenatchee Youth Circus will be in town for two nights of the fair and rodeo, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> is also scheduled to conduct a band and cheer day in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 12</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> explained that the band and cheer day will give area bands who did not have the opportunity to participate in a band camp to come to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and attend a day long band camp presented by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. He said following the camp the students who took part will <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">march</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> parade, as well as perform at the Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo.   "There's a lot happening <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> said. "It's going to be a really exciting event."   The Yakima Valley Fair and Rodeo is scheduled to take place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 11-15</TIMEX>, with the rodeo taking place <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 13</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 14</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

