
<P ID="1">Former Alderwoodr volunteers to help troubled teens
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SPOKANE</ENAMEX> - Former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nancy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Drysdale</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> is carving out her own niche in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> area, helping troubled teens who have been arrested in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> area.   A graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX>, the daughter of local resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wade Drysdale</ENAMEX>, started volunteering for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Accountability Board</ENAMEX> nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>. The board is similar to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Accountability Board</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX>.   "I have three grandchildren that are in their teens now and I was interested in keeping current in what they face and what they're involved with," said the 54-year-old woman.   She said there are more youths in the juvenile justice system than ever before and she hopes the accountability board alternative will make a positive impact in their lives, turning them from repeating their crime.   As a volunteer, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> meets with youths and their parent or guardian and talks with them about the incident. She said it is important to her to hear from the youths their version of what happened.   She also likes to find out the youths likes and dislikes; struggles and successes in life.   After reviewing the case, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> draws up a contract of consequences and reviews it with the youth, who can be between the ages of 8 and 17, and their parents. She said they all have to agree on the contract and sign it.   As a part of a consequence contract, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> said she may have a student who's a gifted artist make an educational poster about teen alcohol use or drug abuse, if that is why they were sentenced to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Accountability Board</ENAMEX>. Also common punishments, besides writing a letter to the victim, is completing hours of community service, counseling sessions and anger management classes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> also monitors the youths' progress though their sentencing.   Volunteering two nights a month to the board, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> said she will work with an average of 48 youths every year.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> said the youths who are sentenced to working with the volunteers on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Neighborhood Accountability Board</ENAMEX> commit a wide variety of crimes, including driving without a license, vandalism, theft, minor assaults and drug and alcohol use, which she said are common.   As a member of one of three Neighbor Accountability Boards in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, she is one of 50 volunteers working with youths.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

