


<P ID="1">Infected <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Holstein</ENAMEX> one of 10 Canadian cows sent to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dairy
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/2/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ron DeHaven</ENAMEX>, chief veterinarian for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX>, announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> that 10 of the 82 cows imported into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, which includes the bovine spongiform encephalopathy infected cow, were found to have been sent to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wavrin</ENAMEX> family's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> dairy.
</P><P ID="5">   Nine of the animals remain at the dairy. The tenth was the animal that was slaughtered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 9</TIMEX>, leading to the discovery of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>' first case of mad cow disease.
</P><P ID="6">   Before killing the cows to test for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, or mad cow disease as it is commonly called, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said the USDA is trying to determine if the cows at the Mabton dairy are birth cohorts of the animal found to have <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, and whether or not the animals came from the same herd in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   "If we're able to absolutely confirm that they weren't fed the same feed as the indexed cow, then we may or may not take the animals at that point," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   Although <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> is slow to say the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> infected cow is definitely from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, he said the USDA's primary line of interest leads to an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> herd.
</P><P ID="9">   "We have good leads on the remaining animals," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> announced one of the 82 cows imported from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX> was recently located at a Mattawa dairy facility, which is now under state hold alert, or quarantine.
</P><P ID="11">   This brings the total number of animals located from the orginal 82 that crossed into the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 4, 2001</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oroville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wash.</ENAMEX> border crossing, to 11, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said. He noted that there is also information that points to one of the animals having remained in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> also announced that the international team of experts that will review the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> case of mad cow disease will be led by Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulrich Kihm</ENAMEX>, the former chief veterinary officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Switzerland</ENAMEX>, who now owns <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Safe Food Solutions, Inc.</ENAMEX>, a private consulting company.
</P><P ID="13">   Also on the panel will be Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Hueston</ENAMEX>, who is the director of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Center of Animal Health and Food Safety</ENAMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Minnesota</ENAMEX>, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dagmar Heim</ENAMEX>, chief of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> control in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swiss Federal Veterinary Office</ENAMEX>, and Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stuart MacDiarmid</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> expert with the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Zealand</ENAMEX> government.
</P><P ID="14">   Also being investigated is the occurrence of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in cows younger than 30 months, which are outside the restrictions implemented by the USDA.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said that although there have been incidents of cattle younger than 30 months with the disease, two in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX> and two in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">European Union</ENAMEX>, he said there have been questions to the accuracy of the Japanese test results.
</P><P ID="16">   He said in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> the entire European beef market slaughtered was tested for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, or about 19 million animals. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said that one of the cows that tested positive was 28 months old and a second 29 months of age.
</P><P ID="17">   "We also know that the incubation period is dose-dependent. The more infectious material that an animal consumes, the shorter the incubation period," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   He said with the new rules banning the sale of meat from "downer" cows for human consumption, there will have to be more work between the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Food</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Drug Administration</ENAMEX> and rendering plants, where cows unable to stand will most likely be sent. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeHaven</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FDA</ENAMEX> will want testing of downer animals that may make it into things like non-ruminant animal feed and pet foods.
</P>   
<P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




