
<P ID="1">Not a good weekend for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> cagers
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Getting everyone on the same page at the same time has proved difficult for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> boys basketball team.   Such was the case again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>, as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> rolled to easy victories over the Grizzly cage team.   "We never had everybody clicking on all four cylinders," <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Steve Urrutia</ENAMEX> said of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s 66-58 loss at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   At home <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>, the Grizzlies seemed content with playing soft ball.   "We weren't aggressive against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>. We weren't taking it to the hoop," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX> said in explaining <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s 97-59 loss to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX>.   The two weekend defeats lowered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> record to 3-9, 4-14 overall. Yet despite sustaining the two losses, the Grizzlies remained one game ahead of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> for the league's sixth and final berth to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> playoffs. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will close out regular season play this coming weekend, needing just one win at either Wapato (2-10) or at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> (1-13) to advance to the postseason.   Even though the Grizzlies are just one victory away from moving on to the playoffs, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX> said his club is viewing both games this coming weekend as must-win affairs.   "Our approach is we have to win both games," he said.   In <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s first meetings of the season against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, the Grizzlies lost by a single point to the Wolfpack and shellacked the Mustangs by a 57-41 score.   The whuppin' <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> handed out to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, though, didn't compare with the throttling the Grizzlies took <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>.   Oddly enough, the Grizzlies opened <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s game looking like they were going to give <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX>, the state's No. 2 ranked 3A team, all it could handle. The early lead <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> forged, though, quickly went by the wayside midway through the first quarter when the Grizzlies missed four or five relatively easy shots. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rams</ENAMEX> then exploded in the second period, increasing their 15-11 first quarter lead to 36-23 at intermission.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> ended any suspense the Grizzly faithful may have had by outscoring <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 30-16 in the third quarter. A 31-20 run by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> in the final period accounted for the final 97-59 score.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Rams</ENAMEX>, sitting atop the conference standings with an 11-1 mark, played without their 6'8" star, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Strait</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strait</ENAMEX> suffered a leg injury the previous night against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>, and his return to the floor in time for the playoffs is iffy. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Strait</ENAMEX>'s absence, teammates <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Corey Wehr</ENAMEX> and E.J. Schoen picked up the slack against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, tossing in 27 and 26 points, respectively.   The lone Grizzly in double figures was senior point guard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Ramirez</ENAMEX> with 15 points.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> and teammate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reid Schilperoort</ENAMEX>, a junior, also led the Grizzlies in scoring the previous night at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. The duo each knocked down 14 points in the 66-58 loss. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> got all 14 of his points in the second half.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s big man, 6'6" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake Thomas</ENAMEX>, was held to 7 points by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>. The Bulldogs shut out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> after intermission.   "It wasn't that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jake</ENAMEX> wasn't hitting his shots in the second half," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX>. "He just didn't get a lot of touches.   "We started casting it off from the outside more in the second half. Our shot selection wasn't the greatest from some of our guys," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX> added.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> had four players in double figures-Andy Aaron with a team high 14 points, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Griffith</ENAMEX> with 12, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Seeback</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Brozovich</ENAMEX> with 11 and 10 points, respectively. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX> canned 8 of his team high 14 points in the final quarter, when the Bulldogs outscored <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> by a 29-23 margin.   "We were only down by two at the end of the third quarter, but our offense sputtered in the fourth quarter," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

