
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> valedictorian learns to see the world from different eyes
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Getting on the bus headed for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council Student Leadership Program</ENAMEX> state conference, a reserved <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosa Aviles</ENAMEX>, 18, noticed one girl on the bus she thought was "mean."   Arriving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> found herself rooming with the girl she had stereotyped as "mean."   Ironically, stereotyping others was one of the topics discussed at the four-day conference held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 4-7</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX>.   "We learned about looking past the outside to who people really are and not stereotyping them, which is what I did when I first saw the girl who became my roommate," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX>.   After <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> got to know the girl, she learned that she was actually a nice person and as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> put it, "she was really cool."   Breaking down barriers was one of the goals of the conference <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> said the theme "Trying to see the world from different eyes" was based on the idea of helping the high school students find themselves, their second face or what's on the inside.   "I see the world from my own perspective," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX>. "I actually learned how to see that other people have problems too. I learned to see people and looking out there I am not the only migrant with different problems."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> said the first day of the conference the 70 teens from around the state learned how to get along with other people. She also learned how to set goals for herself.   "They showed us how to set goals for the future," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX>.   She is no stranger to the idea of goal setting and pushing herself. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> said it has been her goal to be among the top of her high school graduating class. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This June</TIMEX> she will be the valedictorian at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX>. She has also had a goal for higher education. She wants to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzaga University</ENAMEX>, to which she has already been accepted.   A remaining goal for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> is to become an emergency flight nurse.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> isn't sure how she was selected from her school to attend the conference, but she said, "I do a lot of stuff and people volunteer me for a lot of things."   A leader in her school, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> is active in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> program, has helped with the townhall meetings held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, works on community service projects and is a volunteer with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Fire Department</ENAMEX>.   She is also part of the Gate's Achiever program.   The migrant council conference also taught <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX> how to be a problem solver, which she said is important because many teens don't know how to solve their own problems.   "There's a lot of kids out there who commit suicide because they don't know how to solve their own problems," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aviles</ENAMEX>. "At the conference, they showed us a process on how to analyze our problems."   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

