


<P ID="1">New sales manager one of several faces back at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>'s
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/22/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">For a little more than a month, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Dawson</ENAMEX> has been back at work behind the desk at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel Ford Country</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> recently came back to the company as sales manager after spending the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last seven years</TIMEX> working for a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> dealership in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moscow</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> said he first came to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>'s in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early 1990s</TIMEX>, when the dealership was located at the old gas station on the corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sixth Street</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway. He said he started as a salesman and worked for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>'s until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, when he decided to pursue another venture. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1995</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> turned his attention to cooking and purchased an Italian restaurant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, which he operated until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> said he was born and raised in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and when the opportunity was brought forward for him to move back to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> he was more than happy to pursue it.
</P><P ID="7">   For <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX>, sales is a field he has always excelled in. When he first started he was selling farm equipment and was ranked as one of the three top salesman in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> for the sale of Case equipment. It was from there that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Denchel</ENAMEX> recruited <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> to come to work for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>'s.
</P><P ID="8">   This time around, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> once again played an integral role in his return to the local dealership. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> saw him at an automobile auction, where he asked if he would be interested in coming back to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> said with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> buying into the store, he knew it would be a good time to move back.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> said his new position allows him time to work sales, provide good customer service and a chance to get back into the local community. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> explained he is part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>'s new philosophy, noting that his is not the only familiar face at the dealership.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dawson</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>'s goal with the dealership is to make the car buying experience more personal.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX>, who became part owner of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> dealerships in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, said he is working to re-establish the business. He said when things first started there was a more personal way of doing business, which is something he wants to get back to. One way he is doing this is by bringing back familiar faces.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> said the people he has brought back exemplify the type of customer service skills he is looking to re-establish at the local dealership.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Denchel</ENAMEX> said his becoming part owner of the two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> dealerships will also give his brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel</ENAMEX>, a chance to grow his third dealership in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hermiston</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom</ENAMEX> said he and his brother are hoping to take the dealership even further, working to provide a high class, high quality experience for customers.
</P>





 










<P ID="15">Webmaster
</P><P ID="16">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




