


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> approves three annexation requests
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">After waiting more than two years to become a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordan and Rhoda Giffen</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McLean Road</ENAMEX> may finally get their wish.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>, which held three public hearings regarding to annexation requests, agreed to forward the couple's request to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Boundary Review Board</ENAMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>, meeting at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center on Homer Avenue</ENAMEX>, took comments from the public regarding the Giffens' request before voting to give the request its stamp of approval.
</P><P ID="7">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McLean Road</ENAMEX> property owners and their daughter-in-law, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lucille Giffen</ENAMEX>, are seeking the inclusion of their five-acre piece of property into the city limits, which is located at the southwest corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McLean</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alexander</ENAMEX> roads, located within the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port District</ENAMEX>. The area is scheduled to be zoned M-2 for heavy industrial development.
</P><P ID="8">   The Giffens began their quest to be included within the city limits nearly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>. However, the request was shelved in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> when the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> declared any annexation which used the petition method was unconstitutional, explained <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city attorney.
</P><P ID="9">   Historically, annexation requests required that property owners in the area being considered must all agree to the request. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Court Justices</ENAMEX> felt the system didn't take into consideration the desires of other residents living in the area. "They reversed themselves in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 2004</TIMEX>," he said.
</P><P ID="10">   In the meantime, the State Legislature has amended the state statute to require annexation petitions to have at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> approval signatures from the property owners, as well as at least <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the registered voters approval living in the area before it can be considered for annexation.
</P><P ID="11">   Both changes occurred <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said, which has prompted a steady increase in new annexation requests, as well as re-submissions of annexation requests such as the Giffens, he explained.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the Giffens had previously received the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>'s approval, but the city elected to put all annexations on hold until new annexation statutes were developed.
</P><P ID="13">   Only <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jill Nettleton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alexander Road</ENAMEX> voiced any concerns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nettleton</ENAMEX> urged the commissioners to ensure that such issues as weed control and proper buffer zones be a part of any future development in the area. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX> Chair <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Warren</ENAMEX> assured <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nettleton</ENAMEX> that the buffer and weeds and other issues involved in future developments would fall under the city's landscaping and ordinances and property management regulations.
</P><P ID="14">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> also approved a previously submitted request for annexation into the city by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port District</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX> was seeking to annex 38 areas of property located on the northeast corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alexander</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">McLean</ENAMEX> roads, which is already surrounded by city limits. "The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX>'s request was also put on hold in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX>," he said, adding that area will also be zoned M-2.
</P><P ID="16">   There was no comments from the public regarding the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Port</ENAMEX>'s request. It too will be forwarded to the Boundary <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Review Board</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> also approved a request from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Padelford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX>, who seeks to have five aces of property located at the end of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Airport</ENAMEX> runway included in the city boundaries. Following the public hearing on the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Padelford</ENAMEX> request, the commissioners could forward his request to the review board.
</P><P ID="18">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Padelford</ENAMEX> property is located at the northeast corner of Highway 241 and Edison Avenue, and is within the city's urban growth plan, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="19">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="20">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="21">Webmaster
</P><P ID="22">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




