


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> announces run for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> mayor
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/12/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is running for mayor of that community in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s elections.
</P>
<P ID="5">The current <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> city councilman has been working for quite some time on ideas he has for the community.
</P>
<P ID="6">"I'm announcing my intention to be a candidate for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November 2004</TIMEX> Election for mayor," he said.
</P>
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> is retired from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, having served in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. He received many awards during that time. They include the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meritorious Service Medal</ENAMEX>, The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> Commendation</ENAMEX> (five awards), and The Good Conduct medal (seven awards).
</P>
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> works on his farm and has been active in local politics for many years.
</P>
<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> serves as an officer of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County V.F.W</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Post</ENAMEX> 23. He is a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Elks Lodge, and a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P>