


<P ID="1">Local taxpayers get a break with sale of school bonds
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/11/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Jubilation filled the meeting room of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> during a special gathering of directors <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to approve the sale of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> in bonds to construct a new school.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> patrons approved an <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> bond issue to construct the new school in the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller</ENAMEX> roads during a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX> election. At the same time, district voters also approved a four-year <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.4 million</NUMEX> levy.
</P><P ID="6">   But <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting had nothing to do with the levy, but rather with some good news that residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> should be more than happy to hear.
</P><P ID="7">   When the matter was originally put before voters, school district officials expected patrons to be paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.61</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value to cover the cost of the bond issue. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jon Gores</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle-Northwest Securities Corporation</ENAMEX>, which handled the bond transaction for the school district on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, reported <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> to an elated board that district residents will only be paying <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1.51</NUMEX> per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> of assessed property value, or 10¢ less than originally estimated.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> sold all <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> in bonds for the school district <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>) morning.
</P><P ID="9">   The district will see significant savings in interest costs. Originally, it was projected the district would incur an interest cost of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.59 percent</NUMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> sold the bonds <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> at a net interest cost of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.62 percent</NUMEX>, resulting in a savings of slightly more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.2 million</NUMEX> dollars. The actual interest cost on the bonds will be <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4.3 million</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> also reported that because of the way the bonds were purchased, the district will be able to use all <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> for its capital projects fund.
</P><P ID="11">   The bonds will mature in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2017</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX> added the bonds sold well on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, as many buyers were willing to purchase them at a higher value. Purchasing the bonds at a higher value results in more of a significant cash flow being available for the buyer, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "The main reason they (buyers) do it is because they are convinced interest rates are going to go up," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   In the end, the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> in bonds were sold for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.2 million</NUMEX>. The district is able to utilize the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$239,183</NUMEX> in premium money gained to pay for the underwriting of the bonds. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gores</ENAMEX>' company is being paid <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$77,660</NUMEX> by the district for selling the bonds, leaving <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11.1 million</NUMEX> left to utilize for projects. The money in excess of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> will go into the district's debt service fund to help pay for costs associated with the project.
</P><P ID="15">   The bonds that were sold are exempt from federal income tax because the money is being used for a public improvement project.
</P><P ID="16">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> treasurer is expected to release the money for the bonds to the school district on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25</TIMEX>. This is the same date as the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> school board meeting, at which time local directors are expected to approve the hiring of an architect to begin work on the design phase for the construction of the new school.
</P>   






 










<P ID="17">Webmaster
</P><P ID="18">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




