


<P ID="1">New Gospel album combines Motown savvy with street ministry jive
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Perhaps it's no accident that only those who make it in the music world are related to someone else who's in the producing end. But occasionally complete unknowns have been known to walk in off the street to grab the brass ring of fame.
</P><P ID="5">   Such may be the case for the four young singers who have combined their talents to produce a new gospel CD as the group known as "Ramiyah," (pronounced Rah-my-yah).
</P><P ID="6">   Ramiyah's album was produced by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mathew Knowles</ENAMEX>, the father of the new queen of pop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beyoncé Knowles</ENAMEX>. It is loaded with much of the same sound familiar to her fans. One of the songs on the album, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> from God," was written by solo <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">singer-songwriter Solange Knowles</ENAMEX>, Beyoncé's 16-year-old sister.
</P><P ID="7">   The four girls who comprise Ramiyah met during an audition just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year ago</TIMEX>. The album of the same name is their first professional effort.
</P><P ID="8">   I admit they have got a certain hip hop appeal, but I found it hard to understand their singing. However, I did enjoy the blending of voices, finding the sound to be silky smooth.
</P><P ID="9">   Ramiyah's solo 17-track album includes ballads and anthems to their Lord, packed with a passion and a sense of sincerity.
</P><P ID="10">   Tracks on the album I enjoyed included "The Reason" and "Waiting." The songs all deal with fighting temptation and calling on the Lord for guidance and strength.
</P><P ID="11">   This album will make great listening for young Christian music fans. I give this album my 14-year-old granddaughter's thumb's vote, which is probably equal to three stars anywhere else.
</P><P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="13">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="14">Webmaster
</P><P ID="15">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




