
<P ID="1">Dogs threatening kids on school grounds
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/28/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">A tragedy was averted on school grounds <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> when a pit bull grabbed hold of a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> first grader.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Officer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chico Rodriguez</ENAMEX> said the latest dog incident on school grounds resulted in no serious injuries, "...but we've had dog bites before," he said.   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">This morning</TIMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, the pit bull in question only got ahold of the boys' trousers. "But it could have been worse," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>.   "Every day there's dogs out there," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> continued. "It's a safety issue."   The local police department is asking dog owners to secure their pets, or kennel them, so school-age children are not in danger of being bitten.   The pit bull that nipped at the first grade boy <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> was located and picked up by an animal control officer. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> said the dog will be taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, and its owner must contact the proper authorities to gain its release.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

