
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/7/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Recognition appreciated
Thank you so much for the picture and article that you put on the front page of the paper!
I was shocked when I saw it and read it because I feel like I am the "background" for the concerts. It touched my heart very much when I was recognized.
I really do like working with Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX> and the high school choir ladies and gentlemen. The gift they gave me was a surprise and a blessing.
Please remember that (school) concerts are awesome and it is a time for anyone to come and celebrate all that (the students) have learned and worked hard to perform for family and friends.
Thank you, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>, for the blessing you gave me in this way!
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy Cohu</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> choir pianist, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Vote <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX>
Please join me in suporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> board of directors by voting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> for the two proposals on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 3</TIMEX> election ballot.
Why vote yourself a continued tax? It is a great bargain when you consider that the maintenance and operation levy raises <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,422,595</NUMEX> locally, which then qualifies the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,744,357</NUMEX> in state levy equalization funds.
If we don't pass the local levy we can't receive the state matching funds. Then, other westside schols will qualify and receive these matching dollars. These funds are used for a wide variety of eduational programs, as well as maintenance, capital projects, curriculum, technology, safety, music and the unfunded costs for extracurricular programs.
As for the need for another new school, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools have been growing at a rate of 100 students per year for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 15 years</TIMEX>. Since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> when the school board asked you to support the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8 million</NUMEX> bond levy for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer School</ENAMEX>, the student population has increased by 1,106 students. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer School</ENAMEX> was built for 700 to 750 students. This school now houses 935 students with the help of 10 portable classrooms.
The new building bond of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> will build a new middle school, and add classroom space for the ninth graders who are currently housed at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. It will also qualify the district for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">82 percent</NUMEX> reimbursement funds from the state. This means that the local taxpayer will only pay <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">18 percent</NUMEX> of the total cost of a new school building. These reimbursement funds can be used to update and remodel other district school buildings as they age and qualify.
This <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$11 million</NUMEX> can be turned into nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40 million</NUMEX> in new construction and modernization for our existing schools.
What does all this cost? If you own a home valued at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100,000</NUMEX>, you will pay <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX> per year more in school taxes.
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has a great opportunity to continue its fine tradition of educational excellence at a cost that is far less than most of our neighboring school districts.
We have a strong tradition of supporting schools, students, teachers and administrators. I urge you to join me in voting <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES</ENAMEX> in the coming election. If you have questions or need additional information, please call school district administrators or the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YES Committee</ENAMEX> members.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac Chambers</ENAMEX>, retired <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> Superintendent
</P> 


 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

