
<P ID="1">Grizzly linksters pick up two wins
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/30/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Talk about a team effort, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> boys golf team could have provided an instructional video <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.   Firing on all cylinders, the Grizzly linksters defeated both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> to move their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> record to 4-1 on the season. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> tallied a 315 team score, edging <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX> by six strokes and clipping the Bulldogs by 10.   Although it took a true team effort to score the two conference victories at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Black Rock Creek Golf Course, the hero of the day might have been <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zack Hathaway</ENAMEX>.   Golfing in the No. 5 spot for the Grizzlies, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hathaway</ENAMEX> was still out on the course when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s top four golfers were sitting in the clubhouse comparing scorecards. Because of an uncharacteristic blow-up by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Webster</ENAMEX>, who finished with a 98, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> squad knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hathaway</ENAMEX> had to post a score below 90 to have a shot at earning a sweep.   "We were all waiting at the clubhouse," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Glenn Braman</ENAMEX>. "We all knew <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zach</ENAMEX> had to be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">mid-</ENAMEX>80's for us to get the win.   "It was a bit nerve wracking," he said.   When <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hathaway</ENAMEX> finished his round and made his way to his teammates, they quickly learned he had come through big. The 84 on his scorecard was well below what he needed to shoot to get the Grizzlies the team victory.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hathaway</ENAMEX> might have gotten an early clue that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> was going to be his day. On the par-4 fourth hole, after lacing his drive to within 115 yards of the green, he knocked his approach shot out-of-bounds. Taking a penalty stroke and a drop, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hathaway</ENAMEX> swung again from 115 yards out. This time, the ball flew straight, and miraculously, he holed the shot to save par.   Heroics aside, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> couldn't have defeated perenially tough <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">West Valley</ENAMEX> without some superb play from its other team members. And no one came through bigger than junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Lick</ENAMEX>, who shared medalist honors on the day with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Rams</ENAMEX>' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bobby</ENAMEX> Elder. Both golfers carded even-par 72's.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lick</ENAMEX> parred every hole on the front side, and birdied two after the turn to negate his lone blow-up on the back nine-a double bogey. He needed a bird on the finishing 18th to tie Elder for medalist honors, which he got by reaching the green in two and one-putting.   "Another super round by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX>. "It seems like he's always there in the low 70's for us."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Trammel</ENAMEX> also picked a great time to shoot his first sub-80 round of the season. The easy-going, free swinging <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trammel</ENAMEX> turned in a workman-like four-over 40 on the first nine holes of play. He lowered his score to a 39 on the back side.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>'s 79, that's the first time he's been under 80 for us <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX>. "I'm real happy with how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> is playing.   "The more relaxed he is, the better he hits the ball.   "Every kid is different out there, but the key for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> is staying relaxed," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX>. "He came up big for us."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s No. 2 golfer, junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew Schutt</ENAMEX>, didn't exactly get off to one of his better starts <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX> ran into trouble early on and couldn't right the ship, finishing the front nine with a seven-over 43.   "When I saw <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew</ENAMEX> out there, he was noticeably upset," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Braman</ENAMEX>. "He was mentally beating himself up, and he let it snowball a little bit."   The gutsy linkster recovered admirably, though, touring the back side of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Rock</ENAMEX> with a one-over 37. Birdies on 14 and 17 helped turn <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schutt</ENAMEX>'s game around, giving him a respectable 80 for the day.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>'s 98 (43-55) and a 104 by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeramie Drollinger</ENAMEX> weren't applied towards <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s team score. Only the four best individual scores are used for team play.   The Grizzly golfers were scheduled to leave at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX> to compete at the Pendleton Invitational. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will then close out regular season play on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, May 13</TIMEX>, at the Yakima Elks course against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wapato</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

