
<P ID="1"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'82</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> grad finds Iraqi people appreciative of American troops' efforts
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/17/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A mother's eyes. They can speak volumes without a single word being uttered.   Such is the case when you meet <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elsie Bell</ENAMEX>, if, that is, the subject of her son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, comes up in conversation.   A stranger meeting Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> for the first time might describe her as reserved...she chooses her words carefully and speaks directly, to the point. There is no effusing of flowery descriptives. A no-nonsense type person, yes, those meeting her for the first time might agree.   Yet, mention son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX>, and her eyes display a pride that books upon books of words could hardly describe.   These days, her son answers to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>. Actually, his official moniker is <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> Lieutenant Colonel <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Bell</ENAMEX>, who is stationed out of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fort Hood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. That's not to say he is presently living there, though, with wife <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheri</ENAMEX> and 4-year-old son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Warren</ENAMEX> as was the case at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX>.   No, Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX>'s son is now overseas, serving his country in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> with thousands of other American troops. An <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Army</ENAMEX> communications officer, he departed for the Mideast the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first week of January</TIMEX>.   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> can't, or maybe elects not to, tell you what her son's duties are in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. She has been sent photos of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>, standing atop former presidential palaces overlooking the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Baghdad</ENAMEX>, even sitting in a former throne once occupied by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam Hussein</ENAMEX>.   She readily displays the photos when asked, gleaming with an unspoken admiration for the handsome, chiseled soldier that appears in the colored computer prints. Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> doesn't offer up that her son, after graduating from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1982</TIMEX>, went on to graduate with the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1986</TIMEX> class at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">West Point</ENAMEX>. She'll inform you of that fact if you ask her point-blank, but don't expect her to openly brag about son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>' accomplishments. Not, unless, you can read a person's eyes.   A chance meeting with Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> also won't reveal that her son led a very active life while attending high school in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She makes no mention to his being a member of the school's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Honor Society</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Science Club</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Latin Club</ENAMEX>. Oh sure, she'll confirm it for you if you ask, but to let escape such tidbits into a conversation with a stranger might come across as bravado. No, she opts not to mention the pride she felt years ago when son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> took on one of the lead roles, as Snoopy, when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> thespians staged the production of "You're a Good Man Charlie Brown." Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> also remains spendidly mum when it comes to her son's other prep accomplishments, such as being named to the school's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Council</ENAMEX>, or his time on the Grizzly golf team, or his days playing with the Grizzly band, or even him being named the "Most Spirited Boy" during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> homecoming week festivities.   To a stranger, those honors her son accomplished are best discovered in an old <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> yearbook.   But what Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> will readily share are the messages, via e-mails, she now receives from son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX>. She points with pride to his words, that he is one of the American soldiers who is helping to liberate the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>.   "Suffice to say, we serve here to repudiate all that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saddam</ENAMEX> stood for and to help the Iraqi people achieve the stability and peace that has been denied to them for so long," he writes to his mother.   "There are many good things happening here that aren't 'newsworthy'," the lieutenant colonel continues on in his message to his mother. And he quickly adds, "The Iraqi people I've met so far have been appreciative of our presence."   Perhaps it is her son's involvement in returning to the Iraqi people their independence, their lives free of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hussein</ENAMEX>'s torture chambers and death squads, that makes Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX>'s eyes speak out with fierce pride.   Perhaps, it's just knowing that her son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James</ENAMEX> continues to utilize his life to the best of his ability, maximizing the opportunities he has been presented.   Mrs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bell</ENAMEX> won't tell you in so many words, but her eyes...yes, the eyes, reveal what only a mother can feel towards a son who has accomplished so much.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

