
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> seeks new school superintendent
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/11/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> will begin its search for a new superintendent starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Current Mabton</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Chase</ENAMEX> has been hired as the new head of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> is in the process of hiring a firm to assist in the hiring of a new superintendent. He expects the process to begin <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, 42, is excited about his new job as head of the neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX>.   "I think I was ready for a change," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> is a pretty appealing school district. I think (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> is) a district on the move."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> replaces retiring <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Mathis</ENAMEX>, who has overseen the district for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past seven years</TIMEX>.   The home-grown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, who is a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1980</TIMEX> graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, will begin his new position in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 1</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last day</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 30</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> holds a Bachelor of Science degree in agriculture from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>, where he also obtained his superintendent's credentials. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> also obtained a Master's degree in education administration from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1985</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> took on his first teaching job in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger School District</ENAMEX>, where he taught agriculture until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. From 1990-93, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> took over the agriculture education program in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>. From 1993-96, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> served as assistant principal at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. He then took the position of assistant superintendent in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> for one year before taking on his current position in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>, though, wasn't just handed his new <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> position. He beat out two other finalists for the position after enduring a day-long interview process in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late April</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>'s interview process as one of the three finalists involved meeting with all central office staff. He also toured each building in the district and met with building administrators for one hour. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> then met with middle and high school students for an hour, which was followed by two more hours of meeting with various teachers in the district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> then went through a two-hour meeting with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview School Board</ENAMEX>, which was followed by an hour-long meeting with community members.   One of the most apparent things that stood out for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> during the day-long interview process was just how many people he knows in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, he joked.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said he learned a lot of other interesting aspects about <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> during his interview. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said the students, faculty and community members are very much dedicated to continuing the educational success that has taken place in the community. He also learned that the community takes great pride in its newly remodeled school buildings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said he was also taken with how involved and knowledgeable the school board is.   "The board is a good board," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>.   There are notable differences between the two school districts. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> has an enrollment of 907 students and a total staff of 105 employees. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> has 3,100 students and a total staff of 300.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> leaves <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> with several notable personal accomplishments. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said one of the things he is most proud of is how there is a renewed focus on instruction in the district. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> also speaks proudly of the newly remodeled <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Jr.</ENAMEX>/Sr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>, complete with updated educational and athletic facilities. One of the other accomplishments <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> is proud of is the work he has done with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>. The school district has been the recipient of several Gates grants. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> is also the recipient of the Gates Achievers Grant, which assist students in furthering their education. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> is the only school district in the nation to receive money for both programs from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gates Foundation</ENAMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX> said he will miss <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>.   "I love <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>. It was a great place and it still is," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>. "I am just going to be next door."   But, he is looking forward to his new job.   "People are proud of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chase</ENAMEX>. "The first thing I am going to do is get in and listen."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

