31 38 5 13 14 11
</P>
<P ID="5">Wise Words of Weekly Wisdom:
</P>
<P ID="6">  After all it is those who have a deep and real inner life who are best able to deal with the irritating details of outer life.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Evelyn Underhill</ENAMEX>
</P>


<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>,</P>