


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> to be renamed after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/15/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">A discussion at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting on plans to rename <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> took a sharp detour that ended up with one councilman questioning the character of famed civil rights leader Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Martin Luther</ENAMEX> King <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jr.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> brought before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> the issue of renaming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> "Ronald Reagan Parkway," following the massive million dollar reconstruction project scheduled to start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late this year</TIMEX>. But on the same note, it was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> who brought out some fiery sentiments in the audience when he referred to Dr. King as an adulterer.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he was proposing the idea of renaming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> in honor of the former president who died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this month</TIMEX>, following a decade long battle with Alzheimer's Disease, as a fitting tribute to a past president he felt was a great man.
</P><P ID="7">   "I think it is a very good choice," added <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>. "I think it is the least we can do."
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said renaming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> in honor of the late president wouldn't affect very many people. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> noted some of the accomplishments of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, such as having a major part in ending communism, as a reason the city should move forward with renaming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> shared with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> some input he received over the weekend from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frances Sooner</ENAMEX>, who was representing a group of eight senior citizens. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sooner</ENAMEX> requested on behalf of the group that the city doesn't move forward with the proposed name change. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sooner</ENAMEX> suggested renaming a new development on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton Road</ENAMEX> in honor of the former president. The mayor said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sooner</ENAMEX> indicated to him it would be hard for senior citizens to remember the name of a new street.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> added some of the public comment she had received over the weekend. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said many citizens she spoke with were in favor of naming a street after <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX>, just not <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she agreed with the idea, but just felt it should be in a new development.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he also received comments from several people who were in favor of the project. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> also talked about some ideas he received about forming a list of city pioneers that can be utilized when the opportunity comes to name new streets or buildings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said he felt renaming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> would make a positive statement about the community and also be patriotic for the city.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> added his comments to the mix, saying nearly 20 people had contacted him who were in favor of the idea. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> even suggested the possibility the city might be able to obtain a sign on the interstate highlighting the name of the new road.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> interjected and said she was very much in favor of creating a list of pioneer names to utilize later. She suggested adding such noted activists as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cesar Chavez</ENAMEX> and King. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>, though, fired right back, saying he wouldn't want King to be recognized because he is a known adulterer.
</P><P ID="14">   The statement brought the ire of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Campbell</ENAMEX>, a local resident in attendance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, who popped up out of his seat and took the podium, telling <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> he couldn't understand why he would make a comment such as that one. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> noted some of the less than spectacular things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> did as president, such as selling weapons to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iran</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> agreed that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> was a great American, but didn't quite know yet where his place would be in history as president. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX> noted the accomplishments of King.
</P><P ID="15">   "He got us through a very terrible period," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Campbell</ENAMEX>, referring to the civil rights uprising of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960s</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   Local resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carol Stone</ENAMEX>, a regular at city council meetings, recommended the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> wait a year to consider renaming <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX>. She felt the city shouldn't do it now because it was reacting to the death of the president.
</P><P ID="17">   Another local resident in attendance <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Outhet</ENAMEX>, said he felt the city should get the input of local residents before changing the street name, especially the people in the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   "Before you make a change, check with the property owners," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Outhet</ENAMEX>. "If they are in agreement with it, fine."
</P><P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark Tucker</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PW Pipe</ENAMEX>, who was at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting, said the only effect changing the street would have on his business would be financial. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tucker</ENAMEX> said the company has extensive amounts of letter heads and other items with their current address on it.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> expressed his reservations about renaming existing streets.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> disagreed with the mayor and some of the comments expressed during the discussion. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said history has proven <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reagan</ENAMEX> as a great man.
</P><P ID="22">   "I am grateful to the man," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>. "It is good for the city. It is going to make a statement for the rebuilding we are doing."
</P><P ID="23">   In the end, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> voted 4-2 to move forward with plans to rename <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> "Ronald Reagan Parkway." <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> voted against the measure. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> was absent from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting.
</P><P ID="24">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="25">Webmaster
</P><P ID="26">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




