


<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds secure top spot in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CWAC</ENAMEX> standings
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> did what they had to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>. Now, they find themselves sitting alone at the top of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">CWAC</ENAMEX> standings.
</P><P ID="5">   The Lady 'Hounds walked into the gym at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> with confidence and walked out with a number one spot in their league. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team was able to beat Ki-Be in three, winning by scores of 25-15, 25-22, 25-20.
</P><P ID="6">   "It was a good match," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach John LaFever</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said his team played well against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX>, adding that they really kicked up their defense <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   He noted that players <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angie Cabrera</ENAMEX> and Tonhya Wysong were really tough defensively against Ki-Be. Wysong ended the night with 41 digs, while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cabrera</ENAMEX> had 23.
</P><P ID="9">   "They had a good night defensively," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> added that the team also did a good job of spiking and blocking against Ki-Be.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said the Ki-Be team looked good <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>, adding that they did a lot of things really well.
</P><P ID="12">   "They went to their best players over and over again," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaFever</ENAMEX> said of Ki-Be.
</P><P ID="13">   Despite its efforts, Ki-Be wasn't able to pull out a single game win against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   Helping the Lady 'Hounds push past Ki-Be were freshman Kealey Johnston with 13 digs, 5 kills and 11 service points; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Valentina Solis</ENAMEX> with 7 blocks, 13 kills and 12 service points; Danelle Cowan with 20 digs, 5 blocks and 17 kills; Chante Bottineau with 32 assists and 15 service points; and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mari Cornejo</ENAMEX> with 7 digs, 5 kills and 2 blocks.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> (9-0) has won all of its league matches by 3-0 scores this season.
</P><P ID="16">   With only three matches left in the regular season, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will play again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Thursday</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="18">Webmaster
</P><P ID="19">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




