
<P ID="1">Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> go down fighting
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/25/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ELLENSBURG</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX>'s opening round 3A Regional girls basketball game between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> will be known as the one that got away from the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX>.   If it hadn't been for the third quarter heroics of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tiffanie Ulmer</ENAMEX>, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> would be traveling to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington University</ENAMEX> this coming weekend to play <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clarkston</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> pulled the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> back into the game and helped push <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, 38-37.   "We had it all in our hands," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Leo Gomez</ENAMEX>. "And we let it slip away."   What was notable about <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s game is the way the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> played after being blown out 59-19 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> tournament game.   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX>, the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> went tooth and nail with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> in the first half. Both teams posted 14-point opening halves.   "Nobody was shooting the ball that well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said this time around with the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> he went to a match-up zone defense. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX> when <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> played, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> went with man-to-man defense and didn't have the experienced players to match up with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> in the post. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> had 18 points <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> finished with 11 points <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, but scored 7 of those points during a crucial run by the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> midway through the third quarter. With four minutes to go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ulmer</ENAMEX> hit a 3-pointer and then another bucket to put <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> back on top.   "That made the difference," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>.   With six minutes to go in the game, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> expanded its lead to 9 points, only to watch as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> stormed back. Towards the end of the game, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> hit a couple of free throws to open the lead to 3 points. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Bobi Haringa pulled the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> to within a point after sinking two free throws. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> had one last chance with three seconds on the clock, but couldn't get a shot to fall.   "They (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> players) did a great job," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "We knew going into the game we had nothing to lose."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s game was important because it showed his young team they could play with a quality squad such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> finished its 2003-04 campaign with a league record of 5-9. The Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grizzlies</ENAMEX> went 9-15 overall.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX> loses only senior on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s team, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hilary</ENAMEX> is a class act player," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gomez</ENAMEX>. "Having everybody else back <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> is going to be fun."      
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

