


<P ID="1">Proposition #1 will provide much needed funding for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> law enforcement
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Three-tenth's of a penny may not sound like much, but <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Sheriff Ken Irwin</ENAMEX> believes it will be enough to help give the county's criminal justice system a much needed shot in the arm.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX> about Proposition #1, a measure that will be on the ballot <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this November</TIMEX>. Proposition #1 asks voters to approve a three-tenths of a penny sales tax increase that will raise money to help fund the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>, local police departments within the county and the criminal justice system in general.
</P><P ID="6">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX>, the sales tax increase is expected to raise <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.1 million</NUMEX> to be divided between the county and the local police jurisdictions. The county is estimated to receive <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3.6 million</NUMEX>, with the remainder of the funds going to local police departments, like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s, which could see a benefit of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$252,000</NUMEX> a year if the proposition passes.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> told Rotarians that he understands that people don't like to pay more in taxes, but he added that this tax is deeply needed.
</P><P ID="8">   He explained that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1998</TIMEX>, before the passage of several voter approved initiatives that affected funding, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">County Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> had 73 budgeted positions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of this year</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> will be down to having 63 deputies.
</P><P ID="9">   "And that's just too thin out there," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said of the number of deputies out on the road.
</P><P ID="10">   He noted that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> provides services for 90,000 people living in unincorporated <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX> with those 63 deputies.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said most of the funds raised through Proposition #1 will go to putting more deputies and police officers out on the road.
</P><P ID="12">   He added that although most of the funds will go toward supporting local law enforcement agencies, the criminal justice funding issues are something that affect the entire system.
</P><P ID="13">   "It's a system wide issue," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="14">   He told Rotarians that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> County Prosecutor Ron Zirkle has 90 to 100 cases sitting in his office, ready to go.
</P><P ID="15">   "We've <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ID</ENAMEX>'d who the criminal is, but he simply doesn't have the capacity to take those cases to court," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   He said that the county wants to be able to hold those criminals accountable for their actions.
</P><P ID="17">   And adults offenders aren't the only people who are not getting properly processed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said because of a shortage of open beds in the juvenile system, many young offenders aren't being held. He said instead, they are often times being released into their parents' custody.
</P><P ID="18">   "It's not right, we need more beds," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said. He added that if Proposition #1 is approved it would help cover the cost of creating more room in the juvenile system to handle the load.
</P><P ID="19">   "We have a system here that because of reductions...we're not able to provide the service we should be here in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said. "I don't think that's the type of county we want to live in."
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> also asked those in attendance at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>'s meeting not to vote against the measure simply to punish the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">County</ENAMEX> commissioners.
</P><P ID="21">   "You can't wish this problem away," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="22">   He explained that Proposition #1 makes it so the commissioners cannot use funds from the levy to replace any existing funding to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheriff</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX>. He noted that the measure also includes a six-year sunset clause. He said if the measure is passed in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, it is something that will be brought back to the voters in six year's time. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irwin</ENAMEX> said he also plans on providing an annual report to citizens of the county, which will note how the funds are being spent.
</P>





 










<P ID="23">Webmaster
</P><P ID="24">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




