


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> says no to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Diocese</ENAMEX> housing presentation
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Told that <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> meeting was not the correct public forum to present a slide show on a housing development planned for this community, several members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Diocese</ENAMEX> quietly packed up their projector and went home.
</P><P ID="5">   <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">Last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> agenda called for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Family Services</ENAMEX> group to make an informational presentation on a multi-unit, low income housing complex the Diocese wants to build near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX> and 16th Street. But before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Diocese</ENAMEX> spokesman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mario Villanueva</ENAMEX>, or his projector, even got warmed up, he was interrupted by Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, who asked <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> if such a presentation could be heard outside public hearing proceedings.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>, hemming and hawing a bit, responded that the information should be presented in general terms on what the Diocese offers in the way of housing.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> began anew, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> quickly interjected, saying that in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX>'s opening statement the intent was clear that he hoped to persuade the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to reconsider a zoning decision made by a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> planning group recently.
</P><P ID="8">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Diocese</ENAMEX> is seeking to have two pieces of property at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Sheller Road</ENAMEX>/16th Street site rezoned as R-2, to accomodate the construction of a multi-unit housing complex. The recommendation from the planning group, though, was to only designate one of the two properties as R-2.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> took <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s lead and proceeded to ask the rest of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members their thoughts on whether or not the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Diocese</ENAMEX> presentation should be allowed. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> said he and Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-Tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> had potential conflicts of interest with the housing project and shouldn't offer an opinion either way. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> said she was in favor of hearing the presentation.
</P><P ID="10">   "I want as much information on this project as possible," she said.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Raul Martinez</ENAMEX>, recently appointed to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, said he too would like to hear the informational presentation, but cited an uncertainty on the legality of the matter and said he would abide by the Mayor's decision.
</P><P ID="12">   At that point, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Villanueva</ENAMEX> said he was withdrawing his original statement and the intent implied, and merely wanted to provide a general, overall view on the types of housing the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Diocese</ENAMEX> provides for residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   The issue was thrown back in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>'s court, but unlike his earlier statement that a presentation in general terms would be acceptable, the city attorney suggested rescheduling the presentation at either a planning commission meeting or another public forum.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> made the final decision that a presentation by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Catholic Diocese</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting would be inappropriate, saying that in such quasi-judicial matters the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members act as judges. He pointed out that in the appearance of fairness, all such discussions should be conducted at public hearings, where parties from both sides of a land use issue can be present and have the opportunity to speak.
</P>   
<P ID="15">   .
</P>





 










<P ID="16">Webmaster
</P><P ID="17">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




