
<P ID="1"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> downpour downs <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> hop yards
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/25/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> hop growers woke up early this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> to hear the snapping of hop poles just after dawn. The sudden weight created by an unseasonable rain storm on the vine-ripened <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> hops created enough strain to down seven hop yards, ranging in size from seven to 37-acre yards.   Even though the rain hit <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>, most growers weren't able to begin cleaning up the tangle of hop vines until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX>.   Traditionally, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> hop harvest begins near <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20</TIMEX> and continues through the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of September</TIMEX>. The rain damage resulted in a number of growers scrambling to locate heavy equipment and crews to begin the rescue efforts in the damaged yards.   "We lost a 17-acre yard due to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s rains," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Mears</ENAMEX>, general manager of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Segall Ranch</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mears</ENAMEX> said his crews are currently working to brace anchors in other yards to prevent further damage from the water-logged fields.   "We got more than an inch of rain in 20 minutes, which put a huge strain the hop yard braces," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mears</ENAMEX> said muddy conditions in the fields is now making it difficult for the hop harvest crews to get equipment into the fields.   "I don't know if we'll be able to get in there to harvest the downed field," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mears</ENAMEX> said one of the fields owned by S.S. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Steiner Inc.</ENAMEX>, located on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chase Road</ENAMEX>, received so much damage from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s rains that the hop poles, which measure from six- to eight-inches in diameter, snapped in two under the combined weight of the hops and rain.   In addition, there were a number of yards that suffered rain damage in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Upper Valley</ENAMEX> and in the Prosser area.   Among the Alderwood-Grandview area farmers to lose a yard to the rains was Puterbaugh Ranches of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Green Valley Road</ENAMEX>.   "Knock on wood, we only lost one seven-acre yard to the rain," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Diana Puterbaugh</ENAMEX>. She said it took a little while to round up heavy equipment to get into the farm's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Belma Road</ENAMEX> field of hops.   "Fortunately, the harvest crews are beginning to show up for work, so we had men on hand to help with the clean-up," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puterbaugh</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Belma Road</ENAMEX> yard was one of the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puterbaugh</ENAMEX>'s early hop varieties.   She said she's heard of a farmer in the Harrah area who lost a 37-acre yard of one of the later variety of hops.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puterbaugh</ENAMEX> said four yards had also been damaged by the rains in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>.   As clean-up of the yards begins, farmers are hoping that winds don't come along to further complicate the situation.   "We just hope we don't get any winds to further shake loose the hop poles," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Puterbaugh</ENAMEX> said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

