


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council Briefs</ENAMEX>
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">1-Column
</P>

 


<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approves transportation plan
</P>

<P ID="5">Taking the recommendation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved the 22 projects on its new six-year transportation plan.
</P>

<P ID="6">The plan, which includes an extensive
</P>  
<P ID="7">study of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway business corridor, was approved following a short public hearing.
</P>

<P ID="8">Hearing no comments from the citizens, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approved the plan, which <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> was reviewed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="9">According to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Engineer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Bridges</ENAMEX>, the plan calls for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway study, as well as moving ahead on the reconstruction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> and 20 other projects.
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridges</ENAMEX> said a number of the original 26 projects in the plan have been reclassified or completed.
</P>

<P ID="11">He told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> he has allowed for flexibility in the plan
</P>  
<P ID="12">in order to administer projects as funds become available.
</P>

<P ID="13">Topping the 2005-2010 list is the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Valley Highway improvement project from east to west city limits, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South First Street</ENAMEX> reconstruction project, from I-82 to Lincoln Avenue, and the citywide intersection study, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washout Road</ENAMEX> project from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Avenue</ENAMEX> to north city limits.
</P>

 


<P ID="14">Council sets record time
</P>

<P ID="15">In a record 20 minutes, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> dispensed with the items on its agenda <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="16">Meeting at just a few minutes past <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approved a consent agenda, set procedures and a date to interview prospective candidates for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, approved its six-year transportation plan and heard from department heads and fellow councilmen in a swift 20 minutes.
</P>

<P ID="17">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> excused itself for a scant 30-minute executive session, coming back at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:45</TIMEX> to adjourn for the evening.
</P>

<P ID="18">No action was taken as a result of the executive session.
</P>

 


<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> approves four liquor license renewals <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="20">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> gave it approval to four liquor license renewal requests as a part of its consent agenda <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="21">Renewals were approved for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Safeway Store</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">El Conquistador</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mini Mart and Valley Lanes.
</P>

 


 


<P ID="22">Block party street closures approved
</P>

<P ID="23">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> approved street closures for the community's National Night Out block parties to be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Aug. 3</TIMEX>, throughout the city.
</P>

<P ID="24">The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, which won't meet again until <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9</TIMEX>, was invited to attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> National Night Out kick-off celebration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Aug. 2</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="25"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is host of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> event, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>. The kick-off event will be held at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Law</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Justice Center</ENAMEX> from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="26"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> encouraged the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members to be on hand for the community barbecue and evening of entertainment, information fair and games, all planned as part of the evening, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chico Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NNO</ENAMEX> committee.
</P>

 


 


 


 


 






 










<P ID="27">Webmaster
</P><P ID="28">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




