


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ALFONSO ALVAREZ</ENAMEX>, SR
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ALFONSO ALVAREZ</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">SR.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso Alvarez, Sr.</ENAMEX>, 80, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 11, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Health Care Center</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1923</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Blackwell</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Okla.</ENAMEX> and was a Navy World War II veteran. He worked for 35 years at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inland Steel Mill Corp.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chicago</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ind.</ENAMEX> He retired in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1976</TIMEX> and moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> to enjoy his life with his sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso Jr.</ENAMEX>, along with his loving wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso</ENAMEX> was a devoted Jehovah’s Witness.
</P>

<P ID="7">He is survived by his loving wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Soledad Alvarez</ENAMEX>; two sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">David</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alfonso Alvarez Jr.</ENAMEX>; two grandchildren; a sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Connie Flores</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Denver</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Hernandez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lincoln</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Neb.</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="8">Vigil services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, March 15, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Chapel of Valley Hills Funeral Home. Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, March 16, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Chapel of Valley Hills Funeral Home with burial to follow in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens.
</P>





 










<P ID="9">Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




