
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">JV</ENAMEX> Grizzlies gridders score second win of season
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">A strong defensive showing by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School JV</ENAMEX> football team propelled the Grizzlies to an 8-6 victory over <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s junior varsity <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>.   The win was the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV</ENAMEX>'s second of the season.   "It was a good defensive game on our part," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JV Coach Saul Martinez</ENAMEX>. "I can't really single out any one player on defense. It was a great group effort."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> opened a 6-0 lead on the JV Grizzlies with a first quarter touchdown. The score remained the same until the second half got underway.   In the third quarter, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> squared the contest at 6-6 on a 64-yard touchdown pass from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Sambrano</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Coleman</ENAMEX>. He had eight receptions in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s game for 125 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sambrano</ENAMEX> finished the night with 143 aerial yards on 10-of-18 passing.   Later in the third period, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> scored the game winner when defensive end <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Esperson</ENAMEX> sacked <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>'s quarterback in the end zone for a 2-point safety.   "Our entire line rushed on the play," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> charged in and got the sack."   Offensively for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, playing on its home field <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, B.J. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Miller</ENAMEX> led all rushers in the game with 139 yards on 24 carries.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>'s victory upped the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> JV's record on the year to 2-4-1. The Grizzlies close out the season <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Monday</TIMEX> at home against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>'s junior varsity.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

