


<P ID="1">Fire captains air concerns with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget cuts
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">All three captains from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Fire Department-Yan Sing, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Siliano</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bud Jones-were</ENAMEX> on hand at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> budget study session to voice their concerns about the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> budget.
</P><P ID="5">   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> had a message for the fire department. He encouraged staff to weather the storm and said hopefully things will improve in the future.
</P><P ID="6">   The budget for the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire Department</ENAMEX> is divided into three categories-fire control, fire equipment and emergency medical service/ambulance.
</P><P ID="7">   Prior to delving into the budget, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> provided <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> with some history of how the city has improved the revenue stream for the fire department.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> has revamped the ambulance utility tax fee that was ruled unconstitutional by the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Supreme Court</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>. Prior to the ruling by the high court, the city was charging a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> tax on residents' water and sewer bills. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters had approved the tax shortly after the fire department began offering an ambulance service in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> stopped collecting the tax shortly after the ruling by the court <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   The new version of the ambulance utility fee tax will keep the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3</NUMEX> per month fee, but the amount will now be charged to both residents and businesses. The fee is calculated on the average number of residents living in a home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, 3.6. Every business will be charged based on the 3.6 employees ratio up to 100 employees. The new fee will generate <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350,000</NUMEX>, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> was able to clear up <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$70,000</NUMEX> in additional money for the fire department by moving expenses over to the ambulance fund.
</P><P ID="11">   The proposed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> fire control budget is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$595,410</NUMEX>, down considerably from the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$639,220</NUMEX> budget in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   A majority of the fire control budget, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$295,480</NUMEX>, covers the salaries for the 13 positions within the department. The budget does contain a one-time expense of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6,000</NUMEX> to replace a failing boiler.
</P><P ID="13">   One area of significant increase is in overtime. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, the city spent <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,370</NUMEX> in the fire control budget for overtime. That figure will rise to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$31,306</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said overtime expenses are being paid for through a grant the city received. The overtime will go towards training for staff and the 22 members of the volunteer fire department.
</P><P ID="14">   A significant change in the fire department budget is the elimination of two firefighter/paramedic positions. There are currently two staff members serving in the military in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, who are scheduled to return to work <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said under the terms of the labor contract the city's fire staff has, the employees with least seniority will be laid off first. One of the positions being proposed for elimination is held by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamel Linzsey</ENAMEX>, who is serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. The other fireman serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX> is <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Hutchinson</ENAMEX>, who has the most seniority of the two firefighters.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> presented a proposal to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> regarding layoffs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said that since <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linzsey</ENAMEX> is scheduled to come home from active duty at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">beginning of the year</TIMEX>, he asked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to fund <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linzsey</ENAMEX>'s position until the time <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> returns from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. Once <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hutchinson</ENAMEX> returns, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Linzsey</ENAMEX> will be laid off from the fire department. The other position set to be cut is that of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Roe</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> was concerned about laying off any of the firefighters. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Interim Fire Chief Adam Dent</ENAMEX> did acknowledge the fire department has managed without the two staff members serving in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX>, though, did say that without a full staff it does make it difficult to provide needed services. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> said he likes to have four staff members on call each of the 24-hour shifts.
</P><P ID="17">   "We try to provide the highest level of service to everybody in the community at the same time," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> asked how much it would cost to fund a firefighter/paramedic position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said in the neighborhood of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$65,00</NUMEX>, including benefits.
</P><P ID="19">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> with her concerns about reducing the staff.
</P><P ID="20">   "I am nervous losing this large of a percentage of people providing a critical service in the community," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fire</ENAMEX> Captain <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Siliano</ENAMEX> wasn't so optimistic about the department being able to do its job not fully staffed.
</P><P ID="22">   "It is actually a living hell to be running short," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX> said it has been difficult for the captains to do their jobs without a full crew. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX> expressed concerns about not replacing the fire marshal position, which <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dent</ENAMEX> used to hold. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX> said those duties, which include conducting fire inspections, will now fall on the captains. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX> said with more time by the captains being dedicated to fire inspections, there will be less time for important department activities, such as training and being available to fight fires.
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> suggested the captains schedule appointments for fire inspections. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX> said the idea is good in concept, but it won't work. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX> said it is better to show up unexpectedly, which will reveal more problems and in the end assist the business owners in setting up a safer work environment.
</P><P ID="25">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Siliano</ENAMEX> said when conducting a fire inspection it is important to see business owners in their every day work environment.
</P><P ID="26">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> interjected and offered a few comments about the fire department.
</P><P ID="27">   "All we expect you to do is do what you can do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="28">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said by taking action now with the budget cuts, the city will be talking about what to do with increased revenues he is projecting down the road in just a few years.
</P><P ID="29">   The city is getting along now with three less department heads, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="30">   "Are we taking some risks?," asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. "What choice do we have."
</P><P ID="31">   The fire equipment reserve fund budget is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$163,00</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>, up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$148,200</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. The increase is mainly due to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$131,000</NUMEX> in grant monies the department received.
</P><P ID="32">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX>/ambulance fund is budgeted at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$998,990</NUMEX>, which is up from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$890,000</NUMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>. Salaries account for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$449,630</NUMEX> of the budget. The salaries for the fire department are split between <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> and the fire control budgets. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">EMS</ENAMEX> budget will start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX> with a beginning fund balance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$250,000</NUMEX> and end with a projected balance of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$269,580</NUMEX>.
</P><P ID="33">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> wanted to look into the relationship the city has with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">County Fire District</ENAMEX> #5. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>'s concerns dealt with the city firemen, who are also county volunteers, responding to a fire outside city limits. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he was concerned the city wasn't receiving any compensation for the hours spent fighting county fires.
</P><P ID="34">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> wanted to once again begin the discussion about regionalizing county fire department services.
</P><P ID="35">   "Why don't we start waving our flag," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX>. "We are the premiere guys."
</P>





 










<P ID="36">Webmaster
</P><P ID="37">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




