
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> slowly turning over family farm to son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/17/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">From his kitchen window, Cliff Van Belle can see the fruits of several generations of farmers who have tilled the land on property that has been in his family more than 80 years.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX>, who was selected as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>'s Outstanding Agri-business Person this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past March</TIMEX>, said his grandfather homesteaded the farm on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle Road</ENAMEX>, located north of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and grew up in the Liberty area, near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX>. The family homestead has been in his care for most of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 30 years</TIMEX>.   "We moved the original farmhouse off and built our current hone in its place," he said. "But the barn is original," he added.   The old-fashioned barn with its antique weather vane and hay derrick were originally built by his grandparents on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle Road</ENAMEX> farm'ss original 80-acre tract.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> takes a lot of pride in maintaining the historic structure on the family farm.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX>, along with his son <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX>, farms more than 1,000 acres of wheat, corn, hay and mint. His son, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve</ENAMEX>, helps out, but also farms a few acres of grapes down the road, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX>.   While enjoying a quiet conversation with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX>, one wouldn't know how excited he can get about turning the first row of soil each spring. But his family claims he can get as excited as a kid at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX> each spring.   His skills on the farm were recognized in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1997</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> received a national award from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Corn Growers Association</ENAMEX> in honor of his excellent yield and the overall quality of his crops.   A soft-spoken man given to practical jokes, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> plays as hard as he works. For years he admits he was nuts about snowmobiling. "I spent a lot of time each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">winter</TIMEX> playing with the kids on snowmobiles," he said.   These days he is crazy about another type of loud machine. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> is a huge fan of NASCAR racing. "I like going to the races and watching the races on television," he admits.   But his real passion is for his 10 grandchildren, with whom he enjoys fishing and water skiing vacations each <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> and the occasional hay ride each fall.   Recently <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Belle</ENAMEX> has decided to take more time for those family outings. "I've cut back on my farming, letting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris</ENAMEX> take over more of the farm," he said.   But that doesn't mean the long-time farmer has given up watching the weather or current water conditions. He and his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Esther</ENAMEX>, still keep a close eye on the farm.   "We just take a lot more time off," he grinned.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

