
<P ID="1">Business Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/24/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">NW Farm Credit Services</ENAMEX> returns money to clients
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s office of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Farm Credit Services</ENAMEX> has returned more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$294,300</NUMEX> back to its customers.
The agency's interest reduction program returned 50 basis points back to its member-stockholders on theier average loan balance for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>. The average check size was approximately <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,136</NUMEX>.
"The feedback we have received over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX> on this program has been very positive," said the manager of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> office, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandy Minick</ENAMEX>.
"One of the benefits of doing business with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Farm Credit</ENAMEX> is our commitment to return value to our shareholders—our customers," she said.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest Farm Credit Services</ENAMEX> provides financing and related services to farmers, ranchers, commercial fishermen, timber producers and rural homeowners in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Montana</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alaska</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nordberg</ENAMEX> earns insurance honors
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Nordberg</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has been honored for his efforts in helping <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm Mutual Auto Insurance Company</ENAMEX> earn top honors in a recent J.D. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Power</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX> survey that ranks <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> highest overall for customer satisfaction for auto collision repair.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nordberg</ENAMEX> is a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> agent serving <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> is in the business of helping customers manage the risks of everyday life and to recover from the unexpected," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Bishop</ENAMEX>, vice president of operations for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX>. "Our claims employees and agents work hard to provide the best possible service to customers.
"<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">State Farm</ENAMEX> recognizes these associates as the best in the nation and commends them as a true measure of our company's commitment to customer service," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bishop</ENAMEX> added.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> hospital adds second <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRI</ENAMEX> scanning day
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - Beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 2</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRI</ENAMEX> screening services will be available every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser Memorial Hospital</ENAMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRI</ENAMEX> service has been added to the previous Saturday-only schedule to accomodate increased patient need.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRI</ENAMEX>'s are designed to assist doctors in assessing a patient's condition through use of high quality images that allow soft body tissue to be seen in great detail, from nearly every angle, and there are no know side effects.
Patients with a physician referral wishing to schedule an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">MRI</ENAMEX> at the Prosser hospital should call 1-800-657-6647.
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

