


<P ID="1">Push is on for new aquatic center
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Service Area Board</ENAMEX> began strategizing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, one of the first steps to building a new aquatic center in the community.
</P><P ID="5">   The board started <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX>'s meeting by approving a contract with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE Architecture</ENAMEX>, Engineering, Planning, the same group that designed the first aquatic center the city tried to pass a levy for in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2000</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The contract lays out what <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX> will be doing for the city and the estimated cost for the first part of the planning for the aquatic center, which is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10,500</NUMEX>. An additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5,240</NUMEX> will be charged for work by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Margaret Norton-Arnold</ENAMEX>, a public involvement and communications consultant.
</P><P ID="7">   The first phase of the campaign includes gathering public input as to what local residents would like to see in an aquatic center. According to Grandview Parks and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Recreation Director Mike Carpenter</ENAMEX>, the first workshop is tentatively scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 23</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   The planning would also include putting a price tag on the center.
</P><P ID="9">   "We want to know what it will cost or close to it before we get into the workshops," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="10">   He explained that knowing the costs will help them know where they need to cut back or where they can expand. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> added that they also requested that projected revenue brought in from the facility also be calculated.
</P><P ID="11">   The second phase of the planning involves community outreach and awareness. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said this is where a "SPLASH!" committee would come into play. He said a SPLASH! committee will be essential to passing the levy needed for a new swimming facility.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said they have already collected more than 300 swimming pool surveys to gather public input on the pool issue. He said they have collected surveys from senior citizens, civic leaders and service club members, as well as pool patrons.
</P><P ID="13">   Just as important is choosing the right date to hold the bond election, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   He said that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">TSE</ENAMEX> consultants have said that by the beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April</TIMEX> the two phases of the campaign should be complete and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> will be ready for the vote.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX> said that election dates after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">first of April</TIMEX> include <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 26</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 17, 2005</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   "Both of these dates fit within the architects' time frame," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carpenter</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   No other elections are known to be planned for the same time.
</P><P ID="18">   "It's not necessary to set a date tonight. We might want to get some of the workshops and meetings with the architect done before we set a date," said parks board Chairman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Copeland</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   One concern about a spring date that Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Bren</ENAMEX> addressed is that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> residents would have just paid property and income taxes when the levy would be up for vote.
</P><P ID="20">   On the other hand, by having it in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">spring</TIMEX>, outreach to the youths in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> schools will be more effective.
</P><P ID="21">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX> said that what may help the levy is that by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next April</TIMEX>, property taxes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> could go down because the Wal-Mart distribution center will be added into the tax base.
</P><P ID="22">   "You could capitalize on the drop in their property taxes," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>. He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wal-Mart</ENAMEX> head coach <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Gray</ENAMEX> has announced that they will be starting the hiring process for 200 more people in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   "They're going to be having the first promotions within the company," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>. "That is going to make a lot of local people managers out there."
</P><P ID="24">   The city-wide utility tax ends <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> as well, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bren</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   The board is also looking at ways to promote the election. Besides the use of signs and banners, the board is looking at a "shepherding" method, which targets voters who would most likely vote for the aquatic center and encourage them to show up at the polls.
</P><P ID="26">   The levy would have to pass by a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">60 percent</NUMEX> margin or greater for the aquatic center to be approved.
</P>





 










<P ID="27">Webmaster
</P><P ID="28">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




