


<P ID="1">Evening wedding joins <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saenz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cyr</ENAMEX> in marriage
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/21/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delilah</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saenz</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Cyr</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Delilah Saenz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Justin Cyr</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> were joined in marriage <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 31, 2003</TIMEX>, in a ceremony held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saenz</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natividad and Jane Saenz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, wore a beaded white gown and a gem encrusted tiara as she walked down the aisle to meet her groom. The bride wore the same veil worn by her mother on her wedding day more than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">30 years ago</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   The bride's niece, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christina Saenz</ENAMEX>, was maid of honor for the ceremony. Her nieces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kayla Saenz</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Alice Saenz</ENAMEX>, were bridesmaids, and her niece, Adreana Martinez, was flower girl.
</P><P ID="7">   The groom is the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrea Hoff</ENAMEX> and the grandson of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Andrew and Annis Jones</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX>. He is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Davis High School</ENAMEX>. He also holds an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">AA</ENAMEX> degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Community College</ENAMEX> and a Bachelor's of Science from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Breyer State University</ENAMEX>. He is employed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wapato School District</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   He chose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Armstead</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> to be his best man in the ceremony.
</P><P ID="9">   The bride is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> and earned her <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">AA</ENAMEX> degree from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Community College</ENAMEX>. She is employed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Council</ENAMEX> in the accounts department.
</P><P ID="10">   Following the wedding ceremony, the couple celebrated with a reception at Sunny Valley Grange. They are currently at home in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
   






 










<P ID="11">Webmaster
</P><P ID="12">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




