
<P ID="1">Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> sweep <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/7/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greyhounds</ENAMEX> fastpitch softball team got off to a rough start <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> against the visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellensburg Bulldogs</ENAMEX>, starting the first game of the doubleheader with a first inning that included allowing six runs to cross the plate.   In the end, the Grandview girls finished the doubleheader with two losses against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, falling 15-3 in the first game and 14-6 in the second game, which was called in the fifth inning due to darkness.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> Head <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Doug Hansen</ENAMEX> said although his team only had one error during the first game, it was the mental errors and not the physical ones that did in the Lady 'Hounds.   He said starting off the game by giving up six runs to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> was hard, although he did note that the Grandview team was able to come back in the second and third innings to hold the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bulldogs</ENAMEX> to only two more runs. However, in the fourth inning the Grandview team gave up another seven runs.   "Collectively we get our heads down," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> said.   Although the Lady 'Hounds weren't able to come back in the first game, they were able to start the second game of the afternoon off on the right foot, scoring some important runs and keeping the Ellensburg team at bay. At the bottom of the third inning, the score was 5-3, with the Lady 'Hounds only trailing by two runs.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> said during the first three innings his team seemed relaxed and was playing well.   "The girls were looking pretty good," he said.   Then in the fourth and fifth innings little things started to happen and the Lady 'Hounds began to lose their confidence, which led to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> scoring an additional nine runs in the fourth and fifth innings of the game.   The Lady 'Hounds (0-10, 2-14) will play again <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, taking on the Lady <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mustangs</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

