


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> gets ready to start search for new council member
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/6/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">People have approximately a week to think about throwing their hat into the ring, and trying for a seat on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   According to Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, it is anticipated that applications will be available at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Hall beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, July 13</TIMEX>. The applications are being made available to help find someone to fill the seat that will be vacated by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, who will be moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado Springs</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colo.</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said he will be submitting a letter of resignation to the council within the next couple of days.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> noted that the exact amount of time people will have to submit an application will be decided by members of the city council, but he anticipates it will be a one or two week time frame.
</P><P ID="7">   Those who are thinking about submitting an application should keep several things in mind. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> explained that to serve as a city council member a person has to be a registered voter and has to have lived in the city for at least one year. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said the person who is appointed to council will serve until the next election, for which the filing period is the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 2005</TIMEX>. He said the election held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next fall</TIMEX> will determine who will serve the remaining two years of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>'s term, which expires <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec. 31, 2007</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   As for the selection process, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said the city council will go through an interview process with the final action of appointing an applicant to the vacant position taking place during a public meeting.
</P><P ID="9">   "The selection process will be to solicit applications, review applications, interview applicants and select a council member," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="10">   He added that he is hoping to have someone appointed to the position as soon as possible. He explained that the city has 90 days from the time of vacancy to appoint someone to the position.
</P><P ID="11">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eolmstead@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="12">Webmaster
</P><P ID="13">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




