
<P ID="1">Lady 'Hounds leave Wildcats scoreless
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/22/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> came out of the gate on fire <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, scoring the first of two goals against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> in the first few seconds of the game. The goal would ultimately help the Lady 'Hounds defeat the Wildcats, and get them one step closer to postseason play.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> girls soccer team won over the Wildcats 2-0. The game marked senior night for the Lady 'Hounds and their last game of the regular season under the hot lights of the football stadium.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Anne Holden</ENAMEX> said the victory was nice for the team's seniors, adding that both goals were scored by seniors.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Rodriguez</ENAMEX> scored the first goal of the game in the first 10 seconds against the Wildcats, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>. She scored unassisted. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s second goal was scored by senior Akane Tomizawa in the 22nd minute of the match-up. She scored off of an assist from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rodriquez</ENAMEX>.   Overall, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> had 14 attempts on goal for the night, compared to one attempt by the Toppenish team.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said her team played well against the Wildcats, noting that they have really stepped up their game in recent match-ups.   She said her team has also been very supportive of each other, noting that even with several position changes in recent games team members are continuing to push forward and look for the win.   "They've all contributed in their own way," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said of her team members.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said she thinks one big difference has been the recent move of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> from goalkeeper to midfielder. She said bringing her up front has given the team a new confidence.   "It's changed the whole approach," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team (3-7, 4-9) has two games left in regular season play. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> explained that if the team can win against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Othello</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>, they will be tied for the fourth seed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX>. The tie will mean the two teams will have to face off to determine who will go into the postseason.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said the last few wins her team has pulled off has put the Lady 'Hounds in the driver's seat when it comes to the postseason. She explained that they don't have to rely on another team's performance to make it to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Districts</ENAMEX>, instead they just have to win.   "It's up to us," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> team will take to the field <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> at home.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

