
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> boys square league mark at 1-1
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/12/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Snapping a six-game losing streak this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> boys basketball team evened its <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mid-Valley League</ENAMEX> record at 1-1 by slipping past <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX>, 67-65.   "We desperately needed that win," said relieved first year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Coach Steve Urrutia</ENAMEX>.   The victory over the Bulldogs came in just the second conference game of the season for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, after the Grizzlies went 1-5 in non-league competition to open the year.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX> said his entire squad had a hand in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s win, describing the effort against the Bulldogs as "...an overall, good team effort."   Two of his Grizzlies, though, stood out from the pack at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">end of Saturday</TIMEX>'s fray.   Most notable, perhaps, was senior point guard <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessie Ramirez</ENAMEX>, who sank the winning basket in the closing seconds. Teammate Jake Thomas also had a big hand, quite literally in fact, when he swatted away a potentially game tying shot just as time expired.   The Grizzlies were leading <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> by five late in the game and attempted to pull even further ahead when they put up an unsuccessful shot with 1:13 remaining in the contest. The Bulldogs rebounded the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> and fed the ball to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Riley Sieback</ENAMEX>, who nailed a long range 3-pointer to draw <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> to within 67-65. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> turned the ball over on the ensuing possession, and the Bulldogs took advantage of the miscue when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Brozovich</ENAMEX> canned a 2-point bucket to square the game at 65-all.   With the contest knotted up even with 20 seconds remaining, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX> said he elected for his troops to play for the last shot. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> eventually drove the lane, flicking a shot towards the hoop, but the ball rolled off the rim. In a blink of the eye, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> grabbed the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> and popped the ball back through the hoop to give <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a 67-65 lead.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> had four seconds remaining to work the ball upcourt for a desperation attempt, but the potentially game tying shot the Bulldogs got off was swatted out of the air by Thomas-his second but probably his biggest block of the game.   Besides the two blocks he had <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the 6'6" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> poured in a game high 18 points and led the Grizzlies on the boards with a team high six rebounds.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX>, too, put up some imposing numbers against the Bulldogs. He scorched the net for 17 points, 11 of them coming in the second half when the Grizzlies outscored <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> by a 40-36 margin to take control of the game. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> also led <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> with four assists and came away with a game high five steals.   Another Grizzly who excelled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> was junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody Heckert</ENAMEX>, who knocked down 10 of his 12 points after intermission.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cody</ENAMEX> came off the bench and played super for us," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX>.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> coach also had praise for exchange student Branimir Janjevic, a 6'0" senior. Janjevic normally doesn't see a lot of time on the floor, but he played several minutes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> filling in for players who were in foul trouble.   "He gave us some good minutes out there," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Urrutia</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> cage team will make up its home contest from <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>, which was delayed because of the poor weather, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Tuesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> on the Grizzlies' floor. The game at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> that was cancelled <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> will be made up on the Falcons' home floor on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 20</TIMEX>.      . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story,can</ENAMEX> be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or e-mail him   at bstory@hawkpress.com   Ellensburg 14 15 20 16 -65   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 14 13 21 19 -67   2-pt. FG-Ellensburg 15/31, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 18/35. 3-pt. FG-Ellensburg 5/11, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 3/12 (Zamarron 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heckert</ENAMEX> 1). FT-Ellensburg 10/18, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 16/29. Rbd.-Ellensburg 44 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sieback</ENAMEX> 10), <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> 31 (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> 6).   Ellensburg-Robinson 14, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Griffith</ENAMEX> 17, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron</ENAMEX> 0, Fair 4, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brozovich</ENAMEX> 15, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gray</ENAMEX> 9, Siebach 16, Fork 0, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon</ENAMEX> 0.   Alderwood-Sanchez 0, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramirez</ENAMEX> 17, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Cantu</ENAMEX> 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Simmons</ENAMEX> 0, Zamarron 6, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Heckert</ENAMEX> 12, Van de Graaf 6, Schilperoort 2, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas</ENAMEX> 18, Janjevic 0.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

