
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX> arts fest <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 28-29</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GOLDENDALE</ENAMEX> - Organizers of the first ever Maryhill Arts Festival are promising an exciting and uniquely <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> experience.
To be held under a canopy of trees at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum</ENAMEX>'s picnic grounds on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Aug. 28</TIMEX>, and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Aug. 29</TIMEX>, it will make for a fun-filled weekend where art, wine, food and music can be enjoyed by all. Admission to the festival will be free.
Dozens of talented artists from throughout the region are expected to showcase orginal, quality art alongside a special exhibition by the Pacific Northwest Sculptors Assocation. Also being held that weekend is the museum's annual outdoor sculpture invitational, featuring 15 large-scale works.
"Visitors are invited to stroll through beautiful paintings, photography, jewlery, glass, ceramics, sculpture and much more by over 50 artists," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Colleen Schafroth</ENAMEX>, executive director at the museum. "Many of the artists will be giving art demonstrations and there will be free art-making activities for children."
A wine garden at the two-day festival will offer a variety of wines from the seven award winning wineries of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Klickitat Wine Alliance</ENAMEX>. Also, food vendors will be on site, including the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lyle Hotel Restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brian's Pourhouse Restaurant</ENAMEX>, Casa El Mirador and Cafe Maryhill.
Hourly musical presentations on stage will feature such groups as Didgeridoo of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Knehr</ENAMEX>, guitarist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Charles Crosman</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joanie</ENAMEX> and the Chipsters, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Swing Crew</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Humphrey & Smartman</ENAMEX>.
The museum will also be open both days. The new exhibit on display there is entitled "A Passion for Plants: Before and After <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">June & Clark</ENAMEX>."
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Maryhill Museum of Art</ENAMEX>, a castle-like chateau overlooking the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Columbia River</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Goldendale</ENAMEX>, is open daily.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fair</ENAMEX>, ride tickets already on sale
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - If you're planning on attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> and want to save a few bucks on admission and rides, organizers are offering some special prices to those willing to shop early.
Special discount admission tickets are currently available at local credit unions around the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, now through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 23</TIMEX>. The admission tickets are presently being discounted from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> for adults to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8.50</NUMEX>. A special fair family pack is also now available.  The pack includes gate admission for two adults and two youths, 36 ride coupons and three coupons for carnival game and food discounts. A <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$62</NUMEX> value, the pack is now selling for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$39</NUMEX>.
Carnival ride coupon booklets are also being discounted right now. Normally the 36-ride booklets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$36</NUMEX>, but they are now selling for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>.
Besides being offered at credit unions up and down the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, the specially priced tickets are also available at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> fair ticket office, or can be ordered by calling (509) 248-7160.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Peaches, cream social <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - A peaches and cream social for those interested in learning about volunteer opportunities with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX> is scheduled for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Aug. 31</TIMEX>.
All those who might be willing to donate blood, serve on a disaster action team, help out at blood drawings, assist office staff or represent the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Red Cross</ENAMEX> at community events are being encouraged to attend the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX> event at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> chapter of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Red Cross</ENAMEX> office in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> (302 S. 2nd St.). The informational social event will be held from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="6">Local film wins New York Film Festival honors
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BENTON CITY</ENAMEX> - The Promise, an independent family feature film shot entirely in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state featuring local actors, was awarded "Best Drama," honors a  the New York International Independent Film Festival in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July</TIMEX>.
The film stars 9-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pamela Serrano</ENAMEX>, a fourth-grader at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heights Elementary School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>. It also features scenes filmed in nine <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> cities, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pasco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ritzville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX> and Seattle.
The movie chronicles the adventures of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Emily</ENAMEX>, played by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Serrano</ENAMEX>, as she travels the state to find her father, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Charboneau</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Altered Image Productions</ENAMEX>, the film's producer and director.
The movie premiered in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> to a sell-out crowd at the Uptown Theatre in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>. It has also shown to a sold-out crowd at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Grand Cinemas 12 and to audiences at Walla Walla Grand Cinemas and Hermiston Stadium 8 Cinemas.
DVD copies of the film are available at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings Superstores</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Small Town Video</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton City</ENAMEX> and on-line at www.thepromise-movie.com.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> car show registration deadline nears
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest Tejano Music Association</ENAMEX> will host its third annual car show <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 5</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. Open to all types of cars, from low-riders to street cars, the one-day event will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Country Park</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wallace Way</ENAMEX>, said event promoter Tino Patina of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
Entries are also open for vans and trucks and custom bikes, he said.
Pre-registration is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX> per vehicle and the deadline is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31</TIMEX>. Day of the event registration is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX>, he said.
There is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> entry fee for custom bikes. Prizes will be awarded for first, second and third place. Judging will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> with the awards presentation to be held at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>
In addition to the car show, which is open to the public, an afternoon of entertainment and food is planned. General admission is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$10</NUMEX> per person with children 10 and under admitted free.
Gates open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">12 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to the general public. Those with car show entries may begin gathering at the park at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 a.m.</TIMEX>
For car show registration forms call Patina at 882-5050 or visit the music association's web site at pntma.com.
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Fresh Hop Ale Festival</ENAMEX>       set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 2</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Brewing Company</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Council of Yakima</ENAMEX> will host the second annual Fresh Hop Ale Festival <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 2</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s art center, 5000 W. Lincoln Ave., <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.
The festival, which showcases beers produced from fresh <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> hops, will be held from 5 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
To qualify as a fresh hop ale, the beers must be produced with hops picked within 24 hours of being used for brewing. Festival organizers will accept applications from up to 12 breweries.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last year</TIMEX>'s event attracted 1,200 attendees. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, local restaurants, regional wineries and dance bands will all be a part of the festival. The event is a fund-raiser for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Council</ENAMEX>'s children's art programs.
In addition to the ale fest, the Allied Arts second annual art walk will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Sept. 30</TIMEX>, through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 2</TIMEX>. More than 60 businesses and 60 local artists will be participating in the free Art Walk event.
For more information about the festival or artwalk call the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Council</ENAMEX> at (509) 966-0930.
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

