


<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P>



<P ID="3">PAID OBITUARY
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">JUAN CARLOS ROGEL</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan Carlos Rogel</ENAMEX>, 34, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 3, 2004</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="6">He was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 20, 1970</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> to Cantalicio and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Socorro Labra Rogel</ENAMEX>. He came to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">five years ago</TIMEX>. He worked in agriculture.
</P>

<P ID="7">A Rosary was held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Jan. 9, 2004</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Hills Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He will be buried in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley Hills Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> is entrusted with arrangements.
</P>

 


<P ID="8">POLLY <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">KAYE HEAD-CORLISS</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polly Kaye Head-Corliss</ENAMEX>, 37, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodinville</ENAMEX> and a former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> resident, passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Dec. 31, 2003</TIMEX>, at her home with her husband after a seven year battle with breast cancer. 
</P>

<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polly</ENAMEX> was <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 10, 1966</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim and Jean Corliss</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polly</ENAMEX> was <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> valedictorian in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1984</TIMEX>. She attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Washington University</ENAMEX>, graduated Magna Cum Laude with a Bachelor of Science in psychology at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of California Berkeley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1988</TIMEX>, and Phi Beta Kappa with an Master of Arts in education at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Berkeley</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polly</ENAMEX> married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Head-Corliss</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 9, 1986</TIMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="12">She taught at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vale Elementary School</ENAMEX> in Cashmere and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Meridian School</ENAMEX> in Seattle.
</P>

<P ID="13">Her great loves were her family, teaching, scrapbooking, and friends.
</P>

<P ID="14"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Polly</ENAMEX> is survived by her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Head-Corliss</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Woodinville</ENAMEX>; two children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maya</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kellen</ENAMEX>; her parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim and Jean Corliss</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; and one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Corliss</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="15">A life-long United Methodist, Polly’s memorial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Jan. 24, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lake Washington United Methodist Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kirkland</ENAMEX>. You can find directions and memorial gifts information at 
www.lwumc.com
</P>

 


<P ID="16"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GREGORIO RODRIGUEZ</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="17"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, 84, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Jan. 11, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
</P>

<P ID="18"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 30, 1919</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Del Rosario Chavez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe Rodriguez</ENAMEX>. On <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 25, 1959</TIMEX> he married <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria D. DeLeon</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Crystal City</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. In the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late 1960s</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX> family moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio</ENAMEX> was a fire fighter throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX>. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1969</TIMEX> the family returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> for 14 years before settling in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1983</TIMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="19"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio</ENAMEX> attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. 
</P>

<P ID="20">He enjoyed hunting and fishing.
</P>

<P ID="21"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio</ENAMEX> is survived by his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Rodriguez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; 10 children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elva Cornejo</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanca Cortinas</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Cuello</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feliz Rodriguez</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Delores Rodriguez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maribel Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregorio Rodriguez Jr.</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Blanca</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rosario Ayala</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurelio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosemary Diaz</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Crystal City</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josie Moncado</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Van Buren</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ark.</ENAMEX>; 14 grandchildren; and four great-grandchildren.
</P>

<P ID="22">He was preceded in death by his parents; two brothers; and one sister.
</P>

<P ID="23">Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Jan. 12, 2004</TIMEX>, from 1 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be recited at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Jan. 13, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Memorial Gardens, under the direction of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jones Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. 
</P>





 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




