
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozuna</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> to help decide how more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5 million</NUMEX> will be spent on local health care issues
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/5/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A 15-member board has been selected to help manage more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5 million</NUMEX> that will be used to provide health care and other services to the people of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>. Of those 15, two members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community Foundation</ENAMEX> are from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Ozuna</ENAMEX>, both residents of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, were two of the first 10 people appointed to be on the board.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozuna</ENAMEX>, who works for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, who works in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State Migrant Student Data and Recruitment Office</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>, said they are excited to be a part of the foundation during its inception.   "It's exciting to set up all these directions," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozuna</ENAMEX> said.   The board of the new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community Foundation</ENAMEX> will help manage <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6.5 million</NUMEX> from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Providence Health Foundation</ENAMEX>, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1 million</NUMEX> a year for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next 10 years</TIMEX> from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Health Management Associates</ENAMEX> and all profits Providence realizes from the sale of its two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> hospitals. The board will also have the authority to seek out other funding sources to help support charitable health work in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   "This is really an incredible board," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Richardson</ENAMEX>, one of the new board members and former president of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Providence Health Foundation</ENAMEX>. "Every one of the members has an outstanding record of service to the poor and under-served."   Both <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozuna</ENAMEX> were chosen to serve as members of the foundation's board through an intense selection process. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she had to submit a resume, as well as fill out a detailed application. From there she was selected by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Advisory Committee</ENAMEX> to serve as a member of the board.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she felt serving as a member of the board would be a good opportunity to ensure that the foundation's resources are spent on health care needs throughout the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.   "I really thought it was a great opportunity for me to provide some input on our situation in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozuna</ENAMEX> said he also wanted to be a part of the board to ensure that the health needs of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> are met.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said being a member of the board she is looking forward to tackling a couple of issues that are important to her, including providing more resources for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>'s nurse education program, as well as ensuring that health care needs of the Hispanic population are addressed, including heath problems such as diabetes, heart disease and nutrition.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said she knows that over the years the local hospital has been faced with a nurse shortage and has gone as far as to hire nurses from out of the country to work in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She said she is also aware of an educational program the hospital has that encourages people to look to nursing as a possible profession.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ozuna</ENAMEX> said he is going into the process with an open mind, and is really excited to see the entire 15-member board come together for the first time during its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> meeting.   The foundation and its board were developed under a law written by Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Deccio</ENAMEX>, R-<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>. The law regulates the sale of non-profit hospitals to for-profit companies and outlines the roles of state agencies in the process, including those of the Attorney General's office and the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department of Health</ENAMEX>. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Providence/Health Management Associates</ENAMEX> transition is the first time the law has been used.   The Attorney General had the lead in approving the foundation, including the plan for creating the foundation board. The plan was developed with input from more than 24 community members and groups in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

