
<P ID="1">Working Stiff
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A term of service in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX> led <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sheila Cerda</ENAMEX> to her present occupation.   "I learned about being a receptionist while volunteering in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AmeriCorp</ENAMEX> service," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cerda</ENAMEX> explained.   "I worked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Department</ENAMEX> for a while, I learned to do dispatching," she said.   But it was a volunteer position at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX> which led her to her present employment.   "I volunteered as a receptionist at the hospital for about a year," she explained. "When my <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">AmeriCorps</ENAMEX> term was up, the hospital hired me as a receptionist," she said.   Currently, the petite mother of two works three days a week as a technical assistant in the X-ray department at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>, and one day a week she works as a front desk receptionist at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood's Lincoln Avenue Family Medicine Center</ENAMEX>.   "The technical assistant title means I'm a receptionist," she grinned. "But I also get to do other things like moving files between departments, help with patients and do a lot of data entry," she said.   Both of her jobs involve a lot of paperwork, in addition to greeting patients with a cheerful and compassionate attitude and her welcoming smile.   Between her two jobs, she works an average of 40 hours a week, she said, noting that her X-ray department job has her working three 10-hour days while her Lincoln Avenue job has her working a regular 8-hour day.   At the family health clinic, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cerda</ENAMEX> answers phones, schedules patients and helps patients check in for their visit with the clinic's physicians.   "I really like the work," she smiled.   The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1989</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> graduate and her husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco Cerda Jr.</ENAMEX>, have two children, a daughter, who will be 13 in a few days, and a 5-year-old son, who is a kindergarten student <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

