


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> hopes to unseat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/12/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">58-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Michael Kepcha</ENAMEX> knows he has a snowball's chance in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hades</ENAMEX> of unseating 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">District</ENAMEX> Rep. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX> (R) of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   But the Washougal resident, campaigning as a Democrat without the support of the party he represents, strongly believes he is the man for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> of Representatives seat in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> now holds.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX>, whom <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> handily defeated <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>, swung through <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> to tout his views on why voters should consider him for the job.
</P><P ID="7">   "I know I said I wasn't going to run for public office again after the last election <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">two years ago</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> said. "But nobody else decided to run against him <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "I'm re-running for the position because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Newhouse</ENAMEX>. We have different views on what the community needs," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   "I might not be as effective as Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> is in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> concedes. "But I think a different perspective is needed."
</P><P ID="10">   When asked about specifics, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> speaks about more funding for the schools.
</P><P ID="11">   "I'll fight for money for our school districts," he said. "Every year more and more kids are coming out of high school, out into the job market.
</P><P ID="12">   "These kids need to be properly educated so they can find jobs after they're out of school," he stressed.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX> veteran who is unemployed and said he spends much of his time caring for his mother, who is stricken with Alzheimer's, also believes the state needs to find more funding for geriatric and pediatric care.
</P><P ID="14">   "We're not spending enough on the medical care of infants or our elderly," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX>. "More needs to be done for the older people in our community, and for the children who aren't receiving the medical care they deserve."
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> said making health insurance affordable for all <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> residents is a problem that can no longer be addressed at the state level.
</P><P ID="16">   "It's too large of a problem to be fixed in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Olympia</ENAMEX>," he said. "It's something that needs to be fixed at the federal level."
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> went on to detail that he disagrees with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republic Party</ENAMEX>'s torte reform attempts, to put a lid on what people can recover when filing medical claims.
</P><P ID="18">   "I agree that the court settlements have gotten out of hand, but people need to have the ability to recover their losses when mistakes are made.
</P><P ID="19">   "Some kind of cap is probably needed, but not what the Republicans are suggesting.
</P><P ID="20">   "I read somewhere that <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of the doctors are responsible for <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">95 percent</NUMEX> of the claims," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> continued. "The problem could be taken care of if the medical association started to police itself.
</P><P ID="21">   "We also don't need to put a cap on L&I claims or settlements. I've met families who have been injured on the job. They need the money they're entitled to, all of it," he said.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> also disagrees with the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> needs to recalculate how the state's minimum wage is adjusted each year.
</P><P ID="23">   "We don't need to freeze the minimum wage," he said. "We're where we should be at compared to the other states."
</P><P ID="24">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX> said his chances of unseating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Newhouse</ENAMEX> are slim, but he wants to give the voters of the 15th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> an alternative when they vote in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="25">   "The two of us definitely don't have the same views. I'm the other choice," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kepcha</ENAMEX>.
</P>





 










<P ID="26">Webmaster
</P><P ID="27">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




