
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/19/2002</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bowker guestof Heritage College</ENAMEX> all <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Bowker</ENAMEX>, a renowned fiber artist and painter, will serve as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX> artist-in-residence <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next week</TIMEX>.
As part of her residency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowker</ENAMEX> will juror the second annual <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Regional High School Art Exhibit</ENAMEX> that runs <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 22 through April 1</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>. Art teachers at high schools from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Naches</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> have been invited to submit up to five entries of student <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">art.
Bowker</ENAMEX>'s art will be on display along with the student art. The show will be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helen Jewett Student Center</ENAMEX> on the Toppenish main campus. Artwork will be open for public viewing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday through Friday</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowker</ENAMEX>'s art has won numerous awards in painting, jewelry and fiber art. Her work is frequently selected for juried exhibitions nationally and internationally.
A public reception to honor the high school artists and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowker</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 24</TIMEX>, from 6:30 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helen Jewett Student Center</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bowker</ENAMEX> will present a lecture on her work at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> that evening.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Toppenish Eagles lodge oyster feed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - Fraternal Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> members and their guests are invited to an all-you-can-eat oyster feed <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>.
Tickets for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> meal, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$12</NUMEX>, are available by calling the lodge at (509) 865-2229.
The Toppenish lodge will also be serving a prime rib dinner that night, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Dinner showto feature hypnotist
TOPPENISH - Renowned hypnotist Robert Mac will be the featured attraction at a dinner show to be staged at the Toppenish Fraternal Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> lodge.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mac</ENAMEX>'s comedy routine has delighted audiences for years.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 27</TIMEX>, show will feature a steak dinner at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mac</ENAMEX> to perform at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> Dancing to live country western music will follow.
Tickets are available by calling the Toppenish Eagles lodge at (509) 865-2229.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Garden Expoon tap in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early May</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SPOKANE</ENAMEX> - The fifth annual Garden Expo, a community service project sponsored by the Inland Empire Gardeners, will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 8</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spokane Community College</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lair Student Union Building</ENAMEX>.
The one-day, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> event is free and open to the public.
More than 200 vendors will be on hand selling plants, gardening products, services and arts and crafts projects. Local gardening organizations will also be represented at the show. There will also be seminars and show-me-how demonstrations.
In conjunction with the show, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spokane Community College</ENAMEX> cafeteria will be open that day for food service, and the college is offering free parking.
</P> 
<P ID="7">Tattoo art is focusof Yakima exhibition
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The rise of tattoos in American culture has placed the tattooist in the category of fine artist. In celebration of that distinction, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Allied Arts Council of Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> will host an  exhibition of tattoo art, "Tattoo: Past and Present," <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19 through April 9</TIMEX>, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Allied Arts Center</ENAMEX>, 5000 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">W. Lincoln Ave.
Former Alderwoodrs Jim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenni Rosal</ENAMEX> will be featured artists at an opening reception tonight (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19</TIMEX>) from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rosals</ENAMEX>, who own "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jenni</ENAMEX>'s Quality Tattoo" of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, were instrumental in putting together the unusual gallery presentation, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliot Challandes</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Allied Arts Council</ENAMEX>.
"The tattoo display celebrates the tattooist's personal style used to create unique body art," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Challandes</ENAMEX>.
Included in the exhibition will be original tattoo art in ink, pencil, watercolor and mixed media. Works by both contemporary and vintage artists will be also be a part of the display, along with tattooing equipment from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Japan</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Pacific</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> student actors to present ‘Wizard of Oz’ <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this weekend</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Z Center Stage Theater Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Zillah High School</ENAMEX> will present "The Wizard of Oz" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 19</TIMEX> and 20, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at the  high school auditorium.
Additional performances will be offered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 25</TIMEX>, 26 and 27. Tickets are <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for general admission.
Directed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lynn Brant</ENAMEX>, the musical features a cast of 35 student actors. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holly Lacell</ENAMEX> plays <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dorothy</ENAMEX> in the high school drama presentation with Natalia York as her dog, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toto</ENAMEX>. The parts of the Scarecrow, Tinman and the Cowardly Lion will be handled by  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Erich Sauerwein</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tim Baker</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eric Porter</ENAMEX>, respectively.
</P> 
<P ID="9">Larson Galleryto host 32nd annual photography exhibit
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The 32nd annual National Photography Exhibition, a juried competition, will be held at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larson Gallery</ENAMEX> on the Yakima campus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">from April 4 through May 1</TIMEX>.
The exhibition, founded by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herb Blisard</ENAMEX>, a photography instructor at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX>, will open with a reception on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 4</TIMEX> from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> in the gallery, 16th Street and Nob Hill Avenue, and will run through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 1</TIMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s juried competition received submissions from 25 states for a record high of 530 photographs entered, 121 were accepted. A total of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$3,200</NUMEX> in cash awards, including <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$350</NUMEX> for Best of Show, has been awarded to 18 photographers. Awards will be announced during the opening reception.
As part of the exhibition, contest juror <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marita Holdaway</ENAMEX>, the owner and director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Benham Gallery</ENAMEX> in Seattle, will present a free public lecture, "Finding a Place for Your Art - How to be Seen and Get Sold," on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, April 2</TIMEX>. Her lecture will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Anthon Hall</ENAMEX>  room 102, on the Yakima YVCC campus.
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Larson Gallery</ENAMEX> hours are <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday through Saturday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> For more information contact (509) 574-4875.
</P> 
<P ID="10">‘Dance-art dialogue’ exhibit opens <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 20</TIMEX>  at Seattle gallery
Seattle -  The famed <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Trisha Brown Dance Company</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York</ENAMEX> will present an exhibition of dance and art at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Henry Art Gallery</ENAMEX> in Seattle through <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 18</TIMEX>.
The exhibition, "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dance</ENAMEX> and Art in Dialogue," will open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, March 20</TIMEX>. "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dance</ENAMEX> and Art in Dialogue" is a living exhibition that will include events staged in and near the museum in the form of indoor and outdoor performances, workshops and  lecture demonstrations given by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brown</ENAMEX> and members of her company.
Admission to the dance performances is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$8</NUMEX> for adults. Admission is free to high school and college students with identification and for children 13 and under. The gallery, located on  the campus of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>, is open <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX>  to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, and from 11 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> on Thursdays.
For more information about the dance exhibit and other exhibits call (206) 543-2280 or visit the museum web site at www.henryart.org.
</P> 


 




<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

