
<P ID="1">Venison wasn't on brunch menu of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> couple <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/19/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dale Knott</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> was getting ready for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">church</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>, when a scream from his wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX>, sent him running into the couple's living room. There standing on the carpet was a startled young Mule deer.   "The dogs were chasing the deer and it just bolted into the house past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knott</ENAMEX>.   "I didn't know what it was at first," he said. "I thought it was just a big brown dog chasing her (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Becky</ENAMEX>)."   The couple, who live near the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima River</ENAMEX> on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Euclid Road</ENAMEX>, east of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, have seen deer in the area before, but one has never been in the house before, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knott</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knott</ENAMEX> said the animal wasn't scared once she got inside the house, allowing him and his wife to pet her while she camped out in their home.   "She wasn't afraid of us," he said. "Once she got away from the dogs, she settled right down."   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> couple contacted state wildlife agents, who retrieved the young doe <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">later Sunday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>. She will have to be rehabilitated to live in the wild, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Knott</ENAMEX> said.   It is against the law to tame wild animals, he said. He said the deer, they temporarily dubbed "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bambi</ENAMEX>," will have to be checked for diseases before being reintroduced into the area herds.   "It was quite a morning," he added.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

