
<P ID="1">Zillah winery hosts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX> exhibit
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ZILLAH</ENAMEX> - It is fitting that paintings with titles like "Space Winds" and "Winds of Change" should be on display in a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">north Zillah</ENAMEX> gallery named for the area's "good air."   The paintings, distinctive in their blended movements of grays, yellows, blues and whites, are the creative endeavors of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> artist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elena Leonardo</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>, whose work has been shown in galleries throughout <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Europe</ENAMEX> during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last 20 years</TIMEX>, is finishing up a show at the Bonair Winery gallery on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bonair Road</ENAMEX>. She expects to hold a new opening in Seattle in the near future.   For the time being, she is enjoying the winery's visitor's reactions to her work, which is largely centered on a Greek mythological theme.   The use of astrology and mythology has a prominent place in her work as she combines themes such as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helio</ENAMEX>'s son's tragic experience with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Helio</ENAMEX>'s chariot steeds.   "I've always had a need to express my feeling about the universe in a logical way, based on my life's experiences," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonardo</ENAMEX>, who loves to add an underlying element of storytelling in her work, enjoys working with concepts like supernovas and exploring the effects of weightlessness. The power of her feelings resonates from each of the 12 paintings currently on display at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX> winery.   The current show closes <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 2</TIMEX>.   Bonair Winery, at 500 S. Bonair Rd. on the Zillah Fruit Loop, is open daily from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

