
<P ID="1">Elerding sets <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> qualifying times
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/28/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - Competing against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Moses Lake</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Saturday</TIMEX> at Lion's Pool in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patrick Elerding</ENAMEX> swam two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> meet qualifying times.   Elerding posted a time of 22.50 seconds in the 50-yard freestyle, and clocked a 1:01.51 in the 100-yard breaststroke. Both efforts by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elerding</ENAMEX> were first place finishes.   Elerding has set <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> meet qualifying times in all seven events in which he has competed this season. He has also scored a first place finish in every race in which he has competed.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> student will next compete at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> championships <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 6-7</TIMEX>. He has elected to swim the 100-yard breaststroke and 100-yard butterfly.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

