
<P ID="1">Bears GM visits <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> to recruit fans to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> games
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/10/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">A good old-fashioned game of baseball, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">25 cent</NUMEX> hotdogs and fireworks are images that spring to mind when a person begins to think of things that are traditionally American. And <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June 21</TIMEX>, during the Yakima Bears home opener, these are things that everyone in attendance will have a chance to be a part of.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Romero</ENAMEX>, general manager of the Yakima Bears, told members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daybreak Rotary Club</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> about some of the promotional things the organization does during the season, including fireworks at their home opener and crazy games between innings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said their goal is to get those people who regularly attend one game during the season to attend two, and those who normally go to three or four games to go to five or six during the season.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> is the smallest market in the league, playing against teams from places as large as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX>, which has an audience of a million people to draw from.   "It's a night and day difference," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said of the amount of people between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vancouver</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>.   Despite being a small market, the Yakima team, which is an affiliate of the Arizona Diamondbacks, obtains some quality players. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> the team is expecting to get 15 to 16 players coming up from extended spring training in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tucson</ENAMEX>.   "We expect to see a lot of those college guys," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said. "We should be a good team and it should be a fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said for many of the players, being a Yakima Bear <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this summer</TIMEX> will be their first time playing professional baseball. He said it takes them some time to get used to the daily grind, playing 76 games in 80 days.   "This is their job," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said.   He said another challenge for the players is the fact that <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Bears</ENAMEX> play in a tough league.   "A lot of them will come here and deal with failure for the first time," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said.   He added that of the 30 players that make up the team, on average two or three of them will eventually end up playing in the major leagues. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said there are currently 14 or 15 former <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> playing in the major leagues.   "It's the spring board where they kind of launch their careers," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said.   Although it is merely entertainment for the fans, the Yakima Bears organization is also a business. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> said the organization is an independent business affiliated with the Diamondbacks. One of the challenges that comes with operating a business like the baseball team, is that it only has 38 days a year to attract customers. He said it's a discretionary business, explaining that coming to a baseball game is not something people need to do. He said there are also other challenges that come into play, like weather and the players the team gets. The players are chosen by the Diamondbacks organization.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Teddi Fowler</ENAMEX>, director of ticket and group sales, told Rotarians that there a lot of different ticket options for those who are interested in attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bears</ENAMEX> games this season. She said one of those options is to purchase a book of 10 general admission tickets for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$32</NUMEX>. She said the tickets can then be used for any of the games. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fowler</ENAMEX> said another popular option is a book of undated vouchers for reserved seats at the stadium. She said the vouchers can then be used at any game during the season and more than one voucher can be used per game.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Romero</ENAMEX> added that keeping ticket prices affordable is important to the organization.   "I believe the important thing about minor league baseball is keeping it affordable for people," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

