
<P ID="1">Lightning bolts past <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> gridders, 35-7
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">UNION GAP</ENAMEX> - Ouch! The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> football team got stung by a lightning bolt <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>. The LaSalle Lightning racked up a 35-7 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> victory against <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>.   The defeat dropped the Vikes to 0-2 in conference play, 1-2 overall. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaSalle</ENAMEX> improved to 1-1 in league play, 2-1 overall on the season.   "We didn't play assignment defense," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Coach D.J</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>. "And, being physical, we didn't show up with that, either."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaSalle</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carlos DeJesus</ENAMEX> was a one-man wrecking crew. A scatback type runner, he rushed for all three of the Lightning's first half touchdowns. The first came on a 28-yard burst, the second on an 83-yard breakaway run in which he eluded tackle-after-tackle. His third TD run of the opening half was a nifty 34-yard scamper.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeJesus</ENAMEX> ended up with 152 rushing yards. Surprisingly, he gained all that yardage on just seven carries.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DeJesus</ENAMEX> wasn't the only runner that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaSalle</ENAMEX> threw at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>. Four other running backs carried the ball an aggregate 27 times, gaining an additional 84 yards.   The Lightning added 59 yards through the air on 5-of-12 passing numbers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s rushing attack wasn't all that bad, as the Vikes totaled 149 yards on the ground. Their quarterback, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Harris</ENAMEX>, and tailback <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Elizondo</ENAMEX> accounted for most of the yards, as each toted the ball eight times for 33 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tailback Jovani Ochoa</ENAMEX> added a 32-yard rushing performance on seven carries.   Through the air <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>, the Vikes were able to pass for just 9 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX> was 1-for-10 with one interception.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s lone score came in the second quarter. The Vikes capped off a 60-yard drive with a 5-yard TD scamper by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">LaSalle</ENAMEX> added two touchdowns after intermission to account for the final 35-7 score.   This coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>'s game at <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> against visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bridgeport</ENAMEX> (0-2) will be the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Homecoming game for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said his club knows <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bridgeport</ENAMEX> likes to spread the field.   "They'll use a single back and like to throw a lot," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

