
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> names top grads
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Just 14 more days remain until the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> can celebrate graduation from high school and begin the next leg of their journey in life.   Already well on their way to pursuing higher education are those students who during their high school careers have achieved outstanding academic status by climbing to the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> of their class.   Leading the class with matching grade point averages of 4.259 are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josh Barr</ENAMEX>, who have been named class co-valedictorians. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amy Kilian</ENAMEX>, with a 4.222 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, will be the class salutatorian.   Also numbered in the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mayra Carrillo</ENAMEX>, 4.151 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steffani Startup</ENAMEX>, 4.058 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, John Van Wingerden III, 4.087 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alaina Hull</ENAMEX>, 4.035 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel Wells</ENAMEX>, 3.964 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarah Dill</ENAMEX>, 3.949 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kyle E. Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, 3.913 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin Sanchez</ENAMEX>, 3.913 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey Davis</ENAMEX>, 3.892 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ryan Webster</ENAMEX>, 3.888 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Matson</ENAMEX>, 3.882 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Lua</ENAMEX>, 3.870 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mitch Lathen</ENAMEX>, 3.846 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Sambrano</ENAMEX>, 3.806 <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GPA</ENAMEX>.   In addition to be being academically gifted, each member of the top <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5 percent</NUMEX> is also active in some type of community service, sport or extra-curricular activity.   For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX>, who has made a career of being a standout in all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s science classes, has earned numerous state and regional grand champion science fair awards. Most recently she was recognized by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> as its <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Outstanding Young Person. Gorksi, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trish Nixon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Fred Gorski</ENAMEX>, is already enrolled at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University</ENAMEX> of the Sciences in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Philadelphia</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pa.</ENAMEX>, where she plans to study to become an oncologist pharmacist.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck and Ruth Barr</ENAMEX>, already has a direct admission into the computer science program at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. He hopes one day to not only design award winning video games, he hopes to become a novelist. While in high school <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> was an active member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS Apple Bowl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Knowledge Bowl</ENAMEX> teams. He was an <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Evergreen Boys State</ENAMEX> delegate and is an Eagle Scout.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> will be attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> to study biochemistry with plans of attending medical school. A leader in many of the school clubs, she also served as student body secretary, as well as being active in soccer, track, drama, fire squad and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX>. The daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Jean Kilian</ENAMEX>, she was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS Knowledge Bowl</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apple Bowl</ENAMEX> teams and served on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Athletic Advisory Committee</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gerardo and Irma Carrillo</ENAMEX>, has shown interest in high school leadership training groups, such as FBLA and Link Crew, an organization which helps underclassmen adjust to high school life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrillo</ENAMEX>, who hopes to become a family doctor, will attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Startup</ENAMEX>, who not only attended classes at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> but also attended <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College Running Start</ENAMEX> classes, plans to study architecture at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX>, beginning <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. In addition to being interested in music, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Startup</ENAMEX> has been active in Link Crew, drama, flag team and peer mediation. She also found time to be active in volleyball, softball and basketball. She is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don and Cindy Startup</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van Wingerden</ENAMEX>, who has divided his high school career between wrestling, jazz band and working after school, will attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. He expects to earn a degree in biochemistry and perhaps go into research. He is the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John and Deanna Van Wingerden</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hull</ENAMEX>, who has proven herself a leader on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> student council and leaders in action group, plans to travel for a year before settling into college life. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hull</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve and Paula Hull</ENAMEX>, has participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> drama club, fire squad and soccer team. She is very active in her church youth group, which has led to her decision to be a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REACH Youth Ministry</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wells</ENAMEX>, who sees herself eventually working in a big city emergency room, will attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. She plans to major in biology or chemistry. Her graduate school plans include medical school. Active in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX> and math team, she was also a member of the Grizzly fastpitch, bowling and golf teams, as well as being the volleyball team manager. In addition, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sharon Wells</ENAMEX> volunteered her spare time at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dill</ENAMEX> will complete her high school career with her <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> diploma and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Associates</ENAMEX> of Science degree earned while attending the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College Running Start</ENAMEX> program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dill</ENAMEX> has been accepted with distinction as a junior at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>, where she plans to major in biology. Medical or dentistry school looms on her horizon. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dill</ENAMEX> served as captain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> soccer team and currently hold an orange belt in karate. She is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Donna and Jeffrey Dill</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>, a force on the athletic field in soccer, football and basketball, will attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. He sees himself as an orthodontist following graduate school. He is the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod and Lori Van de Graaf</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> will attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>, where his major will be business management. The senior class president hopes to one day to own his own business. He is the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martin and Martha Sanchez</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> will give up his spot as a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> pep band, jazz band and concert band when he graduates. He will attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Idaho</ENAMEX> in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall</TIMEX>. The son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leonard and Susan Davis</ENAMEX>, he was also active in fire squad, Link Crew, as well as track, and cross country while attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin and Tracy Webster</ENAMEX>, will attend the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">University of Washington</ENAMEX>. He is undecided if his major will be in engineering, pharmacy or environmental law. A part-time employee at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Racquet</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Fitness Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Webster</ENAMEX> was a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> golf and football teams. He was also a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Link Crew</ENAMEX>, fire squad and drama club.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matson</ENAMEX> will be headed to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Irvine</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX> to attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Concordia University</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. While attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> she participated in band, drama club, fire squad, Link Crew, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX> and flag team. She is also a swimmer, soccer player and member of the Grizzly girls track team. She is the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeffrey and Doris Matson</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lua</ENAMEX> has the choice of attending <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Central Washington University</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. He wants to major in mathematics and Spanish regardless of which school he chooses. He volunteers his spare time to tutor elementary school students. One day he hopes to obtain a teaching degree. He is the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mercedes Lua</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lathen</ENAMEX> hopes to pursue a career in the recording world, but first he plans to study communications at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Western Washington University</ENAMEX>. He is the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Lathen</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Carter</ENAMEX>. His extracurricular activities have ranged from being the captain of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS Apple Bowl</ENAMEX> team to being a member of drama club, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> jazz ensemble and the boys track team.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sambrano</ENAMEX> sees herself as a leader in the field of interior design within 20 years. But first she will attend <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> to study interior design. The daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sylvia and Enrique Sambrano</ENAMEX>, she split her high school years between fastpitch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">DECA</ENAMEX>, Leader in Action and FBLA activities after school.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

