


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> close to hiring new city manager
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/6/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> made its choice for a new city manager following a hour-long executive session <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. Now all that is left is finalizing a contract that will bring him to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> said he expects to have a report before <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> at the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 12</TIMEX> meeting regarding whether the city has officially hired a new city manager.
</P><P ID="6">   Following <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s executive session, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> made the unanimous suggestion to offer a city manager contract to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Robert Rockford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Provo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> told the audience following <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s executive session that 17 people had initially applied for the open city manager position, which has been vacant since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, following the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dave Fonfara</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> then whittled the list of applicants down to eight for individual interviews. From the eight interviews, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opted to go with three candidates to conduct more extensive background checks. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX> one of the three finalists requested to be removed from the list. The two remaining finalists for the city manager position were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott McClure</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brush</ENAMEX>, Col.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> was laid off <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last September</TIMEX> from his position as vice president of corporate development for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CeriStar, Inc.</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salt Lake City</ENAMEX>. He is also the former city administrative officer for the city of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Provo</ENAMEX>, which is a town of 112,000 residents. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is the former city manager of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alamogordo</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New Mexico</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> held the position in the town of 35,000 people for five years. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> earned his Bachelor of Science degree in justice administration from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brigham Young University</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1974</TIMEX>. He also holds a Master's in public administration, which he obtained from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BYU</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="9">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClure</ENAMEX> holds a Bachelor of Science degree in political science and a Master's in public administration. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClure</ENAMEX> is the current city administrator in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Brush</ENAMEX>, where he also served as assistant city administrator. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">McClure</ENAMEX> also formerly worked in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Gresham</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, as the city's management analyst.
</P><P ID="10">   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past weekend</TIMEX>, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilmen Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Torch</ENAMEX> traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> on a fact-finding mission concerning the final two candidates.
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> told the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> that going into <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>, he had his personal favorite for the position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>, though, said he changed his mind following the contacts the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> trio made during the weekend excursion.
</P><P ID="12">   "There is nothing like meeting an individual in his hometown," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> said he was very impressed with what he learned about <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> and recommended hiring him for the city manager position.
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is his top pick for the city manager job. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said with the experience <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> has, he stood above the three finalists.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said while he didn't go on the trip <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>, he felt that from what he knows <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> is the most qualified of the finalists. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> seems to have what is needed to help the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meet its goals and push the city forward.
</P><P ID="16">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> said she would have liked to have made her own contacts regarding the finalists, but said she was impressed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX> said experience is why he is going with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> for the city manager position.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he completely supports the recommendation of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> to go with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> for the city manager position. Entering the process of hiring a new city manager, the mayor said it was his goal to have unanimous consensus among the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> as to who the city hired. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he has a lot of confidence in the three councilmen who traveled to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX> and in the report the trio provided to the rest of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   Following the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said the weekend was eye-opening for him in regards to offering the city manager position to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   "He is honest and forthright," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   While in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Utah</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Colorado</ENAMEX>, the three councilmen didn't talk to any family or friends of the finalists, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>. The trio did talk to just about everyone else, including a journalist in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>'s town, who spoke very highly of him.
</P><P ID="22">   "I think he will be the right fit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   In its job posting, the city council is offering a salary of between <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$80,000</NUMEX> and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$90,000</NUMEX> plus benefits for the city manager position.
</P>   






 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




