
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/13/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Ice cream social open to the public
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - To celebrate its official name change to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage University</ENAMEX>, college officials are inviting the public to attend an open house/ice cream social on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Aug. 19</TIMEX>, from 3 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX>
The event will take place on Heritage's <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> campus.
Along with the ice cream social, the open house will feature student and faculty displays which highlight some of the university's academic programs.
</P> 
<P ID="4">Grape stomping championshipset for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18-19</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TURNER</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ORE.</ENAMEX> - Turn your feet purple and squish your way to victory.
Willamette Valley Vineyards in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Turner</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> is hosting the Oregon Grape Stomping Championship and annual Harvest Celebration on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Sept. 18-19</TIMEX>. Activities will be held from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">11 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> both days.
Participants are invited to enter the two-person team competition, or just bring a blanket to sit back and enjoy the festivities as a spectator. There is a <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> fee per team, per heat. Winners will receive an all-expense paid trip and the right to represent <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Oregon</ENAMEX> at the World Championship Grape Stomp in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Santa Rosa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Calif.</ENAMEX>
To register to compete in the grape stomping contest, call (503) 588-9463 or 1-800-344-9463.
Visitors are invited to enjoy the fun <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 18-19</TIMEX> with a variety of great foods from Willaby's Catering and award-winning wines from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Willamette Valley</ENAMEX>. The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> admission charge includes the price of a Riedel wine glass and tasting. Those under the age of 21 will be admitted free. The two-day event is being billed as a family affair.
Live music for dancing and stomping will be provided by J.T. & The Tourists.
Willamette Valley Vineyardsis located on Enchanted Way, one mile south of exit 248 off I-5, just south of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Salem</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="5">Dirt track racing <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 20</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 20</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington State Fair Raceway</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> will host the championship race of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Economy Sprint Car Organization</ENAMEX>.
Also that night, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Hornets</ENAMEX> will be running. Hornet racers continue to earn the reputation as being the most exciting racers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, as they battle four and five-wide on the dirt oval.
In addition, modified drivers will compete that <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, Aug. 20</TIMEX>, event will feature free checkered flags for the kids in attendance, who will be encouraged to get their favorite drivers to sign them.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Western art show features new artists
TOPPENISH - Ten new artists will be at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>'s Toppenish Western Art Show, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 20-22</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Railroad Park</ENAMEX>.
Those in attendance will have a chance to interact and observe the artists in action. There is no charge to attend.
Show hours will be from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
A total of 36 artists have signed up to offer fine art subjects of wildlife, western and Native American art in pastels, acrylics, oils, water color, ink, sculptures, pottery, metals and photography.
Kids 'n Art, a special free event for youngsters, will begin at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artist Jerry Nighthawk Raven</ENAMEX> of the Tri-Cities will teach children the techniques for using pastels and creating a portrait of a Native American. Class size is limited on a first come, first serve basis.
New <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX> will be a "Showcase of Student Art," sponsored by a grant from Legends Casino. It will feature works by young artists in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>.
The three-day event also includes a quick draw contest at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, an auction of quick draw paintings at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and a Lion's <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Club</ENAMEX> steak feed following at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="7">Soap box derby fun planned in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview
GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The fourth annual Grandview Soap Box Derby will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Sept. 11</TIMEX>, on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Euclid Street</ENAMEX> near <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Dykstra Park</ENAMEX>.
Reigstration of participants is now underway at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX> (303 W. Wine Country Rd.).
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>'s soap box derby will offer four divisions of competition—youth, adult, corporate wheels and the Celebrity 500, open to city and county officials. Cash prizes will be awarded to the top finishers in the adult division. Top finishers in the youth division will receive medals and savings bonds.
The sign-up fees are set at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> for youths ages 7 to 14 and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX> for all other competitors. The fees include the cost of a derby t-shirt. A parent signature is required at the time of registration for participants under the age of 18. The sign-up deadline is <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Sept. 1</TIMEX>. Late registrations will not be accepted.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Sultana Dancers performance set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - The Fraternal Order of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> lodge in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> will present a performance by the Sultana Dancers <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Saturday, Aug. 14</TIMEX>.
Described as mystical, exotic and alluring, the dancers will take to the stage at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 p.m.</TIMEX>
Preceding <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s show, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> lodge will host a chicken fried dinner, from 6 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6</NUMEX> per person.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>'s show is open to all <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX> members and their guests.
</P> 


 




<P ID="9"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

