


<P ID="1">'Doc' pushes <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> platform
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/20/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Congressman <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Richard</ENAMEX> "Doc" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> has been in the political arena for nearly three decades. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Last Friday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX>, noting that it was nice to talk to members of the local organization again, something he remembers doing for the first time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January 1975</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> talked to members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> about the Republican National Convention and the coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election, noting different races that will end up being important to the political party.
</P><P ID="6">   "We got a good bounce from the Republican National Convention," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> explained that he was surprised by just how much of a bounce, or increase in support, the Republican party saw after the national convention. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> noted that going into the convention and after seeing the minimal bounce in support the Democrats saw after their convention, he was sure that the electoral nation-wide was pretty well divided. He thought that was why the Democrats didn't see the bounce they typically do.
</P><P ID="8">   "But polls showed it was different," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   He said he thinks one of the reasons that Republican have seen growing support since the national convention is because of something President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George W. Bush</ENAMEX> said during his speech. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said he thinks the key was when <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> started talking about the country's future.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> then turned his attention to Democratic Presidential candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Kerry</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said the Democratic party, through <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>'s campaign, is trying to make the candidate into something he is not. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said, for example, the Democrats are the ones who decided to make <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>'s service in the Vietnam War an issue during the campaign.
</P><P ID="11">   "The fact he focuses on this...invites others to look at the facts," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> added that by focusing on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Vietnam</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX>'s team is turning attention away from something that is important - his voting record in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   "We all develop our records," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> explained. "When you start voting on things it should be a pretty good indication to exactly what you stand for."
</P><P ID="14">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said he feels that one of the reasons people are choosing to support <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerry</ENAMEX> is because people know what <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> stands for. "He's more steadfast," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> added that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is a state <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> is hoping to win in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> election, adding that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> will play a big part in making that happen.
</P><P ID="16">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> campaign is in the middle of starting grassroots efforts in battleground states, like <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, to ensure that Republicans get out and vote.
</P><P ID="17">   In other races across the state, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said Republican candidates are putting in a good showing. He noted that in the race between <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> is beginning to make gains in the polls while <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s numbers are beginning to plateau.
</P><P ID="18">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX> is working extremely hard," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="19">   In the race for governor, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said Republican candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dino Rossi</ENAMEX> is looking good against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Christine Gregoire</ENAMEX>. He said in a poll conducted by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rossi</ENAMEX> the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> before the primary election, he was within three points of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregoire</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   "That's very significant for a guy who's never run statewide," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="21">   In the end, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hastings</ENAMEX> told members of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> that in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> it's all going to come down to getting people out to vote.
</P>





 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




