
<P ID="1">Local wine industry has arrived
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Twenty years ago</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington winemaker Brian Carter</ENAMEX> had a hard time convincing <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Coast</ENAMEX> wine drinkers that grapes weren't being raised under umbrellas in the rainy part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pacific Northwest</ENAMEX>.   "We've come a long way," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX>, it is not unusual to see a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> premium Merlot or Chardonnay listed on a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York City</ENAMEX> restaurant wine list, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>, chief winemaker and vice president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Apex Winery</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guest</ENAMEX> speaker at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">morning</TIMEX> meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> said the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 20 years</TIMEX> of wine making in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> have been phenomenal.   When he began his career as a winemaker, there were only 2,000 acres dedicated to wine grapes in the state. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past year</TIMEX>, more than 29,000 acres are covered with rows of some of the best wine grapes grown anywhere in the world.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> told the club members that the production of wine grapes now ranks as the fourth largest crop in the state and contributes more than <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.4 billion</NUMEX> worth of business to the state.   "<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Today</TIMEX> there are more than 240 wineries scattered across the various growing regions of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX> said.   He said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> was the state's first designated wine growing region. "Now, we are seeing more areas applying to be named as regions, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Red Mountain</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Rattlesnake Hills</ENAMEX>," he explained.   "You can expect to see bottles of wines in the future with labels noting growing regions such as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Horse Heaven</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Royal Slope</ENAMEX>," he predicted.   Historically, wine grape have been grown in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state since it was a territory. Some of the earliest winemakers were from the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX>, including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Bridgman</ENAMEX>, who is honored by the Apex winery with a premium wine sporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bridgman</ENAMEX> label.   The industry dropped out of sight during the Prohibition era to resurface again in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1950s</TIMEX> as a minor force on the national market, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carter</ENAMEX>.   Since the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1960s</TIMEX>, the state's wine industry has enjoyed renewed growth.   "In the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> we are blessed with a desert climate which is favored by grapes," he explained.   "We are getting better at growing the grapes for wine, controlling the production of grapes, and adding new varieties, such as the Syrah and Viognier grapes which are proving popular among wine drinkers." he said.   "We are now faced with developing new marketing campaigns to attract the new wine drinkers," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

