
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High junior gold medalist at state science & engineering fair
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/8/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BREMERTON</ENAMEX> - A project on biofiltration of environmental pollutants earned <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Cornelius</ENAMEX> a gold medal at the annual Washington State Science and Engineering Fair, held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bremerton</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>.   As her prize, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelius</ENAMEX> earns an all-expense paid trip to the International Science and Engineering Fair to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 9-15</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce Stark</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> science teacher.   In addition, the young research scientist earned the Water Federation's Stockholm Junior Water Prize and an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evergreen College</ENAMEX> one-year tuition scholarship. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said of the 32 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> students eligible to compete at the state fair, 25 brought home state honors.   She said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> earned a state bronze medal for her project investigating the use of natural compounds to protect healthy cells from radiation during cancer treatments.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX>'s bronze medal made her an alternate for the all-expense paid trip to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Portland</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ore.</ENAMEX> "However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> already has a paid trip to International," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> earned her trip to the international science event as the grand prize winner at the Mid-Columbia Regional Science Fair held in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> explained.   In addition to her bronze medal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> senior, collected special honors from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX>, U.S. Navy and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Metric Association</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> also earned an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Evergreen College</ENAMEX> tuition scholarship and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Society</ENAMEX> - Optical Engineering award.   Earning first place honors at the state fair were Bootsma and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Halley Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, who was attending her first state science fair, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said.   "It was very exciting to see all of the students do well," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX>, who added she was especially proud of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>'s showing at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX>.   "She did very well for her first time" <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rodriguez</ENAMEX>, who presented a project focused on filtering mold and bacteria from the environment, also captured the attention of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> award judges.   "She also won the Intel Environmental Award," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, Bootsma also collected U.S. Navy honors, in addition to her first place medal for her inquiries into the effects of textile effluent on plant physiology.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> also praised sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Skyllar Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, who received second place honors at state. "This was his first year competing in science fairs and he showed a lot of potential for earning more awards," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gonzalez</ENAMEX> collected special recognition from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Society of Professional Engineers</ENAMEX> and the Yale Science and Engineering Fair Award.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Amber Gonzalez</ENAMEX> brought home second place honors in the high school division. Earning third place honors at the state event were sophomores <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Desiree Vasquez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Josefina Chavez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Addy Hernandez</ENAMEX>, and senior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias Wise</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX> also earned the Quality Control Award for his project.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> students also racked up a number of awards at the two-day state event. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> seventh graders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tony Louie</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Janelle Mendoza</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Megan Tyler</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hannah Seeger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Samantha Bridger</ENAMEX> collected first place honors at the state fair.   Earning second place awards in the seventh grade division were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tristan Abbott</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Levi Hagart</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> eighth grader <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenda Barrios</ENAMEX> also earned second place honors at state.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> middle school students earning third place honors were seventh graders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rubi Chavez</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Autumn</TIMEX> Hallaway, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chris Sambrano</ENAMEX> and Naomy Velasco, as well as eighth graders <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jessica Clements</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dacia Drollinger</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nicole Southern</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> said she was very proud of all of the students.   "There are a lot of up-and-coming science students ready to show their potential on the state level," she said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

