

<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/5/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">7/5?spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">cutline   Tim Graff</ENAMEX>/<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> pioneer <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruth Mottley</ENAMEX>'s daughter <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ann Whitney</ENAMEX> (kneeing), was on hand to in unveil a cement paver honoring her mother who was named as a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> Spirit of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> award winner during <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> "Come Back to the Country" <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> celebration. Also pictured are (L-R standing) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Councilmen George Greenway and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rick</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

