
<P ID="1">Entertainment Briefs
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
trioNorte to appearin concert <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb.</TIMEX> 24on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> stage
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Violinist Lenny Solomon</ENAMEX>, guitarist Bill Bridges and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">accordionist Sasha Luminsky—the</ENAMEX> three striking performers who make up the group trioNorte—will appear on stage in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Feb. 24</TIMEX>.
The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX> performance is part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> Community Concert Series. Doors to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> auditorium will open at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> that night. Individual tickets will be on sale that evening at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>. Series tickets will also be available at the door, priced at <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40</NUMEX> for adults, <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX> for students and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$85</NUMEX> for families.
Those who have series tickets will be able to attend all four concerts in the series: trioNorte on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 24</TIMEX>, Alborada on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 14</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overholt & Velta</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 4</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Scott Kirby</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 23</TIMEX>.
trioNorte specializes in several genres of music, including Spanish, tango tzigane, klezmer and jazz.
The relationship between the guitarist and violinist, Bridges and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>, goes back a number of years to their involvement in the unique ensemble Quintessence. The ensemble was a group based in Toronto, consisting of string quartet and guitar. Bridges and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> developed a great musical relationship during their stay with the group, and have continued their collaboration in trioNorte with the help of the brilliant Russian accordionist, Luminsky.
In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2000</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> and Bridges both showed up on a Klezmer "gig", and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX> was immediately impressed with the new accordion player on the scene.
"His talent as a natural klezmer musician surely shone through, but also it was his classical technique and ability to improvise that intrigued me," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>. "I remember thinking at the time that if I was to start a new project, surely (Luminsky) would be the perfect musician.
"Well, time went by and when I began thinking about trioNorte my first choices were (Bridges) and (Luminksy). I feel very lucky to be collaborating with such talented musicians," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Solomon</ENAMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">‘Vines & Wines’</ENAMEX> weekend setfor <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 28-29</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PATERSON</ENAMEX> - Columbia Crest Winery is reviving its wreath-making class at a "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Vines & Wines</ENAMEX>" weekend, set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 28-29</TIMEX>.
A wreath, swag and basket weekend is being offered during the height of the pruning season at Columbia Crest. Guest staff members, along with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nanette Stark</ENAMEX>, will demonstrate and help participants craft a wreath, swag or basket from freshly clipped vines. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stark</ENAMEX> has been teaching weaving for more than a dozen years, and she is a partner in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Prosser's Hang-Ups Gallery</ENAMEX>.
The fee for the <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> event is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15</NUMEX>, which includes instruction and materials. Pre-registration is not required. Those who participate are asked to bring gloves, a pair of pruners and whatever other items might be needed to craft their vine-based creation.
Tours of Columbia Crest Winery will also be offered during the day, along with wine tasting in the wine shop. The winery is located 26 miles south of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> on Highway 221.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rod</ENAMEX> run on tap
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Classic Knights Car Club</ENAMEX> will host a rod run/poker run on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 29</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.
The poker run will include stops at several local wineries. Also, there will be valve cover races, other games, door prizes and trophies for the winners.
The Grandview Fairgrounds will be the site of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 29</TIMEX> event. Those who want to participate are asked to pre-register, at the cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20</NUMEX>, by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 29</TIMEX> (882-2610). Same day registration will also be held from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> at the fairgrounds, at a cost of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25</NUMEX>.
</P> 
<P ID="6">Gospel music jamboree <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 15</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MABTON</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton Grace Brethren Church</ENAMEX> will again be the site of a Gospel music jamboree, this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Feb. 15</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX>
Several local musicians have already agreed to play, including <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heart Strings & Bill Lawson</ENAMEX>, Joyfull Noise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Doug Diamond</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Colson</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sue Plumlee</ENAMEX>.
The jamboree is open to any musician who wants to perform. Goodwill offerings will be accepted at the door.
</P> 
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Stern</ENAMEX> band to be at Jazz Alley in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early March</TIMEX>
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SEATTLE</ENAMEX> - Former Blood, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sweat & Tears</ENAMEX> guitarist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Stern</ENAMEX>, along with his all-star band, will appear at Dimitriou's Jazz Alley in Seattle <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, March 2-3</TIMEX>.
Following a stint with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Billy Cobham</ENAMEX>'s powerhouse fusion band in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1979</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'80</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">New York City</ENAMEX> and was recruited by Miles Davis, playing a key role in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Davis</ENAMEX>' celebrated comeback band of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1981</TIMEX>. During his three-year period with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> appeared on three recordings. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">From 1983 to '84</TIMEX> he toured with Jaco Pastorius' Word of Mouth band, and in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">'85</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> returned to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX>' line-up for a second tour of duty that lasted close to a year.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stern</ENAMEX> appeared with several bands after that, but it was his <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1993</TIMEX> release of "Standards (And Other Songs)" that led to him being named "Best Jazz Guitarist of the Year" by the readers and critics of Guitar Player magazine. He followed that up with two Grammy nominated releases.
For set times and ticket information, call (206) 441-9729.
</P> 
<P ID="8">Public invitedto enjoy the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">artsat Heritage College
TOPPENISH</ENAMEX> - Music, poetry and art will fill the senses <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next Tuesday</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Feb. 17-18</TIMEX>, on the Toppenish campus of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Helen Jewett Center</ENAMEX> on the Toppenish campus, the college will present a recital by its musical staff, with a special presentation by violinist <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathleen Ross</ENAMEX>, the president of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Heritage College</ENAMEX>. There will also be readings by poet Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Loren Schmidt</ENAMEX>, chair of the university's humanities program.
Numerous faculty members and artists will also display some of their works. A reception will follow in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Jewett Center</ENAMEX>.
<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, music, poetry and art will again be presented, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="9">Gold, gem & mineral showFeb. 28-29
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MONROE</ENAMEX> - The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Prospectors Mining Association</ENAMEX> will holds its ninth annual gold and mineral prospecting show at the Evergreen Fairgrounds in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Monroe</ENAMEX> the weekend of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Feb. 28-29</TIMEX>. Show hours will be from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX> and from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">4 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>.
Scheduled are a variety of exhibits, demonstrations and seminars, including how and where to find gold in rivers and streams, how to stake claims on public lands, how to pan for gold, how to use metal detectors and how to make your own gold prospecting equipment.
Admission to the show is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$4</NUMEX>, with children 13 and younger being admitted free.
</P> 
<P ID="10"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dordt College Concert Choir</ENAMEX> to perform locally
The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Dordt College Concert Choir</ENAMEX> is scheduled to perform a concert at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, March 19</TIMEX>.
The choir is performing as part of its spring tour. The group is scheduled to stage two performances in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, including the one at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX>. The school performance will take place during chapel, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX>
The <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 19</TIMEX>, the choir is scheduled to perform at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Reformed Church</ENAMEX>, at the corner of 16th Street and Franklin Avenue, beginning at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7:30 p.m.</TIMEX>
</P> 


 




<P ID="11"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

