
<P ID="1">Plan in place to monitor spread of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/21/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">PROSSER</ENAMEX> - Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rory Meyer</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal Plant Health Inspection Service</ENAMEX>, a division of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">United States Department of Agriculture</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USDA</ENAMEX>), was the featured speaker at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University Research Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> spoke about a testing program USDA has in place to test cattle for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>), better known as "Mad Cow" disease.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> had been a problem in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> for more than a decade, where the cattle supply was nearly annihilated. The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> problem came to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North America</ENAMEX> first hitting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">December 2001</TIMEX> when a cow in nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> was diagnosed with the disease.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> is a neurological disease in cattle. The disease is mainly passed in cattle by feed. However, the disease can also be passed genetically, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX>. Until bans were put into place on the type of feed that could be used, cattle were fed meat and bone meal to help provide the animals with needed protein and calcium.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> said the USDA and other agencies spent six to seven weeks investigating the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> case to ever hit the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> cow in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, which was exported from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, and the cow with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> found in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alberta</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Canada</ENAMEX>, at one time were kept within 50 to 100 miles of each other.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX>, though, said the risk is extremely low for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> to become a problem in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> like it was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX>. He cited a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2001</TIMEX> study done by <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harvard University</ENAMEX> that said with all the safety measures the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> has in place to prevent <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, the risk for the disease to spread like it did in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">England</ENAMEX> is extremely low.   "Even if we were to get it, with all the bans we have in place it should phase out," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX>.   But to help ensure consumer confidence and to find out where the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> situation stands in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">USDA</ENAMEX> has begun a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> testing program, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX>. The program will be overseen by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">APHIS</ENAMEX>) division within USDA. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> said the testing program will be across the country, lasting between 12 and 18 months.   The program began this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past June</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> said, and will be a one-time effort by USDA. The program is meant to see if <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> is present in the cattle industry and if so at what levels.   Under the program, USDA will assist cattle farmers with any cost of participating in the program. USDA officials will only be testing cattle in the high-risk population, meaning non-ambulatory cattle, cattle exhibiting signs of a central nervous disorder, cattle exhibiting signs associated with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> and dead cattle.   "If we are going to find them (cattle with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>), we are going to find them in that high-risk category," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> said the program will be targeting cattle older than 30 months. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> said the target age is older because cattle can carry the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> disease up to 90 months.   USDA will be working with officials at slaughter houses, farms and livestock auctions to find cattle in the high-risk population, as well as cattle farmers.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyer</ENAMEX> said there is also a tracking system for cattle that makes it easy to trace back where the animals came from.   Testing of animals will be done using <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">ELISA</ENAMEX>, which is a rapid screening test that gives officials quick results. USDA is working with various laboratories across the country, including in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state, to provide test results. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meyers</ENAMEX> said any inconclusive results will be double-checked at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Veterinary Services Laboratories</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iowa</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

