
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX> church gives graduates a warm send-off
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">BICKLETON</ENAMEX> - For the nine <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton High School</ENAMEX> seniors there is a lot of love and support surrounding them.   The class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> gathered with family and friends at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bickleton Presbyterian Church</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> for the senior baccalaureate.   A time of prayer and celebration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pastor Michael Clark</ENAMEX> addressed the seniors on finding "Absolute Truth."   Members of the church prayed individually for each of the graduates as they continue their journey away from the small community and make decisions that will affect their lives.   After a time of prayer, each student was presented a study <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said the graduates have an advantage growing up in a rural community and in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bickleton</ENAMEX>.   "This is a community that loves young people," he said. "Those prayers came from their heart."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said that the seniors' journey this far reminds him of flying.   "For a pilot many hours of study and preparation are logged before you even get to touch an airplane," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>.   He said a pilot then flys with an instructor for many hours before they're ready to fly solo.   "You seniors now are ready to solo," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>.   Although it can be intimidating, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said it is important.   "You will be the teachers and parents of future generations," he said.   Like in flying, some rules are fixed in life, such as the law of gravity.   "The truth is still the truth," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. "The world will tell you there is no absolute truth. That is a terrible lie and it is a lie that will rob you of life."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX> said there is absolute truth and it is found in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX>.   "There is no other book that has ever been written that claims to be the word of God," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. "It has stood the scrutiny of time."   He said that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX> is God's word and it is very important to know the truth.   "It will change how you live your life," he said.   The world is a beautiful place, but according to the Bible Satan is the prince of this world, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. He added that inside of each of us there is something the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bible</ENAMEX> calls a sin nature.   "Sometimes we think that people are our enemies, but they're not," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. "Our enemies are Satan, the world system and our own sin nature."   He said that we are constantly bombarded with the message of the world that says abundant life are found in money, possessions and other worldly pleasures, but he said true meaning and true fulfillment will only be found in the message of God.   "The way, the truth and abundant life are found in Jesus Christ," he said.   He said in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">John</ENAMEX> 14:6 <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> said he is the way, the truth and the life.   "He who has the son has life, but he who does not have the son does not have life," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>.   The only way to have abundant life, he said, is to invite <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> into our life as Savior and Lord.   "He will never leave or forsake you," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clark</ENAMEX>. "If you truly know <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX> you will know the way, the truth and the life.   "The choice is absolute truth, choose <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus</ENAMEX>," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

