
<P ID="1">17-year-old girl aces second hole at Black Rock Creek
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/22/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Maybe it was a case of one-upping her grandfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Rice</ENAMEX>. Or perhaps, it might have been that the lessons she's been taking from <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA</ENAMEX> club professional <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff Bender</ENAMEX> are quickly paying off. Then again, it's possible that her cousin, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Rice</ENAMEX>, may be the lucky charm that was responsible for it all.   However you figure it, 17-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime Kolb</ENAMEX> pulled off a rare accomplishment <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when she scored a hole-in-one on No. 2 at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s Black Rock Creek Golf Course.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Couer d'Alene High School</ENAMEX> student, who'll start her senior year this coming fall, just took up the game of golf this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past spring</TIMEX>. Although she is a resident of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Idaho</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolb</ENAMEX> is a regular visitor to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Up until a week or so ago, her parents owned and operated a mini-mart in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. She also has numerous relatives living here in the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.   It was three of those family members she was golfing with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> who can attest to the ace she collected on the 155-yard, par-3 second hole at Black Rock Creek. In <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolb</ENAMEX>'s foursome were her grandfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Rice</ENAMEX>, and her two cousins, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Trey Rice</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolb</ENAMEX> pulled out a 5-iron <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> when she arrived on the second tee block. The club, or more accurately, her swing, worked to perfection as the ball looped straight to the pin and bounded into the cup.   It was the first hole-in-one the second green at Black Rock Creek has ever yielded, since the hole was reconfigured from a par-4 to a par-3 <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three years ago</TIMEX>.   The physically fit, unassuming teen is really just a novice when it comes to playing golf. She didn't take an interest in the sport until this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past April</TIMEX>. But, as <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> illustrates, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kolb</ENAMEX> is a quick learner. She credits part of her game to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PGA</ENAMEX> club pro at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> course, from whom she has been taking lessons.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jaime</ENAMEX> has a lot of potential," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX>.   "She has a real strong swing, which makes it a lot of fun to coach," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bender</ENAMEX> added.   Some of her talent may have rubbed off from her father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dan Kolb</ENAMEX>, an avid golfer with whom she teamed this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Sunday</TIMEX> in a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Father's Day</TIMEX> tournament at Black Rock Creek.   "I wish I could have been in the group with her (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX>) to see it," said her father.   Any luck involved with <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX>'s feat?   Well ironically, it was the 17-year-old girl's cousin <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon</ENAMEX>, two years her senior, who was with their grandfather, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last year</TIMEX> when the elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rice</ENAMEX> picked up a hole-in-one at Black Rock Creek. Could be that a few more golfers may be trying to get the 19-year-old lucky charm to join their foursome.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

