
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> teen serves as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/21/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">OLYMPIA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> sophomore <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ashley Lara</ENAMEX> is serving as a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX> for Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Honeyford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX>, a 10th grader at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX>, is a member of the marketing club, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Key Club</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">International Club</ENAMEX> and her church's youth group. She is a varsity cheerleader and golfer, and is enrolled in martial arts classes.   However, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>, she is taking time away from her classroom studies and busy schedule to pursue other interests in history and politics.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> is one of 23 junior high and high school students serving as <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> pages as part of a week-long program that teaches students about state government.   As a page, she delivers mail, runs errands for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">senators</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> and she will have the opportunity to present the flag. Pages also go to page school, where they learn about the legislative process and its participants.   "It's giving me experiences that I wouldn't otherwise have," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX>. "Everyone should do it. It's a great opportunity."   As a sophomore, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> is considering entering politics and she feels the senate page program is "helping her decide whether [she] want[s] to be a senator."   She said she has liked meeting different people that influence our state, especially Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX>, who is sponsoring her as a page <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this week</TIMEX>.   "He is a very nice person that is easy to listen and talk to," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lara</ENAMEX> said.   "I enjoy meeting with the students participating in the program," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Honeyford</ENAMEX> said. "It's great that such a wonderful opportunity exists for them to take part in."   The senate page program is open to junior high and high school students. Those interested in being a page can go to the website http://www.leg.wa.gov/senate/sadm/senpage.htm.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

