
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> gridders clip <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eagles</ENAMEX>' wings
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">MABTON</ENAMEX> - Win and they're in. But lose this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> football team will have to hold its breath to see if it qualifies for the postseason.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">The Vikings</ENAMEX> are on the cusp of advancing to the playoffs thanks to this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX>'s dominating 53-8 victory over the Soap Lake Eagles. The win pushed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington</ENAMEX> 'B' <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">League</ENAMEX> record to 5-2.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> will close out the regular season on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX>'s home field this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX>'s playoff hopes are barely alive, meaning that they have to beat <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> and then hope for an upset or two from a couple of other teams in their league to advance.   The bottom line, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton Coach D.J</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX>, is that his Vikes need to knock off <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX> this coming <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday</TIMEX>.   "They'll be the best passing team we've faced this season," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said. "And, they're coming off a really big win against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Pateros</ENAMEX>."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> said his club won't do anything out of the ordinary to shut down <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Entiat</ENAMEX>'s prolific passing game.   "It will be assignment football as usual," he said. "We'll stick with our basic game plan."   That may serve the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> football team well. Especially considering what the Vikes did to visiting <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX> this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Friday</TIMEX>. Namely, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> limited <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX> to just 95 yards of total offense.   Offensively against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX> had their way with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX>. By the time the second quarter rolled around, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX> had already built a 33-0 lead. For the most part, the game was over.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Search</ENAMEX> substituted freely after the opening quarter, allowing all of his younger players to get playing time.   "Our younger kids got lots of varsity experience <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX>," he said.   Scoring-wise for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>, the Vikes' defensive unit was responsible for 8 of the 53 points. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Marco Pineda</ENAMEX> blocked a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX> punt in the first quarter and recovered the loose pigskin in the end zone for a touchdown, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jesus Diaz</ENAMEX> sacked <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Eagles</ENAMEX> quarterback in the end zone for a fourth quarter safety.   On the offensive side of the ball, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mabton</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alex Zavala</ENAMEX> ran in two TD's. The first came on a 12-yard burst and the second touchdown was a 43-yard breakaway run. Mabton QB Ryan Harris was responsible for two touchdowns, as well. He tossed a 36-yard scoring strike to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pablo Sanchez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris</ENAMEX>' only throw of the game, and he danced in from 14 yards out on a quarterback keeper. Scoring one touchdown apiece for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">the Vikings</ENAMEX>, all on runs, were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Eli Perez</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ray Elizondo</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ramon Castillo</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Zavala</ENAMEX> had the most carries in the game against <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Soap Lake</ENAMEX>, rushing the ball six times for 68 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sanchez</ENAMEX> added a 46-yard rushing effort on four totes.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

