
<P ID="1">Selection of new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> member to be open, public
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents have a little less than two weeks to submit their application to fill the vacant spot on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will be accepting applications from interested residents to fill the vacancy left by former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> until <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">5 p.m.</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Friday, July 23</TIMEX>.   Applications for the vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> position can be obtained at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> City Hall starting <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>).   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> made it clear at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting that the entire process of selecting a councilman will be open to the scrutiny of the public. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he felt it was important that the public know as much as they can about each of the applicants and who will be filling the vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> spot.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> members officially accepted the resignation of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, who operated the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX>/A&W, at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> was forced to immediately resign his <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> position after a management opportunity with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX>/A&W franchise in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Colorado Springs, Co.</ENAMEX> became available to him.   "I will be taking over a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">KFC</ENAMEX>/A&W there and help grow a depressed market they have had over the past few years," wrote <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> in a resignation letter to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. "Let me make it a point that I have felt honored to serve with you on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>. The experiences I have had, both good and bad, helped me grow personally and professionally."   "It is a great loss for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>. "He will be missed."   The basic requirements of applicants seeking the open seat are that residents must have lived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> for one year and be a registered voter. Applicants will also be asked to provide professional and/or personal references and a history of their education. Other information sought will include the applicant's employment history and answers to a series of questions, such as why the applicant wants to serve on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and what sort of experience and talent can the individual bring to the position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said applicants will be required to have the form notarized due in part to the fact background checks are not allowed to be done. All information submitted with the application will be made available to the public and the media, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>.   The mayor originally wanted to have the application deadline set for <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this Friday</TIMEX>, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> suggested extending the period based on the fact <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> has 90 days to fill the position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> also asked that the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>'s rules of procedure be handed out to each applicant so individuals know what is expected of them.   All interviews for the vacant <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> position will be conducted during open session, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he will talk with Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> to decide how much time should be dedicated to each interview. Both <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> and the public will have opportunities to ask questions of each applicant. The applicant will also be given a chance to showcase themselves during the interview. Following the interviews, which are all expected to take place at the same meeting, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> will convene into executive session and then make a decision on who to select to fill the vacant seat.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

