
<P ID="1">Obituaries
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/1/2004</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">NORA GONZALEZ
NORA GONZALEZ
Nora “Marlen” Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, 11, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> died <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday, Oct. 28, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harborview Medical Center</ENAMEX> in Seattle.
She was born on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 22, 1993</TIMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX>, the daughter of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nora</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Salinas</ENAMEX>) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Gonzalez</ENAMEX>. She was currently attending fifth grade at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  
She is survived by her parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar and Nora Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; one brother, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Oscar Gonzalez Jr.</ENAMEX>; two sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Leslie Brighit Gonzalez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ichnic Maria Gonzalez</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; her grandparents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria Guajardo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elizar Gonzalez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mattawa</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Francisco and Maria B. Salinas</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>; and aunts, uncles and cousins.  
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 1, 2004</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> with a Rosary to be recited at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">6 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mass</ENAMEX> of Christian Burial will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 2, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph Catholic Church</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, is in charge of arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">CECILO CRUZ
Cecilo Cruz</ENAMEX>, 95, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Oct. 27, 2004</TIMEX>, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 22, 1908</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Palafox</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Enriqueta</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hernandez</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX>. He received his early education in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Palafox</ENAMEX>. He migrated from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1951</TIMEX> and worked as a farm laborer, and later as foreman of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Broadview Farms</ENAMEX> until he retired at the age of 65.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cecilo</ENAMEX> was a loving father, grandpa and great-grandpa and enjoyed being with the children. He also enjoyed woodwork, yard work and just being outdoors.
He will always be missed and in the hearts of his three daughters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Irma Martinez</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandy Cavagnaro</ENAMEX> of Seattle and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gracie Bravo</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>; his three sons, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aurtio Cruz</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maria</ENAMEX>, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joe Cecil Cruz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Prosser</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Cruz</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. He is also survived by 18 grandchildren, 19 great-grandchildren and seven great-great-grandchildren.
Viewing for Mr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 1, 2004</TIMEX>, from 4 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX>
with a Rosary to be recited at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">7 p.m.</TIMEX> at Valley Hills Funeral Home Chapel, corner of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">North Ave.</ENAMEX> and 11th Street, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Viewing will also be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 2, 2004</TIMEX> from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> with a speaker, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Glen Steffin</ENAMEX>, at l p.m. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Graveside</ENAMEX> funeral services will follow at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2 p.m.</TIMEX> Valley Hills Funeral Home is entrusted with arrangements.
</P> 
<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">WILLEM HUBERS
Willem “Bill” Hubers</ENAMEX>, 73, of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> passed away <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Oct. 30, 2004</TIMEX>, at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Hospital</ENAMEX>.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> was born <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 15, 1931</TIMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX>, the son of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Adriana</ENAMEX> (Van de Graaf) and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cornelis Hubers</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> received his education and served in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Army</ENAMEX> in The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Netherlands</ENAMEX> before coming to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1954</TIMEX> to join his family. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> worked for various farmers in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> including <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Louis Syria</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harry Visser</ENAMEX>.
He enjoyed going to the coffee shop twice a day, playing cards and taking trips to the casino.  He cherished his nieces, nephews and time spent with family.
<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> is survived by three sisters, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Hubers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Adri Clapp</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Symina Meeker</ENAMEX>, all of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>; three nephews, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lawrence Meeker</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joyce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Clarence Meeker</ENAMEX> and wife, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pam</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Willard Meeker</ENAMEX>; five nieces, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elaine MacDougall</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jeff</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edie Graf</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jana Sall</ENAMEX> and husband, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paige</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Beth Clapp</ENAMEX>; six great-nieces; and two-great nephews.
He was preceded in death by his parents.
Viewing and visitation will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday, Nov. 2, 2004</TIMEX>, from 2 to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">8 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.  Funeral services will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday, Nov. 3, 2004</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wells Funeral Home</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Burial will be at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Memorial Gardens</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Those wishing to honor Bill’s memory may contribute to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Cancer Society</ENAMEX>.
</P>

 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

