
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> mariachi band to perform at local Cinco de Mayo fest
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">5/6/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">"You don't play <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Peter</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Paul</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary</ENAMEX> with an electric guitar," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> band teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Sleater</ENAMEX>, explaining that just like acoustic guitars are used to create a unique American folk music sound, a mixture of trumpets, violins and nylon stringed guitars create a sound unique to mariachi music.   For the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past two years</TIMEX> the school district has been offering a class in a different kind of music. It's mariachi music, a form of Mexican folk music with Swiss European um-pah influences.   "A lot of people think it came from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>, but that's just were it became popular," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>. Mexican culture has added its own flair to the music.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Two years ago</TIMEX> the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wenatchee High School</ENAMEX> mariachi band performed for students in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>. Just before spring registration, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Executive Director of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Community Resources Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX> suggested <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> try starting their own mariachi band.   With the encouragement of high school principal <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dennis Birr</ENAMEX>, the first time mariachi band was offered as an elective the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">fall of 2002</TIMEX>.   "We thought maybe we'd get a dozen kids," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>. "Well, 30 kids signed up."   With a full class of students, most of whom had never picked up an instrument, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX> had to look for someone who could help start the class off right. With 30 years of music education under his belt, he knew what a mariachi band was supposed to sound like, but had never taught a class in mariachi.   "We had kids, but we didn't have any instruments," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>.   With the help of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luis Constansio</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Texas Tech</ENAMEX>, the newly formed band learned the basics of playing and learned what really makes a mariachi band.   Although a mariachi band is normally seven people at the largest, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>'s band includes 36 students <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   "In the future it may take on a different look, but this is how it is for right now," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>.   Most of the time the musicians playing the music are also the singers, but <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX> has a separate set of singers to perform.   A mariachi band is characterized by the intermixing of guitars, violins, accordions, trumpets and occasionally a harp.   As the program develops the youths are becoming more familiar with the instruments.   "The kids know the songs," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>. "Since I don't speak Spanish I don't know what the words are saying, but we get a catalogue of the songs available and I go through it with the kids. They let me know what are good songs.   "We now understand we need to start a group in the middle school, so by the time they get to the high school they are veteran players," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>.   More than anything, the mariachi band has been a way to get students into the music program, who haven't been involved in the past.   "<NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">Ninety-five percent</NUMEX> of the kids in this program didn't come from band and they didn't come from choir," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX>. "We're just glad we can provide a musical opportunity for them, learning a type of music they like.   "It's great seeing the kids interested in learning music. When it's time to clean-up at the end of class they don't want to go. They say, one more song, one more song.   "It's been fun for me to learn a new style and new songs," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sleater</ENAMEX> added. "I find myself singing them all the time at home."   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> mariachi band, which just recently purchased new uniforms, will be performing at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Cinco de Mayo celebration <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, May 8</TIMEX>, at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>. They will be performing in Centennial Square.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

