<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> Announces <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Biotech Lab</ENAMEX> to Locate in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">02/02/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">ALDERWOOD</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> announced <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> that a new biotechnology laboratory will be built here that he believes will increase economic properity and development in the city, after a long period of financial drought.
</P>
<P ID="5">To coincide with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>'s announcement, he announced a private investment by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washen Foundation</ENAMEX> of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000,000</NUMEX> to startup "<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton Laboratories</ENAMEX>", to be named after the world-renowned biologist, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Philip Boynton</ENAMEX>.  Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX>, 85, arrived in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> and stood with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX>, mayor's aide <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laurie Sulfate</ENAMEX>, council members John Torch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jennie Angel</ENAMEX>, and Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> at the press conference in city hall.  <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> also announced <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$225,000</NUMEX> in matching funds from the state's new biotechnology initiative, and said he is working with the Washington State Legislature to secure an additional <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$300,000</NUMEX> for the lab, which is set to open <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>. 
</P>
<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX>, who just retired as the dean of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">College of Environment and Life Sciences</ENAMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">USC</ENAMEX> and himself an investor in the laboratory at a stake of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$25,000</NUMEX>, said a biotech lab in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state made considerable sense.  "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state has the infrastructure to become the nation's leader in biotechnology with it's wealth of universities, high tech companies, and existing scientific mind-share."
</P>
<P ID="7"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Boynton</ENAMEX> explained how the laboratory will focus on a problem area of acute interest to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state residents - mad cow disease. "Mad Cow Disease is the commonly used name for Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy, or <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX>, a slowly progressive, degenerative, fatal disease affecting the central nervous system of adult cattle.  There is a disease similar to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">BSE</ENAMEX> called <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Creutzfeldt-Jacob Disease</ENAMEX> that is found in people. A variant form of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJD</ENAMEX> is believed to be caused by eating contaminated beef products from BSE-affected cattle. To date, there have been 155 confirmed and probable cases of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CJD</ENAMEX> worldwide among the hundreds of thousands of people that may have consumed BSE-contaminated beef products.  We intend to be the laboratory that finds the cure for BSE..."
</P>
<P ID="8"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washen Foundation</ENAMEX> is a privately owned venture capital group known for its forays into high technology.  Reliable sources have reported that independently wealthy <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> is heavily vested in this organization, however <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> did not immediately return phone calls to confirm this.   
</P>   
   
   
   
<P ID="9">   Webmaster
</P><P ID="10">     Copyright 
</P><P ID="11">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="12">   , 
</P>   
   
   
