


<P ID="1">Consent items receive approval
</P>

 


<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/26/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> unanimously approved four consent agenda items, which don't warrant discussion before the voting takes place.
</P><P ID="4">   The consent items that were passed through included approving the minutes of the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 27</TIMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Oct. 6</TIMEX> meetings, approving a list of vouchers for payment in the amount of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$391,502</NUMEX> and approving a request by the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Legion</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">VFW</ENAMEX> to close Ninth Street, from Edison Avenue to Franklin Avenue, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10:30 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Nov. 11</TIMEX> for a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Veterans Day</TIMEX> observance.
</P><P ID="5">   One consent item that was on the agenda-a request by the chamber <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">of</ENAMEX> commerce for assistance with the annual lighted farm implement parade on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Dec.</TIMEX> 4-was pulled at the request of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>. He questioned the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$600</NUMEX> that will be spent in overtime pay for the police department to provide security at the event.
</P><P ID="6">   "Do we set a precedent when we charge for one parade and not another," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Seeger</ENAMEX> asked his peers.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Assistant City</ENAMEX> Manager/<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said it is his understanding that the policy has been that the city does not charge organizers of similar events for police security.
</P><P ID="8">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood Police</ENAMEX> Captain <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Bill Bank</ENAMEX> added that his department has typically absorbed the costs.
</P><P ID="9">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX>, without much fanfare, went on to unanimously approve the chamber's request for assistance.
</P>   
<P ID="10">   Beautification winners named
</P><P ID="11">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> congratulated the latest winners of the community beautification awards.
</P><P ID="12">   The awards are presented on a monthly basis to homeowners and merchants recognized for maintaining an attractive exterior at their respective home or business.
</P><P ID="13">   The latest award winners include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Juan</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martha Chavez</ENAMEX> for their home on Dennis Avenue, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX> and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Moore</ENAMEX> for their home on Olive Avenue, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Best Western Grape Vine Inn</ENAMEX>.
</P>   
<P ID="14">   Annexation proceedings OK'd
</P><P ID="15">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> unanimously approved annexation initiation proceedings by a large group of residents living in the area of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Saul</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">South Hill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Thornton</ENAMEX> roads.
</P><P ID="16">   The original annexation request came from four lot owners, but has since grown to include the owners of 27 lots or homes.
</P><P ID="17">   "This is one of the largest (annexation) petitions we've ever received," said Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="18">   The area in question is being proposed as a "mini ranchette" zone.
</P>   
<P ID="19">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman</ENAMEX> seeks <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Rock</ENAMEX> signage on I-82
</P><P ID="20">   Councilman John Torch <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX> formally asked city staff to look into what needs to be done to get <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Black Rock</ENAMEX> signage added to the exit 69 sign along I-82.
</P><P ID="21">   The signage, he said, would point out the exit that leads to both the proposed Black Rock Reservoir and Black Rock Creek Golf Course.
</P>   






 










<P ID="22">Webmaster
</P><P ID="23">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




