
<P ID="1"><TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> High grad tosses hat into <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> race
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/11/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">KENNEWICK</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brad Klippert</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Kennewick</ENAMEX>, a <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> graduate, has added his name into the hat as a conservative Republican candidate for the U.S. Senate race.   A self-proclaimed evangelical Christian, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX> hopes to defeat incumbent Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>, who is seeking her third term in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX>, a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Benton County</ENAMEX> sheriff's deputy, says he is putting his faith in God's will as he embarks on his campaign.   Saying it is imperative that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> maintain a strong national defense, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX>, a 17-year member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">National Guard</ENAMEX>, believes the rights of every American must be protected.   "I also strongly feel that each American should possess a strong sense of responsibility. Both in service to our nation as a whole and in personal responsibility for one's actions or the lack there of," he said.   A certified teacher with a Master's degree in teaching, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX> said he is supportive of the nation's teachers and in providing a good strong educational system.   A full time law enforcement officer and former paramedic firefighter, he is also supportive of public servants, safety and a justice system that protects citizens.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX>, the son of former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwoodrs Dewayne Klippert</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Klippert</ENAMEX>, said his career in law enforcement gives him a foundation to actively address national security issues and concerns. He said he will be tough on criminals and will pursue the enactment of legislation that supports strong sentences.   "Although we have the greatest government system in the world, ultimately I believe it's the American people that make <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">America</ENAMEX> great. I believe in hard working Americans like the American military, law enforcement officers, firefighters, teachers, farmers, construction workers, health service personnel and legal/justice personnel," he said.   An independent business owner, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX> said he also believes in free enterprise and the entrepreneur, and in the sanctity of human life.   "I believe that the United States of America is great, but I believe it can be greater," he said.   Saying many <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> residents are tired of politicians, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX> hopes to offer voters an alternative in this election.   "I believe they want leaders. Leaders who they know will do the right thing even in the face of adversity," he said.   "I am a God fearing, Bible believing, Ten Commandment honoring, evangelical Christian candidate," he explained.   "I am not ashamed of the gospel of Jesus Christ for it is the power of God unto salvation, to the individual and us as a nation," he said.   In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX>'s primary election, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Klippert</ENAMEX> will face fellow Republicans <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed Davis</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">William Chovil</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tacoma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chuck Jackson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Snohomish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gordon Pross</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ellensburg</ENAMEX> for a place on the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> General Election ballot.
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

