
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library gets thumbs-up from local voters
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/10/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library patrons won't have to retire their Yakima Regional Library System cards after all. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters approved the library annexation proposal with an overwhelming <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">77 percent</NUMEX> "yes" vote.   Friends of the Library, the group supporting the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library annexation into the regional system, are breathing a collective sigh of relief <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>. Had the vote gone the other way, city residents would not have been able to access the regional system.   "We are proud of the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> who voted in favor of the annexation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pat Kezele</ENAMEX>, who shared the chairmanship of the friends group with Bill Flower.   She said she was surprised at the low number of registered voters who actually voted on the matter. "But I'm glad the ones who did vote were in favor of the annexation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezele</ENAMEX> said.   According to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County Election Department</ENAMEX>, 673 of the city's 3,228 registered voters punched "yes" on their ballots, while 196 voters cast "no" votes.   Most of the ballots cast in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s election were cast via absentee ballot, with only 128 persons showing up at the two <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> polling places.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> voters cast 741 absentee ballots, which were mailed to voters in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">late February</TIMEX>.   "I think <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents couldn't imagine their community without the library services of the current standard," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezele</ENAMEX> said. "I sure couldn't."   "The "yes" vote shows they have their priorities set on learning and continuing education," she added.   "It's wonderful," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Saras</ENAMEX>, the long-time chair of the city-appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Public Library Board</ENAMEX>.   "But I wasn't worried," he said of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s vote.   "Our citizens know a good thing when they see it," he said.   The voters' approval of the merging with the regional library system means <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX> and his fellow board members will soon be out of a job.   He said the five local library board members were appointed by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> mayor to serve as an advisory board. With the annexation, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> library will become part of the regional system in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2005</TIMEX>. "Our library will be governed by the regional board," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saras</ENAMEX> explained.   Currently, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cloe Garrison</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melba Fujiura</ENAMEX> serve on the regional library board.   "We're thrilled that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Alderwoodrs</ENAMEX> voted in support of the annexation," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monica Weyhe</ENAMEX>, executive director of the regional library system. "It shows the community's support for the library and its value," she said. "   "It's great news," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mike Rinz</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s interim city manager.   "My hats off to the Friends of the Library and the local library board for their work and support of the annexation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kezele</ENAMEX> said the Friends of the Library began promoting the annexation vote immediately after the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February</TIMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> bond and levy vote.   "We didn't want to confuse voters with the two measures, especially when it came to increasing their property taxes," she explained.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX>'s annexation vote will raise taxpayers' property taxes by nearly 50¢ per <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$1,000</NUMEX> assessed valuation.   "It's a win-win situation for the residents," said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said he had no doubts the voters would vote in favor of the annexation. "The library is a pretty important asset to the community," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said even if the voters had chosen to turn down the annexation, he felt sure the city council wouldn't have abandoned the library.   "We would have found funds to retain the library services, somehow," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said.   "But with the voters' approval, the transfer of library services to the regional system frees up funds for other city projects," he said.   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

