
<P ID="1">'Atta boys' all around
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The late <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ginger Steffen</ENAMEX>, a long-time editor of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>, was fond of handing out praise to hard-working community volunteers which she termed "atta boys!"   She, like we at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX>, knew that sometimes the behind-the-scenes organizers of the wonderful events which are presented to the public in our community, never received their proper due.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This year</TIMEX>, we think she would agree that the organizers of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX>'s two days of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> festivities are overwhelmingly deserving of a whole boatload of "atta boys." We believe everyone connected with the events, from those responsible for setting up the soap box derby race course borders to the people picking up garage at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clem Senn Football Stadium</ENAMEX> all need an "atta boys."   So, if you see a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Young Life</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Kiwanis Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Lions Club</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Sunnyview VFW Post</ENAMEX> and auxiliaries, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, Bierlink Construction, Ace Hardware, The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>'s Market, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s Drive In, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> firemen, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rick Bruhn</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cinco de Mayo</ENAMEX> courts, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian High School</ENAMEX> cheerleaders and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Christian Reformed Church</ENAMEX>, please say "thank you" for making <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this past weekend</TIMEX> an old-fashioned, neighborly <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Independence Day</TIMEX> celebration.   And thank you to the community for coming out to support the events and help to contribute toward <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>'s <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Fourth of July</TIMEX> party.   Atta Boy, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

