


<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> students experience real life research, thanks to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Northwest</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> intern program
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2/5/2002</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Investigating the architectural intregity of the buildings on the 60-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford Reservation</ENAMEX> occupied <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elias Wise</ENAMEX>'s time for eight weeks <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last summer</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> senior worked along side a team of accredited scientists, who are working to refine the structural qualities of the buildings on the nation's nuclear reservation.
</P><P ID="6">   While <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wise</ENAMEX> was busy taking precise measurements of the foundations and corners of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Hanford</ENAMEX> buildings, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Iris Ruiz</ENAMEX> was doing research into pollution prevention with an eye on developing a plan for reducing waste at her high school.
</P><P ID="7">   Nearby, fellow <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> junior <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Burbidge</ENAMEX> was working with professional graphic designers and web designers, who put all of the research data into a readable form for the scientists.
</P><P ID="8">   All three youths took part in the Student Research Apprenticeship Program (SRAP), a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U.S. Department</ENAMEX> of Energy-funded project designed to provide research-based education for members of under represented ethnic groups.
</P><P ID="9">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kathy Feaster</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pacific Northwest National Laboratory</ENAMEX>, which oversees the apprenticeship program, SRAP takes high school students into the world of scientific research for a few weeks every <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> to give them on hands-on science and engineering experience.
</P><P ID="10">   While engaged in their research projects, the students earn a stipend of nearly <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$315</NUMEX> a week as part of their internship experience, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Feaster</ENAMEX> said. The students are given the opportunity to continue their research, working with a mentor throughout the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX>. In some cases the mentor and student continue their research during the school year, she said.
</P><P ID="11">   Students are allowed more than one <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> internship with the program, which also receives the support of the MESA (Math, Engineering Science Achievement) program, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruben Carrera</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> executive director of school and resources.
</P><P ID="12">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> said the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> has participated in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SRAP</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">MESA</ENAMEX> project for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past four years</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="13">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> said the district is currently working with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Cook</ENAMEX> of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University-Tri-Cities</ENAMEX> campus to enhance three careers paths at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>. In order to give <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX> students more exposure to math and science-based careers, Cook is working with the high school nursing, chemistry and biology departments, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> explained. Students in those programs are encouraged to take advantage of the internships, he said.
</P><P ID="14">   The SRAP internship program gives students an opportunity to apply their classroom knowledge to the real world, under the direction of professionals in those fields, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Carrera</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="15">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruiz</ENAMEX> hopes to bring her <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> experience into a practical application at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="16">   While researching ways to reduce garbage by recycling waste, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ruiz</ENAMEX> saw an opportunity to implement a pollution prevention plan at her school. She now plans to reapply for another <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> internship so she can create a workable plan for her prevention plan at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">AHS</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="17">   "I just want to put into action what I've learned," she said.
</P><P ID="18">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at
</P><P ID="19">   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jhart@hawkpress.com
</P>





 










<P ID="20">Webmaster
</P><P ID="21">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




