
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> looks for ways to spruce up downtown image
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/2/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">GRANDVIEW</ENAMEX> - Some downtown areas across the country are struggling for an identity, but the message brought before a sparse crowd <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> was the downtown area of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> isn't all that bad off as some might think.   A meeting was held <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> at the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> senior center to discuss ways to improve and build upon the downtown area.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gregg Dohrn</ENAMEX>, a planner with <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Wells & Stokes</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Bellevue</ENAMEX>, presented some of the information he gathered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX> about downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "We spent some time literally walking up and down the streets," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>. "We had the opportunity to listen and learn a lot."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said the one thing he learned from talking with residents and business owners is there are no shortage of ideas about how to improve the area.   "There are some things that distinguish <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> from other communities," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>.   In talking with people, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said a common theme heard was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> needs to establish its own identity, separate from other communities in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said one of the most valuable assets the community has is the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Valley Community College</ENAMEX> campus. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> especially liked an idea he heard of putting the city and college library services together as one. The downtown area in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> also has many wonderful buildings the community can use to its advantage, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>. Another plus is that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> has a distinctive, well-defined downtown area, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> also touched on some of the challenges facing <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "The appearance of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> is not bad, but does it have the appearance you want?" he asked of those in attendance.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said there are a number of older buildings in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> that need to be better maintained.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> heard from quite a few people about the challenges in establishing a business in the downtown area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> also reminded the audience while it is important to bring new business into the downtown area, it is equally as important to assist the existing businesses, which are already supporting the community.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said to help improve the downtown area in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> the community needs to pay attention to the small items that often get overlooked. One of the cases <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> pointed out was that it is very easy to drive past downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>. He suggested the community look at ways to improve signage that would let people know about and where the downtown area is in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> touched on four areas that are important to the revitalization of the downtown area. The first of which is activities. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said more activities need to take place in the downtown area to attract people to what is being offered. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> suggested bringing some of the existing events in the community to the downtown area, such as the annual 3-on-3 basketball tournament. He also suggested having a car show or some sort of community concert at Stokely Square. There was also talk of having a night set aside where the community can turn out to see a movie.   "Think about your audience," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>.   Another important area to address is the appearance of the downtown.   "Think about things that make it a more attractive place," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>.   Some of the suggestions tossed around included improving the appearance of downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> by placing benches where people can sit, widening sidewalks and planting trees.   One area <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> suggested the community doesn't spend that much time dwelling on is the issue of the color of buildings in downtown. He said the community shouldn't spend their time arguing about the color of a building when there are more pressing issues to address.   As far as supporting the development and growth of businesses, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> suggested having the more experienced business owners in the community work with new business owners. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said some of the most successful companies in the state are in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> and the community should be taking advantage of the owners' knowledge.   The community has already made great strides in working to connect its downtown to people traveling along Interstate 82. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said one of the more crucial improvements <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> has made was getting rid of the bridge that used to hang above <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wine Country Road</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said that has greatly improved the aesthetics of the area. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> has also down a nice job of improving its entrances into <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> should find a way to build on the prominent wine tourism industry. He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> should take advantage of being the site of the first winery Chateau Ste. Michelle established. He also said the new YVCC expansion into the former Safeway building in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> will be a welcomed addition. He felt the city should find a way to build upon the viticulture classes that will be taught at the college.   "That is going to put you on the wine map," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX> also suggested taking advantage of the rich agricultural history in the area, tossing around the idea of a farmer's market.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX> President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Herriman</ENAMEX> said he wanted the community to be known as the friendliest in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>. He felt that is something that could make everyone proud. He also wanted to encourage everyone to shop in downtown <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> because it will benefit the community even more. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX> encouraged more people in the community to turn out and volunteer.   "If we want to see these things happen, we ourselves need to get involved," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Herriman</ENAMEX>.   A number of different suggestions were thrown around by audience members, including encouraging RV owners to utilize the fairgrounds. Another suggestion was that the library and the parks and recreation department stop increasing rates for out-of-town residents, to attract more people to the community.   "There are no simple solutions or simple answers," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dohrn</ENAMEX>. "It is going to take the (idea) that a few small things can add up.   "One of the things <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> has going for it is when you put your mind to (do something), it gets done."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

