
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> drop-out rates improving
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/27/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">With all of the efforts being made to keep kids in schools, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> is seeing a decline in the number of students who leave school. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">This past year</TIMEX> of the 1,347 students who started the 2003-04 school year at the high school, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">8.6 percent</NUMEX> dropped out.   "But that is not to say those students didn't end up deciding to continue their education further down the line," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gary Vegar</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX>'s director of curriculum and learning.   He said the state definition of a dropout refers to those students who leave school failing to graduate with their peers. "Many of the students will continue their education in some other fashion," he said.   For example, some students will return to school at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX>, the district's alternative school, and others will elect to earn their <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GED</ENAMEX>, he explained.   "I think schools are doing a better job of keeping kids in school by offering more support programs, which meet the needs of the non-traditional students.   "For those who don't work well in the regular classroom, we are offering a variety of alternative education and mentoring programs to help them to succeed," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> figures reflect the declining state public high school dropout rate, according to figures issued from the state <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Office</ENAMEX> of the Superintendent of Public Instruction.   The estimated high school drop-out rate for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> public schools students declined <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">6.7 percent</NUMEX> during the 2002-03 school year, down a full percentage point from 2001-02.   However, the reduction in the number of dropouts leaving school without a diploma doesn't show a higher number of in graduation rates. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said that is understandable.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said the state judges the drop-out rate on the total number of students who drop out of school between the ninth and 12 grades, who don't end up graduating on time within the four-year time line.   For some kids, earning that coveted high school diploma in four years is just taking longer, he said.   A number of factors play into the disparity. "For example, some teens drop out to work or have babies, only to return to school several months or <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> to resume their education. One area where the percentage rates are higher for dropout rates is at the state's alternative high schools."   For example, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> shows <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">45.3 percent</NUMEX> dropout rates, based on its 2003-04 school enrollment of 158 students.   But here again the annual dropout rate doesn't show the number of students who may have elected to return to school to complete their education, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> said.   In nearby <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX>, the dropout rate was listed at zero for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past year</TIMEX>, while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> reportedly had 50 students drop out of school, using the state formula.   According to the OSPI figures, an estimated <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">65.7 percent</NUMEX> of the state's students graduated on time in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX>, while another <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">10 percent</NUMEX> remained enrolled to continue working toward their diploma.   The estimated cumulative dropout rate for the state class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2003</TIMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">24.3 percent</NUMEX>. However, about half of those students termed as dropouts were students who could not be tracked after leaving school and had not yet earned a diploma.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vegar</ENAMEX> believes the actual number of students graduating is better than the state's figures. "We just need a better way to track those students who return to earn their diplomas through other programs," he said.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

