
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Forum</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">7/14/2003</TIMEX>
</P>
<P ID="3">1-Column
Pet population
We were reading your newspaper at work, at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Grandview</ENAMEX>, and we noticed the ad for a lost boxer with a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> tag. We researched the issue and found that the person had moved. When we finally found her phone number, we gave her a call thinking she would be elated to find her lost pet. Unfortunately, she had no interest in the dog.
Luckily, the caring person who rescued Princess had already lined up a new home.
I just want to personally extend a heartfelt thank you to the lady who saved Princess and cared enough to not only try and find the owner, but also find her a new home. This is just a reminder to please help control the pet population and have your pets spayed or neutered, to avoid having any unwanted pets.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tammy Everts</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="4">Congratulationsto new fire chief
My warmest congratulations to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian Vogel</ENAMEX> on becoming the new fire chief for <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County Fire District</ENAMEX> #5.
Before I moved away I was fortunate enough to work with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX> as a fire dispatcher for five years. I always found him to be extremely dedicated, knowledgeable and professional...even during times of great pressure and stress.
The citizens living in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Fire District</ENAMEX> #5 can be very proud of their new chief. Way to go, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brian</ENAMEX>!
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lauri</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Holden</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Taggart</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="5">Soapbox derbya great success
The sixth annual soapbox derby held at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Park</ENAMEX> on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, July 3</TIMEX>, was a great success, with many spectators and fans cheering on the 35 competitors.
We want to say "thank you" to the following sponsors for their support of the soapbox derby and encourage all to patronize them whenever possible for their support and dedication to this community: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob</ENAMEX>'s Auto Clinic, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">John Torch and Associates</ENAMEX>, Valley Truck Repair, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White & Company</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ace Hardware</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Inn B&B</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Daily News</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s police, fire and public works departments. They all donated money and time and/or materials, which enabled the soapbox derby to be a success.
We also want to thank all the following volunteers who contributed so much time and effort to enable the program to run smoothly and successfully: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Seeger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Greenway</ENAMEX>, John Torch, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill Underwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Warren</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Laura Berkompas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brooks Salazar</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jerry Paeschke</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Edgar Martinez</ENAMEX>, Luigi Rosal, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jason Aguirre</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Matt Shauers</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kurtis Bierlink</ENAMEX>, Elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cano</ENAMEX>, Elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brown</ENAMEX>, Elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kerrigan</ENAMEX>, Elder <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Welker</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Chad Werkhoven</ENAMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Chamber of Commerce</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Stanton</ENAMEX> and the fire department, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ted Mana</ENAMEX> and the police department, and any others that we may have forgotten to mention. Thank you very much!
<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Parks and Recreation is proud to offer such a successful community event.
/s/ <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Stiles</ENAMEX>, Director, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Dept.</ENAMEX>; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joan Niemeyer</ENAMEX>, assistant
</P> 


 




<P ID="6"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

