
<P ID="1">Car purchases still under review
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/4/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">The purchase of two Toyotas for the Migrant Student Record Systems (MSRS) program is still on hold, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>.   Currently, the purchase of the two vehicles, which was approved by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School Board</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last week</TIMEX>, is under review by the state auditor and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> legal council.   "We just <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">today</TIMEX> (<TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX>) spent an hour on it with legal counsel," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   Called into question was the purchase of two Toyotas, although the price of the vehicles were not the lowest bid in the bid process.   The bid from Toyota of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$20,195</NUMEX> per vehicle. The price quoted to the school district for comparable Fords from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Denchel Ford</ENAMEX> was <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$14,212</NUMEX> each. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harris Ford</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lynwood</ENAMEX> submitted a bid for <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$13,429</NUMEX> for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Ford</ENAMEX> made vehicles.   "There's not going to be any movement on this," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>, who anticipates putting a special line item in the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">March 10</TIMEX> school board meeting to discuss the purchase of the vehicles.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said the school board will have to be updated on the issues, which has the school district purchasing the vehicles on behalf of the MSRS, a grant-funded program.   If a hold had not been placed on the vehicle purchase, the two new vehicles would have been delivered <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">earlier this week</TIMEX>.   
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

