
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">GOP</ENAMEX> challenger for U.S. Senate seat makes campaign stop in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">8/2/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Questions about veterans benefits, renewal energy sources, immigration laws and even voter registration were levied at U.S. Senate candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, who made <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> a part of his campaign trail <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, who broke a 134- year-old Democratic-controlled 5th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> record by unseating then <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Majority Speaker <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Foley</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Spokane</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>, now has his eye on <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senatorial</ENAMEX> chair.   Joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Club</ENAMEX> for a breakfast meeting at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Alderwood's Sunny Spot Restaurant</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> drank coffee with a roomful of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Republicans, answering their questions while seeking their support in his bid to unseat the two-term Democratic senator.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saying Murray</ENAMEX> seems bent on voting "no" on everything passed out of the U.S. House of Representatives, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he wants to help change the balance of power in the Democrat-controlled <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.   "The Democrats in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seem determined to stop dead anything coming out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX>, whether it is welfare reform, defense spending or medical reform," he said.   He said beating <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX> could help turn the tide.   "The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> has adopted an attitude of obstruction," he said.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> is one of the reasons all of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> bills drop dead in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>," he added.   "I decided to seek her seat partly because I want to break the gridlock and to get measures passed that will benefit our nation, and state, by creating legal reform, strengthening Social Security and improving benefits to our veterans," he told the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> club.   In seeking the support of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> group, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> urged the grassroots Republicans to volunteer to help get out the vote.   "Put up yard signs and help get me elected so I can break the standstill," said the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Spokane</ENAMEX> native, who has served in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past 10 years</TIMEX>.   If elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> will be the first <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Eastern Washington</ENAMEX> senator the state has had serving in the nation's capital in 80 years. Saying he would like to see Republicans voted in from the governor's mansion to the presidency, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> urged local Republicans to aid in getting the party ticket approved.   "This is a good year to be running," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said. "Our ideas are right and it galls me that President (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bush</ENAMEX> and Vice President (<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Dick</ENAMEX>) <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cheney</ENAMEX> are being cut by the other side. They are fine, good, decent men and I'm proud to be running with them," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Congressman, he has supported veterans issues and will continue to do so.   "I have two people on my staff who do nothing but handle veterans issues, from helping the veterans get their medals to medical benefits. I will continue to do that," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said.   Saying he knows the importance of agriculture in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he will continue to work for the best interests of farmers while in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>.   Medical reform is a big part of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s campaign to get elected. In the past couple of years, more than 350 doctors have left <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state, he said. He said the reason is because <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s medical liability insurance premiums are so high and "because our reimbursement rates are so low.   "I've talked with doctors wanting to retire who can't get replacements for their practices. That is something that must change," he said.   He said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> has repeatedly voted to increase taxes, block welfare reform and changes in bankruptcy laws, issues <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said the Republicans have tried unsuccessfully to address and improve. "We have to make a change," he said.   "We have to continue to provide for the national defense and for all of the issues before our nation," he said.   Asked if he backs the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Central Washington Black Rock Reservoir</ENAMEX> project, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he is a believer in making wise use of the region's water resources. "Black Rock Reservoir makes sense. We just have to find a way to fund it," he said.   Before getting to the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> must get through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state primary, where he is facing four other candidates who are also seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat. Recently, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> received both the state and national <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Republican Party</ENAMEX>'s approval as a senatorial candidate.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>'s backers said he has the best shot at taking the seat away from the senator once called the mom in tennis shoes.   "I had a nine and half point approval rate in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May</TIMEX>," he said. "And my staff tells me I need a 10 point approval rate by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">September</TIMEX> to win," he added.   "But only <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">50 percent</NUMEX> of the people in the state know me right now," he said, adding that he feels once people get to know him is he is confident he can win.   "It's a very competitive race," he added.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

