


<P ID="1">Former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hughes</ENAMEX> recovering from heart surgery
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/15/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Long-time <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident and former <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hughes</ENAMEX> is recovering nicely following heart surgery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago</TIMEX>, according to a family member.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> was hospitalized while visiting his wife <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mercer Island</ENAMEX> relatives, following a heart attack in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">early September</TIMEX>, according to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX>' sister, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barbara Atherton</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> is now recovering at a Redmond convalescent center and is expected to return home to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> in the near future, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atherton</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="7">   She said her brother had been visiting relatives on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mercer Island</ENAMEX> when he was taken to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Overlake Hospital</ENAMEX>. His surgery was delayed when he became ill with pneumonia.
</P><P ID="8">   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don</ENAMEX> underwent bypass surgery <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a week ago Tuesday</TIMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Atherton</ENAMEX> said. "He is now doing very well," she said.
</P><P ID="9">   People interested in sending cards or notes to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hughes</ENAMEX> may mail them to <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">June</TIMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Don Hughes</ENAMEX>, care of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vincent Kretz</ENAMEX>, 3617 74th Ave. S.E. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mercer Island</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Wa</ENAMEX>. 98040.
</P>





 










<P ID="10">Webmaster
</P><P ID="11">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




