
<P ID="1">Masters of Mexican Music to take the stage at the Capitol
</P> 
<P ID="2">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/29/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="3"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - The sounds of traditional Mexican music will fill the halls of the Capitol Theatre <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next weekend</TIMEX>, as the Masters of Mexican Music bring the sounds of mariachi, marimba and tejano music to the stage.   The Masters of Mexican Music is a collaboration of accomplished artists. In its first national tour, Masters of Mexican Music immerses audiences in the rich musical tradition of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. The performances include <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariachi Los Camperos de Nati Cano</ENAMEX>, which will bring mariachi music to the stage; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Gutierrez y Los Hermanos Ochoa</ENAMEX>, who will perform musica jarocha style music; <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mingo Saldivar y Los Cuatro Espadas</ENAMEX>, who will perform conjunto tejano music; and Marimba Chiapas, which will perform traditional marimba-style music.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariachi Los Camperos de Nati Cano</ENAMEX> is a group led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Natividad Cano</ENAMEX>, who was born into a family of mariachi musicians in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Ahuisculco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Jalisco</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1933</TIMEX>. It wasn't until he moved to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Los Angeles</ENAMEX> that he founded the group <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Los Camperos</ENAMEX>, which he has been directing for more than 40 years. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1990</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cano</ENAMEX> was honored by the National Endowment for the Arts with the National Heritage Fellowship and he has had the honor of performing for two presidents at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">White House</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Gutierrez y Los Hermanos Ochoa</ENAMEX> is a group led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Gutierrez Ramun</ENAMEX>, who was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Costa de la Palma</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX>. He spent his childhood listening to his grandfather, father and uncles play music for enjoyment after a hard day's work. As a small child he took up the guitar and soon learned to play the jarana, a thin-bodied guitar that provides the rhythmic and harmonic base for jarocha music.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mingo Saldivar y Los Cuatro Espadas</ENAMEX> is a group from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Antonio</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX>. The leader of the group, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saldivar</ENAMEX>, was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Marion</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Texas</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1936</TIMEX> and learned to play the guitar by the age of 12. It wasn't too long after taking up the guitar that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saldivar</ENAMEX> learned to play the stand-up base and <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">a year later</TIMEX> he took up the accordion. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2002</TIMEX>, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">San Antonio</ENAMEX> inducted <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Saldivar</ENAMEX> into the Conjunto Music Hall of Fame. Several weeks later he was named a National Endowment of the Arts National Heritage Fellow and later in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2002</TIMEX> he received his second Grammy nomination.   Marimba Chiapas is a group led by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lorenzo Cruz</ENAMEX>, who was born in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Tonal</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Chiapas</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mexico</ENAMEX> in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1928</TIMEX>. He was taught to play the marimba by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Felipe Peoa</ENAMEX>. A marimba is constructed similarly to the xylophone and is often referred to as the "Mexican piano." In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1973</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Cruz</ENAMEX> moved to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX>, where he has continued to sustain the Mexican tradition of marimba music.   Although the musical troupe that makes up the Masters of Mexican Music will perform <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday, Nov. 7</TIMEX>, at the Capitol Theatre, they will be in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley</ENAMEX> for three days performing at different locations. <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, Nov. 6</TIMEX>, the troupe will perform at various outreach locations in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX>, including a free performance at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">2:30 p.m.</TIMEX> at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">St. Joseph's Catholic Church</ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>. Later that night <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jose Gutierrez y Los Hermanos Ochoa</ENAMEX> will perform at Radio KDNA's 25th anniversary celebration at the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima Convention Center</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday, Nov. 8</TIMEX>, Marimba Chiapas will work with students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Granger High School</ENAMEX> at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">9:30 a.m.</TIMEX> At <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">1 p.m.</TIMEX> the same day <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mariachi Los Camperos de Nati Cano</ENAMEX> will work with students at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX>.   <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sunday</TIMEX>'s performance at the Capitol Theatre is scheduled to take place at <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">3 p.m.</TIMEX> Tickets for the Masters of Mexican Music are currently on sale through the Capitol Theatre box office at (509) 853-ARTS and through radio KDNA in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Granger</ENAMEX> at (509) 854-1900. Tickets for the event range in price from <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY"><NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$30</NUMEX></NUMEX>.   .
</P>

 




<P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

