


<P ID="1">U.S. Senate candidate stumps for votes in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/17/2004</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">On a two-day campaign across <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state, U.S. Senate candidate <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX> took time to speak to a group of supporters at the Darigold plant in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, a Republican <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> congressman who hails from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Spokane</ENAMEX>, will be facing incumbent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX> in the general election in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">November</TIMEX>.
</P><P ID="6">   Although they are running for the same position, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said there is no doubt that he and Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> have different ideas about how the nation should be run.
</P><P ID="7">   He said that looking at Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s voting record there is a history of voting for higher taxes. He added that she has voted 282 times to raise taxes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> added that he has consistently supported lowering taxes.
</P><P ID="8">   "That's the right thing to do," he said.
</P><P ID="9">   "She thinks government creates a strong economy. I believe small business builds a strong economy," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> told his <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> supporters.
</P><P ID="10">   He added that <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s voting record taxes people at all walks of life.
</P><P ID="11">   "She didn't want to give parents a child tax credit," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="12">   He added that she wanted first-time taxpayers to pay more, and was also in favor of hirer business taxes, and an increase in taxes for retired people and senior citizens drawing social security.
</P><P ID="13">   "I believe we should have permanent tax relief," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="14">   He said <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX> because of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s voting the average family of four earning <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$40,000</NUMEX> should expect to pay an increase of <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$940</NUMEX> in taxes. He added that the relief giving tax credit to married couples, which Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> doesn't support, is set to expire, which means that non-married couples living together will pay less in taxes than married couples.
</P><P ID="15">   "These are bad judgments by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   On the issue of homeland security, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said that Sen. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX> believes that the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> is the first line of defense.
</P><P ID="17">   "I know that the last line of defense is our homeland," he said, adding that he feels it is important to fight terrorism where it's at.
</P><P ID="18">   He added that the senator has repeatedly voted to weaken the country's military, first by promising <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12 years ago</TIMEX> to cut <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$100 billion</NUMEX> out of the defense budget.
</P><P ID="19">   "'She also voted to cut <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$6 billion</NUMEX> out of the intelligence budget just before <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Sept. 11</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, who flew to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington D.C</ENAMEX>. this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> to vote 'yes' on torte reform, only to fly back to the state <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Tuesday</TIMEX> for the primary election, said that his opponent won't vote for torte reform, essentially choosing trial lawyers over patients.
</P><P ID="21">   "She won't vote for any medical liability referendum," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he is willing to put his voting record up against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s anytime and that he has invited the Senator to debate in every county in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state.
</P><P ID="23">   "The best way to see what people believe is through a debate," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>. "She won't debate."
</P>





 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




