


<P ID="1">New home approved for Eighth Street
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/1/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">The <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX> approved the construction of a new home on the corner of Eighth Street and Grant Avenue.
</P><P ID="5">   The stick-built house will be constructed on a vacant lot that is located within the city's B-3, retail core zone.
</P><P ID="6">   According to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>, using the lot for the construction of a home fits into the neighborhood's use, which is residential.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> said at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Planning Commission</ENAMEX> level there is talk of changing the B-3 zone to allow residential housing, but as of now a conditional use permit is required in the zoning.
</P><P ID="8">   In the staff report prepared by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>, he said expansion of the commercial core into the neighborhood where the home will be located is "doubtful."
</P><P ID="9">   Following staff recommendations, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Board of Adjustment</ENAMEX> members unanimously voted to approve the construction of the single-family residence.
</P><P ID="10">   As part of the permit, applicant <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Thomas Flood</ENAMEX> will have to provide a site plan prior to the start of construction. He will also be required to complete landscaping and property improvements, including replacing the existing sidewalk along Grant Avenue. New curb and gutter will be required of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Flood</ENAMEX>, as will a road patch from the street to the curb and gutter, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="11">   The home will also be required to comply with R-1 zoning setbacks for a corner lot, which is 20-feet from the front yard facing Grant Avenue and Eighth Street. Off-street parking, building height and building code requirements must also be met.
</P>   
<P ID="12">   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail mbrowning@hawkpress.com
</P>   






 










<P ID="13">Webmaster
</P><P ID="14">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




