
<P ID="1">Local woman to teach floral design class
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Melissa Browning</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">3/17/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Swindell</ENAMEX> believes that flowers are not just for special occasions, but are for everyday living.   As a child she remembers her mother's garden and the flowers that bloomed.   "In my mother's garden there were rows of Zinnias, marigolds and nectaroscordum," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX>. "It was my job to go out and cut flowers."   With an endless supply of fresh-cut flowers there were bouquets in every room, filling the house with life and color.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX> hopes to pass her love of flowers on to local gardeners looking for a way to bring the beauty of the outdoors into their homes. She is teaching a floral design class through the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>.   "I hope to teach people the basics of flower design and about the different kinds of arrangements they can make," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX>. She wants to teach her students how to make an English bouquet, which is a gathering of different kinds of flowers.   She also plans to teach students how to make structured bouquets and something appropriate for a dinner party.   Although class participants are encouraged to bring flowers from their gardens, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX> said they may have to supplement with flowers from different floral departments.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX> said a common misconception is that lots of flowers are needed for a bouquet.   "Often times it takes very few flowers to make a dramatic bouquet," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX>, adding that vases don't have to be detailed to make a beautiful bouquet.   Another mistake people make when making floral arrangements is not having a general design idea they are trying to achieve when they begin. She added that table centerpieces are often too big and hinder conversation rather than enhance it.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX> began working with floral design in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1975</TIMEX> when she started decorating for the annual Medical Ball that used to be held in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "One spring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Maynard</ENAMEX> (Huenefeld) asked me if I wanted to come in and do some work," she said. "I learned floral design from them."   As the Huenefelds became more interested in propagating grapes, mint and hops, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX> took over more of the floral aspects of the business.   "I've done flowers for weddings and I do the flowers for the church," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX>, who attends <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Holy Trinity Episcopal Church</ENAMEX>.   She said during the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">summer</TIMEX> months, she uses roses in the church's rose garden in floral displays.   "To see a beautiful rose that's opened naturally, is exquisite," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX>.   "I want to teach people how to use flowers," she said. "Most flowers should blend in."   She added that it's also important for people to know when a floral project is finished.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Swindell</ENAMEX>'s class is sponsored by the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>.   The class will be held <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday, April 3</TIMEX>, from <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">10 a.m.</TIMEX> to <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">noon</TIMEX>. The cost to attend is <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$5</NUMEX> for in-city residents and <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$7.50</NUMEX> for non-city participants. For more information on the class contact the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Parks and Recreation Department</ENAMEX>, 837-8660. The class is limited to 15 students.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

