


<P ID="1">Challenger for U.S. Senate seat makes short visit to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P>

<P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/9/2003</TIMEX>
</P>

<P ID="4">Creating jobs, working to improve health care and ensuring that young people receive a good education are all things that are important to <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">U. S.</ENAMEX> Representative <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, the Republican candidate who is running for the U.S. Senate against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Democrat Patty Murray</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="5">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, who currently represents <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s 5th <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Congressional District</ENAMEX>, <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Thursday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">afternoon</TIMEX> said that he believes giving a child a good education means giving them a good chance at life. He noted that if a child receives a good education, then a good job is soon to follow.
</P><P ID="6">   The lawmaker was in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">yesterday</TIMEX> to present a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> flag to city officials for use at the new community center.
</P><P ID="7">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he wants to be a leader when it comes to improving the job market and economy of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="8">   "This is the number one issue facing the people of our state," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="9">   He said in recent years <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> has not been well led in the U.S. Senate, which has led the state to fall behind the rest of the country in terms of its economy.
</P><P ID="10">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said another issue facing the people of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is health care. He noted that <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> is one of 19 states that is currently in a health care crisis. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he wants to help ensure that all young people have access to health care.
</P><P ID="11">   "I will fight really hard to aid the health care needs of all people," he said.
</P><P ID="12">   When it comes to the budget and national spending, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he has been a part of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX> that worked to balance the budget for four years in a row. He said he also worked to reduce spending and cut the deficit.
</P><P ID="13">   "I have a proud record of fiscal conservatism," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="14">   However, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> added that you can't look blindly at the country's deficit. He said over the past several years the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">United States</ENAMEX> has had to spend money on national defense.
</P><P ID="15">   "We have to do these things," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="16">   When it comes to the war in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Iraq</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he supports President <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Bush</ENAMEX>'s actions.
</P><P ID="17">   "I believe it's necessary for the protection and security of the world and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said.
</P><P ID="18">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> isn't the only Republican seeking <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Murray</ENAMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Senate</ENAMEX> seat. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Reed Davis</ENAMEX>, an associate professor at <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Seattle Pacific University</ENAMEX>, is also running for the position. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said what separates him from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Davis</ENAMEX> is he has the support of organizations like the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Sate Republican Party</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> said he also has a record of accomplishments from his 10 years in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="19">   "I have a record of accomplishments that make me the best candidate to run against <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Patty Murray</ENAMEX>," he said.
</P><P ID="20">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX>, a Spokane native, has served as a <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">U.S.</ENAMEX> Representative since being elected in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1994</TIMEX>. He is a graduate of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington State University</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Gonzaga University School of Law</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="21">   As a member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Congress</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> serves on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Committee on Appropriations</ENAMEX>, as well as the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">House</ENAMEX> Science Committee</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="22">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nethercutt</ENAMEX> is married to the former <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mary Beth Socha</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Summerville</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">S.C</ENAMEX>. and has two children, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Meredith</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Elliott</ENAMEX>.
</P><P ID="23">   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">George Nethercutt...candidate</ENAMEX> for U.S. Senate
</P>   






 










<P ID="24">Webmaster
</P><P ID="25">  Copyright 
<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>
, 
</P>




