
<P ID="1">Pioneers end G'view's season
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">11/8/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">OMAK</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX>'s power-I offense proved to be too much to overcome for the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Grandview High School</ENAMEX> football team <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   The Pioneers claimed a 28-12 opening round <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> win over <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> to earn the right to move on to the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> playoffs. The Greyhounds (3-3, 3-6) saw their season come to a close.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> was poised several times to take the early lead on the Pioneers' home field, but three first quarter stops by <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX> after the 'Hounds had driven the ball deep into Pioneer territory thwarted any such hopes.   First year <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview Coach Dustin Lamb</ENAMEX> said his club had three red zone scoring opportunities in the opening period. "But on two of them we had dropped passes in crucial situations, and with the other we had a penalty that backed us up."   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX> also snuffed a couple of other <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> drives in the first half when the Pioneers came up with a pair of interceptions.   The 'Hounds were forced into playing catch-up football after <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX> posted three touchdowns in the second quarter. Two of the TD's came on passes, from Pioneer QB Cody Campbell to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brenden Kaermingk</ENAMEX>.   "They had us down 21-0 at the half," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX>.   Neither club could muster much of anything in the third quarter. But in the final period of play, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> made a run at the Pioneers. The Greyhounds finally got on the scoreboard when their quarterback, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Brandon Artz</ENAMEX>, hit running back <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Silas Hansen</ENAMEX> with a 24-yard scoring strike. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> followed up the TD with another touchdown toss to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX>, the second one a 22-yarder. The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX> hook-up cut <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX>'s lead to 21-12.   The Pioneers didn't allow <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> to get any closer, though. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Omak</ENAMEX> put an insurance touchdown on the scoreboard to account for the final 28-12 score.   The Greyhounds put up some decent numbers on offense, despite being limited to two touchdowns on the night. Rushing-wise, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> tallied 88 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> got most of the yardage, gaining 63 yards on 17 carries. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Frank Medina</ENAMEX> toted the ball six times and picked up 17 yards for <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX>, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">James Vela</ENAMEX> totaling eight yards on three carries. Through the air, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX> was 19-for-35 for 176 yards. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Vela</ENAMEX> grabbed 10 of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Artz</ENAMEX>'s passes and picked up 93 yards on the receptions. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hansen</ENAMEX> had three catches for 54 yards, with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kevin Concienne</ENAMEX> gaining 25 yards on four receptions and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Medina</ENAMEX> hauling in two passes for four yards.   The Pioneers tallied just over 350 total yards on the offensive side of the ball.   In assessing his first year as coach of the 'Hounds, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said he is pleased with how <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Grandview</ENAMEX> fared this season.   "We were in every game, with the exception of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">East Valley</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Othello</ENAMEX> contests," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Lamb</ENAMEX> said. "For our seniors, it was their second straight appearance in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">District</ENAMEX> playoffs.   "I compliment our seniors for a good season, especially with having to learn new stuff <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this year</TIMEX>.   "And, we played a lot of younger kids this season. By no means is our cubboard bare," he added.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

