
<P ID="1">MOOvin' out
</P><P ID="2"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Story</ENAMEX> by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bob Story</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">10/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">"Merry <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Christmas</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">City Councilman John Torch</ENAMEX> exclaimed joyfully <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> after the announcement that the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX> family had agreed to sell its 150-acre feedlot to the city.   Following a 25-minute specially called executive session <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">evening</TIMEX>, city officials reconvened into open session and released details on the impending <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> purchase of the cattle feedlot owned by the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX>'s. The purchase of the land, located west of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> between <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Outlook Road</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima Valley Highway</ENAMEX>, is being viewed by many as not only a quality of life improvement for local citizens, but as a way to boost economic development in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   "A city can grow by default or by design, and this is by design," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Torch</ENAMEX> said.   The <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> will be paid to the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX> family in three installments, all tied to the phased closure of the cattle operation and the clean-up of the feedlot. Under the terms of the agreement, the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX>'s will not have any more cattle delivered to the feedlot after <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">February of next year</TIMEX>. The agreement also stipulates that all cattle will be removed from the feedlot no later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Aug. 31 of next year</TIMEX>, and that the clean-up of the site by the feedlot owners will be completed by <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">July 31, 2006</TIMEX>. The clean-up is to include the removal of corrals, outbuildings, manure and "black soil." The <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX>'s have also agreed to not operate a feedlot within a 20-mile radius of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>.   Unlike past proposals in recent years to purchase the feedlot, where local citizens would have had to vote in a bond issue to fund the buyout of the property, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> residents aren't being asked to dig into their pockets this time. The city is financing the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2.5 million</NUMEX> purchase by making an internal loan to itself, from invested reserves that are yielding low returns.   "We're utilizing our existing cash reserves," <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tom Rockford</ENAMEX> said <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>, hastening to point out that raising taxes or implementing fees isn't required to complete the deal.   "It's a real win-win situation," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> added.   He said the city intends on recouping the money it spends on the purchase of the feedlot by reselling the land to developers. As of right now, he said, the intention is not for the city to hold on to any of the property. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> detailed that the 150 acres will be available for development as soon as the clean-up is complete and municipal services are extended to the property.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> said the agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX> family comes after several months of serious discussions.   The 15 or so people who attended <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s meeting gave the city council and city staff several rounds of exuberant applause as the council signed the resolution that makes the purchase official. One of those in attendance, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ed Werkhoven</ENAMEX>, took the opportunity to praise those involved with the deal.   "I congratulate everyone for their persistence on this," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Werkhoven</ENAMEX> said. "You found a way for all of us to win."   The vote to approve the purchase agreement was unanimous by the city council-a rare occurrence considering the volatility and make-up of the group when dealing with major issues in the past. But, there was no conflict <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>. All seven of the council members were in whole-hearted accord on the matter.   The praise for the deal that was brokered ranged from <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> describing <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX>'s actions as "...a big day for all of us," to Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> singling out <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX> as having putting forth a tremendous effort to come to an agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX> family. Newly appointed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Raul Martinez</ENAMEX> added his acclaim, citing the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City</ENAMEX> Attorney <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX>, as well as <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rockford</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> also praised the sellers.   "I thank the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX>'s for coming to the table (on this agreement)," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Martinez</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> exclaimed she was excited to be a part of this agreement with the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monson</ENAMEX> family, calling it "...a great value for the citizens of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>."   Agreeing with her was <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Jim Sarducci</ENAMEX>, who said it's a wonderful opportunity for the city. "This is the kind of economic development we need to see," he said.   Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX> might have summed it up best, when he said, "It's truly an investment for the community of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>."   The feedlot in question has been blamed by many over the years as chiefly responsible for the air quality issues local residents complain of on an almost daily basis. The odor and dust problems are expected to dissipate with the removal of the approximate 2,500-head cattle operation. Some in the community speculate property values, especially those homes on <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s neighboring <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Harrison Hill</ENAMEX>, will increase once the westside corridor into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> has been transformed into a business or industrial district.   Local realtor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Hank Timmermans</ENAMEX>, though, isn't so sure local residents will see the value of their homes increase.   "I don't foresee any large increases in property values," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timmermans</ENAMEX> hesitantly answered when contacted <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">this morning</TIMEX>, adding that he was caught off-guard by the inquiry. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timmermans</ENAMEX> did explain that the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> area is comprised chiefly of moderate to low income families, and he doesn't believe there will ever be a large market for higher priced homes. He said if property values were to rise too much, most people living in the area would be unable to afford the purchase of higher priced homes.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kenny Nelson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">DK Bain Real Estate Inc.</ENAMEX> agreed with <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Timmermans</ENAMEX> that residential property values probably won't rise in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> as a result of the elimination of the dust and odor problems.   "But the quality of life will definitely be a major improvement," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Nelson</ENAMEX> said emphatically. "Maybe people will start looking at moving to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> instead of looking to move into <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX> or <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Zillah</ENAMEX>."
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

