
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> withdraws support of outreach program
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1/13/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilwoman Jennie Angel</ENAMEX> wanted to know where the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> stood on its support of the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Valley Rural Enterprise Community</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>) Outreach Program. Well, she got her answer at this <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> meeting.   In a 3-2 vote, with Councilman John Torch not casting his vote on the matter, the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">City Council</ENAMEX> opted to withdraw its support of the community outreach program.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Alex de la Cruz</ENAMEX> joined <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> in voting to continue city support of the program. Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rex Luthor</ENAMEX>, Mayor <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pro-tem George Greenway</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman James Sarducci</ENAMEX> voted in favor of withdrawing the city's support.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Tom Seeger</ENAMEX> was not in attendance at <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Monday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>'s meeting, having received an excused absence the week prior.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>, who also sits on the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> board of directors, has headed up the community outreach effort for the non-profit agency. She also was instrumental in forming the partnership with the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City of Alderwood</ENAMEX>, and the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> in joining together to hold the meetings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> brought the issue before the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">last night</TIMEX> following recent discussions the governing body has had in trying to obtain all remaining money from the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> to help fund maintenance of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX> admitted he wasn't familiar with the outreach program, but wondered what the city's financial stake was. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Interim City</ENAMEX> Manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bruce Rinz</ENAMEX> said the city's financial contribution for participating in the program is minimal, consisting mainly of compensatory time and in some Sings overtime pay. <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">City</ENAMEX> staff members, including police officers and firemen, have been in attendance frequently at the community outreach meetings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Rinz</ENAMEX> clarified a concern of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">de la Cruz</ENAMEX>, saying if the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Council</ENAMEX> opted to not continue its support of the outreach program, then none of the city employees would be compensated for their involvement with the meetings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> praised <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> for her efforts, but wondered if the money couldn't be spent for more useful programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> said the meetings he attended had very few people in attendance. He also talked to two families, who had attended past outreach meetings, and they told him they wouldn't attend again "because it was a waste of time."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX> asked <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> what the <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$15,000</NUMEX> allocated for the outreach programs was used for and if the city could be compensated for its financial expenditures.   "I think the concept is excellent. I really do," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Greenway</ENAMEX>. "I am concerned about (how) the money is being spent."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the money is used for postage, supplies and other needed items in getting the word out about the meetings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> also said she can ask if the city could be financially compensated, but said it was her initial understanding the city's contributions were in-kind.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the outreach program has tried to gear its presentations around what was identified in a community survey as major concerns.   "The program is kind of evolving," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> defended the reason for community members not attending meetings. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said some meetings were held at the wrong times throughout the year. She added not all meetings were sparsely attended. In <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">May 2003</TIMEX>, 40 people attended a meeting in the downtown area, which she said greatly benefited the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> Housing Up! rehabilitation program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the meetings have been averaging between 20 to 25 people.   "It depends on the area and the time of the meeting," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX>.   In response to a question from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> citizen <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">M'Liss Bierlink</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> said the door-to-door efforts to inform people about the meetings reaches between 300 to 400 homes. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bierlink</ENAMEX> said it was unfortunate that only 20 to 25 people on average were attending the meetings.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> said he felt the outreach program was going into too many different directions, instead of focusing on a few concerns. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Luthor</ENAMEX> also felt the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> would do better to give the outreach dollars to the police department to help the agency expand its community outreach programs. The mayor also expressed concern about the sustainability of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> outreach program.   Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jim Stevens</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> heralded the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Angel</ENAMEX> with the outreach program, but said he felt the remaining <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> money should be used for other programs. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> suggested using the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> money to fund the efforts of <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Danny Mendoza</ENAMEX> to build a skate park at <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">SunnyView Park</ENAMEX>. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Stevens</ENAMEX> said he felt the skate park could help unite the communities of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Councilman Sarducci</ENAMEX> was equally impressed with the purpose of the outreach program, but said he felt the meetings, some of which he had attended, weren't very well organized. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> expressed concerns about the financial management of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">REC</ENAMEX> program. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX> said he has tried to get in contact with <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> grants manager <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Steve Hill</ENAMEX> over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last two weeks</TIMEX> to obtain information on the program and hasn't heard anything back yet.   "I am just worried about who is running the show right now," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sarducci</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">John Panni</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or email him at mPanni@hawkpress.com
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

