
<P ID="1">State WASL achievement gaps narrow, local schools make significant gains
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">9/3/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">"We are beginning to achieve momentum" said new <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sandra Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX>.   Her comments echo the praise given by the leader of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> state education, Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Terry Bergeson</ENAMEX>, who on <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> proclaimed major increases in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Assessment</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Student Learning</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASL</ENAMEX>) scores given to fourth, seventh and 10th graders.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> singled out a number of school districts, including <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, that have made notable gains in their <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASL</ENAMEX> scores.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s fourth, seventh and 10th grade students reached higher levels of achievement on the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASL</ENAMEX> than they ever have before," she said.   Scores in math, reading, writing and science rose in every grade across the state, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> said.   "In addition, outstanding gains were made in many of the districts that were struggling to achieve academic success," she added.   Among those were schools in the <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Granger</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Selah</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mount Adams</ENAMEX>, and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> school districts <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> said. Each of these districts made outstanding gains in math and reading on all levels.   "All of these gains can be attributed to the hard work of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX>'s wonderful teachers in partnership with support staff, administration, parents community and business leaders and, of course, the students," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton School District</ENAMEX> is one of five schools in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> to show outstanding improvements in state test scores, agreed Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jane Gutting</ENAMEX>, Superintendent of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Educational Service District</ENAMEX> (<ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX>) 105.   "Significant gains have been made at all of our schools in the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">ESD</ENAMEX>," Gutting said. "There are many such success stories," she said.   "We're very excited that our district's students' test scores are increasing," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said. "Even the students are excited about their achievements." .   Mabton Junior High students showed <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> increases in reading, <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20 percent</NUMEX> in writing and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12 percent</NUMEX> gains in math, while <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Mabton High School</ENAMEX> students made <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">21 percent</NUMEX> gains in writing and <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">14 percent</NUMEX> gains in math, said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Keith Morris</ENAMEX>, who is principal for both the schools.   Meanwhile in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Washington Elementary School</ENAMEX>'s use of the Reading First program is credited with helping to achieve double digit gains in that building's reading scores, said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Washington Elementary</ENAMEX> students showed a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">27.6 percent</NUMEX> increase in reading, as well as a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">17 percent</NUMEX> increase in writing and a whooping <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44 percent</NUMEX> gain in math," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> schools all made gains in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASL</ENAMEX> reading achievements. "We very proud of all of our schools for the significant gains being made," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> did an outstanding job of boosting its achievement scores," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX>'s results from the 2003-04 <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASL</ENAMEX> were its best over the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past five years</TIMEX>, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> explained.   "Our fourth grade <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASL</ENAMEX> reading scores have shown an upward trend and steady growth for the <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">past eight years</TIMEX>," he said.   In addition, four of the six <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> district schools also made significant gains in math, ranging from <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">0.6 percent</NUMEX> to <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">44.2 percent</NUMEX>.   "Five of our schools also made upward of <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">16.6 percent</NUMEX> gains in writing," he added   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Pioneer Elementary School</ENAMEX> had its highest gains ever with a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">20.2 percent</NUMEX> gain in reading and a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">12.1 percent</NUMEX> gain in math scores. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outlook Elementary School</ENAMEX> made a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">3.9 percent</NUMEX> gain in reading.   In addition, <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Harrison Middle School</ENAMEX> seventh graders showed a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.9 percent</NUMEX> gain in reading scores while <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> 10th graders showed a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">5.9 percent</NUMEX> gain. <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">PRIDE High School</ENAMEX> students turned in a <NUMEX TYPE="PERCENT">4.4 percent</NUMEX> gain in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">WASL</ENAMEX> reading scores.   Math scores also showed gains at the elementary schools and at the middle school.   Credit for many of the gains made by the districts is the result of the implementation of research-based curriculum changes. For example, in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX>, improvements were made by adopting school-wide improvement programs and a dramatic change in teaching practices, explained school officials.   "We have hit upon the formula for success," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Pasiero-Davis</ENAMEX> said.   "We are seeing steady gains year after year and that is the most powerful way to achieve momentum," she said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> credits the gains to the willingness of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Mabton</ENAMEX> education staff to share teaching practices and to adopt change as needed. He also credits the students with taking a more active role in their education.   "We are focused on quality instruction in every classroom with high expectations for all students," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Morris</ENAMEX>' comments were echoed by <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>, who said <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> teachers' efforts are similarly based on research-based curriculum changes. "   "The good news is we are seeing benchmark growth from fall to spring," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> said.   ""It's clear that our decade-long efforts to improve <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Washington</ENAMEX> schools are working," agreed <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX>.   "We know now how to improve students' reading comprehension, writing and mathematics skills. The primary challenge now is to commit the resources to spread these strategies across the state so that every school and district can benefit from them," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bergeson</ENAMEX> said.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Jamie Smart</ENAMEX> can be contacted at   (509) 837-4500, or you can e-mail her at jSmart@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

