
<P ID="1">Grads bid farewell to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mel Sacher</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">6/7/2004</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Leading 275 students onto the field of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Clem Senn Field</ENAMEX>, 80-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Roy Culver</ENAMEX> was the oldest graduate to receive his diploma at the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> commencement exercise <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">last Friday</TIMEX> <TIMEX TYPE="TIME">night</TIMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> graduated as part of the Operation Recognition program, which allows military veterans who left school early to join World War II ranks to receive high school diplomas. As a part of the ceremony <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX> not only received his diploma, but a long-awaited standing ovation from the crowd.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Culver</ENAMEX>'s recognition set the tone of the event, at which both <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">School District</ENAMEX> Superintendent Dr. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Aaron Bones</ENAMEX> and class speaker, American History and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">CWP</ENAMEX> teacher <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Monty Johnson</ENAMEX>, encouraged the young graduates to be part of their communities and vote.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX> also encouraged the graduates to, no later than <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Saturday</TIMEX>, sit down and think about what their goals are and to raise them.   "It's important to set your goals high because you can do it," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bones</ENAMEX>. "You are successful. Don't be afraid to fail or challenge your future."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> addressed the class saying, "You're the sons and daughters of this community. Take pride in yourselves. We have invested in you and we have invested well."   He said there is much that faces the graduates as they leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> and enter the world.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX> said as <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> thrives and grows local residents will try to better it with our own interests in mind, to draw back some of the recent graduates.   He encouraged the youths to become a part of their community, whether it be <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> or another town. He encouraged the youths to find a community and become a volunteer, join a service club or help a friend in need.   "Don't consider your education complete," he said, encouraging the young adults to be constant learners, informing themselves about what is going on in the world around them.   He also encouraged the youths to participate in the country's democracy.   "Many of you are 18, or soon will be. I encourage you to vote <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">this fall</TIMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>.   He added that to vote and not know what you're voting for is worse than not voting at all.   "I know the world holds a lot for you," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Johnson</ENAMEX>. "So be informed, participate in the process and never ever sell yourselves short."   Also speaking at the graduation were <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">salutatorian Amy Kilian</ENAMEX> and co-<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">valedictorians Stacey Gorski</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Joshua Barr</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said as an eighth grader she was sick a lot and her grades began to slip. In danger of getting a C, she went to her teacher to beg for a better grade.   In her mind, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said, the sky turned black, the teacher sprouted devil horns and bellowed down on her NO!, when in fact that was all in her mind.   In reality, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said, when she was in eighth grade she was able to get a B in the class she was afraid she would get a C in and it was the last B she ever got. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said memories are just fact-perception and image.   "Scientists have proven that you choose how you remember things," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Kilian</ENAMEX> said she will always remember the funny moments with her classmates, including the slow-motion portions of the drama club's presentation of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Joseph</ENAMEX> and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat.   She said if her fellow classmates' memories include <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Miss</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Schuette</ENAMEX> sending them home because their shorts had a 2" inseam, they probably shouldn't wear those shorts to a job interview.      She encouraged her classmates as they leave <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> to spice up their lives, just like they spice up their memories.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> said that it was eight years before that he decided to be valedictorian. He said it was because of friends, teachers and family that he was able to make it.   "For better or for worse they form the core of who you are," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>.   As a middle school student, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> remembers the day his father asked him if he wanted to go to the library.   "Now, it wasn't the library downtown, but it was the one in <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Richland</ENAMEX>," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, explaining that his father took four hours out of his life just to take him to the library.   "The little things can mean so much," said <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX>, who is always reading, which he said has been instrumental in his academic success.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> said as a youngster he didn't want to learn to read, but his mother got him interested, which changed his life.   As a second grader, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> remembers being punished for reading ahead, which almost squelched his interest in education.   "Teachers," he said, "Your job is not just to guide your students though a series of lessons. Don't worry about what they'll learn <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">next year</TIMEX>, there are always things to learn."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Barr</ENAMEX> said that through his life, God has been his strength.   "He has been my shield, my rock and my saviour," he said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX>, an award-winning science fair contest participant, examined the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> as if it were a science fair project.   She said the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> science fair project would be called "Driven, Determined and Dedicated."   She said her classmates have not only shown these qualities in their success, but also in their friendships to each other.   The hypotheses of the project, she said, is "We, the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX>, can conquer and do anything with hard work, diligence and creativity."   The goal of the project is to use creativity, put in all you have, be diligent and successful, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> said.   She said the class has plenty of evidence to support the goals for their projects with pictures of family and friends, state games and meets traveled to, some of which were won and some lost, drama productions, homecoming and Senior Follies, which raised <NUMEX TYPE="MONEY">$2,100</NUMEX>.   She said the conclusion would read that the class of <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">2004</TIMEX> can conquer anything because they are driven, determined and dedicated.   "You see," she said, "It's scientifically proven that you will succeed."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gorski</ENAMEX> was later presented the Outstanding Senior Girl award. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Tanner Kellogg</ENAMEX> was named <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Outstanding Senior Boy</ENAMEX>. Outstanding Senior Boy Athlete was awarded to R.J. Elizondo and Isley Gonzalez was presented Outstanding Senior Girl Athlete.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

