
<P ID="1"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> truancy commissioner works to keep kids in school
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">4/14/2002</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4"><ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">YAKIMA</ENAMEX> - <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">State</ENAMEX> law makes it mandatory for every child between the ages of six and 18 to attend school and it's Truancy Commissioner <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Sid Ottem</ENAMEX>'s job to ensure that all of the youth of the Lower <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Valley</ENAMEX> are doing just that.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX>, who has served as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> truancy commissioner since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">January</TIMEX>, said he travels to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> to oversee cases where students, for one reason or another, are not attending school on a regular basis. He said he works out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Municipal Court</ENAMEX> when he is in the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX>, often times seeing as many as 20 to 25 cases during his time here.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> explained that because of state law, every school must keep attendance records noting when a student is in school and when a student is absent. He said if a student is found to have 10 unexcused absences over the course of a year or seven unexcused absences in a month, the school district brings a petition before the court, which both the student in question and their parents must respond to. This is where <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> steps in.   He explained that the process begins with a petition hearing, during which time a student has to explain the reason for their absence. It is during this time that the court also works to determine if the school's attendance records are correct. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said once this hearing takes place the court will typically take jurisdiction over the student, meaning that they now held responsible for attending school by not only their parents and the school district, but also by the court.   "Now the court is going to be involved in this process," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said.   He said if a student continues to have unexcused absences the school district will once again submit a petition and this time a contempt hearing is held. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said during the hearing the student comes into court with their parents to explain the reason for their continued absence.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said at this point if the court finds the student's explanation of the absences to be unsatisfactory there are provisions that can take place, including everything from performing community service to putting them in a juvenile facility for up to seven days.   "Our main goal is to get the student in school," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX>, who has been a <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">court commissioner</ENAMEX></ENAMEX> in <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Yakima County</ENAMEX> since <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">1999</TIMEX>, said serving as a truancy commissioner is not his only responsibility. He said he also serves as a water rights adjudication commissioner, which is his main focus.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said he first got involved as the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> truancy commissioner because of his interest in school and students. He noted that he served as a football coach for <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">LaSalle High School</ENAMEX> for two years.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said he enjoys serving as a truancy commissioner, especially when it comes to helping students figure out ways they can succeed and do better.   He said although he's only held the position for several months, he is finding that most of the parents he sees every other <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">Wednesday</TIMEX> are interested in their student going to school.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said working out of the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Municipal Court</ENAMEX> he deals with students from various <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lower Valley</ENAMEX> school districts, from <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Toppenish</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">White Swan</ENAMEX> to <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>.   "We're just trying to provide another opportunity to keep students interested in going to school," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ottem</ENAMEX> said of the position. He noted that sometimes the solution to an attendance problem can be as simple as ironing out communication between the school district, the parents and the student.
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

