
<P ID="1">Young cattleman hopes to grow herd from four to 60
</P><P ID="2">Story by: <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX>
</P><P ID="3">Date Published to Web: <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">12/30/2003</TIMEX>
</P><P ID="4">Fourteen-year-old Outlook resident <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne Mandrell</ENAMEX> just recently used the money he had been saving from livestock sales through <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4-H</ENAMEX> to start building his own herd.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> said one day he hopes to turn the four head of registered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Angus</ENAMEX> heifers he purchased <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">three months ago</TIMEX> into a herd of up to 60 cattle.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX>, who grew up in the cattle industry, said the animals are currently housed on five acres of pasture located behind the <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Lester Road</ENAMEX> home he shares with his parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>.   As if purchasing and caring for his own animals isn't enough responsibility for the 14-year-old <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Alderwood</ENAMEX> <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">High School</ENAMEX> student, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> also recently became a junior member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Angus Association</ENAMEX>.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> said he decided to become a member after the person who sold him the registered heifers talked to him about the advantages of being associated with the national organization.   "[He] said it would help me some day," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> said.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> and his father, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX>, explained that being a member of the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Angus Association</ENAMEX> will give the younger <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> access to a higher caliber of breeding services, which will help produce higher quality offspring and therefore a higher market price.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX>'s parents, <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Bill</ENAMEX> and <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX>, both agree their son has always shown an interest in being involved in the cattle industry. Over the years the Mandrells had a herd of 50 to 60 head of cattle their children helped them care for.   "<ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Wayne</ENAMEX> always planned on being a cattleman," <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Gloria</ENAMEX> said of her son, who is the youngest of four children. "He always had the interest and the eye for it."   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> is also a six-year member of <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">4-H</ENAMEX> and is in his first year as an <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">FFA</ENAMEX> member. <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> credited the two groups for helping him choose the four heifers he did.   <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mandrell</ENAMEX> said he plans on breeding his animals in <TIMEX TYPE="DATE">April 2004</TIMEX> and hopes to be able to sell his own heifers in five or six years.   Also joining the <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Angus Association</ENAMEX> are <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Mark and Renee Nelson</ENAMEX> of <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Grandview</ENAMEX>. The couple just recently became members of the organization.   The <ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">American Angus Association</ENAMEX>, with more than 34,000 active adult and junior members, is the largest beef cattle registry association in the world. Its computerized records include detailed information on more than 14 million registered <ENAMEX TYPE="LOCATION">Angus</ENAMEX>.   . <ENAMEX TYPE="PERSON">Ellie Olmsen</ENAMEX> can be contacted at (509) 837-4500, or e-mail her at eOlmsen@hawkpress.com   
</P>

 




<P ID="5"><ENAMEX TYPE="ORGANIZATION">Webmaster  Copyright Hawk Press Inc.</ENAMEX>, 
</P>

